<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00007527">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Joseph Pain</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00007527">
                    <persName>
                      Joseph Pain
                        (Ballard County, Kentucky, common laborer)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="c1820"></birth>
                      <death when="unknown"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Ballard County, Kentucky, common laborer. Tennessee native. Married to Mary L. Dyre Pain on February 27, 1850. Father of Mary Pain, William J. Pain, David Pain, Mira Pain, Bird Pain, Louisa Pain, Benjamin F. Pain, Lucy Pain, and Elizabeth Pain. Farmer in Van Buren County, Tennessee, in 1850. Common laborer in Ballard County in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1850), Population Schedules, Tennessee, Van Buren County, District 5, p. 381. <em>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Ballard County, Picketts, p. 115. <em>Tennessee State Marriages, 1780-2002</em>, microfilm, Van Buren County, 1850, Tennessee State Library and Archives Nashville, TN (accessed via Ancestry).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
