<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00006584">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Benjamin Grant Willis</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00006584">
                    <persName>
                      Benjamin Grant Willis
                        (Bracken County, Kentucky, attorney)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1823-03-09"></birth>
                      <death when="1884-02-18"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Bracken County, Kentucky, attorney. Bourbon County, Kentucky native. Son of Benjamin Garrett Willis and Ann Moseby Grant Willis. Married to Clara J. Payne Willis on July 29, 1845. Father of Harry P. Willis, Benjamin P. Willis, Letitia Willis, Annie Willis, Clara Willis, and Charles Willis. Attended Indiana University at Bloomington, Indiana, from 1833 to 1836. Attended Miami University in Oxford, Ohio, from 1839 to 1840. Studied law under James M. Preston in Burlington, Kentucky, from 1840 to 1842. Admitted to the bar in 1842. Attorney in Burlington from 1842 to 1844. Attorney in Helena, Arkansas, from 1844 to 1848. Moved to Brookville, Kentucky, in 1848, and resumed the practice of law. Attorney in Bracken County in 1850. Judge of the Bracken County Court from 1851 to 1854. Member of the Democratic Party. Attorney in Bracken County in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>The Biographical Encyclopædia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</em> (Cincinnati, OH: J. M. Armstrong and Company, 1878), p. 417-418; <em>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Bracken County, p. 477; <em>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Bracken County, Germantown, the Eastern District, p. 127; <em>Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Bracken County, Brooksville, p. 7; <em>Find A Grave</em>, &quot;Benjamin G. Willis (1823-1884),&quot; Memorial #114276009, http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=114276009 (accessed May 26, 2017).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
