<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00007185">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Robert H. Yantis</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00007185">
                    <persName>
                      Robert H. Yantis
                        (Garrard County, Kentucky, physician)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1838-02-02"></birth>
                      <death when="1918-09-19"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Garrard County, Kentucky, physician. Kentucky native. Son of James H. Yantis and Margaret A. Stewart Yantis. Married to Mary Yantis. Father of Maggie Yantis and James Yantis. Resident of Garrard County in 1850. Physician in Garrard County in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Garrard County, Division 1, p. 266. <em>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Garrard County, Lancaster, p. 12. <em>Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fleming County, Poplar Plains, p. 16. <em>Vital Statistics Original Death Certificates – Microfilm (1911-1964)</em>, Fleming County, 1918,  file no. 22462, Microfilm rolls #7016130-7041803, Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives, Frankfort, Kentucky. KYR-0001-029-0573.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
