<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00006527">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Henry Crecy Yarrow</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Samuel T. Whittaker</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00006527">
                    <persName>
                      Henry Crecy Yarrow
                        (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, physician and soldier)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1840-11-19"></birth>
                      <death when="1929-07-02"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, physician and soldier. Philadelphia native. Son of John Yarrow and Caroline Crecy Yarrow. Married to Anna Provand Dryburgh on April 10, 1862. Father of John Yarrow. Received early education in Philadelphia private schools and in Geneva, Switzerland. Studied medicine under Dr. J. L. Ludlow and J. J. Woodward. Graduated from the University of Pennsylvania Medical School in 1861. Practived medicine in Philadelphia in 1861. Medical examiner of recruits in 1861. Assistant surgeon in the 5th Pennsylvania Volunteer Cavalry Regiment (&quot;Cameron Dragoons&quot;) from July 1861 to January 1862. Acting Assistant Surgeon of United State Volunteers and served as the Executive Officer of the Broad and Cherry Street United States Army Hospital in Philadelphia from 1862 to 1866. Founding member of the Hardwick Oil Company in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, in 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>&quot;Yarrow, Henry Crecy&quot; in <em>Physicians and Surgeons of America: A Collection of Biographical Sketches of the Regular Medical Profession</em>, Irving A. Watson, A.M., M.D., ed. and comp. (Concord, N.H.: Republican Press Association, 1896), p. 683-684; <em>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1850), Population Schedules, Pennsylvania, Philadelphia County, Philadelphia, South Mulberry Ward, p. 50; <em>Index to Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers who Served in Organizations From State of Pennsylvania</em>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M554, Roll 0135; <em>Find A Grave</em>, &quot;Dr. Henry Crecy &quot;H.C.&quot; Yarrow (1840-1929),&quot; Memorial #49339884, http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=49339884&amp;ref=acom (accessed May 23, 2017); KYR-0001-007-0332.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
