<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00003723">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Adam Rankin</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00003723">
                    <persName>
                      Adam Rankin
                        (Henderson County, Kentucky, court clerk)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="c1834"></birth>
                      <death when="unknown"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Henderson County, Kentucky, court clerk. Kentucky native. Son of William Rankin and Frances Rankin. Clerk of the Henderson Circuit Court from 1862 to 1870.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Henderson County, Henderson, District 1, p. 270. Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Henderson County, Henderson, Ward 3, p. 12. KYR-0001-029-0511. William T. Samuels, <em>Annual Report of the Auditor of Public Accounts, of the State of Kentucky, for the Fiscal Year Ending October 10, 1865</em> (Frankfort, KY: George D. Prentice, 1866), p. 11. William T. Samuels, <em>Annual Report of the Auditor of Public Accounts, of the State of Kentucky, for the Fiscal Year Ending October 10, 1867</em> (Frankfort, KY: John H. Harney, 1867), p. 356. D. Howard Smith, <em>Annual Report of the Auditor of Public Accounts, of the State of Kentucky, for the Fiscal Year Ending October 10, 1869</em> (Frankfort, KY: S. I. M. Major, 1869), p. 172. D. Howard Smith, <em>Annual Report of the Auditor of Public Accounts, of the State of Kentucky, for the Fiscal Year Ending October 10, 1870</em> (Frankfort, KY: S. I. M. Major, 1871), p. 162.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
