<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002188">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Lewis S. Lee</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Krista Kinslow</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002188">
                    <persName>
                      Lewis S. Lee
                        (Ballard County, Kentucky, sheriff)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1810-02-17"></birth>
                      <death when="unknown"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Ballard County, Kentucky, sheriff. Davidson County, Tennessee, native. Son of John Lee and Jennie Tuggle Lee. Married to Nancy Watson Lee in September 1829. Married to Mary Lee. Father of Robert B. Lee, John M. Lee, Sarah L. Lee, Henry H. Lee, and Thirga A. Lee. Relocated to Ballard County in 1833. Farmer in Ballard County in 1850. Deputy sheriff in Ballard County from 1855 to 1858. Sheriff of Ballard County in 1858 to 1866.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>J. H. Battle, W. H. Perrin, and G. C. Kniffin, <em>Kentucky: A History of the State</em>, Part II (Louisville: F. A. Battey Publishing Company, 1885), p. 138-39. <em>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Ballard County, p. 255A. <em>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Ballard County, McCuistians district, p. 183. <em>Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Ballard County, District No. 2, p. 6.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
