<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00003203">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John W. Cardwell</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Krista Kinslow</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Krista Kinslow</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Krista Kinslow</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00003203">
                    <persName>
                      John W. Cardwell
                        (Mercer County, Kentucky, bank cashier)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1809-02-01"></birth>
                      <death when="1882-02-09"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Mercer County, Kentucky, bank cashier. Kentucky native. Married to Sophia B. Cardwell. Father of John T. Cardwell, Tilulia Cardwell, James M. Cardwell, Susan L. Cardwell, Thomas M. Cardwell, Samuel Creed Cardwell, Wesley K. Cardwell, Nannie Cardwell, and L. Davis Cardwell. Trustee for the Harrodsburg Church in 1842. Notary public in Mercer County. Resident of Mercer County in 1850. Owned three enslaved persons in 1850. Bank cashier at the Harrodsburg Savings Institution, in Harrodsburg, Kentucky, from 1860 to 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, District No. 1; <em>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, District No. 1; <em>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer county, Harrodsburg, p. 1-2; <em>Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Mercer County, Harrodsburg, p. 1; &quot;An Act Authorizing Joel P. Williams and Others, to Sell a Certain Church in Harrodsburg,&quot; <em>Acts of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, Passed at December Session, 1841</em> (Frankfort, Ky.: A. G. Hodges, State Printer, 1842), 174; <em>Journal of the Senate of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</em> (Frankfort, Ky.: A. G. Hodges, State Printer, 1841), 387; <em>Journal of the Senate of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</em> (Frankfort, Ky.: A. G. Hodges, State Printer, 1851), 458; <em>Find A Grave</em>, &quot;John Wesley Cardwell (1809-1882),&quot; Memorial #100176979, http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=100176979 (accessed August 30, 2017); KYR-0001-007-0051; KYR-0002-225-0043; KYR-0001-019-0109; KYR-0001-020-1640.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
