<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00001705">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Daniel Wolsey Voorhees</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Courtney Buchkoski</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00001705">
                    <persName>
                      Daniel Wolsey Voorhees
                        (Representative and a Senator from Indiana)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1827-09-26"></birth>
                      <death when="1897"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Representative and a Senator from Indiana. Liberty Township, Ohio, native. Graduated from Indiana Asbury University in Greencastle, Indiana, in 1849. Married to Anna Hardesty Voorhees. Children included Mary Voorhees, Harriet Cecelia Voorhees, James P Voorhees, and Reese H Voorhees. Admitted to the bar in 1851 in Covington, Indiana. Moved to Terre Haute and continued the practice of law. Unsuccessful candidate for election in 1856 to the Thirty-fifth Congress. United States district attorney for Indiana 1858-1861. Elected as a Democrat to the Thirty-seventh and Thirty-eighth Congresses and served from March 4, 1861 to March 3, 1865. Presented credentials as a Member-elect to the Thirty-ninth Congress and served from March 4, 1865, to February 23, 1866, when he was succeeded by Henry D. Washburn, who contested the election. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>&quot;VOORHEES, Daniel Wolsey - Biographical Information,&quot;  http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=V000116 (accessed March 6, 2017). </p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
