<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00007722">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Charles G. Wintersmith</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00007722">
                    <persName>
                      Charles G. Wintersmith
                        (Hardin County, Kentucky, attorney)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1812-07-15"></birth>
                      <death when="1881-10-14"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Hardin County, Kentucky, attorney. Kentucky native. Attorney in Hardin County in 1850. Owned five enslaved persons in 1850. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, from Hardin County, in 1838, 1847, and from 1851 to 1855. Speaker of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1853 to 1854.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hardin County, Northern District, p. 306. <em>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Hardin County, Upper or Northern District. <em>Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hardin County, Elizabethtown, p. 41. Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <em>Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky</em>, vol. 2 (Covington, KY: Collins &amp; Co., 1874), 307.  Zachariah Frederick Smith, <em>The History of Kentucky</em> (Louisville: Courier-Journal Printing Company, 1892), 899. <em>Find A Grave</em>, &quot;Judge Charles G. Wintersmith (1812-1881),&quot; Memorial #11924891, http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=11924891&amp;ref=acom (accessed June 27, 2017).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
