<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00007170">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Aquilla C. Doyle</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00007170">
                    <persName>
                      Aquilla C. Doyle
                        (Fleming County, Kentucky, miller)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="c1810"></birth>
                      <death when="unknown"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Fleming County, Kentucky, miller. Kentucky native. Married to Fanny Hurst Doyle on January 6, 1835. Father of Martha A. Doyle, John H. Doyle, James Doyle, William Doyle, Parmelia Doyle, Eliza N. Doyle, and John F. Doyle. Wagon-maker in Fleming County in 1850. Miller in Fleming County in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fleming County, District 1, p. 340. Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fleming County, District 2, p. 58. Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fleming County, Poplar Plains, p. 8. Elizabeth Prather Ellsberry, comp., <em>Marriage Records of Fleming County, Kentucky, 1798-1851</em> (Chillicothe, MO: Elizabeth Prather Ellsberry, c1965), 1835 (accessed via Ancestry).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
