<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00004826">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Henry T. Duncan, Jr.</title>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
              <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
            </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
                <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
              <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
            </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00004826">
                    <persName>
                      Henry T. Duncan, Jr.
                        (Fayette County, Kentucky, law student)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="c1838"></birth>
                      <death when="unknown"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Fayette County, Kentucky, law student. Kentucky native. Son of Henry T. Duncan, Sr. and Eliza Duncan. Resident of Fayette County in 1850. Law student in Fayette County in 1860. Household owned twenty-one enslaved persons in 1850 and sixty-three in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, District 2, p. 254. <em>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, District 2. <em>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, District 1, p. 60. <em>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Fayette County, District 1, p. 41-42.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
