<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0490"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. W. Wake et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4609</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-277 to BR9-278</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency T. E. Bramlett, Governor of the State of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>The petition of the Subscribers, citizens of Lyon County, respectfully Showith: That one Issac Skimmerhorn, at the <date when="1859-10">October term 1859</date> of the Lyon Circuit Court, was endicted for the crime of felony, and at the <date when="1860-06">June term 1860</date>, the Said Skimmerhorn was admitted to bail in the Sum of Two Hundred and Fifty dollars, whereupon he executed Bond to the Commonwealth of Kentucky for the aforesaid sum of Two Hundred and Fifty dollars, with Elias Smith and W. J. Smith as his sureties for his appearance at the next term (<date when="1860-12">Dec 1860</date>) of the Court. And said Skimmerhorn, failing to make his appearance as required by Said Bond, at the said <date when="1860-12">Dec term 1860</date> the said Bond was taken as forfeited, and at the <date when="1863-12">Dec term 1863</date>, Judgement was rendered upon the Said Bond against John W. Clark, the administrator of Said Elias Smith, for the sum of <hi rend="underline">One Hundred and Twenty five dollars</hi>. Just after the bail Bond was taken as forfeited the Said W. J. Smith wor<hi rend="str">ked</hi> hauled the said Skimmerhorn and delivered him to the Jailor of Said county, and Sometime after this, the Said Skimmerhorn broke the jail and fled to Illinois, where report <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> said he died. The individual debts of Elias Smith ^are^ quite small, but his Security debts amount to thousands of dollars, and will consume the greater part of his estate. That Elias Smith befriended many poor men of the county, who were Striving to get along, there is no doubt, and for So=doing his estate now has to Suffer<pb/></p>
<p>Your petitioners therefore pray your Excellency to exercise your executive clemency in behalf of Said estate, and that your Excellency remit the Said Judgement, or So much thereof as may be deemed just and proper.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>R W Wake
<lb/>J. L. James Jr.
<lb/>Wm Steen
<lb/>W R Lester
<lb/>R M Ethridge
<lb/>James Boyd
<lb/>J. N. Holloway
<lb/>C. H. Boyd
<lb/>S. <unclear/>
<lb/>W H Long
<lb/>J W Ethridge
<lb/>John Long
<lb/>M. S. Lyon
<lb/>Jas M Bernbray
<lb/>G M Huggans
<lb/>Arch Hantor
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> T. Taylor
<lb/>R R O'Hara
<lb/>James OHara
<lb/>W. W. Hollman
<lb/>W H H Robertson
<lb/>S W Hawastern
<lb/>James H Catlete
<lb/>W. C. Noel
<lb/>W. C. Bigham
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Charles Wood
<lb/>J T Young Shff Lyon County
<lb/>W M Bowman
<lb/>Geo C. Lester
<lb/>W. P. Strubb
<lb/>Urey. Henry
<lb/>L M Cobb
<lb/>Robt. A. Leickson
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> B Paine
<lb/>O M. Jenkins
<lb/>W. W. Pinner
<lb/>J M Bigham
<lb/>John Stacker Jr
<lb/>W. W. Smith
<lb/>E Z Smith
<lb/>J C Holloway
<lb/>F. A. Wilson County Atty
<lb/>Robt L Cobb
<lb/>F. H. Skinner P J L C C
<lb/>A H Dudley Clerk Lyon Circuit Court
<lb/>T. J. Wattins<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>to be further considered<pb/></p>
<p>Lyon Cir Court
<lb/>vs
<lb/>H. J. Smith &amp; Admr of Chas Smith. J. W. Clarke
<lb/><date when="1863-12">Dec term/ 63</date>
<lb/>$250 -- 
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/><date when="1864-02-09">9th Feby 1864</date></p>
<p>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
