<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2615"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Stanford Mitchell to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7252</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-194 to BR16-195</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Barren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-03">3 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlette Governor of the State of Kentucky at Frankfort.</p>
<p>Your petitioners Standford Mitchel and Joseph E Bromfield very respectfully show to your Excellency. that Mark Mitchel and John Mitchel in <date when="1865-02">February 1865</date> was confined in the jail at Glasgow charged with Felony and your petitioners become their bail in the sum of Three hundred dollars <hi rend="underline">each</hi> for their appearance at Tompkinsville in Monroe county on the 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of the <date when="--04">aprile</date> Term thereafter to answer said charge They show that in good faith your petitioners procured them to attend court to answer said charge and after they made their appearance in court and asked to be tried they were informed by the court that no indictment had been found against them. They went off and when indictments were found they did not appear and said bonds were forfeited without any fault of your petitioners. They show that they are now both old men and have each of them large families to support and very little property In fact nothing which is not exempt from Levy except a small tract of land each worth about five hundred dollars and if the Judgments amounting to six hundred dollars are collected from them it will sweep away<pb/>
<lb/>their little homes and turn them out dependant tenants in their age and infirmities they show that the two defendants Mark and John Mitchel were sons of Stanford Mitchel and the said Stanford not being worth six hundred dollars procures your petitioner Joseph E Bromfield to go on said bonds went <unclear/> The confidently expected said defendants to appear in discharge of said bonds But they joined the federal army and your petitioners are informed that their officers advised them to not stand trial and they took their advise Your petitioners are blameless in the whole affair But judgment find has been rendered against them at the <date when="1865-10">oct Term 1865</date> of the Monroe circuit court upon said bonds for Three hundred dollars each and the same will be collected off of them by a sale of their lands unless prevented by Your Excellency.</p>
<p>In Tender consideration whereof they humbly pray Your Excellency to interfere in their behalf and remit said Judgment, and grant them such relief as may seem Just to Your Excellency and as in duty bound they will every pray &amp;c.</p>
<p>Stanford Mitchel says the foregoing petition is true.</p>
<p>Stanferd Mitchel</p>
<p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed in open court at Tomkinsville on the <date when="1865-10-03">3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> day of oct 1865</date>.</p>
<p>James B Evans D C<pb/></p>
<p>Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlett
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky at Frankfort</p>
<p>Your petitioners citizens of Monroe Simpson &amp; Allen counties in said state show Your Excellency that they are now &amp; have been for maney years were acquainted with Stanford Mitchel one of the foregoing petitioners that he is a very poor man and has a large family to maintain that he is now and old gray headed man we further state that he is an honest upright and worthy citizen and his statements are entitled to full faith &amp; confidence we are not acquainted with the petitioner Joseph E Bromfield but believe what petitioner Mitchel says as to him &amp; therefore we recomend them to your Excellency for executive clemency</p>
<p><date when="1865-10">Oct 1865</date></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J. H. Beals
<lb/>william Emerton
<lb/>John Ferguson
<lb/>A, J, Hibbits
<lb/>Thomas Key
<lb/>J mcpak
<lb/>W M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Peak
<lb/>J. J Johnson
<lb/>T J Wakefield
<lb/>giddian gregory
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Jeptha. S. Hurd
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Murray
<lb/>Allen Stephens
<lb/>L A Smithwich<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Barren
<lb/>Stanford Mitchel &amp; Joseph E Bromfield
<lb/>To } Petition
<lb/>Thomas E Bramlett
<lb/>Governor &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
