<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-006-0004"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas E. Bramlette, Warrant</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1050</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Requisitions for the Return of Fugitives from Justice, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR6-4 to BR6-4-1</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-09-19">19 September 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENT</p>
<p>I, THOMAS E. BRAMLETTE,
<lb/>GOVERNOR OF SAID COMMONWEALTH,
<lb/>TO ALL SHERIFFS, AND CONSTABLES IN SAID COMMONWEALTH, GREETING:</p>
<p>WHEREAS, It has been made known to me by O. P. Morton Governor of the State of Indiana that a certain John Hoffer or Hoofer of said State, stands <hi rend="str">indicted</hi> convicted in the state of Indiana Court for the crime of Grand Larceny a copy of which <hi rend="str">indictment</hi> conviction duly authenticated, is now on file in this Department; and that the said John Hoffer or Hoofer has fled the State of Indiana, thereby evading the justice of its laws, and is going at large within the limits of the State of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Know Ye, Therefore, That I, THOMAS E. BRAMLETTE, Governor as aforesaid, do hereby require and enjoin all Sheriffs and Constables within this State to apprehend and arrest the said John Hoffer or Hoofer, and upon his apprehension, to bring him before some Circuit Judge of this Commonwealth, that the said Circuit Judge may proceed, by proper and legal testimony, to inquire into the matter, so far as shall be necessary, to ascertain the identity of the said John Hoffer or Hoofer and if he the person mentioned in this, my warrant, shall be identified, that the said Judge may order him to be delivered up to D. W. Miller, who has been duly authorized by the Governor of the State of Indiana to receive and convey the said John Hoffer or Hoofer to the State of Indiana, to be dealt with according to law: And in case the said D. W. Miller should not appear to receive him, that the Judge may commit him, the said John Hoffer or Hoofer to jail, on the charge aforesaid, to be dealt with according to law: and that you report forthwith to the Governor of this Commonwealth your proceedings under this warrant. And furthermore, that if the said John Hoffer or Hoofer shall be committed to the jail of any county in this State, that the Judge so committing him may immediately inform the Governor of this Commonwealth of the commitment thereof, and to what jail he has been committed.</p>
<p>In Testimony Wherof, I have hereunto set my hand, and caused the Seal of the Commonwealth to be affixed, at FRANKFORT, on the <date when="1863-09-19">19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of September in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and 63</date> and in the 70<hi rend="sup">th</hi> year of the Commonwealth.</p>
<p>BY THE GOVERNOR: Tho. E. Bramlette
<lb/>E. L. Vanwinkle, SECRETARY OF STATE,
<lb/>By Jas R. Page
<lb/>Asst. Sec.
<lb/>Commonwealth Office -- WM. E. HUGHES, State Printer<pb/></p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Oldham Circuit } Sct. <date when="1863-09-21">Septr 21<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1863.</date></p>
<p>This day personally appeared in open court D. W. Miller having in custody John Hoffer or Hoofer under a Warrant from his Excellency the Governor of Kentucky issued upon a requisition from His Excellency the Governor of Indiana, and the court having heard proof touching the identity of said prisoner, and being satisfied that he is the same person referred to and named in said Warrant -- It is therefore ordered that said Miller, Agent of the State of Indiana retain said prisoner in his custody and safely deliver him to the Warden of the State ^Prison^ of Indiana -- All fees and expenses to be first paid by said Miller -- </p>
<p>I W. C. Mahan Clerk of the Oldham Circuit Court in the State of Kentucky do hereby certify that the foregoing order is truly copied from the records of said court -- </p>
<p>In Testimony whereof I have hereto set my hand and affixed the seal of said court at LaGrange this 21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> day of September 1863 -- </p>
<p><figure type="seal"/>
<lb/>W. C. Mahan clk.
<lb/>Fee $1.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">50</hi></hi> paid</p>
<p>I Peter B. Muir Judge of the <hi rend="str">6</hi>7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Judicial District of the State of Kentucky do hereby certify that W. C. Mahan whose genuine signature appears to the foregoing certificate is and was at the time of signing the same, Clerk of the Oldham Circuit Court in the state aforesaid, and that full faith and credit are due all his official acts as such -- &amp; that his certificate &amp; attestation are in due form of law.</p>
<p>Given under my hand this <date when="1863-09-21">21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> day of Septr 1863</date></p>
<p>P. B. Muir<pb/></p>
<p>came to hand <date when="1863-09-19">Sept. 19, 1863</date> at 12 <hi rend="sup">1</hi>/<hi rend="sub">4</hi> oclock P. M.</p>
<p>J. W. Pruett, c. f. c.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
