<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-021-0049"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Theophilas Steele, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG3119</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Apprehension of Fugitives from Justice Papers, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG8-140 to MG8-141</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Fayette County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky Fayette Circuit Court</p>
<p>Pleas held before the Honorable William C Goodloe Judge of the Court for the Circuit aforesaid at the Court House in the City of Lexington on the <date when="1855-06-12">12' day of June 1855</date></p>
<p><hi rend="str">C</hi>The Commonwealth of Kentucky Plaintiff
<lb/>against } on Indictment
<lb/>Theophilas Steele Defendant</p>
<p>(Be it remembered that heretofore to wit on the <date when="1855-02-22">22<hi rend="sup">d</hi> day of February 1855</date> at a Court continued and held for the Circuit aforesaid)</p>
<p>The Grand Jury empanelled and sworn herein returned the following Indictment, viz:</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Indictment</note>
<lb/>"Fayette Circuit Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky 
<lb/>against
<lb/>Theophilas Steele</p>
<p>The Grand Jurors for the Commonwealth of Kentucky, empannelled and sworn in and for Fayette county, in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth aforesaid, upon their Oaths represent that Theophilas Steele on the <date when="1855-02-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of February 1855,</date> in the County of Fayette, did challenge James Blackburn to fight him in single combat with pistols, contrary to the form of the Statute in such cases made and provided and against the peace and<pb/>
<lb/>dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>S Noland Com Atty<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>And afterwards to wit at a Court continued and held for the Circuit aforesaid on the <date when="1855-06-12">12' day of June 1855</date> -- </p>
<p>"This day came the parties by their Attorneys, and the Defendant plead not Guilty, and thereupon came a Jury, viz: James Dourning, Henry Bourman, Wm Busby, Uriah Stone, Jesse D Winn Charles F Rogers, Granville Smith, Hezekiah Martin, John Moore, John B Johnson, Albert Hay and David Harp who were elected tried and sworn well and truly to try the Issue and a true Verdict render herein -- The Trial progressed -- Whereupon on motion of the Attroney for the Commonwealth, It is ordered that this case be dismissed -- "</p>
<p>True Copies
<lb/>Att John B Norton Clerk
<lb/>Fayette Circuit Court<pb/></p>
<p>Commonwealth of Ky
<lb/>Copy
<lb/>v } Indictment &amp; Order of Dismission
<lb/>Steele, T<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>fee 50¢ paid</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
