<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-022-0003"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William S. Botts to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11929</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>37th - 76th Regiments Enrolled Militia Primary Source Documents (1861-1866)</collection>
      <idno>Box 80, Folder 863-65 FLEMING COUNTY 39th Rgt. Ky. Militia Recruiting and Raising the Co. Consolidated with Rowan and Hickman Counties</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Flemingsburg, Fleming County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-11-01">1 November 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Flemingsburg Ky
<lb/><date when="1863-11-01">Novr 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>Governor Bramlette
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>Capt Wm E Rice who served as a Captain in the 10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Cavalry desires a Commission as Col of the Troops proposed to be raised for state defence under your late Proclamation.</p>
<p>Captain Rice is a citizen of this County and acquired direction for his galantry he was popular as an officer with his men and has been represented to me as a fine Disciplinarian</p>
<p>When the appointment is to be made it would be gratifying to many of<pb/>
<lb/>your friends in this county if you would confer the appointment on him. I am informed that such is the desire of citizens of Bath County as for as expressed among whom Capt Rice is well known and where as an officer much of his Service was reward</p>
<p>Verry Respectfully yours &amp;c
<lb/>Wm S Botts.<pb/></p>
<p>General Bramlette
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>I am well acquainted with Capt W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> E. Rice He is a neighbour of mine -- I most cheerfully concur with Judge Botts and recomend him as worthy of a commission</p>
<p>very Respectfully
<lb/>yours W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Bell<pb/></p>
<p>Govenor Bramblett
<lb/>Dr Sir.</p>
<p>Several of the lading Union men of Bath &amp; Mtgomery wish me to be in command of the the forces raised for State defence which I will acept with commissioned to raise a full reg-: I belonged to the 10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky ^Cavalry^ about fourteen months and scouted all the eastern portion of the state and am very well acquainted ^with^ all portions of the state</p>
<p>Resp<hi rend="sup">ly</hi> &amp;C
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> E Rice</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
