<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2276"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">C. W. Cook to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6913</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-122 to BR15-123</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Dixon, Webster County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-08-23">23 August 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>C. W. COOK,
<lb/>Attorney at Law,
<lb/>DIXON, KY.,
<lb/>Will practice his profession in the Circuit Courts of Webster, Union and Hopkins Counties.
<lb/>Special attention given to the securing and collections of Claims.</p>
<p>Office of C. W. Cook,
<lb/>ATTORNEY AT LAW,
<lb/>Dixon, Ky., <date when="1865-08-23">Aug 23<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> 1865</date></p>
<p>At the <date when="1865-03">March Term 1865</date> of the Webster Circuit Court, John A Brooks a Confederate soldier (belonging to Col A R Johnson's Reg) was indicted in two cases for "robery" (impressing horses). At the Sep<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Term following Brooks having quit the Rebel service &amp; being in Court both cases wer continued, and with S B Vance D H Hughes &amp; J A Spalding as his securities entered into recognizance in the sum of $500 in each case for his appearance at the next term of the Court. Since that time Brooks has appeared and regularly in Court &amp; had his cases continued, standing upon his former recognizances until the summer of <date when="1864">1864</date> when he left the state and failed to appear at the <date when="1865-03">March term 1865</date> at which time his recognizance was taken as forfeited &amp; summons awarded against his securities.</p>
<p>Brooks resides, or did reside in this place, I had not seen him for<pb/>
<lb/>some time prior to his leaving from the fact that the County at that time was overrun by numerous bands of guerillas and I was absent form considerations of personal safety. But upon my return home it was my understanding from information derived from Citizens with whom Brooks was daily &amp; intimately associated (and of the truth of which I have no doubt) that he had been cursed and severely abused by some of the U S soldiers &amp; perhaps ordered to leave the state that he did at least leave on account of justly apprehended personal danger from that source and with the intention of returning again as soon as it would be safe to do so.</p>
<p>I received a letter from Brooks but a short time since asking particularly if I thought it would be safe for him to return, and I have no doubt he will return this fall. His family (wife &amp; one child) are here.</p>
<p>The release of his securities we think would be a commendable exercise of executive<pb/>
<lb/>clemency</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>C W Cook</p>
<p>T E Bramlett Gov Ky
<lb/>Frankfort Ky<pb/></p>
<p>Webster Cir Ct</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
