<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1097"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. W. Calvert to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5734</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-187-1 to BR11-188</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Burlington, Boone County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-08-18">18 August 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Burlington Ky <date when="1864-08-18">August 18/64</date>
<lb/>His Excellincy Thos E Bramlet Gov of Ky
<lb/>Dr Sr:</p>
<p>At the <date when="1858-04">April term of the Boone Circuit Court 1858</date> James H Landrum charged with stealing an old watch and some six dollars in mony appeared in discharge of his recognisance -- when the case was continued &amp; deft with John S Lucas -- Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> &amp; Frances Landrum of Grant County &amp; Wickliff Grubbs of this county on his surities executed a new bond for defts appearance at the <date when="1859-04">April term 1859</date></p>
<p>Grubbs went on the bond at the instance of Lucas &amp; Thos &amp; Francis Landrum James H Landurm did not appear at the <date when="1859-04">April term 1859</date> &amp; I believe it is generally thought that his brothers &amp; Lucas advised him to run off It was said he went to California and has not been heard of since ^til recently^ At the <date when="1859-04">April term 1859</date> there was a forfeiture of the bond &amp; summons ordered</p>
<p>At the <date when="1859-09">Sept term 1859</date> Judge Nuttal opened court and sat til dinner of the first day and being too unwell to continue on the bench I was selected by the bar to finish out the term</p>
<p>In the morning while Judge Nuttal was on the bench an order was made continuing the case there being no service upon any but Grubbs and of this order I had no knowledge</p>
<p>In the afternoon Grubbs came into court<pb/>
<lb/>with P U Major then atty for the commonwealth and consented that judgment should then be rendered against him for $300 the amount of the bond This I know was done by Grubbs upon the positive promise of Judge Nuttal and the assurance of Major that he should be released from all the fine except the cost and twenty per cent It was afterwards respited by Gov M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin &amp; I believe at my instance and I think he intended ultimately to release him Afterwards at the <date when="1860-04">April term 1860</date> judgment was taken against the other surities and a <unclear>Case</unclear> issued to Grant County which was on the <date when="1860-06-11">11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of June 1860</date> returned -- respited for twelve months -- and the further endorsment -- the cost &amp; 20 pr ct repleved Grubbs in the mean time died &amp; the atty for the Commonwealth failed to make his 20 pr ct &amp; costs on the replevin bond</p>
<p>This the whole matter rested til <date when="1864-04">April 1864</date> when -- the case was renewed against Grubbs and<unclear/> &amp; heir It has frequently been said of late that J H Landrum is dead -- but with what truth I cannot say I am confident however that but for the assurances given Grubbs by Nuttal &amp; Major that Grubbs would long ago attended to it himself and if not released exerted himself to have the amount of<pb/>
<lb/>the fine made off the surities who induced him to go on the bond His widow asks me to make this simple statement of facts to you asking to release her &amp; her children from the three hundred dollars forfeitures I trust that you will under all the Circumstances feel yourself constrained as well by a sense of justice as the ever potent appeal of the widow &amp; orphan to grant the relief asked</p>
<p>your ob svt
<lb/>J, W, Calvert</p>
<p>Enclosed I send a memorandum of all steps taken in the case except the orders of <unclear/></p>
<p>J W C<pb/></p>
<p>Boone Cir Ct
<lb/>vs</p>
<p>Remit the judgt as to the <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> Representatives &amp; heirs of Wickliffe Grubbs decd<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>$300.
<lb/><date when="1864-08-24">24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Aug'/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
