<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0407"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky vs. William Porter, Abstract</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8859</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-157 to R4-158</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lewis County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-06-02">2 June 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Lewis Circuit Court
<lb/><cb n="2"/>2nd day
<lb/><date when="1863-06">June Term 1863</date>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Commonwealth of Kentucky Plt
<lb/>Against
<lb/>William Porter Deft</p>
<p>The prisoner being unable to employ counsel, the court appointed W H Wadsworth to defend for him. By consent the arraignment of the prisoner is dispensed with -- the parties appeared by their attorneys, and the defendant plead not guilty, thereupon the following Jurors viz. Seth Parker. W. P. Sanders, A. C. Henderson, Edward Roe, B W Clark, S. B Pugh, D H Brightman Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> H Connell, Amos Means, Cary Wilson James Henderson John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cormick ^who were duly empannelled &amp; sworn^ The Defendant then asked and obtained leave to withdraw his plea and plead guilty to the indictment -- the jury having heard the evidence &amp;c returned the following verdict viz: We the jury find the defendant guilty, and fix his term of imprisonment at four years in the penitentiary, but recommend him to the clemency of the Governor and to pardon on condition of his volunteering in the army, in pursuance of his volunteering in the army in pursuance of his intentions at the time of his arrest -- <pb/>
<lb/>Signed Seth Parker Foreman.</p>
<p>It is therefore ordered that the Prisoner be committed to the Couty Jail -- </p>
<p>C</p>
<p>Commonwealth of Kentucky Plt
<lb/>Against } 6th day
<lb/>William Porter Deft.</p>
<p>The defendant was this day brought into court, and being informed of the nature of the indictment plea. and verdict was asked if he had any legal cause to show why Judgment should not be pronounced against him, and none being shown, it is adjudged that the defendant, be taken by the sheriff of Lewis County to the State Penitentiary and there confined at hard labor for the period of four years</p>
<p>Copies
<lb/>Teste John T Parker Clk
<lb/>By A. V. Wilson D, C.<pb/></p>
<p>Commonwealth of Ky vs. W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Porter -- </p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Johnson states that he knows the Prisoner W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Porter &amp; his father &amp; family. His father lives in Carter Co. is a good christian man &amp; patriot -- the young man is also a young man of good character. He states that the rebels have plundered the prisoner father, taken two horses from him &amp; two from another Son &amp; one from a brotherinlaw, also taken his bed clothes &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi> &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>. He states that the prisoner could not safely stay at home on account of the guerrillas &amp; was on his way to join the Army at Catlettsburg, when he was induced to retaliate on the rebels by taking a horse ^(to go to camp)^ from one Garland, who was represented to him as a rebel. Affiant firmly believes these facts, &amp; has no idea that the prisoner would have taken the horse, except under such peculiar circumstances. The prisoner is about 18 years old &amp; a country boy without experience.</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Johnson</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Johnson <date when="1863-06-02">2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> day of June 1863</date>.</p>
<p>Jno. T. Parker, Clk</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
