<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0431"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">H. G. Petree to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8883</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-191 to R4-192</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Elkton, Todd County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-06-18">18 June 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Elkton Ky. <date when="1863-06-18">June 18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>.
<lb/>To his Excellency the Govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.
<lb/>Dr Sir</p>
<p>The accompanying transcript will show that Lewis W Garth was indicted in the Todd Circuit Court for the alledged offense of sending a challenge to fight a duel Col B H Bristow &amp; myself being engaged as counsel for Mr. Garth became his bail in his recognizance to appear in said Court. Garth appeard at several terms of the court but the atty for the Comth not being ready he renewed his recognizance &amp; the case was continued until the <date when="1862-04">April term 1862</date> when he failed to appear &amp; a forfeiture was taken &amp; summons ordered vs him Col B &amp; Myself &amp; which has been served on Col Bristow &amp; Myself but not upon Garth who before the forfeiture had joined the rebellion &amp; left the county of his residence and is now I presume in the Service of the Rebel concern. Process cannot be served on Garth &amp; unless relieved Col B &amp; Myself will have the $500 to pay. If not inconsistent with your judgment of right, &amp; propriety, &amp; your practice in such cases I will thank you to remit the recognizance</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>H. G Petree<pb/></p>
<p>Todd Circuit Court
<lb/><date when="1859-10">October Term 1859</date>
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against
<lb/>Lewis Garth</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Todd County in the name and by the Authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky accuse Lewis Garth of the Crime challenging to fight a duel Committed as follows viz The said Lewis Garth on the <date when="1859-10-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> day of October 1859</date> in the County aforesaid did challenge J. C. Dickerson to fight a duel with deadly weapons, Against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J Crabb
<lb/>Foreman of the Jury
<lb/>John E Arnold Atty for the Commonwealth
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Information given
<lb/>By G. A. Henry
<lb/>F. N. Chiles
<lb/>Lewis Waller
<lb/>S. H. Sullivan
<lb/>E. G. Sebree
<lb/>Dr Baily</p>
<p>Todd Circuit Court
<lb/><date when="1862-04">April Term 1862</date></p>
<p>At a Circuit Court continued and held for Todd County Kentucky at the Court House in Elkton on Tuesday <date when="1862-04-22">April 22" 1862</date></p>
<p>Present Hon. T C. Dabney Comlt<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">h</hi></hi> vs L W Garth } Challenging to fight duel</p>
<p>This day came the attorney for the Commonwealth and the Defendant failing to appear in discharge of his recognizance, which is therefore taken as forfeited It is ordered that summons issue against said<pb/>
<lb/>Garth &amp; his Securities, B. H. Bristow and H. G. Petree returnable to the next term of this court requiring them to appear and show cause if any they can why the Commonwealth shall not have Judgement &amp; Execution against them for the sum of Five hundred Dollars, that being the amount they acknowledged themselves in their said recognizance given in this court on the <date when="1861-04-16">16<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of April 1861</date></p>
<p>A Coppy
<lb/>Attest
<lb/>Ben T Perkins C. L. C. C.<pb/></p>
<p>Todd Cir. Ct
<lb/>$500 } Forfeiture
<lb/>B. H. Bristow &amp; H. G.Petree</p>
<p>The secretary will issue a remission of the amount to the security</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J F Robinson</hi>
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-07-01">July 1. 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
