<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2180"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. C. Thomas to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9256</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-287 to MG24-288</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>B. Magoffin Gov of Ky</p>
<p>The undersigned your petitioner, J. C. Thomas respectfully states, that on the <date when="--07-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of July last</date> he became security or bail for one D. A. Laymans appearance at the <date when="--09">September Term</date> of the Kenton Circuit court at Covington Ky. in the sum of six hundred Dollars as shown by a copy of the bond herewith enclosed, &amp; states that said Layman was charged with the offence of shooting at one Charles Leonard with intention to kill, as shown by a copy of the Indictment filed herewith, said D. A. Layman did appear on the first day of the said Term of said court_ &amp; the cause being postponed for two weeks &amp; Day set for trial said Layman went to cairo in search of an important witness &amp; has never returned acording to the stipulation of said bond, &amp; at the <date when="--12">present December Term</date> of said court. Judgement was taken against your petitioner upon said bond &amp; an Execution is now in the hands of the sheriff of this county for said amount against your Petitioner -- and your petitioner further States at the time of his becoming security for the said Layman that he had in store &amp; on storage some house hold &amp; kitchen Furniture, &amp; 16 Blls<pb/>
<lb/>of Domestic Liquors belonging to the said D. A. Layman which he Layman represented as being worth the full amount of the aforesaid bond. all of the things being enclosed in large boxes. &amp; upon examination found to contain nothing but old clothes belonging principally to his wife &amp; children which is worth nothing to any one but themselves -- and as for the Domestic liquor. it is not worth more than raw whisky which is worth to day <date when="1861-01-14">Jany 14<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi>/ 61</date> fourteen cents pr Gallon all of which to day would not bring one hundred Dollars and if I am compelled to pay the whole amount of said bond it will greatly embarrass me &amp; the officer will have to sacrifice my effert to make the required amount -- I would therefore pray your Excellency to remit so much of said bond as you can controll under the constitution &amp; laws of the state.</p>
<p>Respectfully &amp;c
<lb/>J. C. Thomas</p>
<p>we the undersigned would cheerfully recomend the Granting of the Prayer of the Petitioner</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>S, F, Roberts
<lb/>J. C. Howard
<lb/>John. T. Levis
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J G Carlisle
<lb/>James. B. Gray
<lb/><hi rend="underline">S. C. Perrin</hi><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">C A. Withers</hi>
<lb/>W. E. Arthur -- Atty for Com'th</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
