<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2029"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">M. C. Davis to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6666</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-194</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Dixon, Webster County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-08-25">25 August 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Dixon Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-08-25">August 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Gov. Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Bramlette,</p>
<p>At the <date when="1863-03">March Term of the Webster Circuit Court 1863</date>. John A Brooks a confederate soldier was indicted for taking or pressing horses, said Brooks left the confederate service, returned home and took the Oath and at the September term 1863 of said Court entered into Recognizanse in two cases ^$500. each^ worth. D H Hughs J A Spaulding &amp; S. B. Vance as his sureties, at subsequent terms of said Court these causes were continued, and during all this time said Brooks had remained at home a peaceable and orderly citizen, during the <date when="1864">summer of 1864</date> our country was filled with soldiers both Federal and Confederate &amp; Guerillas. Brooks deeming it unsafe to remain at home (having been threatened by both sides, so he informed me) left and went to Colorado territory where he has remained ever since, he writes me he intends to return about Christmas next, and I believe he intends to return &amp; will return if he lives. his family are still residing here, at the last term of our Court his bonds were taken as forfeited &amp; Sum<hi rend="sup">s</hi> awarded. Brooks writes me that it will be impossible for him to reach home by the next term of our Court, and ^he &amp; his sureties^ are desirous that Judgment be suspended until his return I am confident he will return. Enclosed with this I send his letter -- </p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>M, C, Davis<pb/></p>
<p>If his Excellency has not acted <hi rend="underline">favorably</hi>, in the matter of my petition in the two cases of the Comlth vs Jno, A. Brooks, in the Webster circuit court, will Mr. B, please hand him this letter of M. C. Davis, clerk of the Webster Circuit court, &amp; also the enclosed letter of Brooks, &amp; oblige -- </p>
<p>Yours,
<lb/>S. B. Vance</p>
<p>Webster Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>D H Hughes &amp; J. A. Spalding, &amp; S. B. Vance
<lb/>Respited for<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>12 months
<lb/><date when="1865-09-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Sept/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
