<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0890"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Mastin Hunter, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5008</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-367 to BR10-368</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jessamine County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-05">May 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky, Jessamine County Sct..</p>
<p>Personally appeared before me a Justice of the peace within and for said State and County Mastin Hunter who states on oath That in this case in the Jessamine Circuit Court for permitting Gaming upon his premise described in the petition hereto, That at the time and place mentioned by the Witness in the trial of said Hunter in the Circuit Court of this county <date when="1864-03">March 1864</date> said Hunter and others of his neighbors did play cards but there was nothing bet, lost or won and that they were playing for amusement. And he verily beleives that the witness (Brumfield) was influenced by spite ill will and malice which caused him to give the evidence before the Jury he did in order to be revenged on him (Hunter) for making ^Brumfield^ pay a debt to him (Hunter). That at the same Term of the same Court he was fined sixty dollars for keeping a Tippling house upon the testimony of the same person alone, that the same animus prevailed with Brumfield in both cases. that he ^Hunter^ is a distiller and has never sold whiskey in less quantities than the law allows him to sell, nor has he ever at any time permitted tippling or drinking upon his premises, that the fine against him is for selling whiskey in less quantities than the Law allows, he denies and says he has not so sold whiskey or any other intoxicating liquor.</p>
<p>The payment of the fines mentioned or either of them would add greatly to his already embassassed condition that he has a large a growing and helpless family entirely dependent upon him for support and he humbly and respectfully requests the Honorable Thos <unclear/> Governor of Kentucky to exercise executive clemency<unclear/> petitioner.</p>
<p>Mastin Hunter</p>
<p><unclear/>Subscribed and sworn to before me by Mastin Hunter this <unclear/> day of <date when="1864-05">May 1864</date></p>
<p>J. G. Bruce J. P. J. C<pb/>
<lb/>James O. Henry Juror
<lb/>O H Perry Juror
<lb/>E W Wallace Juror
<lb/>H B Aherrn Juror
<lb/>David D Bowen Juror
<lb/>Robert Smith Sen Juror
<lb/>Joseph Nabb Juror
<lb/>Jacoby M. Courathy Juror
<lb/>Daniel Ford Juror
<lb/>Nat. Lafon Juror
<lb/>John Dickerson Jurors</p>
<p>I certify that the persons signed as Jurors were the Jury who tried the case</p>
<p>Att S. Noland Clk.</p>
<p>Jessamine Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Mastin Hunter</p>
<p>Remit except fees &amp; costs in the case for gaming &amp; also for tiplling</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>2 Judgts
<lb/>one of $200 Gaming
<lb/>one of $60 Tipling
<lb/><date when="1864-05-23">23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> May/64</date><pb/>
<lb/>To His Excelency Go<hi rend="sup">v</hi> Bramlette</p>
<p>Your undersigned petitioners state that thay are citizens of Jessamine County and ware of the Jury that tried the case of the Commonwealth against Mastin Hunter upon Indict<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">mt</hi></hi> for suffering Gameing at the <date when="1864-03">March term of the Jessamine Circuit Court 1864</date>.- Upon the trial of said case it was proven by one witness only that upon one occasion he saw Mastan Hunter and others playing cards in the still House of said Hunter and upon said Game a treat was bet won and lost. There was some contrariety of testimony, but under the proof and the instruction of the Court your petitioners felt constrained to find the defendant guilty and we assessed his fine at <hi rend="str">100</hi> 200 the least same we had a right to do under the law Your petitioners however believe that M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Hunters case demands. Exectative Clemency and interposition, We would therefore aske your Excelency to remit the ^said^ fine against Mastin Hunter and your petitioners will ever pray &amp;c.</p>
<p>Davis Bowen</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
