<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-014-0001"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. M. Mills, John S. Hays, and J. H. Garrard, Report of Inspectors of Penitentiary</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1232</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Joshua D Farrington</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Special Studies and Reports to the Governor, 1864, 1867</collection>
      <idno>BR1-372 to BR1-373</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-09-06">6 September 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Report</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Frankfort <date when="1864-09-06">September 6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Hon Thomas E. Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Ky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>Our reports as Inspectors of the Penitentiary have been less frequent during the present year than the law requires, but this is owning to the fact that such reports would have consisted only of a repetition of the subjects which had been previously mentioned, and to which your attention was called in detail. We would here state however that the requisition of the law in regard to our weekly visits has been fully complied with and the inspections regularly made.</p>
<p>It is a matter of regret that our suggestions did not meet with the approval of the last Legislature, and that the bill which contained approporiations for sundry improvements failed in its passage. Those improvements were suggested because there were deemed indispensable and necessary, and your attention is called to the fact, that the necessity for them existed at the time the present keeper assumed charge of the institution. We here express our decided conviction that if the improvements are made and the buildings put in a good condition, the law rendering it obligatory upon the keeper to <hi rend="str">keep</hi> ^continue^ them so, could be more easily complied with, and it would be ^a^ measure of economy on part of the state. A succeeding keeper would then be releived to a great extent, from making up for the defects of his predecessor in this respect.</p>
<p>The resolution adopted by the Legislature, required the "hemp house, meat house, shed stable, engine house, and a<pb/>
<lb/>lot of damaged sheet iron roofing to be sold and the proceeds paid to contractors for work done on, or repairing buildings in the Penitentiary." This was adopted while the bill above referred to was pending and doubtless in anticipation of its passage, as in the new buildings proposed to be erected, we had already reccommended the material in the old ones to be used. But even if this were not the case, we could not fully carry out the order of the resolution, as the meat house was in use and there was no other building in the yard to answer for such a purpose, and the sale of the old hemp house and engine shed would not have contributed to any advantage whatever. If the new buildings proposed had have been enected, the material in the old ones being right at hand, would have been worth something, and a great part ^of^ it advantageously applied, but the amount realised from a sale, solely with a purpose of getting the material out of the yard, would have been trifling indeed. The bill will be up for consideration again, and we await further action in regard to it. Should it fail again, and the resolution still stand, the directions of the latter will be carried out to the best advantage possible.</p>
<p>A quantity of old iron castings, unfinished machines, and other material belonging to the former keepers and other parties still remain in the yard, and as they serve only as incumbrances, we have recently caused an advertisement to be inserted in the Commonwealth, requesting the owners, of such property to remove the same within thirty days<pb/>
<lb/>from the date of advertising, or the keeper will be directed to place it outside the walls at the owners risk.</p>
<p>The following named buildings need new roofs -viz -the chapel, all to the private dwelling occupied by M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Whitesides, assistant keeper, kitchen connected with same, and the brick building occupied by M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Lawler.</p>
<p>The floor of the cell building needs repairing at several points. It is earth covered over with cement, and the latter has worn away.</p>
<p>The floor in the southern end of the new hemp house has settled down in several places, over the pits of the old privies, and should be filled up.</p>
<p>On the night of the <date when="1864-07-30">30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> July last,</date> nine prisoners made their escape in the following manner. The doors of the cells are closed, then bolted, and the lock secures the bolt. Some of the prisoners managed by an ingenious contrivance to make the bolt appear in its proper place, although the guards passed around and saw the key fully turned. The turning of the key was done by a prisoner whose duty it is to keep the cell walk clean and perform other duties essential in that department. About midnight, when the guards are releived by their comrades, just as the releif had taken their places, the prisoners opened the doors, creeped stealthily upon the guards around a corner, disarmed them, prevented them from giving the alarm by threats of death, and then made their escape, two going through the yard and the remaining seven boring through the roof. The keep made deligent effort to effect their<pb/>
<lb/>capture and succeeded in getting back six of them. One was killed by the officers for resisting them when endeavoring to take him, and two are still at large.</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>J. M. Mills
<lb/>John. S. Hays
<lb/>J H Garrard } Inspectors Ky Penitentiary</p>
<p>Report
<lb/>Inspectors
<lb/>Penetentiary
<lb/><date when="1864-09-06">Sept 6<hi rend="sup">th</hi>/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
