<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0935"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James M. Buckner et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10403</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-483 to MG19-484</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Munfordville, Hart County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-04-12">12 April 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><hi rend="str">To</hi> Munfordville Ky <date when="1861-04-12">April 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>To his Exelency Beriah Magoffin Govenor of Ky.</p>
<p>your petitioners would respectfully represent that at this term of our Hart Equity &amp; Criminal court H. H. Lock was fined the sum of fifty dollars for selling liquor to a miner, we state that were the jury who tried his case under the indictment for that office and take pleasure in recomending him to Executive clemency and believe that his fine should be remitted as we have no idea that it was his intention to violate the law, though under the instructions of the court we were bound to find him guilty.</p>
<p>we state that the circumstances are about these a young man by the name of Cumpton deupty clerk of both of our courts and who transacts the business of both of the clerks offices in a great degree and who stands as high as a sober correct man as any in our county and who had been doing business for him self for 2 or 3 years and has the apperance of a man of 21 years old. and H. H. Lock being a licensed liquor seller not knowing him to be under age sold him a few drinks of spirits, when the fact turned out to be that Mr. Cumpton was not quite 21 years old but over 20, We are clearly of opinion that it was a mistake on the part of Mr. Lock and that he had not intention of violating the law when he sold the spirits to Cumpton and it was for this selling that he was indited</p>
<p>They also state that there was <hi rend="str">also</hi> an<pb/>
<lb/>inditement at the same court for the same offence of selling liquor to the same man against Nathan Goldmsith a Licensed liquor seller in our county who amediately after the verdict in the case of H. H. Lock was rendered, confessed judgment in his case for the penalty stating that he did not deny Selling the spirits to cumpton as was charged in the indictment, beleaving that he was of age from his appearance and his occupation. -- who we likewise recomend to Executive clemency as we do not beleave that there was any intention on his part to violate the law. wherefore we ask for them that your Exelency will interpose and and remit the fines of both Lock &amp; Goldsmith</p>
<p>This <date when="1861-04-12">april 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861,</date></p>
<p>James. M. Buckner
<lb/>H. B. White
<lb/>B. F. Brickey
<lb/>Riley Chaney
<lb/>Willis Johnson
<lb/>Thomas Constant
<lb/>W L Lester
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Hardy
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Eliott</hi> <hi rend="underline">V</hi> <hi rend="underline">Bolton</hi>
<lb/>B R Hodges
<lb/>S, C, Lafferty
<lb/>A G M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Hatton<pb/></p>
<p>Hart Eq. Ct
<lb/>Petition of the Jury to remit fine of Lock &amp; Goldsmith<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/>B M
<lb/>$50 each } Selling liquor to a minor
<lb/>Iss <date when="1861-05-21">May 21. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
