<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-019-0143"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Unknown, Note</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1449</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG5-240 to MG5-242</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Note</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><hi rend="str">You</hi> From the commencement of the unhappy hostilities now pending in the <hi rend="str">Un</hi> County the people of Kentucky have indicated an earnest desire and purpose as far as lay in their power <hi rend="str">to</hi> ^while^ maintain^ing^ their original political status, to do nothing by which to involve themselves in the war. Up to this time they have succeeded in securing to themselves and to the State domestic peace and internal tranquility, as the fruits of the position assumed. My object now is to promote the continuance of those blessings to the people of this state. </p>
<p>Until within a brief period the people of this state were tranquil and calm, free from domestic strife and internal commotion. They have <hi rend="str">done</hi> <hi rend="str">nothing</hi> resisted no law, rebelled against no authority, engaged in no revolution or insurrection but constantly proclaimed their purpose quietly to pursue their peaceful avocations, earnestly hoping their own soil would be spared the presence of armed troops and the scene of conflict be kept removed from the<pb/>
<lb/>border of their state. By thus giving no occassion for the introduction of bodies of soldiers and <hi rend="str">furnishing</hi> offering no provocation or just cause for the presence the of millitary force they have labored to preserve the <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> in this state the public peace and avoid the calamities of <hi rend="str">hostile</hi> blody hostilities. <hi rend="str">I request</hi> <hi rend="str">that</hi> Recently a large body of soldiers has been enlisted into the United states Army and collected in <hi rend="str">a</hi> military camps in the central portion of the state. This movement was preceded by the <hi rend="str">intr</hi> introduction ^into the State^ of public arms and munitions of war distributed exclusively to a class of the people, and the active organization of companies Regiments &amp;c con<hi rend="str">pared</hi>^sisting^ of men sworn into the U. S. service under officers holding commissions from Yourself. Its ordnance and munitions of war are being <hi rend="str">brought</hi> transported into the state and placed in their camps. In a word an Army is now being organized and quartered within this state supplied with all the arms &amp; munitions of war, and that internal tranquility so earnestly sought to be maintained by the people of Kentucky, <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> and succcessfully<pb/>
<lb/>secured to this time is now imminently threatened -- <hi rend="str">Vol</hi> Within Kentucky there has been <hi rend="str">no</hi> and is likely to be no necessity or plea for the presence of military force, and the
<lb/>people <hi rend="str">are</hi> <hi rend="str">in</hi> <hi rend="str">no</hi> feel not the slightest apprehension of any occasion arising to invoke the protection of the Federal arms. They have <hi rend="str">only</hi> asked that their soil be left free from military camps and the<hi rend="str">ir</hi> <hi rend="str">states</hi> ^peace of their^ communities left unwounded by soldiers, <hi rend="str">and their</hi> <hi rend="str">In</hi> They do not desire that Kentucky be required to supply the battle <hi rend="str">ground</hi> fields ^for the contending armies^ or become the theater of war. In the name therefore of their <hi rend="str">In</hi> <hi rend="str">view</hi> <hi rend="str">therefore</hi> <hi rend="str">of</hi> <hi rend="str">the</hi> people, and with a single &amp; earnest desire to <unclear/> from their present peaceful fireside &amp; tranquil home the horrors of civil war I appeal to you to remove from the limits of Kentucky the forces now organized &amp; in camp <hi rend="str">be</hi> within their state, and <hi rend="str">that</hi> <hi rend="str">you</hi> to arrest the introduction ^<hi rend="str">into</hi> <hi rend="str">the</hi> <hi rend="str">state</hi>^ of <hi rend="str">munitions</hi> <hi rend="str">war</hi> <hi rend="str">and</hi> troops, arms &amp; munitions of war -- A favorable response will as I firmly believe secure to <hi rend="str">this</hi> the people of Kentucky <hi rend="str">power</hi> <hi rend="str">&amp;</hi> the blessings of peace and protect the state from the <hi rend="str">blo</hi> surging conflicts -- now spreading ruin &amp; <unclear/> within other states.<pb/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Important Copy</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
