<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0312"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">H. H. Bingamon to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8764</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-10 to R4-11</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>New Hope, Brown County, Ohio</placeName>
    <date when="1863-04-08">8 April 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The Captured Battery.
<lb/><hi rend="str">Apr</hi> <date when="1863-04-08">1863
<lb/>New Hope Ohio Apr 8</date>
<lb/>To the Governor of Kentucky
<lb/>Mr J<hi rend="underline">as</hi> F Robinson</p>
<p>My daughter cauld to se you on the <date when="1863-03-30">30 day of March</date> Cornelious sister you promist hur that iff she would send alist of persons names to the amount seventy five or more that to sho that he was a lawyel Boy &amp; that he was a Boy of good caracter i am satisfied that you have got itin your power to releas him The charges a gainst him unavoid you have all redy satisfied your sets of that<pb/>
<lb/>I beg to you in the name of God to releas my sun I say that I am a younior man Governor you must Excuse my Awkwar a Letter as I can not read my name nor rite it I have dictated to young feeling I have Declated this Letter I put Hels Letter in yours you read his Letter and oblig yours</p>
<p>H H Bingamon</p>
<p>To J<hi rend="underline">as</hi> F Robinson Govenor Ky<pb/></p>
<p>Georgetown O <date when="1863-04-09">April 9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency,
<lb/>James F. Robinson
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky
<lb/>Dear Sir:</p>
<p>Inclosed you will find a request for the pardon of Cornelius Benjamon signed by about eighty of the citizens of the neighborhood in which he was "<hi rend="underline">born</hi> <hi rend="underline">and</hi> <hi rend="underline">raised</hi>,"</p>
<p>They deeply regret the young man's misfortune, and hope you will pardon him And permit him to return to his house believing that his sole experience of the consequence of vice will greatly conduce to his reformation &amp; that his pardon at the request of his friends will induce him to so demean himself in the future<pb/>
<lb/>that they will have no cause to regret the course they have taken. His fathers letter hereto attached, is presented for your consideration, Inclosed you will find a letter to the Young man containing 20$ which will bear his expenses home. You will please hand the same to him whether he is released or not,</p>
<p>Receive the assurance of the highest consideration from</p>
<p>Yours truly
<lb/>Wiley W. Young,</p>
<p>Please acknowledge receipt
<lb/>W, W, Y,</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
