<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0273"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Jeremiah Cash to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4392</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-434 to BR8-435</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1863-11-23">23 November 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Tho E Bramlette Govr Ky</p>
<p>your petitioner Jeremiah Cash would state that on the <date when="1859-07-13">13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of July 1859</date> he was fined sixty Dollars by the Hardin Circuit Court for keeping a Tipling House</p>
<p>your petitioner states that he was nearly blind &amp; unable to do any thing to support his family &amp; his neighbors advised him to set up a little grocery &amp; that as he was too poor to pay for a license and blind that he would be in ^no^ danger. your petitioner was not well posted in law &amp; driven to necessity did sell some whiskey &amp; when Indicted for it came to court made no defenses acknowledged the act &amp; asked for mercy, but the Jury had to find against him</p>
<p>Petitioner states that he is yet nearly blind &amp; poor &amp; a family of six children to support, that since he was indicted he quit selling and asks your excellency as an act of mercy to remit the fine
<lb/><date when="1863-11-23">Nov. 23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1863</date></p>
<p>Jeremiah Cash<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned are acquainted with the petitioner and believe he has told the truth about the matter named therein &amp; hope the fine will be remitted <date when="1863-11-23">Nov 23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1863</date></p>
<p>Saml Haycraft
<lb/>A. H. Cunningham<pb/></p>
<p>Hardin Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>J. Cash
<lb/>$60 -- 
<lb/>Tipling
<lb/><date when="1863-12-07">7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Dec/ 63</date></p>
<p>Remit all except fees &amp; costs
<lb/>T E Bramlette</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
