<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2423"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Coriden Frost et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7060</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-366 to BR15-367</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Monticello, Wayne County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09">September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Monticello Ky <date when="1865-09">Sept 1865</date></p>
<p>His Excellency Thomas E Bramlett Governor of the Commonwealth of Ky your Petitioner George K Marcum would most respectfully represent to your excellency that he has Served his country faithfully for two years in the Federal army and <hi rend="str">he</hi>has been honorably discharged that some time in the fall of <date when="1862">1862</date> there was many acts of wrong being done in the county of Clinton and Wayne Union men were being robed as they believed at the instance of Rebels and amongst the rest Daniel P Wright was robed by the rebels of a large amount of goods -- and the fact was notorious that said rebel band had been conducted to the county by W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> H Harrison to this fact Mr Wright is ready to certify that Harrison pointed out his store to them and had him robed your petition at the time had attached himself to a company (which afterwards nearly or quite all Joined the federal Army) for his protection as he could not stay at home that Said company was about the time Wright was robed in Clinton County and they being experated at the treatment Wright had received at the hands of the Rebels went to Albany and destroyed a remnant of Goods belonging to Harrison in retaliation for Wrights loss your petitioner did not desire and was not profited anything by the taking of Harrisons goods. At the last Term of the Clinton circuit court your petitioner with some others were presented to the Grand Jury and these bills found against them for the taking of Harrisons goods now your petitioner would most respectfully<pb/>
<lb/>represent that he has been raised in Wayne County and can Sustain a character for honesty not inferior to many who have had superior advantages over him and as evidence of his good Standing at home he has Since the occurrence for which he is now Indicted been twice Elected County Judge of Wayne County Judge of Wayne County which position he now holds at the hands of the people receiving 75 votes Majority over all his competitiors three in number your petitioner would most respectfully ask your Excellencys interposition in his behalf preventing any further prosecution against him in the case and as in duty bound will ever pray</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Coriden Frost
<lb/>J, E, Vickerey
<lb/>F, N, Alexander
<lb/>W, H, Gregory
<lb/>Thomas Dolan
<lb/>Jesse Rector
<lb/>Thomas Simpson
<lb/>R. C. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Beath
<lb/>Richard Ramsey
<lb/>Francis ,D, Shearer
<lb/>Amos Acre
<lb/><unclear/>. P. Ramsay
<lb/>Hiram Griffey
<lb/>Nathaniel Hicks
<lb/>Constant Griffey
<lb/>G, A, J, <hi rend="underline">York</hi>
<lb/><cb n="2"/>C, D, Dalton
<lb/>Thomas Rains
<lb/>Jasper C. Choat
<lb/>A J Lyon
<lb/>John Horry
<lb/>John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Beath
<lb/>G. W. Fleming
<lb/>Richard, Burnett<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>I am of the opinion that Marcum ought not to be held responsibile for the act mentioned in the petition for which he is indicted -- </p>
<p>He done wrong I have no doubt but he was <hi rend="underline">mad</hi> I &amp; he had good reason be <hi rend="underline">mad</hi> I have looked into his case &amp; am confident that Marcum has been "Sinned against" as well as Sinning himself</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">E L VanWinkle</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Clinton Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Geo K. Marcum
<lb/>Pardoned <date when="1865-10-07">7 Oct 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
