<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1458"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Henry Thomas to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6095</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-268 to BR12-269</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thos. E. Bramlette Gov. of the State of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your petitioner Henry Thomas, f. m. c. would respectfully state, that at the <date when="1864-12">December</date> term of of the city court of Louisville, he was fined $50, &amp; costs, for carrying concealed a deadly weapon -- a pistol.</p>
<p>He says that he was not in the habit of carrying this, or any other weapon; but being engaged at Willard's Hotel as a Servant, he one night Started to go upon Preston Street a distance of Some half mile, to his washer-woman's house to get his clothes, he put a pistol in his pocket; and on his way he got in company with two other colored men, and one of them run against a white man and jostled him somewhat. Thereupon the white man drew a pistol, ordered your petitioner ^and the others^ to halt. The two others ran away, and your petitioner stoped; and the white man took him and delivered him over to a Policeman, who Searchd him, and finding on him a pistol he was put in Jail. Afterwards he was inducted &amp; fined as af'd.</p>
<p>Your petitioner says, that he did not run against the white man, nor did he intentionally or otherwise offer any insult or indignity to him. Your petitioner says that about that time the city was infested with Robbers &amp; thieves, who nearly every night assaulted and robbed or atempted to robb persons on the Streets; and Such outrages upon colored persons were frequent; and<pb/>
<lb/>that he only took the pistol along with him to protect himself against such assaults. He says that he is a poor man that it requires all he can make to support himself; and that if he has to pay the whole fine &amp; costs some $65 or more, he will perhaps have to work it out or a part of it in the city work-house. This he thinks would be very hard, as he had not harmed any one nor intended to; nor did he intend to violate any law</p>
<p>He therefore prays your excellency to remit all except the attorney's fee, and costs.</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>Henry Thomas, f. m. c</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Louisville, respectfully present that we Know the above pititioner; and that we think his Statements are Substantially true. Some of us, Mr Willard &amp; his clerks, would state that he is a most excellent Sevant: a Sober, Steady well-behaved, industrious man. And we most earnestly request your Excellency to remit all of said fine which you have the power to.</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J W Willard</hi>
<lb/>J, A, Patrick
<lb/>Phil Tomppert Jr C, C, C, L,
<lb/>Fred'k Wobbe Dpy Clk C. C. L.
<lb/>W, G, Reasor atty<pb/></p>
<p>Governor Bramlette
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>The Petitioner is a colored man &amp; is hired as a servant at the Willard Hotel, &amp; they give him a splendid character for peace &amp; sobriety, I think Executive Clemency would be worthily bestowed</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>J H. Price
<lb/>L. A. Wood</p>
<p>Gov Bramlette
<lb/>Dear Sir:</p>
<p>I could have got a large number of signers, but I did not deem it necessary. The city clerkes, Mr Reaser the city atty have signed it; and I know of my own Knowledge, that this is a good boy -- and that this is a case of merit. I trust therefore you will send me a Remission for him</p>
<p>Yours &amp;c
<lb/>L A Wood<pb/></p>
<p>Louisville City Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Henry Thomas
<lb/>$50.
<lb/>Henry Thomas. f m c
<lb/>Petition
<lb/>to the Gov.
<lb/>Concealed
<lb/>Weapons
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1865-01-03">3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Jany/65</date></p>
<p>L. A. Wood</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
