<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1098"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. James H. Landrum, Judgment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5735</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-188-1</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Boone County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Boone Circuit Court <date when="1858-09-13">Sept 13 -- 1858</date>
<lb/>Comlth vs James H. Landrum } Larceny</p>
<p>deft appeared in dis recog. cause continued and deft with wic Grubbs, Jno. S. Lucas Thos. Landrum &amp; Francis Landrum bail in sum $300 for ap. next term</p>
<p><date when="1859-04">April 1859</date></p>
<p>Recognizance forfeited and summons ordered</p>
<p><date when="1859-11-12">Sept 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1859</date></p>
<p><note place="left margin">Early in day</note></p>
<p>comlth vs Jas. H. Landrum</p>
<p>cause continued until next term of this court</p>
<p><note place="left margin">late in day</note></p>
<p><date when="1859-11-12">Sept 12 1859</date></p>
<p>came the atty for comlth and the defts Jno S. Lucas Thos. Landrum &amp; Francis Landrum not having been summoned this cause is continued as to them and the Deft. Wickliffe Grubbs having been duly summoned and failing to answer answer It is adjudged by the court that the commonwealth of Kentucky recover of the defendant Wickliffe Grubbs the sum of $300 the amount for which he undertook as bail for James H. Landrum at the <date when="1858-11">Sept Term 1858</date> of this court and which was forfeited and that said Grubbs pay the costs herein expended<pb/></p>
<p><date when="1860-04-16">April 16th 1860</date></p>
<p>Judt on forfeited recognizance against Jno. S. Lucas</p>
<p>Thos. Landrum
<lb/>Francis Landrum</p>
<p>Execution issued ags Grubbs alone <date when="1859-11-27">27 Sept 1859</date> which was never taken out of the office</p>
<p>The clerk made a memorandum thus,</p>
<p>It was the agreement with the atto for the commlth and deft that no execution was to be issued for three months in this case</p>
<p>att clk,,</p>
<p>on <date when="1860-04-23">23 april 1860</date>
<lb/>ca. sa. issued
<lb/>agst
<lb/>Jno. S. Lucas Thos Landrum and Francis Landrum for $300 &amp; costs returned thus.</p>
<p>"The fine in this case respited for 12 months see respite herein The costs in the case and 20 per cent of fine Replevied with Daniel Smith security <date when="1860-06-11">June 11<hi rend="sup">th </hi>1860</date></p>
<p>F. M. Combs
<lb/>DS for S Lucas S. G.C</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
