<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2287"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Q. A. King to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6924</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-153 to BR15-154</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Paducah, McCracken County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-08-21">21 August 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Paducah Ky <date when="1865-08-21">Aug 21/65</date>.
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>Tho E. Bramlette
<lb/>Frankfort Ky
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>This will be handed you by Mr James C. Calhoun, at whose instance I write it -- During the adm<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">n</hi></hi> Genl. Paine at this place, he caused the late Shff, G. W. Ratcliffe to resign, and the office remained vacant until May last, and all civil business was either suspended or taken in charge by the military, which produced mucn confusion, and litigation -- feeling the great necessity of a Sheriff, and no one being willing to take the office for fear of the military, a large number of citizens, in Town and County, urged the acceptance of the office on Mr Calhoun, who reluctantly gratified them, and he was appointed Shff by the County Judge to fill the vacancy occasioned by the resignation of Mr Ratcliffe<pb/>
<lb/>he has been acting Since <date when="--05">May</date> last, to the entire Satisfaction of all -- At the Aug election he was a candidate for the Same Office, and Saturday before the election he was arrested by the military authorities and placed in the guard house, for what Cause, he, nor his friends, have not found out -- and was discharged from prison on tuesday, after the election, upon executing a bond to the Military authorities, in the penalty of $5,000, I think, not to leave the town &amp;c -- Now he is Sheriff by appointment and by election, and no one else can act, and he is the choice of 99 out of every 100 in the County; he is about 50 years old, an honorable and high toned Citizen, and popular with all -- Our court commences in <date when="--10">October</date> &amp; Summons &amp; Subpoenas &amp; executions must be Served, he has executed all the bonds req<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> by the statute as Shff, and he is the Collector of all the taxes, and more efficient man, Cannot be found in the State -- and you see at once, if he is<pb/>
<lb/>firmly bound by his military bond, what great confusion, loss and injury, will insue, not only to the State, County &amp; town but the host of litigants in Court. Mr Calhoun is what was termed, a Southern Sympathiser, but never was engaged in the Service of the confederacy or any state thereof, in a civil or military capacity, nor gave them aid or Comfort; has remained all the time at home, except when private business Carried him elsewhere -- He has been at all times a law abiding Citizen -- and a man of incorruptible integrity -- &amp; he wishes your interposition, to enable him to perform <hi rend="underline">freely</hi> the various duties of his office in town and County, without incurring the hazzard of a forfeited Military bond -- &amp; I hope your Excellency will exert yourself in his behalf -- </p>
<p>Yours truly
<lb/>John Q. A. King</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
