<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1435"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Turner to Smoloff P. Love</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6072</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-234</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mount Sterling, Montgomery County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1866-10-01">1 October 1866</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Mt. Sterling Ky. <date when="1866-10-01">Oct. 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1866</date>
<lb/>Col S. P. Love:
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>At our late court, Dury the attorney for the commonwealth admitted that the Judgment against you was irregular and that we could reverse it &amp; consented that it should be set aside, and the order was directed to be made but by some means the clerk failed to make an entry of it &amp; the records now show no such order. Dury is now absent at the Carter court &amp; will not be at home for about four weeks, I am confident if he were here he would write to the sheriff to stop the collection of the execution against you. but as the sheriff of your county will not probably wait that long. You must either replevy the execution or get the Gov. to stay it for six months</p>
<p>Neither of these steps will prejudice you in your rights to reverse or vacate the judgment, do so &amp; I will take the case up and reverse it. but I will not be able to get the record copied for some two or three weeks &amp; it will be the best to either replevy<pb/>
<lb/>or stay the judgment. The reversal will vacate the replevin bond &amp;c</p>
<p>Yours
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Thomas Turner</hi></p>
<p>(F)</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
