<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1388"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Martin Bijur, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6025</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-156</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><persName ref="cwgk:N00006510">Simon Livingston</persName>: stated that on Thursday night about 10 Oclock I arrived in the City from <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000393">Evansville</placeName> &amp; went to my home in the Omnibus, on Floyd between Market &amp; Main street, while I was Knocking at the door (I had a pair of saddle Bags on my shoulder.) in order to arouse my wife to open the door. Three men came up to me (accused are the same men) &amp; asked me What I was doing there &amp; I told them it was my home &amp; one of them seized me by the collar of my Coat another one struck me &amp; one had hold of my saddle Bags: I had some $25.<hi rend="sup">00</hi> in Silver in my saddle Bags: and some Spectacles &amp; about $500. in paper Money on my person. I called watch &amp; my wife who had come to the Window, also called watch &amp; accused ran away -- when they first accosted me, one of them asked me what I had in my saddle bags, the one who had hold of the Saddlebags attempted to pull them away from me, the watch came up just as accused run. I peddle Spectacles &amp; have lived on Floyd Street about 2 years. I believe it was <persName ref="cwgk:N00006465">Cunningham</persName> that struck me. Christian Votter lives in same house with last witness, on Thursday night last heard him Knocking at the door &amp; calling his wife then heard him say what do you want<pb/>
<lb/>&amp; looked out of my window and saw Livingston &amp; three men at the door &amp; saw one of the men strike Livingston &amp; then run away all three. Livingston &amp; his wife who had been aroused, called for the watch very loud and the men ranaway. don't Know who they were <persName ref="cwgk:N00006468">James Shindler</persName>, I &amp; Cochran arrested accused. Heard the cry of murder &amp; ran out from corner Floyd &amp; Markt &amp; Saw three men running down Floyd towards main- purused &amp; arrested them. -- Jno. <persName ref="cwgk:N00006511">Cochran </persName>Same as last witness. -- Bail each in $300- to answer. -- </p>
<p>The above contains substantially the Evidence in the case</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00005665">Martin Bijur
</persName><lb/>Atty for Common<hi rend="sup">th</hi></p>
<p>Chas Miller
<lb/>Richd. Cunningham
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006466">Edwd. Vincore</persName></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
