<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0213"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. O'Hara, Jr. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9681</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-171 to MG17-172</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-12-07">7 December 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Covington Ky
<lb/><date when="1860-12-07">Decr: 7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1860</date>,
<lb/>My Dear Sir -- </p>
<p>I have the most pittiable case to lay before you At a late term of the Kenton circuit court Nevilla Timberlake a youth about fourteen or fifteen years old was indicted for <hi rend="underline">grand</hi> <hi rend="underline">larceny</hi> commited as alledged in stealing four pen Knives form the store of J. P. L. Woodward in this city of the value of $1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">25</hi></hi> each -- </p>
<p>There is no Doubt about his guilt but it is the first thing of the Kind set down to his account -- His father -- (he has no Mother<hi rend="str">)</hi> she died when he was an infant) is a respectable man, and under the misapprehension sent him to the Country and<pb/>
<lb/>he was absent at the time appointed for trial so that his recognizance for $50. was forfeited -- It is needless for me to discant upon the ill consequences that would almost inevitably follow a year or two's incarceration of such a youth in the pentitentiary amongst the theives, robbers and murderers collected there, even should you allow him to go there in the event of a conviction -- I hope it may be your pleasure to grant the little fellow a <hi rend="underline">free</hi> <hi rend="underline">pardon</hi> for the offense -- He has been for some months and is now dilligently engaged at work with his father: I have seen him almost daily during that time and can testify to his dilligence and attention to his duties -- I make this appeal to you because I have no doubt<pb/>
<lb/>that he would be convicted by a jury and I hope to save the father from the additional mortification of the trial and conviction and the little boy from the accumulated disgrace, not doubting that you would not hesitate after conviction to discharge him without ^his^ entering the prison -- His is quite as meritorious a case as that of "Dwelley" whom you pardoned after conviction last winter, but he has not so many rich relations or intersted friends -- His name is <hi rend="underline">Nevilla</hi> <hi rend="underline">Timberlake</hi> <hi rend="underline">indictment</hi> <hi rend="underline">for</hi> <hi rend="underline">grand</hi> <hi rend="underline">larceny</hi> <hi rend="underline">found at the <date when="1860-06">June Term 1860</date>. of the Kenton Circuit Court at Covington</hi> I respectfully and earnestly invoke your clemency -- </p>
<p>Yours &amp;
<lb/>J. O'Hara Jr<pb/></p>
<p>O. Hara for Timberlake -- Pen</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
