<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1952"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">O. H. Strattan et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11420</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Bradley Strait</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG23-400 to MG23-401</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-06-25">25 June 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville <date when="1862-06-25">June 25<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin</p>
<p>Your Petitioner would respectfully state that at the <date when="1862-05">May</date> Term of the Louisville Circuit Court he was fined the sum of sixty dollars The true statement of the facts in the case is To wit -- The Commonwealth vs Edward Barnes for an Asault &amp; Battery on M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> Daugess Your Petitioner called at the house of M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Daugess on buisness and she insulted petitioner without cause or provocation having said nothing to her calculated in the least to arrouse her feelings against him he did all he could to avoid any difficulty with the women She called him several names that are not identified with his character and he pushed her away from him and she fell down In open court she stated that he struck her which he did not do his mouth was closed so far as Evidence in Court was concerned and could not say to the contrary But he was confined to his room or at least in a condition that he could not be at court on the<pb/>
<lb/>day of trial had no counsel engaged and the case therefore went by default -- Had he been able to have made a defence in the case it would have been differant. Your Petitioner further states that he has not nor never did ^have^ any ill fealing toward the said women But on the contrary he has had they verry best fealing toward her. He further states that he is pore and has to make a living by his daily labor but he is out of Employment and can not pay the said fine of sixty dollars</p>
<p>Wherefore he prays your Exclency after due consideration of the facts in the case will remit the said fine which in the event you do not extend this acts of mercy your Petitioner will have to work it out in the work house, having at this time no money Hoping your Excelency will after due reflection of his please will release him from said fine he says he will as before endevor to conduct himself in a manner of ^a good citizen^ That in no wise will he troubel the time of Court</p>
<p>Respectfully<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned sitizens of Louisville state that the case of Barnes is worthey of your Exclency's Consideration and ask the <hi rend="str">the</hi> fine of sixty dollars adgudged against him in the Court ask the same to be remitted<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>O H Strattan Clk C C L</p>
<p>Mr Bond did not attend the Trial of this case -- The witnesses against him are low prostitutes. Mr Bond has behaved himself well since my acquaintance with him (for several years -- and was recently Elected a night policeman by the General Council. He is poor &amp; if he had attended the Trial, from the statements made to one which I believe the result would have been different, I respectfully Join with him &amp;</p>
<p>W G Reasor city atty,
<lb/>W R Hydes city <unclear/>
<lb/>H C Russell <unclear/>
<lb/>J F Shukler
<lb/>Robt A Hamilton
<lb/>S. D Johnston
<lb/>C. K. Fairfax
<lb/>G. F. Tate
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J D Stone</hi>
<lb/>Jeff Brown.<pb/></p>
<p>Louisville City Court
<lb/>Petition of Edward Bond<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>$60. } Assault
<lb/>Edw<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Bond
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-07-22">July 22 1862</date></p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
