<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-028-0057"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">H. Fletcher to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7712</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Appointments by the Governor, Military Appointments, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R2-193</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Oakford, Daviess County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-10-02">2 October 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Oakford, Daviss Co. Ky.
<lb/><date when="1862-10-02">Oct. 2, 1862.</date>
<lb/>Sir,</p>
<p>I was examined on <date when="1862-07-04">4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> July last</date> by the Medical Board of Louisville, receiving a certificate of qualifications and recommendation as Regimental surgeon or assist. surgeon. I presented my claims to the Military Board, with a letter of commendation from Messrs T. Woodson &amp; Maj. G. S. Shanklin of Jessamine, who have known me all my life, and where I have resided most of my life.</p>
<p>There were no known vacancies in Ky. Regiments at the time, that were not offered to other gentlemen. I have since heard that there were vacancies in Regiments of Buell's Division. As this Division is now in Louisville, -- as I understand, -- these vacancies may come to your knowledge as the appointing power; or, if there should be a vacancy of Surgeon or assistant in any other Ky. Reg<hi rend="sup">t</hi>., You will, I hope, not overlook my claims.</p>
<p>I have been in this county but nine months -- I am poor, and not satisfied with my location: -- afflicted with chills, surrounded with secesh, and bedeviled with the guerrilla's, who stole my only riding horse by force of arms a short time since, worth $150 -- ; I am anxious to go into the service as surgeon for the war, and afterward find a more congenial locality to practice my profession. A blue-grass man can't long<pb/>
<lb/>be satisfied out of bluegrass.</p>
<p>If you think there is any probability of my getting a position by going to Louisville, and will be kind enough to let me know soon, I will visit there.</p>
<p>Very Respectfully,
<lb/>Your Obt. Servt.
<lb/><hi rend="underline">H. Fletcher.</hi></p>
<p>Hon. Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. F. Robinson,
<lb/>Acting Govn<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi>,
<lb/>Louisville,
<lb/>Ky.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
