<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2337"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Henry Sikking to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6974</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-232 to BR15-233A</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-15">15 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E. Bramlette Governor,</p>
<p>The Petition of the Subscriber Henry Sikking will respectfully show. That some months since his Brother in Law Henry Maas then a citizen of Louisville had some words of difference with a Tenant who was living in his house and the Tenant called as watchman who coming on the premises without the Knowledge of Maas who is a German &amp; a Man of considerable <unclear/> an altercation commenced between the Watchman &amp; the wife of Maas who is the Sister of your Petitioner. The watchman Insisting on coming into the House &amp; the wife refusing &amp; as the wife stated the watchman having drawn his Pistol Maas seized his Gun &amp; fired at the Watchman, <unclear/> which several shots was fired between the parties outside the House, during which firing the watchman was slightly wounded by shot in the <unclear>head</unclear> Maas also received a wound; the parties got together outside the House &amp; blows was given with their Weapons &amp; whether the Watchman received his wound on the head from the shot or a blow of the Pistol used by Maas is a matter of question. Maas was arrested &amp; held to bail in $400 by the city court to answer in<pb/>
<lb/>the circuit court of Jefferson county at the <date when="1865-05">May Term 1865</date>, for Malicious shooting failing to appear at the time a Forfeiture was Entered &amp; at the <date when="1865-08">August Term 1865</date> of said Jefferson circuit cout a Judgement was rendered against your Petitioner for $400 &amp; costs on said forfeited recognizance he having become bail for said Maas on the bond for his appearances. Your Petitioner will state that said Maas has been but a short time in the country is Ignorant of the Law &amp; <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> was greatly alarmed for the consequences of the act which he has committed &amp; previous to the <date when="--05">May</date> Term last of the said circuit court, left the state, takeing his family with him &amp; leaving your Petitioner to meet the responsibility, which he had taken upon himself as Bail &amp; having nothing to Indemnify your Petitioner. Your Petitioner states that he has no property Except a verry limited amount of Household furniture, that he has a wife &amp; Two children to support that he has a place in the Fire Department in the city &amp; receives about $60 per month which is his only Income &amp; which is barelly sufficient to support his family. under all the circumstances he prays your Excellency to remit all of said<pb/>
<lb/>Judgment Except Fees &amp; costs. that amount being more than in Justice to his family he is able to pay. &amp; he as in duty bound will ever pray &amp;c.</p>
<p>Henry Sikking</p>
<p>The undersigned are personally acquainted with Henry Sikking &amp; unite in asking a remission of the Judgement rendered against him. He is an Industrious Sober, good citizen, and we think the case presents strong grounds for Executive clemency. &amp;c</p>
<p>A Y Johnson
<lb/>T. Jack Conn clerk
<lb/>Jeff County Court
<lb/>W K Thomas
<lb/><hi rend="underline">G,W, Anderson</hi>
<lb/>Daniel Needy
<lb/>the Person Wounded<pb/></p>
<p>Governor Bramlette</p>
<p>I have no doubt of the worthiness of the petitioner Henry Sikking. He is now &amp; has been for some time in the Employment of the Fire Department of the city. His Salary is small and he is poor. I trust you will give the petitioner remittance <date when="1865-09-15">Sept 15 1865</date>.</p>
<p>Yours very truly
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Jo G. Wilson</hi></p>
<p>I concur in the above</p>
<p>P. B. Muir
<lb/>W, G, Reasor City atto
<lb/>Pat Dillon M, C, C, L<pb/></p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Henry Sikking
<lb/>$400,
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Remit</hi>
<lb/><date when="1865-09-18">18 Sept 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
