<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0906"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Zachariah Tate to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5025</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Bradley Strait</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-393 to BR10-394</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Clark County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-05-05">5 May 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excelency the Governor of the State of Kentucky. Your petitioner Zachariah Tate, says. that he was fined at the present <date when="--05">May term</date> of the Clark circuit Court upon indictment for carrying consealed upon his person a pistol the sum of $50. He says the facts are these. he was engaged by James Price to go to the County of Bath, to apprehend a runaway slave in the year <date when="1860">1860</date> and Price advised him to arm himself and he accordingly did get a pistol and put in his pocket just as he was starting on the business of trying to apprehend said slave, and the handle of it was seen by a witness and the court ruled that the above facts which were all the facts of the case, rendered him liable to judgment, and did not bring him within the savings of the act. of <date when="1864-03-11">March 11<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1854</date>. 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Vol. Stanton R.V. <hi rend="str">statutes</hi> page, 414, He says he purchased said pistol for no other purpose than that of protecting his person in the business he entered upon to capture said slave, and he did use it for no other purpose. and it was not his and only borrowed But the court gave a preventory instruction to find against him. He says he has a very large family and is very poor and the fine upon him is oppresive and in fact he cannot pay it. He asks Executive Clemency </p>
<p>Zach'r Tate</p>
<p>Sworn to by Zach'r Tate, <date when="1864-05-05">May 5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>R. D Davis D C
<lb/>For A H Buckner clerk<pb/></p>
<p>John B Huston states that he defended Tate on the charge named in this petition as a gratuity. Tate being too poor to pay anything and he then and now believes that the spirit and meaning of the savings of the act of <date when="1854">1854</date> protected Tate. But the Court ruled absolutely for the Commonwealth. The facts set out by Tate in his petition are these He is a very poor man and has a family of twelve children, and not one of them twenty one years of age, and he is a harmless man, and he sincerely recomends him to the favor of the Governor</p>
<p>J B Huston </p>
<p>I think the case one that merits the clemency of the Executive. </p>
<p>W. S. Downy 
<lb/>com aty </p>
<p>We the Jury who fined Tate recomend him to Executive Clemency and only felt constrained by the instructions of the Court to find against him. </p>
<p>B Y Crim 
<lb/>A L Haggord 
<lb/>E C Browning 
<lb/>William Johnston 
<lb/>J. B. Thomos 
<lb/>William Garner </p>
<p>The other jurors are scattered<pb/></p>
<p>Clarke Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Z. Tate 
<lb/>$50</p>
<p>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/>Thos E Bramlette 
<lb/>conc<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Weap 
<lb/><date when="1864-05-05">5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> May/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
