<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0031"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Alexander T. McElroy to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9499</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17A-91</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-01-28">28 January 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Caldwell. Co. Ky. <date when="1861-01-28">Janu 28 } 1861</date>
<lb/>Mr. Berih. Magoffin</p>
<p>Dear. Sir. I once for the first time in my life take my pen in hande to rite you a <unclear/> conce<hi rend="str">r</hi>rning the murder of Mr Cartewright which was one by Mr Wadelton, and how <hi rend="str">mr</hi> Wadelton has hade afare triel and is condemed to bee hung on the first of March and now Sir they are giting up a Pentisers to have him repreved from hanging and Sende hime to the Penitentry and they are giting all of the little boyes to sine the Pertition they are leting every thing Sine hit they cane persuade in to hit or either hive theme to done hit And now sere Wadelton, has hade a fare triel and the Jurors. was got out of a nother county men that node nothing about either. Wadleton or carterite they wernt interested in the <unclear/> in noe maner what ever and now nothing more then haning would bea rite he has murderde his felow mane in one of the affules maner that any man ever was mirderd in before hea <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> Shot hime all to peases and then after hea was dead hea thene took a axe and chop hime all to peases and Mr Carterite. was one his one Primeses upon Wadleton. kild hime atending to his one afares. A now sere this Pertition is the most of the names is forge to hit and then the worst of all all of the little boys has sinded hit this ivol to bea the fact hit<pb/>
<lb/>is going one here rite in mye one settlemente and now sere if you wil jeste let the law have here one way ruld wil git shut of one of the meanest men in our contry hea ought to a bin hung ten year agoe hit would a Stoped a great deal of means his father is well of and some pore Devils looks one hime as a Perfict god hea is as me^e^ne as there is aney youse of any ware beaing and now sere fore the sake of heaven gest Say hang old Tomes, Wadleton, hea has murderd his felow man one of the finest men in our county a perfict gentleman a mane of hie ranke respectied by all men and as onerbel aman as ever the sone frome heaven ever Spired one think of the Pore mane how hea was murderd by the olde slirk caled from time to eternity taken frome his friendes now Pleas gest let us have the pleasure of hanging old. Tome. Wadleton our county is more than wilen to pay Some man to put the rope a round his neck imus bring my leter to a close thoe I hant half three with my subgect</p>
<p>Remaing your <unclear/> friend til Death so fare well
<lb/>Alexander,, T, M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Elroy</p>
<p>I can git this backed by a large number of our citizens I rote this by a request of a good old sitizen and my one opinion</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
