<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2166"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Jem. G. Cooper et al. to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9242</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-262 to MG24-263</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency the Governor of the state of Kentucky</p>
<p>We whose names are hereto subscribed would most respectfully represent to your Excellency that about <date when="1862-05">May 1862</date>, William Henry was convicted in the courts of Louisville Ky, and sentenced to five years imprisonmnet in the Penitentiary at Frankfort. Your petitioners are impressed with the firm conviction that said William Henry, a youth of only eighteen years, was led from the paths of rectitude and propriety by evil associations, and is not naturally a bad young man. He was deprived of the advise and counsil of a parent at that time when parental control is most efficacious, by the death of his father, and has now a mother surviving. She has two sons in the Union army; and is dependent, alone, for her support, upon her own personal efforts.</p>
<p>Your petitioners would most respectfully suggest whether the law<pb/>
<lb/>in the conviction and imprisonment of William Henry for two years, has not been fully vindicated. They entertain a most confident hope that William Henry will return to an affectionate, ^mother^ and to the community as a useful member, having learned a lesson by which he will always profit.</p>
<p>We suggest that his case is one which addresses itself to your Excellency. is one entitled to Executive clemency, and we would feel highly gratified, could your Excellency deem it consistent with your official only: to grant William Henry an unconditional pardon and restore him to his mother &amp; friends at home, and your petitioners will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Je<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> G Cooper
<lb/>Capt U S. Rect Officer &amp; Dept Prov Mar 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Dist Mo,
<lb/>E H Huff 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Lt 11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Cav M<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Vols
<lb/>Albert Smith pilot on lor Mississ
<lb/>F. L Weber Cap<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> 2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Inf
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Charles</hi> Eichler Capt 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Inf <unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J M Melbourne
<lb/>S. G. Cato. Atty at Law. &amp; Ex Judge of U.S Courts of Kansas Territory.
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Geo Wilson</hi> Ex Judge of Probate in Kansas<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>Judge Aglett Buckner of St Louis will send a letter.<pb/>
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Henry
<lb/>Refused</p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
