<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0306"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky vs. A. C. Murrey et al., Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8758</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-453 to R3-460</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hart County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-12-01">1 December 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="left margin">Preamble</note>
<lb/>Please before Charles Green Judge of the Hart Equity &amp; Criminal Court at the Court House in Munfordville on the <date when="1860-10-13">13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of October 1860</date></p>
<p>Commonwealth Plaintiff
<lb/>against } Motion for Judgment on Forft<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Bail Bond of Rich<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Murray
<lb/>Thomas Hodges A C Murray sn<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> &amp; A C Murray Jn<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> } Defts</p>
<p>Be it remembered that heretofore to wit on the <date when="1860-01-07">7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of January 1860</date> came R A Dawson Esq a Justice of the Peace for Hart County into the office of the Clerk of the Hart Equity &amp; Criminal Court and filed with the clerk thereof a certain Warrant and Bond upon which is the following indorsement, "Received by hands of R A Dawson Esq &amp; filed <date when="1860-01">Jany 60</date></p>
<p>Att Jas H Compton from D C,,
<lb/>which bond &amp; warrant reads as follows, </p>
<p><note place="left margin">Warrant</note>
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky to any Constable or Sheriff of Hart County Greeting, Information having been given me on oath by John T. Thornbury that Richard D<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">2</note>
<lb/>Murray has threatened his life &amp; that he the said John T Thornsbury is <hi rend="underline">affraid</hi> that said Richard D. Murray will him or do him some great bodily harm you are therefore Commanded to arrest said Richard D Murray &amp; bring him before me or some other Justice of the Peace for Hart County to be dealt according to law. Given under my hand this <date when="1860-01-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of January 1860</date>.</p>
<p>R. A. Dawson J P H C</p>
<p>Sums as witness for plaintiff John Buckner John Crouch &amp; Elijha M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cubins</p>
<p>R A Dawson J P H C</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Petition</note>
<lb/>Arrested R D Murray the <date when="1860-01-06">6 of Jany 1860</date> and Brought him before R A Dawson in Hammonville on the same day this <date when="1859-01-06">6 of Jany <hi rend="underline">1859</hi></date></p>
<p>E Hawkins C H C</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Bond</note>
<lb/>Commonwealth of Ky
<lb/>vs } Bond
<lb/>Richard D Murray</p>
<p>Richard D Murray being in custody under a peace warrant sworn out by John T Thornbury and being admitted to bail in the sum of two hundred dollars<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">3</note>
<lb/>For his appearance in the Hart Circuit Court to answer the charge of John T Thornburry on said peace warrant, now we A C Murray Thomas Hodges &amp; A C Jnr hereby undertake that the said Richard D Murray will appear before the Judge of the Hart Equity &amp; Criminal Court on the first day of its next <date when="--04">April</date> Term to answer said charge &amp; not depart hence without the leave of said court &amp; will at all times hold himself amenable to the order of said court &amp; in the meantime will keep the peace towards all good citizens of this Commonwealth especially John T Thornburry &amp; if the said Richard D Murray shall fail to perform any of the conditions of this bond that we will pay to the Commonwealth said Two hundred Dollars</p>
<p>Witness our hands this <date when="1860-01-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of January 1860</date></p>
<p>A C Murray
<lb/>Thos ^his X mark^ Hodges
<lb/>A C Murray Jnr</p>
<p>Attest
<lb/>James H. Shipp
<lb/>R A Dawson J P H C<pb/></p>
<p><note place="header">4</note>
<lb/>And Afterwards To wit at an Equity &amp; Criminal Court Commenced and held for Hart County at the Court House in Munfordville on the <date when="1860-04-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of April 1860</date></p>
<p>Commonwealth Plff
<lb/>against } Recognizance to keep the peace
<lb/>Rich<hi rend="sup">d</hi> D Murray Deft</p>
<p>This day came the atto for the Commonwealth &amp; the Defendant Richd D Murray failing to appear in discharge of his recognizance, It is ordered that the same be &amp; it is hereby forfeited &amp; process is awarded as A C Murray, Thos Hodges &amp; A C Murray Jr his returnable to the next Term of this Court to show cause if any they can why Judgment shall not be rendered against them on said Bond for the sum of Two Hundred dollars,</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Sums</note>
<lb/>The summons issued in persuance of the above order was returned by the Sheriff of Hart County Executed on Thomas Hodges <date when="1860-08-31">Aug 31<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1860</date> and upon A C Murray and A C Murray Jr, <date when="1860-09-08">Sept 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1860</date></p>
<p>Afterwards To wit at an Equity &amp;<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">5</note>
<lb/>Criminal Court Continued and held for Hart County at the Court House aforesaid <date when="1860-10-13">Oct 13" 1860</date></p>
<p>Commonwealth Plaintiff
<lb/>Against } Motion for Judgment on Forft<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Bail Bond of Richard Murray
<lb/>Thomas Hodges A C Murray sen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> &amp; A C Murrey Jn<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> } Defts</p>
<p>This day came the Atto for Commonwealth and the Defendants having been duly summoned &amp; failing to attend and show cause to the contrary It is adjudged by the Court that the Plaintiff recover of the Defendants the sum of Two Hundred dollars (The amt of the Bail Bond forfeited) and also her costs herein expended and may have Execution &amp;c,</p>
<p>Upon the foregoing Judgment the following Executions have been issued to wit</p>
<p>N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 55 N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 72, N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 111. &amp; No 165
<lb/>No 55 R4eads to wit</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Exon P N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 1</note></p>
<p>The Commonwealth of Kentucky To the Sheriff of Hart County Greeting We Command you that of the Estate of A C Murrey Sen Thos Hodges &amp; A C Murrey late<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">6</note>
<lb/>of your bailiwick, you cause to be made the sum of Two hundred Dollars with interest thereon at the rate of six per Cent per annum from the <gap/> day of <gap/>18<gap/> until paid which The Commonwealth of Kentucky lately in our Hart Equity &amp; Criminal Court recovered against them for Debt on forft<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Bail Bond of Richd Murrey also the sum of $4,65 which in the same Court was adjudged to the said Commonwealth for his costs on that behalf expended whereof they are convicted as appears to us of record: And that you have the said sums of money before the Judge of our said court at the Court House in Munfordville on Saturday after the first Monday of January next to render to the said Commonwealth of the Debt and Costs aforesaid; and have then there this writ Witness G T Wood clerk of our said Court at the Court House aforesaid the <date when="1860-11-19">19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of November 1860</date> and in the 69<hi rend="sup">th</hi> year of the Commonwealth</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">G T. Wood C H C C</hi><pb/></p>
<p><note place="header">7</note>
<lb/>Came to hand <date when="1860-11-19">Novr 19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1860</date>
<lb/>John Rowe D S for
<lb/>H S Shondy S H C</p>
<p>Nothing made on the within fild <date when="1861-01-07">Jany 7<hi rend="sup">th </hi>1861</date>,</p>
<p>John Rowe D S for H S Shondy SHC
<lb/>Reld <date when="1861-01-10">Jany 10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>,
<lb/>Att Jas H. Compton D C </p>
<p><note place="left margin">Exon P N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 2</note>
<lb/>Execution N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 92, Reads as follows To wit The Commonwealth of Kentucky &amp; The Sheriff of Hart County Greeting We Command you that of the Estate of A. C. Murrey S<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Hodges &amp; A C Murrey Jr late of your bailiwick you cause to be made the sum of Two Hundred Dollars with interest thereon at the rate of six per Cent per annum from the <gap/> day of <gap/> 18<gap/> until paid which The Commonwealth of Kentucky lately in our Hart Equity &amp; Criminal Court recovered against them for debt on forfeited Bail Bond of Richard Murrey Also the sum of $5.15 which in the same court was adjudged to the said Commonwealth for her costs on that behalf expended whereof<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">8</note>
<lb/>They are convicted as appears to us of record; and that you have the said sums of money before the Judge of our said Court at the Court House in Munfordville on the Saturday after the first Monday of <date when="--03">March</date> next to render to the said Commonwealth of the debt and costs aforesaid and have then there this writ </p>
<p>Witness G T Wood, Clerk of our said Court at the Court House aforesaid the <date when="1861-01-11">11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Jany 1861</date> and in the 69<hi rend="sup">th</hi> year of the Commonwealth</p>
<p>G T Wood C H C C</p>
<p>Come to hand <date when="1861-01-11">Jany 11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>John Rowe S H C</p>
<p>Replevied <date when="1861-03-02">March 2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>John Rowe S H C</p>
<p>Retd <date when="1861-03-01">March 7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Att Jas H Compton D C</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Replevin Bond</note>
<lb/>The Replevin Bond Returned with the foregoing Exen Reads as follows viz:</p>
<p>We A C Murrey S<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Thomas Hodges &amp; A C Murrey Jr principal And J Chase security do bind ourselvs three months After date to pay The Commonwealth of Kentucky (The Plaintiff in Execution)<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">9</note>
<lb/>The sum of Two Hundred &amp; Ten dollars and 67 cents, with interest thereon from this date being the amount of Principal interest and costs of an execution N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 72, which issued from the Clerk's office of the Hart Equity &amp; Criminal Court on the <date when="1861-01-17">17<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of Jany 1861</date> in favor of the said Commonwealth of Kentucky for the sum of
<lb/><table rend="rules">
<row>
	<cell>principal</cell>
	<cell>$200.00</cell>
	<cell>Two Hundred dollars 00 cents</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Interest</cell>
	<cell><gap/></cell>
	<cell><gap/> dollars <gap/> Cents Interest</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Costs</cell>
	<cell>5.15</cell>
	<cell>Five dollars 15 cents of suit</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Sheriff half <unclear/></cell>
	<cell>5 12</cell>
	<cell>Five dollars 12 cents Sheriff <unclear/></cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Writing Bond</cell>
	<cell>40</cell>
	<cell>Commission and forty cents for writing this bond 40</cell>
</row>
</table></p>
<p>Amount 21067 amounting in the whole to the sum of Two hundred &amp; Ten dollars 67 Cents against the said A. C. Murrey Sr Thomas Hodges &amp; A C Murrey Jr and we the said A C Murrey S<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Hodges &amp; A C Murrey J<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> principal and J Chase security have replevied the same.</p>
<p>Witness our hands and seals this <date when="1861-03-02">2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> day of March 1861</date></p>
<p>A C Murrey sr<figure type="seal"/>
<lb/>Thomas ^his X mark^ Hodges<figure type="seal"/>
<lb/>A C Murrey Jr<figure type="seal"/>
<lb/>J Chase<figure type="seal"/></p>
<p>Attest as to A C Murrey sr Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Hodges &amp; J Chase John Rowe S H C<pb/></p>
<p><note place="header">10</note>
<lb/>Upon the foregoing Bond is the following indorsement to wit "Exon issued <date when="1861-06-28">June 28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>Att J H Compton D C,</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Exon 6 No 3</note>
<lb/>Exon No 111 Reads as follows viz</p>
<p>The Commonwealth of Kentucky To the sheriff of Hart County Greeting: You are hereby Commanded that of the estate of A C Murrey s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Thomas Hodges A C Murrey Jun<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> and J Chase late of your bailiwick you cause to be made the sum of Two Hundred and Ten dollars and sixty seven cents ($210.67) with interest thereon at the rate of six per centum per annum from the <date when="1861-03-02">2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> day of March 1861</date> until paid which the commonwealth of Kentucky lately in our Hart Circuit Court recovered against them for debt due on Replevin Bond Also the sum of 50 which in the said Court was adjudged to the said Commonwealth for her Costs on that behalf expended whereof they are convicted as appears to us of record, and that you have the said sums of money before the Judge of our said Court at the<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">11</note>
<lb/>Court House in Munfordville on the Saturday after the first Mondy of September next to render to the said Commonwealth of the debt interest and costs aforesaid, and have them there this writ. Witness Geo B. Wood clerk of our said Court at the Court House aforesaid the <date when="1861-06-28">28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of June 1861</date> and in the 69<hi rend="sup">th</hi> year of the Commonwealth.</p>
<p>Geo T Wood, C H C C</p>
<p>No Security of any kind to be taken
<lb/>Att Jas H Compton D C</p>
<p>Came to hand <date when="1861-07-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of July 1861</date> 10 A M&gt;
<lb/>F. A. Smith S H C.</p>
<p>Served this fifa <date when="1861-09-06">Sept 6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date> on 75 acres of land as the property of Thomas Hodges, R W Compton D S
<lb/>For F A Smith S H C</p>
<p>N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> sale fine respited for 12 months see Respite filed herewith <date when="1861-10-07">Oct 7 1861</date>
<lb/>R W Compton D S
<lb/>For F A. Smith S H C.</p>
<p>Returned <date when="1862-01-18">Jany 18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>Att Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H <hi rend="underline">Compton D C</hi></p>
<p>The Respite filed in the foregoing Exon Reads as follows To wit<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">12</note>
<lb/><note place="left margin">Respite </note>
<lb/>Duplicate</p>
<p>Beriah Magoffin, Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky To all who shall see these presents Greeting Whereas A Judgment has been rendered by the Hart Equity court for $200, against Tho Hodges &amp; others and whereas it appears from satisfactory evidence that the case of the said Hodge &amp; others presents strong considerations for the interposition and indulgence of the executive, Now know Ye that in consideration of the premises and by virtue of the power vested in me by the Constitution, I have thought proper to Respite, and do, by these presents, stay And respite the collection of said judgment save fees &amp; costs for the term of Twelve months from the date hereof and do hereby enjoin All officers to respect this Respite and govern themselves accordingly,</p>
<p>In Testimony whereof I have here unto set my hand, and caused the seal of the Commonwealth to be Affixed at Frankfort on the <date when="1861-02-15">15 day of Febry<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">13</note>
<lb/>In the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and 61</date> and in the 69<hi rend="sup">th</hi> year of the Commonwealth</p>
<p>B Magoffin</p>
<p>By the Governor
<lb/>Tho B Monroe Jr
<lb/>Secretary of State
<lb/>By Jas W Tate Asst secy</p>
<p>on the foregoing Respite is endorsed the following viz: Filed in the office clk Hart Circuit Court <date when="1862-01-13">Jany 13 1862</date>,</p>
<p>Att Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H Compton D C.</p>
<p>Exon N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 165 is now in the hands of the sheriff of Hart County</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Hart Equity &amp; Crimiinal Court Sct</p>
<p>I James H. Compton clerk of said Court do Certify that the foregoing 13 pages contain a full and complete Transcript in the case of the Commonwealth of Kentucky against A C Murrey &amp;c in as full a manner as the same remains on record in my offices</p>
<p>Given under my hand this <date when="1862-12-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> day of December 1862</date></p>
<p>Jas H <hi rend="underline">Compton Clk</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Hart Eq &amp; Crim Ct
<lb/>Commonwealth of Ky
<lb/>vs } Transcript
<lb/>A. C. Murrey &amp;c<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>$200 } Recognizance
<lb/>For J Chase Esq
<lb/>Remission
<lb/>Iss <date when="1863-03-17">Mar 17. 1863</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Fee $2,60</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
