<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0468"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Catherine Knight to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9936</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-230</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Whitley Court House, Whitley County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-01-23">23 January 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Whitly C. H. Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-01-23">Jan 23<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>To His Excellency Beriah Magoffin Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky your Petitioner Catharine Knight would respectfully represent unto your Excellency that of the <date when="1859-03">March Term of the whitly Circuit Court ^1859^</date> Judgment went against her son Benj Knight for ten ^$10 -- ^ dollars for an assault and that afterwards rather than see her son incarcerated in prison She replevied said Judgment and afterwards on the <date when="1859-07-18">18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of July 1859</date> The Governer respited ^the collection of^ said fine for the Term of six months and said time being out your Petitioner will have the Judgment to pay unless your Excellency interven and remit the same your Petitioner would further represent that she is very Poor hardly able to live and has a family and is now old and feeble and that her son is perfectly worthless and will pay nothing and nothing can be made out of him the premises considered the prayer of your Petitioner is that you remit said<pb/>
<lb/>fine <hi rend="str">for</hi>or release her from the payment thereof for which she will ever feell greatful</p>
<p>Catharine Knight</p>
<p>We the undersigned Join in the prayer of the forgoing Petition &amp; cincerely hope your Excellency will remit the fine</p>
<p>R. Boyd
<lb/>Martin Caddell
<lb/>Jo<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Tye
<lb/>J. D. Gilliss
<lb/>W C Murphy
<lb/>John Smith
<lb/>S P Brawner
<lb/>J. Q. Barton
<lb/>Lee Lefarce</p>
<p>Whitley Cir. ct
<lb/>Remitted 
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>$10, } Replevin Bond
<lb/>Catharine Knight
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-01-30">Jany 30 1861</date></p>
<p>fine for which she will ever <unclear/></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
