<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0686"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Benjamin Helm Bristow to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4805</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-50 to BR10-51</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hopkinsville, Christian County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-04-22">22 April 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Hopkinsville Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-04-22">April 22<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Gov Thos E. Bramlette
<lb/>Frankfort Ky
<lb/>Governor</p>
<p>In behalf of a personal friend &amp; a poor but worthy citizen of this town. I have the honor to ask a favor at your hands. I hand you herewith a transcript from the Christian Circuit Court from which it will be seen that M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Faddin entered into recognizance bond with J. T. Savage &amp; T. G. Clark his sureties which was forfeited by reason of M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Faddin failure to appear.</p>
<p>McFaddin has left the country &amp; his whereabouts are unknown. Clark is utterly insolvent and the whole burden of the forfeiture will fall on Savage- who is an honest<pb/>
<lb/>industrious Stone Mason, <hi rend="str">a</hi> worthy citizen in every respect and <hi rend="str">not</hi> worth but little more than the sum named in the bond. A judgment against him would break up his business and ruin him pecuniarily.</p>
<p>He was induced to go in the bond by reason of the fact that M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Faddin was working in his employment as stone cutter and gave the most pointed assurances of his purpose to appear in discharge of the recognizance In this he has been deceived &amp; betrayed by M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>F and now has no hope of deliverance save in Executive interpostition in his behalf</p>
<p>Mr Savage could very readily procure a petition signed by the best citizens of this place but does not deem it necessary.</p>
<p>Your interposition in this case will save a worthy citizen from great oppression if not<pb/>
<lb/>absolute ruin and will meet the approbation of all good citizens.</p>
<p>With high regard
<lb/>I have the honor to be
<lb/>Yr friend &amp; obt Svt
<lb/>B. H. Bristow<pb/></p>
<p>Christian Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>J. T. Savage &amp; T. Y. Clarke
<lb/>$200 -- </p>
<p>Remit ^<hi rend="str">Judgt</hi> forfeiture^ except 30 per cent the fees of the Atty for Comth &amp; the costs of prosecution</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>send to Bristow 
<lb/>Forfeited Recognizance
<lb/><date when="1864-04-27">27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Apl/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
