<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0029"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. Rodes et al. to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14058</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1863</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-07-15">15 July 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Bowling Green Ky
<lb/><date when="1863-06-15">July 15 1863</date>
<lb/>To
<lb/>Gov J F Robinson:</p>
<p>Dear Sir: We wish to call yr attention to the Regiment which Co<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Jno W Green is authorised to recruit in this Section -- </p>
<p>There are guerilla bands all through our County stealing horses: -- indeed, that seems to be their business. In a month or two more they will steal enough to mount a Regiment or nearly So -- unless checked in this course -- Now, we have the Stock in this Country -- and if the Government will purchase we can procure horses enough to mount this Regiment -- If we do not, an equal number will in all probability be lost to this <unclear/> by the thefts of these bands of plunderers -- So that it would be a positve gain to the State -- for the Govm<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> to purchase them. -- </p>
<p>Moreover, we find it infinitely easier to enlist and recruit men, for the M<hi rend="underline">ou</hi>nted Service than for <hi rend="underline">infantry</hi> alone -- Indeed, a gentleman said he could enlist twenty to one -- for the mounted <unclear>one</unclear> infantry service -- </p>
<p>If you can find it consistent with duty or law to allow Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Grider to enlist <hi rend="underline">mounted</hi> <hi rend="underline">men</hi>, we believe the Regiment can be raised very soon; otherwise it is doubtful whether it will be fully raised other than by the application of the draft -- This is a serious matter with us in<pb/>
<lb/>this Country -- exposed as the people are to these bands of depridaton &amp; plunderers -- One good Reg of Mounted men -- raised in our M<hi rend="underline">id</hi>st, who know the Country &amp; dont have to Study maps or geography to learn it, will do us a vast amount of good -- and prevent a great amount of evil -- We earnestly invite yr attention to our request &amp; hope it can be granted -- </p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>R Rodes -- 
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> V. Loving
<lb/>A. C. Dickinson
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J. H. M Goodman</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">P,, Hines</hi></p>
<p>Bowling Green
<lb/><date when="1863-07-15">July 15/63</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Rodes. R. and others.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Guerrilla depredations and recruiting in his section<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Military R. Rodes &amp;c
<lb/>Bowling green</p>
<p>The Govr. has no power to mount the Regt.
<lb/>J W F</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
