<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0875"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Josiah Harris, Jr. to Grant Green</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10343</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-378 to MG19-379</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Paducah, McCracken County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-03-24">24 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Paducah Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-03-24">March 24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Grant Green Esqr
<lb/>Frankfort
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>At M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> Powells request I write you in answer to your of the <date when="1861-03-19">19<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi></date> and State to you the facts, in the case of the Com<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> vs J. H. Powell</p>
<p>He was accused under the indictment of felloniously taking &amp;c one Carpet bag and contends the property of -- Gardiner, it was proven he had the Carpet bag he acknowledged it when first asked as the whereabouts of the Bag. by Gardiner, and never denied having it, Powell got the Carpet-bag from the Hotel where he and Gardiner were stoping, both of them arriving there upon the Same day, Powell<pb/>
<lb/>from Memphis Tenn, Gardiner from almost entirely an opposite direction from the country back of Paducah, entire strangers Powell, had baggage of different kinds Trunks &amp;c &amp;c, he went to the Clerk and asked for his bill and carpet bag, his trunks then being in his room, he paid off his bill, the clerk gave him the carpet bag, he took it left it in the city at a furniture store upon the Same street or nearly So, that he had obtained boarding for himself wife &amp; child, he leaves the Carpet bag -- goes to the Wharf boat to get Some furnature and carpenter tools, he left there when he came up from the boat,</p>
<p>Gardiner identifies to an unsatisfactory extent the money he had in his carpet bag, Says he had a 20$ bill on a certain bank<pb/>
<lb/>and a 10$ bill on another bank, and a five dollar bill on another bank, naming the banks, knows no number of the bills, nor any thing the law requires upon Satisfactory indentity -- Powell has about the Sam Gardiner Swars to, he pays it over to the Mayor until after the trial, Gardiner loses none of his money -- nor any thing else, These are the facts,</p>
<p>Now as to a letter written to Frankfort, by Geo Smedley our Police Judge, I am Satisfied that he is a man of the bitterest feelings now living, he first upon examination convicted Powell and he thinks the Soundness of this judgment would be greatly impaired if Powell were to pardoned, he is a strange man, as t<hi rend="str">he</hi>o the report that Powell had been before in the<pb/>
<lb/>Penetentiary of Va. the men <unclear/> who were Said to have seen Powell there, now deny ever Saying they Saw him, but upon the contrary deny ever Seeing him before</p>
<p>With the hope that the Gov, will do Something to relieve M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> Powell</p>
<p>I remain yours with
<lb/>Respect
<lb/>Josiah Harris Jr</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
