<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0324"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Arden McClanohan et al. to Cicero Maxwell</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4443</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-20 to BR9-21</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Franklin, Simpson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-12-01">1 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Franklin Simpson County Ky.
<lb/><date when="1863-12-01">1 December 1863</date>.
<lb/>To Col Cicero Maxwell
<lb/>Bowling Green Ky.</p>
<p>The undersigned citisens of Simpson County, and loyal to their government, and the old flag<hi rend="str">e</hi> of their country, have heard that Same thought exists of Ordering, Major S F Johnson with the force under his command at this place to same other part of duty.</p>
<p>We beg leave respectfully to protest against it. We do so in behalf of the truly Union citizens of Simpson County, whose feelings on this question we know we represent.</p>
<p>A few, (every few) persons, who <hi rend="underline">claim</hi>, to be loyal we are aware desire his removal but the really loyal men of the County. Than who are so from principal, desire that he &amp; his command Should continue here, Why's Because there is as much if not more of rampant treason in this county than any similar amount of territory in the State. Major Johnson Understands the native, and extent of that treason, and knows how to manage it. He can crush it or keep it within bounds. He has labored hard to recruit the 52 Reg. and a portion of it having Just been mounted<pb/>
<lb/>he is now in a Condition to operate against the guerilla theives, and Robbers who are infesting the Country.</p>
<p>We are Satisfied that he will very soon share his efficiency in Capturing guerillas and Suppressing raids. He will afford ample protection to the Railroad within the District in which he operates.</p>
<p>We could say much more in remonStrance, but regard it unnecessary. Major Johnson is emphatically the man for this post. And if you Should not be the proper officer to appeal to on this question, you will we hope receive this as an expression, of the sentiments of the loyal citizens of Simpson, for the Post Commander at Franklin.</p>
<p>If the thought of the removal of the troops from this place is based upon the fact that a portion of the 52<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Reg are necessarily Stationed at Scotville, and the additional fact that Scotville is in Gen Hobson's district, while Franklin is in yours, we would then Suggest that there seems to us no impropriety in so changing the boundary of the Districts as to place Scotville &amp; Allen County in your District. And if necessary we will petition the proper<pb/>
<lb/>authorities to make Such change for the good of the loyal cause, certainly not because of any objection personally to that brave and excellent Officer &amp; gentleman Gen Hobson</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Arden. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clanohan
<lb/>Christopher Elliott
<lb/>Benj C. Hawthorne
<lb/>John W. Lewis
<lb/>S D Stanley
<lb/>Jas. H. Flemings
<lb/>Stephen Blackburn
<lb/>B Fleming Esqr
<lb/>John Cox
<lb/>G. B. LeGin
<lb/>Rev. James Copeland
<lb/>C. H. Stanly
<lb/>Rev. John Redman
<lb/>C R Stuart
<lb/>Judge W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Kidd
<lb/>D. W. Saunders
<lb/>Rev. James. A. Chase
<lb/>John B Tarrerts
<lb/>ES Howard
<lb/>R. H. Haden
<lb/>James B Masters
<lb/>Mraslee Corcorn
<lb/>John Barthick
<lb/><cb n="2"/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> B Jones
<lb/>R. M. Green
<lb/>N R Harris
<lb/>James Willson
<lb/>S. B. Wooten
<lb/>J. M. Cartney
<lb/>Merrick Wright
<lb/>G. W. Datton
<lb/>J Berriger
<lb/>J. S. Procter
<lb/>H Woodward
<lb/>H. A. Procter
<lb/>B. Flemming
<lb/>R. H. Haden
<lb/>H. Procter
<lb/>James Roberts
<lb/>Geo F Randall
<lb/>R C Blakey
<lb/>C C Brown
<lb/>Joseph Brown
<lb/>J. S. Black
<lb/>S T Barnes
<lb/>J. B. Bogan
<lb/>L. B. Goodman<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>K. T. Skeen
<lb/>John Gabrett
<lb/>G A Tapscatt
<lb/>James W Lewis
<lb/>John Hay
<lb/>N. R. Harris
<lb/>Ed Briant
<lb/>J. C. Mallory
<lb/>Eli. H. Blewell
<lb/>Hiram Roach
<lb/>G. T. Tisdale
<lb/>Jason Neely
<lb/>John Neely
<lb/>R. D. Salmons
<lb/>W. L. Mallory
<lb/>Price Snider
<lb/>Stephen A. Harris
<lb/>T. W. Turner
<lb/>Alec Finen
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. F. Potter
<lb/>H. Hodan
<lb/>D. B. Booker
<lb/>H. G. Harris
<lb/>G Carter
<lb/>Saml Lawler
<lb/>S. B. Wooten
<lb/>W M Haney
<lb/>S. F. Lawler
<lb/>S M. Horne
<lb/><cb n="2"/>U J Haimmen
<lb/>T J Hoy
<lb/>James Powell
<lb/>P. P. Strait
<lb/>Saml. Sadler
<lb/>Tyler Sadler
<lb/>Peter King
<lb/>M. F. Johnson
<lb/>S. Sympson
<lb/>John Dunn
<lb/>James Stwearts
<lb/>F. D. Wade
<lb/>A. B. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Eherain
<lb/>J L M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goodwin
<lb/>William Sadler.
<lb/>Timothy Sadler
<lb/>Jacob Spears
<lb/>John Hoy, Jr<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>This is respectfully referred to District Head-Quarters with the request that it be forwarded to the Governor of Kentucky Several, whose names appear to this petition, are personally know by me to be among the best loyal men in Simpson county, and I have it from undoubted authority that they are all truly loyal Union men, and law and order Caring citizens I heartily endorse what they say of Major Johnson, and I regard the cancelling of his commission as an act of great injustice to a faithful vigilant officer I have been informed by the Judge Advocate of the court, That once had the charges against him under investigation, but which was dissolved before the trial was concluded that all the <hi rend="str">proof</hi> evidence adduced did not amount to any proof of criminality on the part of Johnson The certificate of, the Judge Advocate will be forwarded in a day or two</p>
<p>C. Maxwell Col. 26th M. K. Vols
<lb/>Comdg South Western Ky.
<lb/><date when="1863-12-11">Dec. 11th 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
