<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1268"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George W. Brooks et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5905</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-451</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jamestown, Russell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-10-25">25 October 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Jamestown Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-10-25">October 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Your Excellency Gov Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Bramlette
<lb/>Dear sir</p>
<p>on yesterday George. W. Brooks of Russell County Ky confessed a Judgement in the Russell Circuit Court under an indictment for Trespass for the sum of $25 dollars including an attos fee of $5 -- desiring not be troubled further with it in the way of making defense and We the undersigned citizens of said County would most Respectfully represent to your Excellency that the said George W Brooks has lost considerably by the armeys both Union men and Rebels which has reduced his condition to poverty &amp; almost ruin he haveing a large family to mantain and take care of. He is a peaceable quiet man and as We believe not guilty of the trespass afore said which was alledged to have been committed on the <gap/> day of <gap/> <date when="1861">1861</date> We hope that you will extend to him your generally known magnamnity that prompts you to use your master efforts to relieve our citizens from their very and numerous ^Injuries^ distresses Therefore We desire you to &amp; think you ought to remit that portion of said Judgment that you are authorized to do by the Laws of the state of Ky</p>
<p>George W Brooks states that the facts set forth in the foregoing Petition are true</p>
<p>G. W. Brooks</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this <date when="1864-10-25">25<hi rend="sup">d</hi> of October 1864</date></p>
<p>George Bryan Exam
<lb/>RC</p>
<p>I respectfuly solicit the Governor of Kentucky to remit the fine imposed on the Petitioner above mentioned</p>
<p>Fon T Fox<pb/></p>
<p>I respectfully join in the within Petition &amp; prayer for a remission of the fine but know nothing of the facts</p>
<p><hi rend="str">Jamestown Ky</hi></p>
<p>T T Alexander</p>
<p><hi rend="str">Oct 22nd 1864</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="str">My Dear Aunt</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="str">With pleasure do I tonight seat myself to address you -- I am well and doing very well</hi></p>
<p>I am of the opinion that the within fine ought to be remitted</p>
<p>J. A. Williams co atto
<lb/>Jarvis Dunbar jr
<lb/>J E Hays
<lb/>John Q <unclear>Boone</unclear>
<lb/>W. T. Jackman S.R.C.
<lb/>T. C. Winfrey
<lb/>S P Collins
<lb/>A. P. Simpson</p>
<p>Russell Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Geo. W Brooks
<lb/>$25 -- 
<lb/>Remit -- 
<lb/><date when="1864-11-08">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
