<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2392"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William H. Cord to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7029</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-320 to BR15-321</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Flemingsburg, Fleming County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-11">11 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Flemingsburg, Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-09-11">Septr 11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Dear Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi></p>
<p>Permit me, after my best respects, to appeal to you and I hope with Success (as I do so <hi rend="underline">voluntarily</hi>, &amp; without fee, or reward) for and on behalf of young Felix Edwards who Stands indicted in our Fleming Circuit Court upon the mere supposed alleged grounds of criminal <hi rend="underline">intent</hi> <hi rend="underline">charged</hi> in the indictment and as set forth in his petition_</p>
<p>The Proof against him &amp; upon which he was indicted was general -- that he was with a crowd of Rebel Soldiers who robbed Mr Ed. Pearce -- Some 6 miles from Flemingsburg on the Hillsboro road -- while ^in fact^ he lived with his father abut 1 <hi rend="sup">3</hi>/<hi rend="sub">4</hi> miles from the Town -- had been sent on an errand &amp; was returning as Stated in his petition which is duly <hi rend="underline">Sworn to</hi>, <hi rend="underline">by him</hi> &amp;<pb/><hi rend="underline">
<lb/></hi>vouched for by the other affiants reliable men &amp; good citizens who know he was at home. Sent on the errand stated, and fully <hi rend="underline">believe</hi> his statements as duly sworn to, many more affidavits might be obtained &amp; petitions with numberless names for your clemency on his behalf and prayed for. He is a ^very^ young man <hi rend="underline">now</hi> desirous of doing right, fully warned by the present dilemma of "<hi rend="underline">the right</hi> <hi rend="underline">way being</hi> the <hi rend="underline">only</hi> <hi rend="underline">true</hi> &amp; at <hi rend="underline">all</hi> <hi rend="underline">times</hi> <hi rend="underline">the</hi> <hi rend="underline">best way</hi>" He was only 14 years old, when so <hi rend="underline">put</hi> &amp; held under duress, while other <hi rend="underline">evil</hi> <hi rend="underline">doers</hi> were at <hi rend="underline">their mischief</hi> -- Believing this, a <hi rend="underline">real</hi> <hi rend="underline">case</hi> for your executive clemency -- I hope you can extend it to him -- &amp; that he <hi rend="underline">deserves</hi>, &amp; <hi rend="underline">will</hi> appreciate it. -- Our Circuit Court is not till the 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Monday in <date when="--11">Nov</date>, while he desires to go to ills &amp; put in a crop opf wheat -- is poor not able to stand expenses &amp; returning to Court -- His father is poor and will move <date when="--10-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> oct</date> &amp; needs his Services</p>
<p>Yours truly <hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> <hi rend="underline">H</hi>. <hi rend="underline">Cord</hi>.<pb/></p>
<p>Flemingsburg, Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-09-11">Sept 11, 1865</date>,
<lb/>My Dear Gov -- </p>
<p>I Know nothing of the facts in this case. but I Know A Tower and <unclear/> -- I know that Mr Tower is a very reliable man and I would believe any thing that he would swear to -- I would believe the affiants. I Know that Mr Cord would write you nothing but what he thinks, are the facts in the case -- <hi rend="str">you</hi> If you Could Consistently with your duty as Gov, pardon the young Man, I would think it all right</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>J, W, Anderson</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
