<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0221"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Edward B. Mitchell to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4340</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-340 to BR8-341</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Caseyville, Union County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-10-24">24 October 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>T E Bramlett Gov. of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Edward B Mitchall would state that some time in the month of <date when="1862-10">October 1862</date> James D. Amos I had learned <hi rend="str">there</hi> was engaged with the gurrillas in <unclear>feering</unclear> into the S B Nashville on the Ohio River at whats called Bucks Island abot six miles above Caseyville Union County Ky I charged said Amos with being concerned in the shooting in the boat he cursed me called me a Dam lyar and a dam Linconite I returned the lye in the same language Amos is a large man weighs ovo 200 pounds and overbaring I weigh about 145 pounds Amos drew a pistol on me and shot the ball gowing through my clothes we then clenchid I succeedid in getting his pistol ater he had me down he got off of me as soon as I got the pistol and run I shot at him twice ^one^ of the shots struck him in the back on <unclear>tretched</unclear> his hand it was Amos own pistol I shot him with and the same he fired at the <unclear>passanir</unclear> of the stemer Nashville with I am and always have been a Union man and that was the whole cause of our difficulty said Amos often said he would drive every Union man from his neighorhood<pb/></p>
<p>The Grand Jury found bills agains myself and Amos and the <date when="--10">October term</date> of the Union Circuit Court I was fined seventy five dollars. All the witnesses were what is call Sothern Simpethisers or Rebills In the part of the county that I reside in there was only three Union men besides myself. And under the circumstances, your petitioner would humbly ask your Excilancy to remit the fine of 75$. Amos was fined the same amount</p>
<p>E. B. Mitchell</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this <date when="1863-10-24">24 day of October 1863</date></p>
<p>Attest
<lb/>J W Fennie P. J. C.</p>
<p>We the undersigned Union Men of Union County would respectfully ask the Governor of Kentucky T E Bramlet to remit the fine of seventy five dollars imposed on E B Mitchall at the <date when="--10">October term</date> of said Court we know Mitchall to be a true and loyal man and dont think he should be made pay one cent for shooting Dr. James D Amos. We know Amos and when <hi rend="str">he had his Rebells with him</hi> he is overbaring and very abrusive Further we think Mitchell under the circumstances would have been justifiable had he killed Amos at the time</p>
<p>We would respectfully ask your exclency to interpose your authority and remit said fine your Respectfully<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J W Fennie
<lb/>J G Burough
<lb/>G. P. Riggs
<lb/>James Love
<lb/>Whit Mitell
<lb/>William Besen
<lb/>William Robinson
<lb/>John Cocker
<lb/>J J Batey
<lb/>P. W. Anderson
<lb/>John Yeakey
<lb/>J H Carhe
<lb/>D A Burroughs
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Harroway
<lb/>J M Gentery
<lb/>William Waltserf
<lb/>D Finnie
<lb/>D J Berry
<lb/>Jno Moyer
<lb/>Jerouse A. Gregory
<lb/>W H Cowan
<lb/>Robert Miller
<lb/>Jno Bunyer
<lb/>Hardin Omer
<lb/>Danl. A. Brooks
<lb/><cb n="2"/>T A Buckham
<lb/>Miles Davis
<lb/>W H Shook
<lb/>S Orr
<lb/>W. C. Metcalfe
<lb/>John Tate<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>There is an affidavt filed in my office proving all the statement of E B Mitchell by a man that was with the gurillars at the time of S B Nashville was fired into and a man killed </p>
<p>Given under my hand as Police Judge of Caseyville Union County Ky
<lb/>J W Fennie
<lb/>P. J. C<pb/></p>
<p>Union Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>E B Mitchell
<lb/>$75 -- </p>
<p>Breach of Peace
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1863-11-05">5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov/ 63</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
