<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0051"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William W. Gladish, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9519</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17A-123</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-02-08">8 February 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Caldwell County sct.</p>
<p>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> M. Gladdish states, that he was one of the Jury, that was empanneled and found the virdict in the Caldwell Circuit Court in the case of the Commonwealth of Kentucky against Thomas B. Wadlington decided at the last term of the Caldwell Circuit Court. He states, that at the time of rendering said verdict he did believe that the evidence justified the Jury in finding a verdict of guilty but he states, that since the rendering said verdict, he has taken much pains to ascertain the facts of the case as they really occured, and from the fact of previous threats repeatedly made by the deceased Cartwright against said Wadlington and from the violent and dangerous character of said Cartwright, as he has ascertained it from reliable and good men, and from his investigation of the character of both Wadlington and Cartwright since the finding said verdict, he is well satisfied in his own mind that great injustice has been done said Wadlington by the verdict. He further states, that he does now verily believe, <hi rend="str">th</hi> from all he has been able to learn that a false impression as to the manner of the killig, and as to who brot on the rencounter was made on the minds of the Jury by the evidence of Prince and Blalock, and he does believe that the false impression so made on the minds<pb/>
<lb/>of the Jury occasioned the finding of the verdict wrongfully against said Wadlington. He is now fully satisfied in his own mind from all the facts, and circumstances as he now understands them, that the killing of said Cartwright was in justifiable self defence.</p>
<p>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> W. Gladish</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed before me by W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> M. Gladdish this <date when="1861-02-08">8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of Feby 1861</date>.</p>
<p>J. C. Barnes D. C.
<lb/>for E. P. Watkins clk
<lb/>Caldwell Circuit Court</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
