<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1040"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William F. Moore et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5677</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR[11]-102 to BR[11]-103</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisa, Lawrence County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-07-22">22 July 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisa <date when="1864-07-22">July 22" 1864</date>
<lb/>Hon Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Bramlet Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Would Respectfully represent unto your excellency that at the <date when="1864-04">April term 1864</date> of the Lawrence Circuit Court two Judgments were rendered against the petitioner for Keeping a tipling house The facts in case are these Redhead and your petitioner were Sutlers of the 14" Ky Inf the Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi>. Comdg ordered that Whiskey should be Kept by us and we permitted none to be sold unless upon the order of the officer Comdg except in a few cases when it was represented to be for the sick and in no instance did we prmit it drank on the premises Your petitioner objected to selling Liquor under any state of case but his partner Mr Redhead would persist in keeping it Your petitioner was indicted alone and has had all the cost to pay Beleiving it unjust that he should pay fines when he has committed no offence he respectfully asks Your Excellency to remit, and as in duty will ever &amp;c,</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> F Moore</p>
<p>The Undersigned are well acquainted with the facts in the case set out and beleive it in whitch Execution interfered<pb/>
<lb/>Is Justly remited we therefore respectfully Ask that the fines be remited</p>
<p>P. S Dury Comth Atty
<lb/>J. H Allison SLC
<lb/>G. R. B. Chapman
<lb/>R. F. Vinson C.S.C.C.
<lb/><unclear>W</unclear> A. J. Adkins
<lb/>J W Haws Judge of Lawrence County Kentucky
<lb/>R. F. Prichard. County Attorney.<pb/></p>
<p>Lawrence Ct Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W. F. Moore &amp;c</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
