<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0592"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George R. Searun et al. to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9044</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-433 to R4-434</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To the Hon. <persName ref="cwgk:N001004">James F. Robinson</persName>
    <lb/>Governor of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O001025">Comt'h of Kentucky</orgName>-</p>
<p>Your petitioners beg leave respectfully to submit to your Excellency the subjoined facts by way of inducement for the relief solicited -- <hi rend="underline">viz</hi> -- </p>
   <p>Prior to the month of <date when="1861-05">May in the year 1861</date> one <persName ref="cwgk:N00004718">F, S. Grisnier</persName> incurred the enmity and ill-will of sundry persons in the <placeName ref="cwgk:P00004717">City of Newport</placeName>, <placeName ref="cwgk:P00001874">Campbell County, Kentucky</placeName>, conspicuous among whom were one <persName ref="cwgk:N00004722">George E, Fennell</persName> and one <persName ref="cwgk:N00004723">Marion Hukill</persName> -- </p>
<p>In the night-time those persons invaded Grismiers dwelling-house, laid violent hands on him, dragged him to a convenient spot, stripped him and tarred and feathered him -- for which they were subsequently indicted by a Grand Jury of the County -- (<hi rend="underline">see margin</hi> x) </p>
<p><note place="left margin">x Grisnier instituted an action for damages against Messrs Hukill &amp;- Fennell for the injuries they <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> did him and obtained a verdict of the Five hundred dollars against each of tem</note></p>
   <p>Subsequently in the month of <date when="1861-05">May 1861</date> Fennell and Hukill, in the Mayors Court for the City of Newport, before Hon, <persName ref="cwgk:N00004720">Ed. W, Hawkins</persName>, Judge of that Court, bound over Grismier to keep the peace -- </p>
   <p>Grismier was thereupon required to execute two several Bonds- At the solicitation of Grismier Messrs <persName ref="cwgk:N00004721">Jacob<pb/>
    <lb/>Hawthorn</persName> (now a member of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000923">General <hi rend="str">Assem</hi> Assembly</orgName> from the County of Campbell) together with Mr <persName ref="cwgk:N00004719">George Coy</persName>, who had long known Grismier and believed him a blameless and an abused man, consented to become his bondsman</p>
   <p>Hawthorn and Coy were neither of them present at the hearing before the <persName ref="cwgk:N00004724">Mayor</persName>, but the Mayor subsequently meeting with them, the subject was mentioned between them, and Hawthorn and Coy understanding from their conversation with the Mayor that the preposed Bonds were merely for the appearance of Grismier at a subsequent day to answer before the Mayor told his Honor that they would go on his Bonds -- The Mayor then requested them to drop into his office, at their convenience, and execute the Bonds, remarking that if they should ^happen^ in when he was out to leave their signatures on blank sheets of paper and he would fill up the Bonds upon his return -- </p>
<p>Sometime afterwards, Hawthorn &amp; Coy, relying on the above understanding, went with the Mayors office, and the Mayor being out, signed two blank sheets<pb/>
 <lb/>of paper (Hawthorn signing both sheets -- Coy but one of them) which the Mayor subsequently filled up with two Bonds in a penalty of two Hundred and fifty dollars each, not for the appearance of the Defendant Grismier before him, but for Grismiers appearance before the Circuit Judge, at the next ensuing Term of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000361">Campbell Circuit Court</orgName> at Newport on the 2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Monday in <date when="1861-08">August 1861</date> -- Which Bonds were returned to that Court, and the Defendant not appearing, he doubtless being misled as his securities were, the Bonds were adjudged forfeiteed and are now pending in that Court for judgement for &#36;500 -- against the sureties, Hawthorn and Coy-</p>
   <p>In the meantime Grismier kept the peace in good faith, and prior to the term of the Court at which the Bonds required him to appear enlisted in the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00001186">army of the United States</orgName> and was marched into the <placeName ref="cwgk:P00002510">state of Arkansas</placeName></p>
<p>Finnell &amp; Hukill left Newport and are understood to have gone South,</p>
<p>The above facts demonstrate to your Excellency that Hawthorn &amp; Coy never<pb/>
<lb/>authorized those Bonds as they now appear -- and that their signatures to them is the result of inadvertency and misunderstanding between themselves and his Honor the Mayor,</p>
<p>It is submitted that they would be irreparably injured if they should be required to pay them; To impose such a burden upon them would be extremely unjust and oppressive.</p>
<p>Therefore, in view of all the facts, <hi rend="str">H</hi> Hawthorn &amp; Coy are warmly recommended to the clemency of the Executive, And the undersigned respectfully ask your Excellency to remit the entire penalty of both Bonds -- </p>
   <p><persName ref="cwgk:N00004725">Geo, R, <unclear><hi rend="underline">Fearons</hi></unclear></persName></p>
<p><note place="left margin"><hi rend="underline">Signed</hi>-</note>
 <lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/><hi rend="underline"><persName ref="cwgk:N00004727">Ira Root</persName></hi> atty at law
<lb/>I am Satisfied its all right
 <lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00004728">R T Baker</persName> atto at Law</p>
<p><cb n="2"/>I am personally knowing to many of the facts mentioned above &amp; from the statements of truthful men believe all the above facts are true and feel satisfied that Hawthorn &amp; Coy ought to be released from their bonds -- </p>
   <p><persName ref="cwgk:N00004738">F, M. Webster</persName>
<lb/>Atto at Law
    <lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00004739">W T. Berry</persName>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Atty at law</hi>
<lb/>Robt B MCrackin
<lb/>Mayor of Newport
    <lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00004274">W, E, Arthur</persName> -- </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
