<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0381"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George M. Thomas et al. to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8833</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-117 to R4-118</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Greenup County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Jas. F. Robinson Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The Undersigned members of the Bar of the Greenup Circuit Court respectfully and earnestly recommend to your Excellency to pardon Charles Freeman who has been convicted of Larceny at the present <date when="--05">May</date> Term of the Greenup Circuit Court. They will not minutely detail the circumstances of the case, but they are such as strongly appeal to Executive clemency, so strongly that the Jury in their verdict unanimously recommended his pardon.</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Geo M Thomas
<lb/>Comths atto 10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Dist
<lb/>E. C. Phister
<lb/>Jesse Corum
<lb/><cb n="2"/>L D Ross
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Tho</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> J. Throop</hi>
<lb/>Geo, E, Roe
<lb/>Jeremiah Davidson,
<lb/>John F. Rate.</p>
<p>I think Freeman ought to be pardoned -- He is a young man, with a young, interesting and respectable wife. From what I have learned of his character, he is not a man of crime. No public interest would be subserved by his confinement in the Penitentiary -- and I concur with the Jury &amp; atto for Commonwealth that he is a proper subject for Executive Clemency -- I am not attoney, nor otherwise interested in the matter -- </p>
<p>Respectfully yours
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W. C. Ireland</hi><pb/></p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Greenup Circuit Court
<lb/><date when="1863-05">May Term 1863</date>.
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky Plaintiff
<lb/>against } Indictment for Larceny
<lb/>Charles Freeman Defendant</p>
<p>I certify that the followin is a true copy of the verdict in this cause,</p>
<p>"We the Jury find the defendant Charles Freeman guilty and find his term of service in the state prison one year, and recommend him to the mercy of the Governor"</p>
<p>Attest
<lb/>William Corum clerk</p>
<p>Greenupsburg <date when="1863-05-12">May 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi>/63</date>
<lb/>To His Ex<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> James F Robinson
<lb/>Govenor of Ky</p>
<p>Dr Sir On this Sheet is the verdict of a Jury in the case stated their unanimous recommendation of the party to your Excellency as an appropriate case for Executive Clemency. Also the Recommendation of Geo M. Thomas the Commowlths attony. And all the Bar. all Soliciting an <hi rend="underline">immediate</hi> pardon of Freeman.</p>
<p>Allow me as Judge of this circuit most respectfully to call your attention to this application, as are <hi rend="underline">entirely</hi> and <hi rend="underline">certainly</hi> <hi rend="underline">worthy</hi> of Executive Clemency. I am very sure that there exists in this case many.<pb/>
<lb/>strong grounds of extenuation, and such as marks it as appropriate for you to interpose. by granting him an immediate pardon. and restoring him to a deeply afflected and meritorious young wife &amp; child. I therefore <unclear/> that your Excellency will take immediate action as it will save costs and trouble of Laws <unclear/> him to Frankfort. should you conclude to grant this application and return your pardon to this place directed Will Corum clerk of this court.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Your friend</hi>
<lb/>L. W. Andrews.<pb/></p>
<p>Greenup Cir Ct
<lb/>Pardon granted
<lb/>J F Robinson
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Freeman
<lb/>Larceny
<lb/>Send to Will. Carnum
<lb/>Clerk of Greenup Cir. Court
<lb/>1 yr Penty
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-05-16">May 16. 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
