<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-021-0012"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. William Foster, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG3082</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Apprehension of Fugitives from Justice Papers, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG8-84 to MG8-85</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Knox County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-12-18">18 December 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Knox Circuit Court
<lb/>Commonwealth Plaintiff
<lb/>Against } Copy Record
<lb/>William Foster Defendant</p>
<p>Be it remembered that heretofore towit on the <date when="1860-09-19">19<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of September 1860</date> being the 9<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of the Term of the following Indictment was returned into court by the Grand Jury of Knox County <hi rend="str">upon</hi> which was ordered to be filed and a Bench Warrant ordered to issue against the defendant therein named admitting him to bail in the sum of five hundred dollars (viz)</p>
<p>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>agt } Indictment
<lb/>William Foster</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Knox County in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky accuse William Foster of the crime of Grand Larceny committed as follows towit. The said William Foster on the <date when="1860-09-13">13<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> of Sept. 1860</date> in the county aforesaid unlawfully and feloniously stole, took and carried away one hundred dollars in Kentucky Bank notes and twenty dollars in silver money the property of Alex Black &amp; Sam<hi rend="sup">l</hi>. Black, and of the value of more than four dollars against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Dishman
<lb/>Comlth atty.</p>
<p>Endorsed A True Bill
<lb/>A. Reeder foreman</p>
<p>And on the <date when="1860-09-26">26<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of September 1860</date> a<pb/>
<lb/>Bench Warrant issued against the defendant William Foster admitting him to bail in the sum of five hundred dollars which was delivered to the Jailer of Knox County and by him returned with the following endorsement thereon (viz)</p>
<p>Executed on the within named William Foster <date when="1860-09-26">Sept. 26<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1860</date> by arresting him and committing him to Jail in the Jail of Knox county the said Foster failing to give the Bail required in the within Bench Warrant.</p>
<p>Calvin Brogan, Jailer
<lb/>of Knox County.</p>
<p>State of Kentucky Knox County &amp; Circuit Sct.</p>
<p>I, George M. Adams Jr. Clerk of the Knox Circuit Court do certify that the foregoing is a true and complete transcript of the Record and proceedings in case therein named of the Commonwealth of Kentucky Plaintiff against William Foster Defendant, now pending in the Knox Circuit Court.</p>
<p>Given under my hand this <date when="1860-12-18">18<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of December 1860</date></p>
<p>George M. Adams Jr.
<lb/>clk Knox Circuit Court.</p>
<p>To his Excellency, Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Governor of the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Calvin Brogan would respectfully state to your Excellency, that on the <date when="1860-09-26">26<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Sept 1860,</date> a Bench warrant in the above case of the Commonwealth of Kentucky was placed in his hands as Jailer of Knox County against the Deft W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Foster <hi rend="str">and that</hi> upon a charge of Grand Larceny, and on said day he arrested the said Deft Foster and<pb/>
<lb/>in default of Bail he was committed to the Jail of Knox County Ky, upon said charge after the above indictment had been found against said W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Foster -- He says that said Foster remained in Jail for some time and on the <date when="1860-11-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> day of November 1860,</date> the said W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Foster broke Jail and made his escape -- He says that the Deft Foster has never been tried of on the above indictment, and that he is informed and he verily believes it true that the same W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Foster is now incarcerated in the Jail of Greenville Tennessee upon said charge as he offered a reward of twenty five dollars for the apprehension of said Foster, and he has received reliable information that said Foster has been apprehended and is now in Jail awaiting the requisition of the Governor of Kentucky -- He therefore asks your Excellency ^to^ issue your requisition <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> for the said Foster, and authorize <hi rend="str">H</hi>your Petitioner to bring him to this state -- and to the County of Knox so that he may be tried upon said charge -- He asks your Excellency to ^do^ whatever is necessary in the premises to bring back the said Foster in order that he may <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>be tried -- He says <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> that <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> he was Jailer of Knox County at the time the said Foster was imprisoned &amp; is still Jailer of said County of Knox -- </p>
<p>Calvin Brogan</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by
<lb/>Calvin Brogan this <date when="1860-12-18">18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Decr 1860</date>
<lb/>J, W, Ridgell J K C C<pb/></p>
<p>Knox Co</p>
<p>Issue requisition &amp; appoint applicant agent -- B.M.</p>
<p>Tennessee
<lb/>Requisition for W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Foster
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1860-12-24">Dec 24 1860</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
