<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0886"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Samuel W. Chiles, Joseph Jones, and Richard M. Webb to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5004</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Andrew P Patrick</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-360 to BR10-361</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Clark County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-05-27">27 May 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Clark County Sct.</p>
<p>Samuel W Chiles, Joseph Jones, &amp; Richard M Webb state that each of them and Caleb Parrish deceased, were sureties of Albion T Ryan on his bail bond for the sum of $5000- That at the <date when="1858-07-28">July Term of the Clark Circuit Court July 28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1858</date> Ryan failed to appear and his <hi rend="str">bond</hi> recognizence was forfeited - and said sureties ordered to pay the $5000 amount of said bond. That the sureties Petitioned Governor C. S. Morehead to remit said forfeiture or so-much thereof as the law would permit him to remit and said Governor did remit $3000. of said forfeiture and respited the balance of said forgeiture (except the part allowed the Commonwealth's attorney being $1500.) Said balance of $500 - was respited until <date when="1860-10-13">October 13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1860</date>. Said governor at the time he respited the $500 remarking that by the time the respite runout it would be ascertained whether Ryan could be caught, and then a new application for the remission of said ^balance of said^ forfeiture would be heard &amp;c- They state that they had no idea that Ryan would fail to appear<pb/>
<lb/>at court and render himself up for trial they were up-held in this belief by the conduct of Ryan theretofore as a History of his case taken from the records of the court will show. "A. J. Ryan Indicted for murder <date when="1854-10-25">24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> October 1854</date>" "<date when="1864-10-25">Oct 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1854</date> He gave Bail". <date when="1855-04-25">1855 April 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi></date> Trial by Jury lasting some days the Jury Hung and are discharged. New Bond executed by Ryan.</p>
<p><date when="1855-07">July 1855</date> Appeared Recognizance respited until next term &amp; contd.</p>
<p><date when="1855-10">October 1855</date> Appeared Commonwealth continued the case Recog - respited &amp; cont.</p>
<p><date when="1856">1856</date>. Special Judge elected refused to serve, case continued-</p>
<p><date when="1856-07">July 1856</date>. Recognizance respited &amp; cont<hi rend="sup">d</hi>..</p>
<p><date when="1856-11">November 1856</date> do do do </p>
<p><date when="1857-05">May 1857</date> Same order.</p>
<p><date when="1857-07">July 1857</date> Same order.</p>
<p><date when="1857-11">November 1857</date> Same order.</p>
<p><date when="1858-05">May 1858</date> Same order.</p>
<p>Gov- C. S. Morehead ordered special term to try the case <date when="1858-06-07">June 7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1858</date> - to commence on <date when="1858-06-04">4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Monday in June 1858</date>.</p>
<p>Judge J. W. Moore appointed Spec<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Judge<pb/>
<lb/>And at said <date when="1858">Special Term of said court 1858</date> Judge J W Moore Presiding new bond executed when Samuel W Chiles, Richard M Webb Caleb Parrish and Joseph Jones, became sureties in said bond &amp; case continued until the <date when="1858-07-28">28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of July 1858</date>.</p>
<p>And at said Special term of said court held <date when="1858-07-28">July 28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1858</date>. Recognizance forfeited said bond being for $5000. and Gov C. S. Morehead Remitted $3000 - and respited the $500 as here-in- and said Sureties have paid to William S Downey Commonwealths attorney his part of said forfeiture being $1500 - And they respectfully ask your excellency to remit said $500 being balance of said forfeited recognizence for which there is Execution in the hands of officer.</p>
<p>Saml W Chiles
<lb/>Jos F Jones
<lb/>R M Webb</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to by Samuel Chiles, Richard M. Webb and Joseph <unclear/>, before me this <date when="--05-27">27" day of May</date> <unclear/> 4. 
<lb/>Geo. T. Fishback J. P. C. C.<pb/></p>
<p>Govenor, the facts are all correctly recited in the foregoing petition except as to amt paid <unclear/> In view of what I regarded a great hardship upon these sureties who are all excellent gentlemen I forgave them a part of my Fee. If you can show them clemency I hope you will</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>W. S Downey
<lb/>Lexington <date when="1864-05-27">May 27 1864</date></p>
<p>As Clerk of the Clark Circuit Court I was personally cognizant of the facts stated in the forgoing petition, and they are substantially stated therein. </p>
<p>All the parties including young Ryan are persons of fine characters. Mr Caleb Parrish saw Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Morehead when we procured the remission of the $3000. and respited the $500. He informed me that the Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> said he would remit the whole, but he had offered a reward for Ryan's arrest <unclear/> arrested he would require the surety to pay the <unclear/> was $500. I believe Parrish's statement were true. He <unclear/> I cordially concur in the pray for remission. <unclear/></p>
<p>A H Buckner <date when="1858">1858</date>
<lb/><date when="--05-27">May 27</date> Judge.</p>
<p>Affidavit of Chiles Webb &amp; Jones for Remission of $500 forfeited
<lb/>Recognizance 
<lb/>A. T. Ryan</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
