<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1902"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George W. Riley to William H. Hays</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6539</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-13</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lebanon, Marion County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-05-27">27 May 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Lebanon Ky. <date when="1865-05-27">May 27<hi rend="sup">th</hi>/65</date>
<lb/>Col. W. H. Hay's
<lb/>Dear Sir:</p>
<p>Enclosed I send a petition signed by two hundred citizens of Washington Co -- praying the Governors pardon for the killing of Cap. Miller. I desire you to present it to the Govenor with the <hi rend="underline">best</hi> <hi rend="underline">recommendation</hi> you can give -- You know Yocum and doubtless remember something of the circumstances -- R. B. Yocum was a member of my company -- Is at home, married and desires to live as I beleive a peacable good citizen -- Yocum can get as many more signers as are to the enclosed papers but I guess the Govener will need no more -- I presume that You heard enough of Millers conduct in <date when="1862">1862</date> to enable you to present this petition Cheerfuly -- By attending to this request you will confer a great favour on your</p>
<p>Most obedient servant
<lb/>Geo. W. Riley</p>
<p>P. S. If this pardon is granted please enclose same to me.<pb/></p>
<p>Taylor Shoke in Springfield Today -- I desired to go over with him very much -- but a rush of business prevented me, Taylor is cheerful hopeful, but not altogether sanguine as regards his success -- It is very difficult, to tell as yet what development may be made of things by next august, The people in this part of the Country are mad at every thing that has occured in the last four years, sour and predisposed to much grumbling -- a good prospect for a crop or a new and heavier tax law may frighten them into a good humor The original Rebels -- I think will either vote for Taylor or stand aloof -- The discharged soldiers will vote for him almost unanimously -- He seems flattered at his canvas of Casey-adair and Green counties which he has made lately -- I wish him entire success -- </p>
<p>I have not paid Springfield a visit since Gen Whorten and myself were there, Don't know mutch of our ole beat.</p>
<p>Give my best regards to Harlan</p>
<p>Yours Truly
<lb/>Geo W. Riley</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
