<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3441"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">E. A. Hensley to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5560</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-349 to BR42-350</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Wolfe County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency The Govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>your petitioners Edward A. Hensley would most respectfully represent unto your Excellency that he Stands indicted in the Wolf Circuit Court charged with the murder of A S Tremble he states that him &amp; Tremble was brothers in Law and both Lived in the town of Hazelgreen &amp; had Lived there for Several years &amp; so far as the Petitioner is concerned supposed that they was on friendly relations at Least it so existed on the Part of your petitioner &amp; So on or about the <gap/> day of<gap/> <date when="1864">1864</date> your Petitioner was at home attending to his own avocations &amp; business and went out to his yard gate near where he had a waggon Standing &amp; was Just in the act of Sending his son to the Smith shop to have his horse shod when his attention was drawn up main Street &amp; he Seen the Deceased approaching him in his short Sleeves &amp; he cried out to your Petitioner to prepare himself that he was going to give him (your Petitioner a) <unclear>desired</unclear> whiping when he just observed the Deceased approaching he was some 50 or 60 yards off &amp; at the time he made the remark he was <hi rend="underline">going</hi> <hi rend="underline">to</hi> <hi rend="underline">whip</hi> <hi rend="underline">him</hi> your Petitioner paid but little attention to it not supposing for a moment that he desired carrying on this threats. the deceased Still approached your Petitioner &amp; when he came tolerably close your Petition seen that he was or Seemed to be angry and had a Knife open in his hand still threatening to whip or kill the Petition at this time your Petitioner became alarmed &amp; called out to the deceased to Stop he done this as often as these terms but he still pursued his purpose &amp; came and rushed up to your Petitioner &amp; caught him with his left hand in the coller of his shirt &amp; crevat &amp; raised his right hand with the open knife to stab your Petitioner &amp; again cried out to the Deceased to let him go he paid no attention to this &amp; your Petitioner believed that his life was in Eminent danger and he drew from his pocket a small pocket Pistol and shot the deceased which proved fatal Your Petitioner done what he done in Self Defence &amp; to save his own life &amp; for no other purpose or desire Since the unfortunate occurence Your Petitioner understands that the Deceased was induced to persue the course he did from some false<pb/>
<lb/>representation that was made to him by some one &amp; which was unknown to your Petitioner no one regrets the occurance more than your Petitioners Was actuated by no other Design thank to save his own life or from great bodily harm wherefore he prays your honour to Pardon him &amp; will ever pray</p>
<p>E A Hensley</p>
<p>We the undersigned concur in the statements in the above Petition &amp; ask your Excellency to Pardon the said Petitioner</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> W Hazelrigg
<lb/>John W Kendall
<lb/>P. J. Livingston
<lb/>J. F. Spradlin
<lb/>J. W. Gordon
<lb/>Solomon F Spradlin
<lb/>Isaac Henry
<lb/>James Eden
<lb/>Amos Darrs
<lb/>James.B. Fuqua
<lb/>James D bay
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Lewis
<lb/>J H Mcquire
<lb/>W T. Harvey
<lb/>R C Day
<lb/>James P Holderby, P. M.
<lb/>G. W. Cox
<lb/>H. H. Stanifer
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John. T. Hazelrigg Clk M C C
<lb/>W H Elam S M C
<lb/>I N Cotter
<lb/>Saml J Adams
<lb/>Thomas Mann
<lb/>J. J. Suitman
<lb/>G. Evans</p>
<p>Will H Winn of Mt Sterling Kentucky.
<lb/>B. A. Seaver
<lb/>of Mt Sterling Ky<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>I never in my life before signed a petition to pardon, before trial, &amp; never believed that I would, but if there is a case that I cannot myself dismiss &amp; yet should be dismissed, this is it.</p>
<p>J. S. Durry
<lb/>Com<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Atty.<pb/>
<lb/>The undersigned know personally or by reputation <hi rend="str">more</hi> ^many^ of the signers to the within petition <hi rend="str">They</hi> ^Some of them^ are among the best &amp; most substantive citizens of the county. The list embraces minister of the gospel, merchants, business men and public officers.</p>
<p>E. Patrick</p>
<p>I have no ^sufficient^ personal knowledge of the facts in the case, and only speak with reference to the respectability and reliability of some of the signers to the petition</p>
<p>E. Patrick<pb/>
<lb/>E A Hensley</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
