<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1605"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Willis Reynolds, Judgment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6242</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-45 to BR13-46</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jessamine County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Jessamine Circuit Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>Against
<lb/>Willis Reynolds</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Jessamine County in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky accuse Willis Reynolds of the offense of Standing Jack without license committed as follows viz. the said Willis Reynolds on the <date when="1861-09-02">2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> day of September 1861</date> in the county aforesaid did stand a Jack without having obtained license so to do which he permitted to serve mares and Jennets at the price of $10<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> each against the peace and dignity of the commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>W. S. Downey
<lb/>Com. Atty</p>
<p>Witnesses
<lb/>Benedict Baker
<lb/>Harrison Stinnett</p>
<p>Willis Reynolds being in custody charged with the offence of standing a Jack without license and being admitted to bail in the sum of $100 -- now I. John I. Reynolds of Jessamine County Kentucky hereby undertake that the above named Willis Reynolds will appear in the Jessamine<pb/>
<lb/>Circuit Court on the 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of its <date when="1862-09">next September</date> term to answer said charge and will at all times render himself amenable to the orders and process of said Court in the prosecution of said charge and if convicted will render himself in execution thereof; or if he shall fail to perform either of these conditions that I will pay to the Commonwealth of Kentucky the sum of One Hundred Dollars -- </p>
<p>Witness my hand this <date when="1862-08-08">8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Day of August 1862 -- </date></p>
<p>Willis ^his X mark^ Reynolds Sr.
<lb/>John I. Reynolds</p>
<p>Taken and subscribed before me as Sheriff of Jessamine County Ky.</p>
<p>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E Rutherford D. S.</p>
<p>At a Circuit Court held for Jessamine County <date when="1865-03-06">March 6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865 -- </date></p>
<p>The Defendant Willis Reynolds altho duly summoned and recognized to appear came not but made default -- It is therefore adjudged by the court that said Willis Reynolds make good his fine to the Commonwealth by the payment of Forty Dollars and also her costs herein expended and<pb/>
<lb/>that he be taken therefor -- And the Defendant Willis Reynolds failing to appear herein according to his recognizance entered into by him said recognizance is adjudged by the court forfeited and it is ordered that a summons issue against the surety in said recognizance returnable to 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Day of the next term of the court to show cause if any ^he can^ why Judgment shall not be rendered against him for the same and costs</p>
<p>A Copy
<lb/>att S. Noland c. J. c. c.<pb/></p>
<p>Jessamine Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Willis Reynolds &amp; Surety</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1865-04-07">7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Apl/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
