<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-033-0011"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Frances Huff to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1474</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Jacob A Glover</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Apprehension of Fugitives from Justice Papers, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-34 to R3-35</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-08-11">11 August 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Frances Huff a resident of Louisville respectfully states that at the <date when="1859-10">October Term 18<hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>59</date> of the Jefferson Circuit Court her son William A. Huff was tried on an Indictment charging him with a Felony (stealing jewelry from a Jewlers store) and convicted &amp; Sentenced to Four years &amp; Six months in the penitentiary where he has been ever since confined, He was charged with the commission of the offense in company with one charles Stephens who was tried at the same time convicted &amp; Sentenced for the same term -- She states that at the time of his conviction her said son was under 18 years of age, and the oldest of Ten children, Seven of whom are living. -- </p>
<p>She states that shortly after the conviction of her son; his father the Husband of your petitioner being much grieved &amp; mortified at the conviction of his son left his home and family &amp; went South to engage in work at his business as a Blacksmith, that for some time she has not heard from her said Husband &amp; does not know whether he is living &amp; if alive what his conditions and circumstances are * <note place="left margin">* since this petition was written his father has returned &amp; Joined the army he also served in the Mexican War</note></p>
<p>That given the absence of her husband she has supported by her own labor; being poor &amp; without other means of support, herself &amp; her six children at home with her; she is getting in years &amp; declining in health &amp; needs the help of her son now in prison to aid her in supporting the family. -- Your petitioner will not attempt an apology for her son<pb/>
<lb/>but she Insists that the punishment put upon him by the Jury was unreasonably severe for one of his years, charged for the first time of offense against the Laws; she has understood that the object of the punishment Inflicted upon those who violate the Law is to reform them and she submits to your Excellency if there is not a danger by Imposeing too severe a penalty on the young; that they may become reckless &amp; in their desperation make resolves to be avenged on what seems to them to be unjustly and unreasonably severe, Her son has now been confined Two years &amp; <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>Ten months at hard labor, certainly a sufficient time to effect a reformation if such can be effected by Imprisonment &amp; Labor, and she fears a longer confinement may result in Injury rather than good to her <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>unfortunate son She therefore most humbly beseeches your Excellency to Pardon her said son, that he may before it be too late enter upon a course of life which will regain for him a good name &amp; make him useful to himself, to your Petitioner &amp; <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>his unfortunate Brothers &amp; Sisters &amp; your Petitioner as in duty bound will ever pray &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi></p>
<p>Frances Huff</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Frances Huff <date when="1862-08-11">August 11<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1862</date></p>
<p>Geo W Johnston J. c c L.<pb/></p>
<p>To His Excellency the Governor</p>
<p>In view of the considerations presented in the foregoing petition, I hope the clemency of the Executive may interpose. the punishment was very severe, and I cheerfully join in the prayer of the petitioner
<lb/><date when="1862-08-09">August 9 1862.</date></p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>E S Craig
<lb/>Atto for Commonwealth
<lb/>7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Jur dis</p>
<p>In consideration of the time young Huff has been Imprisoned and a Sympathy for his aged &amp; afflicted Mother we unite in the Petition that he be released.</p>
<p>Tho. Joyes</p>
<p>I am well acquainted with the mother and family of young William Huff and Knew him when he was my Sundy school s<hi rend="str">sk</hi>chollar -- He was a promising boy till a short time before he was led off to commit the crime for which he is now punish<hi rend="str">d</hi>ed, being about 17 years of age -- I hope the Executive will feel at liberty to release the ballance of young Huffs time and extend to him the Executive clemency</p>
<p>S. A. Atchison</p>
<p>Gov. Jas F. Robinson
<lb/>D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Sir.</p>
<p>The Petition was written previous to the resignation of Gov Magoffin &amp; is addressed to him, but the circumstances are the same now as when it was written; &amp; I have advised Mrs Huff that you will act upon it, as readily as if addressed to yourself &amp; that she need not be <unclear/><pb/>
<lb/>trouble to see those who have signed the Petition <hi rend="str">again</hi> to get their signatures again to another. -- </p>
<p>Very respectfully
<lb/>Geo. W. Johnston -- </p>
<p>I have known young Huff a Bout 12 or 15 years and I think his Punishment is a Nu<hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>gh at this time My Store is in the Neighborhood Where he Was Raised and Where his Mother Now Lives</p>
<p>Very Respectfull
<lb/>J. R. Browne</p>
<p>Jefferson
<lb/>Cir. Ct</p>
<p>Pettn granted Pardon
<lb/><date when="1862-08-20">20 Augt 1862</date>
<lb/>J F R.</p>
<p>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> A. Huff
<lb/>4 ys &amp; 6 Mos.
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-08-20">Aug 20. 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
