<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0262"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. B. McWhorter and J. B. Beams to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4381</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-413</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To the honourable Thos E Bramlett governor of Kentucky the undersigned petitioners would represent unto your honor that at the last term of the Taylor Circuit Court a fine of $20 was assessed against Thomas Spratt, on an indictment for "gaming on the premises of an other" two persons were indicted for the same thing in different indictments, the proof in the two Cases was <hi rend="str">the</hi>by the same wintesses and was <unclear>Pawt=ically</unclear> the same in both cases the jury in one case acquitted the other, &amp; fined Spratt, in his case, the proof was clear that the game was not played on the premises of the man named in the indictment, but on that of an other in the possession occupany &amp; under the controll of an other -- Spratt is a poor man does not follow gaming &amp; the proof stated they were only playing for 5 cents &amp; but a single Game, the undersigned respectfully petition your honour to remit said fine.</p>
<p>J B McWhorter S. T. C
<lb/>J. B. Beams D<hi rend="sup">s</hi><pb/></p>
<p>To his Excellency T. E. Bramlett Governor of Ky
<lb/>Sir.</p>
<p>Having investigated, the facts in the case of the within named Spratt said of the opinion that that it would not be detrimental to the public interest and to justice if the fine assessed against him, be remitted. I therefore respectfully ask that you will remit the Same.</p>
<p>Very Truly Your
<lb/>J. C. Chandler</p>
<p>Refused
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette</p>
<p>Taylor Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Thos Spratt</p>
<p>Refused
<lb/><date when="1863-11-10">10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov/ 63</date>
<lb/>Ans<hi rend="sup">d</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
