<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2418"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James L. Ruffin to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7055</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-358</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Cincinnati, Hamilton County, Ohio</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-23">23 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>CITY OF CINCINNATI,
<lb/>Office of Chief of Police, <date when="1865-09-23">Septr 23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>Gov F, C, Bramlette
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>Permit me to introduce to you the bearer Miss Maggie DeBeck of our City she is an estimable lady and respectibly connected -- she visits Frankfort interfered in behalf of Geo. C. Barnes now in your Penitentiary sentenced for ten years the half which he has now served out -- I have Known him for a number of years and considered him more misguided than criminal, he has influencial but think <unclear/> and distance prevented him from applying to them I can cheerfully say that I consider him a suitable subject for executive "clemency" and if consistant with your duty to "pardon" him I think he will endevour to become once again a worty member<pb/>
<lb/>of society as he has been most severly punished for his indiscression.</p>
<p>I am your respectfully
<lb/>Jas L Ruffin
<lb/>Chief of Police</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
