<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0385"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Robert Payne to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4504</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-112</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1863-12-07">7 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Honorable Governor. Bramlett Kty
<lb/>Dear Sir,</p>
<p>Permit me to address you from my short acquaintance with you whilst at my House in behalf of my neighbour M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Jeremiah J. Martin who stands charged in an inditment for suffering gambling to be carried on in his House, and I must truly say that I have lived a neighbour to M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Martin for six or seven years and have never seen a card thrown in his ^House^ for money nor no other species of gambling, I have frequently been present when there were parties of Gentlemen who would play a game of Euckir or Whist to pass of the time and I for one have joined the party, and no money <unclear/> this suggestion of several Gentlemen of your acquaintances made by Judge Cox &amp; the Captain is a very good one far better than a Petition goten up and signed by Bob. dick, Tom &amp; Harry that you know nothing of, and reminds me me of my own situation when I lived at the Town Bluelicks and Kept a Hotele there. I was find in the same way a fine of five Hundred dollars stood against me for the same offence, and I was advised to get some Gentlemen of my acquaintance to write to the governor which I did Gov. Clarke presided then, and the Honl. Gov. Metcalf Honl John Chambers Hol John Grin and several others addresed the Old Gentleman in my Behalf<pb/></p>
<p>when those letters were presented to the Old Gentleman they found him in his office, after presenting of them he turned to his clerk and told him to remit the fine, there were the other cases who had large Petitions presented that were got them omitted, then gentemen stated they had been Boarders at my House and never saw anything of the kind only as I have spoken as a Party of Gentlemen for there own amusement and Believe me D Sir yours with sentiments of high Respect</p>
<p>Robt Payne
<lb/><date when="1863-12-07">Deb 7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
