<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1070"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. W. A. Harris, Lee Harris, and P. K. Christian, Judgment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10538</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-168</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Commonwealth of Ky Plff
<lb/>against } assault &amp; Battery
<lb/>W A Harris Lee Harris &amp; P K Christian Defts</p>
<p>This day came the attorney for the Commonwealth and the defendants by their attorneys and thereupon came a jury towit: P G Roby. B L Waller, D Hooser, Sal Wolf, John Lindsay, J W Stovall T J Wilson, Sam<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Calpin, Stephen Latham N C Lewis, J C Millen and S P Standard who being sworn well &amp; truly to try the issue joined and having heard the evidence &amp; arguments of the Counsell and being Charged by the court, upon their oaths do say "we of the Jury find the defendants <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>W A Harris &amp; P K Christian guilty of an assault and assess the fine at forty five dollars on each and Lee Harris not guilty as charged in the indictment" B L W -- </p>
<p>Wherefore it is considered by the court that the plaintiff recover of each of the defendants W A Harris &amp; P K Christian the sum of forty five dollars &amp; her cost herein expended.</p>
<p>A copy attest
<lb/>Ben L Perkins C T C C<pb/></p>
<p>Todd Cir. Ct
<lb/>Respite 12 mo
<lb/>B M
<lb/>$45. each
<lb/>W. A Harris &amp; P. K. Christian
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi>. <date when="1861-05-11">May 11. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
