<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1412"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Stephen H. Young to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6049</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-198 to BR12-199</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His excellency Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. E. Bramlett
<lb/>Gov of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Stephen H Young would respectfully represent to Your Excellency that while stationed at camp at Grayson Carter Co. Ky with his camp. "K" of the 40<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Reg Mounted Infantry, and in the month of <date when="--10">Oct.</date> last a woman by the name of Margaret Cooly -- of bad fame &amp; character, got into the lines and being diseased with venerial disease, innoculated many of the men of the Company. This Petitioner sought all mild &amp; proper means to rid the neighborhood of her presence. This brought down on him her vengeance and caused her to take down the fences around his lot and yard &amp; trespass on his premises. Finding she was desperate &amp; he could not rid himself of her than by some harsher course. he caused her to be ordered off. this induced her to assail him with vulgar and abusive language, now in a fit of passion, for which he now regrets as she was a woman or female he slaped her. She endeavored to have him presented by the grand Jury. They ignored her Complaint and on the day he was ordered away with his company to Mt -- <pb/>
<lb/>Sterling a warrant from a Justice of the Peace on her complaint was served on him Being enabled to stay &amp; attend to it, during his absence, the case was tried &amp; he fined $30. &amp; costs. He has been kept away from his home at Grayson, in the service, so that he could not appeal the Case. and indeed he did not learn of it in time to do so</p>
<p>Therefore he asks the interposition of your excellency even for a remission of the fine</p>
<p>S H Young capt
<lb/>Comdg Co (K). 40<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Reg Ky Vols</p>
<p>We the undersigned say that we are acquainted with the general moral character by reputation of Margaret Cooly and do say that it is bad &amp; that of a very Common prostitute.</p>
<p>Thos H Mannen
<lb/>Maj 40" Ky Vols</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Vincent Blankinship
<lb/>James C Pirkins
<lb/>Benjamin F
<lb/>Barnett
<lb/>Warren H Devon 1st, Lt a.c.
<lb/>John W Davis
<lb/>John Bisell
<lb/>Andrew Wood
<lb/>Sameul Former
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Robert, T, Duncan
<lb/>William Frisby
<lb/>J. B. Leslie
<lb/>J. B. Capt Co, C, 40<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky
<lb/>John C Blevens 1.<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Sergt Co (K) 40 Ky
<lb/>Marshal Butrum
<lb/>Louis R. Ulen
<lb/>Elisha S Rice<cb n="2"/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette<pb/></p>
<p>Carter Co.
<lb/>Stephen H Young</p>
<p>Fine 30 before Justice of peace for breach of the peace upon person of Margaret Cooly -- </p>
<p>Mail to young
<lb/><hi rend="str">at W</hi>
<lb/>care of col True
<lb/>Paris
<lb/>Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
