<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1158"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Stephen Schwind et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10626</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-312</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-12">12 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1861-06-12">June 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>B Magoffin Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned petitioners Joseph Valke, Jacob Darnis, Jacob Schloeterer, Herman Koehler, Francis Graff &amp; Louis Weyd, Joseph Bosser, Peter Sinden, Micheal Smith, George Devill, John Fisher Steven Schwinger John Wahl -- and John Senty would most respectfully state that at the <date when="1861-06">June term 1861</date> of the city court of Louisville, they were each fined Twenty Dollars for once Selling liquor without license, they state that they have kept coffee houses in said City for a number of years, that they have always paid their license for the Same, that it is almsot impossible to collect money now in Said City, that a few days Elapsed between the Experation of their old license and their renewel, that the delay was not occasioned by any desire on their part to injure the City in her reveneus, but because they could not get the money Sooner to pay their license, they trust that in view of the facts of the case Your Excellency will grant to Each of the -- undersigned, a <hi rend="underline">seperate</hi> <hi rend="underline">remission</hi> of Said fine,</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Stephen Schwind
<lb/>John Wahle
<lb/>John Fisher
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Joseph Valke
<lb/>Jacob Darnis
<lb/>Jacob Schloeterer
<lb/>Herman Koehler
<lb/>Graff &amp; Wiyd
<lb/>Joseph Bosser
<lb/>Peter Sinden
<lb/>Micheal Smith
<lb/>George Devill
<lb/>John Sinty
<lb/>Steven F<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned Citizens of Louisville unite with the within petitioners in asking your Excellency to remit said fines -- believing theirs a case that Calls for Executive Clemency</p>
<p>W Clark. Price
<lb/>I. W. Allen D. C
<lb/>W J Ward
<lb/>H. S. Johnston D. M
<lb/>F. B. Jones D M
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Shryock D clk
<lb/>L Beckman
<lb/>Carl Johnston</p>
<p>The Statements contained in the foregoing petition are true, ^some of^ the parties paid for their license before trial -- and the balance after trial. Their License were dated back to the time when their original license Expired &amp; the City has lost no time. We Join with petitioners &amp; ask for a remission of their fines</p>
<p>W G Reasor City atto.
<lb/>Geo. W. Johnston</p>
<p>Send to Care of W. C. Price</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Louisville City Ct
<lb/>$20 } Gaming
<lb/>Iss Valke &amp; others.</p>
<p><date when="1861-07-18">July 18. 1861</date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Petition</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
