<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1274"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Campbell et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5911</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-459 to BR11-460</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-10-26">26 October 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlette Gov. of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Thomas Campbell would respectfully represent unto your excellency that at the <date when="1864-02">Feby Term of the Rockcastle Circuit Court 1864</date> he was fined the sum of $250 and costs -- he is a citizen of Madison Cty Ky and the Ca. Sa. was sent to his county -- and it says for a fine but does not say what for, but your petitioner had a summons served on him from Rockcastle County and he went out to attend the trial in <date when="1863-02">Feby 1863</date> and during the time of court and before the trial came up. there was an alarm caused by the report of a rebel raid, and almost every person was flying from town, when your petitioner went to the judge and inquired what would be done with his case, the judge told him to go home that he need not pester himself about it, he accordingly done so, and knowing that he had committed no offence against the laws, he thought it was done with, and never knew any better until the Exr was presented to him when he found that in his absence and without his Knowledge and without making any defence he was fined as aforesaid</p>
<p>The facts of the case on which the indictment was found, and the fine assessed were as follows -- your petitioner was at M<hi rend="sup">t</hi>. Vernon and just upon starting home he was in a grocery when a man intoxicated rode up to the door and attempted to ride in the house, he told the man not to ride in the house, the man replied that he owed the grocery keeper ten cents and wanted to pay him he (Campbell) replied that he would pay it for him, and turned to do so when the gro-<pb/>
<lb/>cery Keeper looked and saw who it was and told Campbell that the man did not owe him any thing, by this time the man had got down and came again, swearing he did not owe any thing, Campbell told him he knew nothing about it only that he said he did, The man then called him (Campbell) a damned liar and commenced feeling as if he was attempting to draw his arms -- when he Campbell drew his pistol but the crowd interfered, and no damage was done in any way=your petitioner therefore prays your exellency to remit said fine (except fees &amp; costs) as he thinks the same was unjustfully assessed against him</p>
<p>Thomas Campbell</p>
<p>Thomas Campbell this day made oath before me an Examiner for Garrard County that the statements in the above petition are true this <date when="1864-10-26">26<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Oct 1864</date></p>
<p>E D Kennedy Exr GC</p>
<p>I Absalom Pollard being sworn state that I was present with Thos Campbell at Mt Vernon at the time of the affray mentioned in the foregoing <hi rend="str">petition</hi> and for which the fine was assessed, and was also present with him when he went to the judge as spoken of and I know that the statements made by Campbell in the foregoing petition are true, and I had no idea from what the judge told Campbell but that the case would be dismissed</p>
<p>A Pollard</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by A Pollard this <date when="1864-10-26">26<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Oct 1864</date></p>
<p>ED Kennedy - Examiner GC<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned join in the prayer of the petition of the foregoing petition</p>
<p>E D Kennedy
<lb/>Ab. Pollard
<lb/>J. F. Cook
<lb/>S. C. Hallen
<lb/>J H Burnam
<lb/>John Baker
<lb/>W B Wright
<lb/>William Wallace
<lb/>Dr. W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Chase
<lb/>N. D. Willmot. (late Lieut 3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Ky. Inf
<lb/>James Patterson, late Judge of garrard County Court
<lb/>Jas A Anderson Co atto.
<lb/>Jas L Anderson SGC</p>
<p>I have no doubt but this is a case <hi rend="str">of</hi> in which executive clemency <hi rend="str">ought</hi> ought to be <unclear>executed</unclear> &amp; have heard the case fully stated from reliable sources</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Humphrey Bert
<lb/>Jas A Scott
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Frank Wolford
<lb/>G. W. Dunlap<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Rockcastle Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Thos Campbell
<lb/>To } Petition
<lb/>Gov. Bramlette<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>$200 -- 
<lb/>Remit -- <hi rend="underline">for affray</hi>
<lb/><date when="1864-11-10">10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
