<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0602"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">G. P. Hawkins to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4721</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-456 to BR9-457</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Nicholasville, Jessamine County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-03-30">30 March 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Nicholasville Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-03-30">March 30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Go<hi rend="sup">v</hi> Bramlett
<lb/>D Sir</p>
<p>M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Martin Hunter of Jessamine County was convicted upon an Indictment for suffering Gameing and fined Two Hundred dollars &amp; costs at the <date when="1864-03">March Term of the Jessamine Circuit Court 1864</date>.</p>
<p>I was in court and heard all the evidence upon the trial and was supprised that the Jury should upon the evidence find him guilty, One witness (who admited that he was hostile to the defendant Hunter) stated that upon one occasion he was at the Distilery of Hunter and same Hunter and others playing cards. and upon that game a treat was bet. One of the partys who the witness represented to have plaid in the game, hapened to be in court<pb/>
<lb/>and stated that he had plaid cards with Hunter but alone for amusement and never for money or property. That he had frequently or several times plaid at Hunters still house for amusement. And upon that proof above the jury found Hunter guilty</p>
<p>M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Hunter is an industrious business young man of more than ordinary energy and application and I believe him to be reliable</p>
<p>I would therefore aske your Exelency if consistent to official duty to release M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Hunter from said fine &amp;c.</p>
<p>M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Hunter was also Indicted at the same court for keeping a Tipling House upon the testimony above of the same witness in two cases. and under the impression that the witness would state any thing that was necessary to a conviction, and the advice of his council and by agreement to have one case dismissed, he confessed judgment in the other, which we<pb/>
<lb/>says is untrue and unjust that he never at any time suffered Tipling on his premises. and that he was alone induced to confess judgment on the one case from the causes above stated and from the further part that it would be impossible to disprove the statement of the witness.</p>
<p>From my knowledge of Hunter and the information that has been given me in relation to the witness who was percecuting him. I am of the opinion that Hunters statement is entitled to credit.</p>
<p>Most respectfully
<lb/>your obd servt
<lb/>G P Hawkins</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
