<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2189"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. P. Tredaway to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9265</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-306 to MG24-307</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency Beriah McGoffin Gov of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your petitioner R P Tredaway would respectfully represent unto your excellency that at the presant term of the Clay Circuit Court a judgement was rendered against him for the sum of six hundred Dollars upon an indictment Charging a violation of the law against the importation of slaves into this ^state^ the facts of the case are about as those agreed upon in an agreed case that was submited to the Judge of the Clay Circuit Court by <hi rend="str">which</hi> ^whom^ judgement was rendered against the Commonwealth but the court of appeals reasoned the case and upon their mandate the judgement was rendered -- The petitoner is a poor man with a family and his wife had an interest in some slaves in North Carolina which could not be divided amongst the heirs inkind and your petition bid off and of the slaves which was paid for out of his wife's estate and believing that they had inherited the same and that they were in the same provisions of the statute the petitioner sold s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> slave but he did not believe that he was violating any law in the sale of sd slave he makes the facts agreed to between the Commonwealths attorney and himself a part of this petition and prays your excellency to remit s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> fine </p>
<p>R. P. Tredaway<pb/></p>
<p>And we the undersigned pray to be heard in behalf of the petitioner that your excellency May remit s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> fine the petitioner and his wife are old &amp; the fine would be equal to the value of the little Negro and ruin the petitioner to have s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> fine to pay and we -- have not the remotest idea from the agreed facts that Tredaway thought that he was violating any law in the sale of s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> slave</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>B Bohr
<lb/>W D Sigmon
<lb/>John Sigmon
<lb/>H L WHite
<lb/>G. W. Puce, Clerk, Clay, Circuit, C M
<lb/>S, W, Bates
<lb/><cb n="2"/>David G. Lyttle
<lb/>E. G.. Bingham
<lb/>Abner Holcomb
<lb/>Clinton H. Godsey
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W. H Randall</hi>
<lb/>B. Hutton
<lb/>John Chestnut
<lb/>Rich Herndon
<lb/>Green Adams
<lb/>J. S. M. Dickinson
<lb/>Ruben Baker
<lb/>Stephen Parsons
<lb/>Thos Roberts
<lb/>Borton Potter
<lb/>John Parsons
<lb/>Brtton Doniell
<lb/>R. G. Potter
<lb/>A Morgan
<lb/>Thos C Pierce
<lb/>J H Pierce
<lb/>James <unclear>Herdshoff</unclear><milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>Manchester <date when="--11-22">Nov 22<hi rend="sup">nd</hi></date>
<lb/>Gov Magoffin</p>
<p>I know R P Tredaway well and am fully convinced that he did not intend to violate the Law I once decided that he had been guilty of no violation of Law and the court of Appeals reviewed the decision he is poore and unable to pay the fine I hope that you will remit the Judgement</p>
<p>Yours Respectfully
<lb/>Granville Pearl</p>
<p><hi rend="str">Respited 8 M</hi><hi rend="str"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi><hi rend="str">s</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="str">Respited -- </hi></p>
<p>Remited -- &amp; enclose to D. G. Lyttle at Manchester Ky.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
