<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0485"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">A. H. Heron to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9953</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-254 to MG18-255</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excelency Beriah Magoffin Govenor &amp;c, your petitioner would represent to you that on <gap/> day of the <date when="--06">June Term</date> of the Kenton circuit court at Covington he became Security in said Court in the sum of Fifty Dollars for one Franklin Bouen for reasons not necessery to mention in detail Suffice it to say that <hi rend="str">for</hi> some <hi rend="str">five</hi>two weeks previous to the arrest and conviction of Said Bouen which was for carrying concealed weapons to wit a pistol, The city of Covington and many of her citizens had been seriously damaged by the Torch of an incendiary to the Burning of three of four stable and one the property of the sonin law of your petitioner containing four valuable Hoses and Harniss worth $800<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> your petitioner was naturally exorcised upon this and taxed to its utmost his sagacity as a Police officer to arrest and put a stop to the midgnight Torch of this wicked Man who was almost nightly destroying property by Fire. Your petitioner succeeded in arresting a vagrant stranger at which he thought suspicon pointed, and in the prosecution of the charge for this Man was Indicted and by a Jury of his countryman tryed but was <hi rend="str">dis</hi> acquited, The said Franklin Bouen was an important witness in the prosecution of said charge, and view<pb/>
<lb/>of the further fact that from the night of the arrest of the party charged with the burning of these Stables there has not been a solitary Fire of any damage in this city nor was there a fire from the time of the arrest <hi rend="str">upto</hi> to the time of the trial. your petitioner became the security of said Bouen with the knowledge and consent of William E Arthur commonwealths Attony, and with the mutual understanding that an application would be made for a remission of Said fine the said Arthur who was fully conversant with all the facts in the case agreeing to donate or remit to the said Bouen his percent of said fine, your petition has no interest or relation with said Bouen, but has already sufferd to the amount of -- Dollars in the Burning of said Horses and Stable,, and suffer the sum of Twelve of fifteen Dollars to Sherif clerk and witness for $7,00 of which he he has paid and attachment in hands of the proper officer for the collection of said fine of Fifty Dollars the petitioner ask a remission of said fine and will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p>A, H, Heron
<lb/>Jailer K, Co, Ky</p>
<p>The facts set forth in the within petition I believe to be correct -- And I sincerely hope the Governor will grant the prayer of the petition</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">W, E, Arthur, Atty for Comlth</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Kenton Cir. Ct.
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/>B. M.
<lb/>$50 } Bail Bond
<lb/>A H Heron
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-01-15">Jany 15 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
