<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2193"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Willis T. Bunton to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6830</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-434 to BR14-435</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Laurel County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-08-24">24 August 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thomas E Bramlette Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Willis T Bunton would respectfully Represent unto your Excellency that at the <date when="1865-08">August Term of the Laurel Circuit Court 1865</date> Judgment went against him (upon Indictment in favor of the Commonwealth for retailing) for the sum of twenty dollars your Petitioner would further represent that Harvey Haynes Post Sutler at Camp Pitman near London ^in this county^ was selling ardent Spirits there and your Petitioner Telegraph repairer to that place and was frequently there and one day s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Haynes Steped out of the Room where he was retailing and requested your Petitioner to wait upon his guests present which <hi rend="str">your</hi> he did thinking that said Haynes had a perfect right to sell the Liquors and that your petitioner was doing no wrong by Steping in and letting out Whisky as aforesaid never thought of violating law or he woud not have done so The premises considered the prayer of your Petitioner is that you remit said fine for which He will ever<pb/>
<lb/>feel greatful your Petitioner is a Poor man</p>
<p>Willis T Bunton</p>
<p>Willis T Bunton Says the Statements in the foregoing Petition are true</p>
<p>Willis T Bunton</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Willis T Burton this <date when="1865-08-24">24<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of August 1865</date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Tho</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> J Carnifax P J</hi></p>
<p>We believe the Statements <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> in the foregoing Petition are true and join in the prayer thereof</p>
<p>R Boyd
<lb/>Charles Kirtley</p>
<p>Gov Bramlette I do not believe that Mr. Bunton intended to violate law and hope you will remit the fine</p>
<p>Yours truly
<lb/>H. F. Finley</p>
<p>Gov Bramllete</p>
<p>I concure with M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Finley</p>
<p>Granville Pearl
<lb/><unclear>Wm</unclear> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee
<lb/>N, B, Jones
<lb/>C B Faris
<lb/>Robert Hays<pb/>
<lb/>Wm T. Moran<pb/></p>
<p>Laurel Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Willis T. Bunton
<lb/>$20,
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-09-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Sept/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
