<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0789"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John L. Overshiner et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10257</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Bradley Strait</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-229 to MG19-230</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency B Magoffin Governor of Kentucky </p>
<p>Your petitioners Citizens of Christian County would respectfully represent to your Excellency that at the <date when="--03">present March term</date> of the Christian Circuit Court, Johnathon Greer was tried on an indictment against him for murder, That the jury acquited him for murder But found him guilty of man-slaughter, and fixed his punishment, by Confinement in the Penetentiary for a period of five years. </p>
<p>Now your petitioner will state that said Greer is an old man, being about sixty years of age, having a large family of Children That he was involved in the fight or affray, in which Adison Ferrill for killing of where he was tried was killed that the proof on the trial established the fact that Stephen Shelton who was also killed in the same affray by, Abner Greer, a son of said Johnathan Green, and said Abner who was very dangerously wounded by Shelton were engaged firing with pistols at each other that they both fell, That Ferrill after they fell was in persuit of William Greer who was married and firing at said William (who was also a son of Johnathon Greer) that Johnathon Greer the Father, having his rifle gun in his hands and being himself severely wounded by a pistol shot his son Abner shot down and Ferrill pursuing and firing at his son William who was unarmed and retreating fired upon said Ferrill and killied him which ended the affray. </p>
<p>Now your petitioners taking into consideration all the circumstances in the case the relation of father &amp; son that extended between Johnathon Greer and his sons Abner &amp; William fully appreciating the parental feeling of said Johnathon Greer at the time of the killing cannot but think that it is a Case addressing itself with peculiar force favour to the Consideration of your<pb/>
<lb/>Excellency and we the more readily urge his cause before your Excellency for the reason that Johnathon Greer has been in our midst from early youth to old age and has ever bourne the Character of a peaceable quiet sober &amp; industrious citizen a good neighbor a fine friend and a Kind and affectionate Husband &amp; father. </p>
<p>Taking all things Consideration and we respectfully present his case to the favorable Consideration of your Excellency and earnestly ask for him a full &amp; free pardon believing as we do that such an act of Clemency would meet with the hearty approval of an overwhelming majority of the best Citizens of the Country. </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>John L. Overshiner
<lb/>Austin Brener 
<lb/>P Gibson
<lb/>Stanley Walker
<lb/>James Berry 
<lb/>James Stevenson 
<lb/>J. H. West
<lb/>R. G. Wood 
<lb/>Ira F. Ellis 
<lb/>A. G Wooldridge
<lb/>F A M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kinzie 
<lb/>Emberson Henderson 
<lb/>Jonathon Armstrong 
<lb/>Isaac Stein 
<lb/>S W Abott
<lb/>E B Higgen Sr
<lb/>D. J. Hooser
<lb/>Josiah Gray 
<lb/>A <unclear/> Wallin
<lb/>T E Evans 
<lb/>E Kelby&gt;
<lb/><cb n="2"/>F. A. Jury 
<lb/>Louis Ells
<lb/>H Oppenheimer
<lb/>N. L. Ring 
<lb/>R H Lovin 
<lb/>Z J Batink 
<lb/>S A Jones
<lb/>R J Martin 
<lb/>C S White
<lb/>George Hored
<lb/>George B Starling
<lb/>M M West
<lb/>D S Hays
<lb/>B. H. Bristoso
<lb/><hi rend="underline">H. A. Phelps</hi>
<lb/>E M Buckner 
<lb/>H. A. Johnson
<lb/>H. L. Boales
<lb/>R D West 
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E White
<lb/><hi rend="underline">G. A.</hi> <hi rend="underline">Champbin</hi> 
<lb/>Horace Bettermorth<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>L Knoster
<lb/>E Higgins Jr
<lb/>Henry Amendson 
<lb/>S P Mayes 
<lb/>James. O. Scott
<lb/>Horace Hankins 
<lb/>Phil Bartley 
<lb/>John Wilkerson 
<lb/>Wm Hurt 
<lb/>Henry Johnson 
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> F. Campbell 
<lb/>W H Scott
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. Shackelford 
<lb/>M Beglan
<lb/>Jas &amp; K <unclear/>
<lb/>John Barner 
<lb/>David Gamble 
<lb/>Yeatman Clark 
<lb/>Wm D Gentry 
<lb/>J. F Wilson 
<lb/>G B Long
<lb/>J M Graves</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
