<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0849"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">H. Rodman et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10317</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-335 to MG19-336</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Exc'y B. Magoffin Gov'r of the Com'th of Ky -- </p>
<p>Your petitioners respectfully represent unto your Ex'cy that T. S. Fontaine a cadet of the Ky. Military Institute was fined in the Police court of the city of Frankfort the sum of Fifty dollars &amp; costs for carrying concealed a deadly weapon ^other than an ordinary pocket Knife^</p>
<p>Your petitioners are informed and believe and state the fact to that the said Fontaine was on a little spree, and did nothing wrong, He was in an auction and got into a dispute with an auctioneer and some loud words passed and this was all -- there were no blows struck -- no assualt made, and no attempt to disturb the peace in any way -- there was only some little quarreling &amp; rapid passes of wit and rather improper reportees -- Your petitioners state that Fontaine is a minor, that his parents are nonresidents and that he is a student who is ambitious of graduating, and having the whole affair unknown to his professors, and friends where as we deem the fine improperly imposed and if properly assessed <hi rend="str">and</hi> as excessive <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>we <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>recommend and pray that the same be forever remitted, as he is a minor<pb/>
<lb/>a stranger and unknowing of our laws we think the case one that demands executive interposition and in that view it is that we pray for the remission, all of which is respectfully remitted, your Obedient Servants -- </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>names
<lb/>H Rodman
<lb/>M, B, Chrisman
<lb/>G Warren
<lb/>Samuel South
<lb/>J. L. Gibbons
<lb/>W. S. Dehoney
<lb/>J R Watson
<lb/><cb n="2"/>names
<lb/>W. J. Chinn
<lb/>B. F. Johnson
<lb/>A. Conery
<lb/>Jon. n. Crutcher
<lb/>S, I, M, Major
<lb/>J. M. Helms
<lb/>S. Black
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H. Taylor
<lb/>G. B. Barnsley
<lb/>S. C. Bull<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Frankfort Po. Ct
<lb/>$50 } Weapons
<lb/>T. S. Fontaine
<lb/>Remission Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi>
<lb/><date when="1861-03-19">Mar 19. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
