<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3289"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Elisha Clark to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5408</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-105</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency the Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky your petitioner Elisha Clark would represent that some time since a young and thoughtless son of his was unfortunately found in company with persons who had stolen property in their possession and they were all arrested and charged with stealing the property a court of inquiry before whome they were brought for trial sent them on for further trial and on future to give bail my son a mine boy was committed to the Lebanon Jail which at the time was filthy unwholesome and infested with vermin your petitioner moved by the ordinary feelings of a parent became his sons bail in the sum of $500.00 and his son having failed to appear in court as required by his bail bond the same was as ordered forfeited <hi rend="str">at</hi> ^&amp;^ at the last term of the Marion circuit court judgement was rendered against your petitioner for said sum and costs an execution has issued upon the judgement and has been placed upon your petitioners property and unless your excellencys clemency shall be <unclear/> for the relief of your petitioner it will require the whole of his property or nearly all to pay said judgement &amp; costs- Your petitioner has an family five children and a sickley wife to be provided for and they will be left destitude unless your excellency shall she proper to offer them some relief he therefore asks that part of the judgement afsd may be remitted</p>
<p>Elisha Clark</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Marion county cheerfully unite in the prayer of the above petition J. R. Thomas</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="3"/><cb n="1"/>T. C. Jackson
<lb/>D. H. Howard
<lb/>F B Meremel
<lb/>W M Spencer
<lb/>W. H. Spencer
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John. C. Maxwel
<lb/>S A Spalding
<lb/>G H Chandler
<lb/>A F Gowdy
<lb/>Edws. M Hidler
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/> Ky
<lb/><cb n="3"/>B Spalding
<lb/>J. G. Phillips
<lb/>James M Kyle
<lb/>F M Chandler
<lb/>J. M Robards
<lb/>R. H. Rowntree<milestone unit="column" n="2"/><pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>Sam Spalding
<lb/>H B. Ray
<lb/>S Saunders
<lb/>W. C Hamilton
<lb/>D S Maxwell
<lb/>J M Cardwell
<lb/>Jno Lancaster
<lb/>G. J. Bosley
<lb/>T B Hamilton
<lb/>E P Mahon
<lb/>T. H. Cleland.
<lb/>R. P. Berniss
<lb/>Geo H. Speirs
<lb/>H H Hughs
<lb/>A. W. Ensland
<lb/>H. Johnstone
<lb/>H T Jackson
<lb/>N F Garten
<lb/>Jas Rinchart
<lb/>J. B. Blain
<lb/>John.F. Purdy
<lb/>W C. Purdy
<lb/>C. Savge
<lb/>Ben Spalding Jr
<lb/>R. Prewitt
<lb/>Edward Miller
<lb/>W. D. Robbins
<lb/>W. J. Abell
<lb/>W. H. Hopper
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John. D. Belders
<lb/>Samuel Belders
<lb/>H B Phillips
<lb/>Ichabod Cole
<lb/>Joseph.H. Miller
<lb/>R Prewitt
<lb/>J. M. Graham
<lb/>H. J. Finley
<lb/>J. S. Kellys
<lb/>Fletcher Wilson
<lb/>E. A. Gringe
<lb/>W. G. Mills
<lb/>J. Wm Hamilton
<lb/>P M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Donough
<lb/>E. S. Story
<lb/>M. H Earlen
<lb/>M. Wimsatt
<lb/>E. S. Mayes
<lb/>H D Gilmore
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>,, Durham</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
