<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3245"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Carnes to J. J. Landrum</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5364</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-39</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Dry Ridge, Grant County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Drye Ridge Grant Co Ky</p>
<p>Hon J J Landrum Sir</p>
<p>I send by this A potition to <hi rend="str">the</hi> the Govinor which will explain its self will you be so kind to lay it before the Govinor, if you will look over the potition you will recognise nearly all of the names as being good cittisan of our county, if you will Notice the names you will find Most of the county officers names there on, I could of got any quanty of names to the paper but thought it useless, if the facts ware lade before the govinor as they ware your herd the trile of webster and cant not be mistaken at the general apbrobation of the people in his favour of all partyes and all classes of people there are three of the five juriars <hi rend="str">he</hi> who ware for conviting him has singed this petition Jurix (G W. Nichols J W. Degarnett and George Nortin) I did not se the other two <hi rend="underline">Coln</hi> it is a case which grew out of the war and I am for wiping out all them things, Webster is a poor inofensive man he is a nobur of mine and I think he is not gilty, I under stand there has been a counter potition sent the the govinor, for the Law to take its corse, the onely thing that will do will be to Ruin Webstr financially and cost the state monny unnecesarily I intended to send this to you at Warsaw. but I thought I would wate untill you would go to Frankfort so you cold sea the govinor in person<pb/></p>
<p>Write to me at Drye Ridge Grant Co Ky the Govinors action on the potition I remain yours truly <hi rend="str">John</hi></p>
<p>John Carnes</p>
<p>To
<lb/><unclear>Mr</unclear> J J. Landrum
<lb/>Frankfort Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
