<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1159"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Henry Lyne, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10627</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-313 to MG20-314</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Henderson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Henderson Circuit } <hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">Sct</hi></hi>
<lb/><date when="1861-06">June Term 1861</date></p>
<p>At a circuit Court held for the County of Henderson and state aforesaid the following order was made on the <date when="1860-12-18">18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> December 1860:</date></p>
<p>The Grand Jury returned into court the following Indictmetns viz: 
<lb/>an Indictment against Henry Lyne for permittng slave to go at large &amp;C <gap/> which were severally endorsed a "true bill" and upon which process and bench warrants are awarded in each case to be endorsed that the Defendants may severally give bail for their appearance at the next Term of the Court in the sums fixed by the Court in the endorsement made on each Indictment. And the Grand Jury not having concluded their findings retired to their room to consider of their indictments."</p>
<p>The Indictment filed in the above order reads as follows towit: -- Henderson Circuit Court
<lb/>Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against
<lb/>Henry Lyne</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Henderson County in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky accuse Henry Lyne of the offense of permitting his Slave Chris to go at large; and hire himself out for his own benefit 
<lb/>(ov)<pb/>
<lb/>or that of another; committed as follows towit; The said Henry Lyne on the <date when="1860-12-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of December 1860</date> in the County aforesaid did suffer and permit his slave Chris to go at large and hire himself out for his own benefit or that of another, He the said Lyne being at the time aforesaid the owner and controler of said slave Chris -- against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">L. M. Lowe.</hi>
<lb/>Comth -- Atty</p>
<p>Information By
<lb/>R G Beverley
<lb/>John Ager
<lb/>Asa Parker
<lb/>Issd</p>
<p>Bail is fixed on this indictment at one hundred Dollars</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">W. P. Fowler</hi>.
<lb/>Judge</p>
<p>Upon which Indictment a Bench warrant issued returned Executed &amp; bond given with W P Grayson security.</p>
<p>G. A. Sugg S. H. C.</p>
<p>And afterwards towit: At a Circuit Court held in and for the County of Henderson and State aforesaid the following order was made.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against } Indictment
<lb/>Henry Lyne</p>
<p>This day came the Commonwealths attorney and also the Defendant who for plea says he is not guilty and thereupon the following Jurors towit John J Fowles Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> W Powell J H Farley J T Hicks J W Cheatham, G W Hunter, Radford Dunn A. W Agnew Alfred Oliver J E Fagan<pb/>
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Eblin and J H Priest who were sworn to try the issue and having heard the evidence returned the following verdict towit: "We of the Jury find the Defendant guilty as charged in the within indictment John J Towles Foreman" It is therefore adjudged by the Court that the Defendant is guilty and that he make his fine to the Commonwealth in the sum of Forty Dollars the amount fixed by law and the costs of this prosecution &amp; may be taken &amp;c</p>
<p>A True copy ^of the Record^ attest
<lb/>S. J. Hopkins C H C O
<lb/>By Fred Pentecost D C<pb/></p>
<p>Comm'th of Kentucky
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Henry Lyne
<lb/>Transcript of Record</p>
<p>File in the papers, submitted-
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Henderson Cir. Ct
<lb/>$40 } Selling liquor to a slave</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-07-18">July 18. 1861</date></p>
<p>$1.00</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
