<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2846"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. A. Russell to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7483</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-136</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Elkton, Todd County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-14">14 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Elkton <date when="1865-12-14">Decr 14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov of Ky</p>
<p>The undersigned would state that at the Oct term of the Todd Circuit Court George Athison was tried on an indictment for Grand Larceny &amp; Convicted and his punishment fixed at two years Confinement in the Penetentiary of the state</p>
<p>The testimony in substance was that D K Nichols a grocer missed from his drawer more than twelve months prior to <date when="1865-10">Oct 1865</date> &amp; suspecting young A, as the thief charged him with the taking when Atchison gave <hi rend="str">the</hi> up the money except a few Dollars Nichols recognised the money as the same taken from the Drawer Atchison was seen n<hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>ear grocery Door after dark the night money was taken on his trial counsel appointed by the Court defended him -- He was suffering from a wound received a short time previously</p>
<p>Atchison was quite young at the time of the Commision of the offense I do not believe that the offense was a consequence of moral turpitude or depravity Young A<hi rend="sup">s</hi> parents and Family are reputed honest industrious <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>people possessing more than ordinary inteligence I think his youth &amp; inexperience his former good conduct<pb/>
<lb/>The abscence of moral depravity the crippled condition of Young A the character &amp; reputation of his Parents &amp; family require the interposition of Executive clemency I believe this act of youthful indiscretion <hi rend="str">&amp; reckless</hi> resulted <hi rend="str">as</hi> <hi rend="str">much</hi> more from the recklessness of the time than want of honesty I was one of the Counsel appointed to defend said Atchison, believed then as I now do that he should be dealt with in mercy -- </p>
<p>J A Russell</p>
<p>I am well acquainted with Young Achison and his Parents, witnessed his <unclear/> and endorse the Statements above made by Mr J A Russell that <date when="1865-12-14">14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Decr 1865</date></p>
<p>J. G. Hollingsworth Judge Todd. Co</p>
<p>M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> S W Kennedy is not in Town I am confident he would also indorse the above he was one of the Counsel appointed to defend</p>
<p>Jas Russell</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
