<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0369"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Reynolds to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9837</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-66</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Bariah Magoffin 
<lb/>Governor of Ky.</p>
<p>Your petitioner William Reynolds states the he Exhibited a Menagerie of animals in a boat upon the Cumberland River on the <date when="1860-04-28">28<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of Apl. 1860</date>, &amp; again on the <hi rend="str">first</hi><date when="1860-04-30">30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of <hi rend="str">May</hi> sd April same year</date>, without obtain^in^g license to do He states that he in good faith believed that he had the right to show on the river without licence &amp; had been so advised He has been arrested &amp; fined $200 for said offences &amp; has paid or secured by strange disinterested friends, the price of the license &amp; costs &amp; replevied the remainder. He has 14 in family to provide for, &amp; is in a verry bad health &amp; has no money or property except the animals he Exhibited out of which to pay said fines, or to support his family he prays your Excellency to interpose your Executive clemency &amp; pardon $140 of said fines the rest he has paid or securred to be paid. Each bond is for $100 dated <date when="1860-05-01">May 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi>. 1860</date>, payable to the Comth of Ky, with E. Mcfall surety.</p>
<p>William Reynolds</p>
<p>I prosecuted Mr. Reynolds as attorney for Russell county ^in the above case^ the facts stated above I am satisfied are all true &amp; the people &amp; citizens I think all want the fine remitted. &amp; he has acted innocently as I think &amp; gentlemany about the matter, &amp; especially on account of his want of health &amp; money, &amp; his family I hope your Excellency will pardon the fines</p>
<p>Jo. E. Hays cty atty<pb/></p>
<p>I as sheriff of Russell County arrested Mrs Reynolds for the within described offence, I am satisfied that all is true that is herein stated &amp; hope your Excellency will pardon the fines immediately</p>
<p>Enos Carter</p>
<p>We the undersigned are Knowing to the facts of the cases described in the petition &amp; Mr. Mcfall a good citizen of our county has been Kind enough &amp; through sympathy has repleived the fines to relieve Mr. Reynolds under the advise of all present ^that^ your Excellency would releave him we hope your Excellency will pardon the fines as it is a case of undoubted merit</p>
<p>Joseph E Hays
<lb/>Jacob ,A, WIlliams
<lb/>H V, Polley
<lb/>Moses Higginbottom
<lb/>W, a, Eubanks
<lb/>M. S Givens
<lb/>B H Flowers
<lb/>John Brown
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> M Northrip</p>
<p>Remitted &amp; enclose to Green. B. M</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
