<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1529"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Carr et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10997</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-128 to MG22-129</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mason County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin Governor of the State of Kentucky:</p>
<p>Your petitioner William Carr resident of the county of Mason ^states^ that in the month of June last, he had a personal difficulty with a man by the name of Hall of which the following is a true history; your petitioner keeps a tavern in the villiage of Mayslick, Hall had been severely wounded with a knife of one Wilkinson and he was taken to the house of your petitioner where he was kindly nursed and his wants supplied by him and his family until he had entirely recovered; Hall was a stout and athletic man able to work, but rather unwilling, and was upon several occasions solicited to settle and pay his Board, which he persistently refused, in June your petitioner called on him again, when he peremptorily refused to pay observing that he must not trouble him any more on that subject, and accompannied this declaration with two blows; -- your petitioner is a weak and feeble man, excited by the refusal and conduct of Hall<pb/>
<lb/>and smarting under <hi rend="str">the</hi> his most unprovoked attack and blows, he drew a pistol, seeing which Hall ran followed by your petitioner who discharged at him the pistol, fortunately not wounding; for this he was indicted and tried by the Mason Circuit Court and fined fifteen dollars; he is a peaceable, quiet and inoffensive citizen; and he respectfully prays you to remit said fine believing as he does that the circumstances under which the offence was committed authorize the exercise of executive clemency;</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Carr:</p>
<p>The undersigned ctizens of Mason County respectfully and cheerfully concur and unite in the prayer of the foregoing petition</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>H. S. Johnson
<lb/>J. L. Reed
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Emery Whitaker
<lb/>Jno R. Clarke
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Jn</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> D</hi> <hi rend="underline">Taylor</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Tho J. Throoss</hi>
<lb/>Sinclair Dirmmitt
<lb/>John T. Wilson
<lb/>J. V. Burgess
<lb/>J. W. Watson
<lb/>L C Coulter<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/><unclear>Jos. M Howe</unclear>
<lb/>A Kelly -- 
<lb/>James W. Burgess
<lb/><hi rend="underline">R. T. Taylor</hi>
<lb/>Edward Myall
<lb/>T. A. Polmer
<lb/>Mitchel Miller
<lb/>John Smalls
<lb/>Jas. W. Bullock
<lb/>R. T. Rigger
<lb/>J. <unclear/>. Mitchell
<lb/>E Laytham
<lb/>Henry. L. Parry
<lb/>J. H. Watson
<lb/>Geo T Allen
<lb/>E. M. Groves
<lb/>J Laytham
<lb/>Henry T Jefferson Dept Sheriff
<lb/>George, Wells<pb/></p>
<p>Mason Cir. Ct
<lb/>$15. } Misdemeanor</p>
<p>Remitted 
<lb/>BM</p>
<p>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Carr
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-11-06">Nov. 6. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
