<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0003-092-0120"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George W. Johnson to Anne E. V. Johnson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14412</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>George W. Johnson Papers</collection>
      <idno>Folder 5</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-01-23">23 January 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Bowling Green Ky.
<lb/><date when="1862-01-23">January 23. 1862</date>
<lb/>My Dear Wife,</p>
<p>I have just heard that an opportunity is offered me, of a chance to get a letter to you to let you know how we are here.</p>
<p>Matty came in to my room last night about 10oclock from Morgan's Camp, to bring to Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Hardee a paper and report of a scouting expedition of Morgan's within the very pickets of the enemy and the burning of the <unclear>toll</unclear> road Depot full in their sight -- all of which was accomplished with six men ^4 men &amp; Morgan &amp;^ of whom I am proud to say Matty was one. They watched their chance took the house with 5 men in it and stayed till the roof fell in. He is now very well and you may be assured that I make him take every means to secure good health, although the exposure is very great at times.</p>
<p>You have no doubt heard through the papers the melancholy news of the death of John Viley. He died in my room on the <date when="1861-12-27">27 of December</date> of Typhoid fever. I had not heard of his sickness till he sent me word he was in the hospital. I immediately went to see him and had him removed to my room, where he had every attention possible and the best medical treatment, but he gradually got worse and and at the expiration of 8 days after I got him<pb/>
<lb/>him into my room. I had him buried in a box and metalic coffin, in the garden of <hi rend="str">the</hi> Col Grider who is now in the Lincoln Army. He left his house and garden here in the possession of a family by the name of <unclear>Kline</unclear> and I am boarding with them. I buried him here so that the place could always be identified and because I was living here. I hope Warren and Jane may be able to bear the loss. It seemed to me that I could hardly do so. I have taken care of all his letters, and clothes and took care to save for his parents some of his hair.</p>
<p>It is most horrible to think of the crimes and follies of this war. Who can estimate correctly the amount of sorrow, and of misery to say nothing of the loss of money, caused by those, who wantonly broke down the safe-guards of our rights and who determined to make us submit to their will. God knows that I love my family, my friends and my home, but come what, neither death nor any other sorrow, grief or any misfortune shall make me the fixed purpose of my life. Never will I submit or compromise the question. It is with in all truth and the sober <unclear>reality</unclear> "victory or death".</p>
<p>When I think that my and your honour my Dear Ann, call upon me for this calm determination, and think that it may for a still long time seperate me<pb/> 
<lb/>from you and my dear children and home I know not <hi rend="str">to think that</hi> how I have been inspired with such unshaken resolution. Never for one moment, with good or bad news before me, have I felt my mind waiver in the purpose I compelled to believe it, to be the inspiration of honour &amp; of duty. I console myself at times with the reflection, that when I return to you it will then be the day of my compensation when I take you once more to my arms, and my children gather around, to welcome me back to my old home, I feel that God will have sufficiently rewarded me for my troubles It occurs to me every night, the images of each one of my family, Martha, Junius, Henry and Euclid. God bless them.</p>
<p>The courier is waiting for me and I must close my letter. I will continue to write as I have done, although so many of my letters have failed to reach you. I have not received but one letter from you although I got Stoddard's letter of the <date when="1861-12-10">10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of December.</date> Why did you not send me a postscript if nothing more, so that I might have been cheered with the sight of something from <hi rend="underline">your</hi> hand. Give my love to Stoddard and Eliza.</p>
<p>Willa is on his farm &amp; Lilly has lost her baby -- they are well</p>
<p>God bless you
<lb/>George W Johnson</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
