<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-002-0021"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James W. Gault to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG0885</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Jacob A Glover</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Appointments by the Governor, Military Appointments, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR5-342 to BR5-343</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-04-29">29 April 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1865-04-29">April 29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865.</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>Governor Thomas E Bramlette.
<lb/>Governor.</p>
<p>Having in pursuance of my appointment and your instructions, entered upon the duties of my position as Military Agent. for the State of Kentucky. to visit hospitals camps &amp;c and looks after Kentucky's sick and wounded Soldiers: I find that the act of the Legislature under which my appointment was made does not (in my opinion) give me authority to conduct the business pertaining to my office in such manner as to be of the greatest service to Kentucky's Soldiers.</p>
<p>The act referred to appears to contemplate only a very small portion of the duties of a military agent. such as visiting Hopitals camps &amp;c. and rendering pecuniary aid. while in my opinion matters of more importance. and which would result in greater benefit to the Soldiers have been entirely overlooked. such as giving information and advice. referring papers to the proper authorities<pb/>
<lb/>to ennable soldiers to join their commands, get transfers from one Hospital to another, to procure their descriptive rolls in order that they may be paid, getting them furloughed, -- to have them mustered out of the Service when their time has expired, to get them out of prison when unjustly confined &amp;c &amp;c &amp;c.</p>
<p>A great many cases under the above named heads have already come under my observation, and I find Soldiers suffering great inconveniencies and subjected to unnecessary wrongs and outrages simply because they have no one to appeal to for relief or redress who would be likely to interest themselves in their behalf. This appears to me to be the legitimate business of a military State agent, and if clothed with proper authority a field in which he could be exceedingly useful. But to attend to these duties properly he must establish an office through which all necessary papers may be forwarded and as these matters will require his personal attention He should have authority to employ some one to visit Hospitals from time to time as may be necessary reporting their condition &amp;c. This plan would accomplish every thing contemplated by the act, without incurring any greater expense<pb/></p>
<p>I find as a general rule that the Soldiers in Hospitals are comfortable, and do not need much money. The Sanitary Commission supplies them with Tobacco clothing, and such other articles as are indispensible for their comfort. Occasionally, money judiciously used might afford great relief. But if it is generally understood, that an agent is disbursing money, he is liable to frequent impositions while in a great many cases the money would do the recipient more harm than good.</p>
<p>If your views accord with my own in regard to discharging the duties of my position, I respectfully ask that you authorize me to act in accordance with my suggestions, As I feel unwilling to incur the responsibility myself without first consulting you.</p>
<p>I have the honor to be Very Respectfully
<lb/>Your obt Servant
<lb/>J. W. Gault,
<lb/>Military Agent State of Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
