<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1571"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. H. Duncan to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6208</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-426 to BR12-427</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Whitley County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-03-29">29 March 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excelency
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. E. Bramlit
<lb/>Gov. of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned petitioner would most respectfully state, that some years since He was indicted in the Whitley circuit court for gaming. at the <date when="1862-03">March Term 1862</date> He was fined <hi rend="str">the</hi> Twenty dollars and cost of the prosecution -- </p>
<p>He would further state that the amount staked or risked was merely nominal none in the game being gamblers, the playing was for the amusement and but little was thought <hi rend="str">was</hi> or entertained of the amount bet.</p>
<p>That since the fine and before the fine He Has had all destroyed by the Armies and roving bands of plunders and to be compeled to pay the fine small as it, would be greatly oppressive at this time -- He would therefore most respectfully ask that the same be Remitted.</p>
<p>That if your Excellency is unwilling to remit. He asks that same be respited until He is more able to pay with out detriment to His family</p>
<p>W H <hi rend="underline">Duncan</hi></p>
<p>Sworn to before me by said Duncan this <date when="1865-03-29">29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of March 1865</date></p>
<p>Burgess Pearl. J. P.<pb/></p>
<p>The undersigned Citizens of Kentucky and who are acquainted with the Petitioner W. H. Duncan believe His statements are true -- and asks the Gov. to remit the fine</p>
<p>David Y. Lyttle
<lb/>Alex Levin
<lb/>Christopher Hamm
<lb/>R. Herndon
<lb/>H. H. Hunter
<lb/>James Sparks
<lb/>B M. Landrum
<lb/>John Smith
<lb/>R. Boyd
<lb/>J. W. Davis
<lb/>Thomas Gining
<lb/>Calvin Brogan
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W. H. Randall</hi>
<lb/>H. L. Tyler</p>
<p>At the time the Judgment was rendered I was Commonwealth Atty. The facst are as stated in the <hi rend="str">Indict</hi> Petition</p>
<p>John Dishman</p>
<p>I concur with M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Dishman and hope that the fine will be remited</p>
<p>G Pearl<pb/></p>
<p>Whitley Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W. H. Duncan</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
