<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2254"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. S. D. Mcgowan et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9330</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-414 to MG24-415</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Honorable Beriah Magoffin Governer of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your petitioners would respectfully State, that some months Ago, as petition numerously required by the citizens of Jefferson County, was prepared for presentation to your predecessor, respectfully urging executive clemency in behalf of Presley Ashby, now confined in the penetentiary of this state for felony, and that said petition has been lost or mislaid </p>
<p>Ashby was tried &amp; convicted in the Jefferson Circuit Court some twelve or fifteen months ago for killing George Gossage. There was no denial of the facts upon the part of the prisoner, but he plead and relied in extenuation upon being roused to phrensy by jealously, he having been informed by certain persons, that Gossage was in the habit of visiting his house during his absence at work and that he was too intimate with his wife, and goaded by this information he sought relief in liquer, and in this condition went<pb/>
<lb/>home, when a difficulty occurred between him &amp; his wife, and in the midst of this difficulty Gossage made his Appearance and interferred. &amp; the report that he had heard &amp; the unexpected appearance of Gossage, at a time when he was maddened by the information he had received, gave coler &amp; substance to his suspicions, a <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi><unclear/> conflict ensued between them which resulted in the death of Gossage. Ashby is personally known to most of your petitioners, and to all by reputation. Furthermore most of your petitioners are cognizant of the facts in this case.</p>
<p>He is a hard working, industrious, honest and worthy man, and much respected by those who know him. His little patrimony was exhausted by his trial and confinement. He has at home a wife and six children in penury and want.</p>
<p>In behalf of this man whom we believe to be so worthy, but in this one instance misguided -- in behalf of his children who are suffering for a fathers care<pb/>
<lb/>and support, and who are appealing with so much earnestness and anxiety for his repreive -- in behalf of that wife who tho' <unclear>traduced</unclear> by him thro' the intervention of wicked &amp; designing persons, has never deserted him nor swerved for one instant from her marital vows, we most earnestly but respectfully ask your Ecellency to grant him a free and full pardon, confidently believing your Ecellency will never have cause to regret this act of Clemency</p>
<p>W. S D Mcgowan Shff of Jeff County
<lb/>Jas P Chambers clk Jeff. Cir. Court
<lb/>S S Hik Depty Sheff Jeff "
<lb/>John Jones Jr County attorney
<lb/>Geo. Stealey city Engineer
<lb/>S. S. Meddis Dep Sh.. Jeff County
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Thos M Thraston</hi> Clk County Court Jeff
<lb/>W. C. D. Whips Marshal Lou Cty Court
<lb/>P B. Muir
<lb/>J Tevis
<lb/>U C Sherrill</p>
<p>I know nothing of the guilt innosence, trial or conviction of Ashby, nor I have I known any thing of his deportment for the<pb/>
<lb/>past ten years, previous to that time he was an industrious &amp; worthy man. He has a large ^and worthy^ family who are in a destitute condition.</p>
<p>D Meriwether</p>
<p>Ashby's case -- </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
