<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1217"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">O. D. McManama et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5854</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-371</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Grant County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency The Govenor of the Commonwealth
<lb/>Kentucky. Thos. E. Bramlett.</p>
<p>The undersigned Citizens of Grant County. would respectfully represent and State that under an Indictment of the The Grant Circuit. in the name of the Commonwealth of Ky agst. Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. Childers &amp; others one ThomaS. Powers was recegonized in the Penal Sum of fifty Dollars. to appear and testify as a witness at the <date when="1853-09">Sept Term of said Court 1853</date> and that in persuance of what he conceived to be his duty he did appear in the Town of Williamstown the day designated but at the Calling of the cause was not present in the Court when called in consequence of which his said recognizance was forfeited <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> &amp; at the <date when="1854-04">April Term of said court 1854.</date> Judgt was had on s<hi rend="sup">d</hi>. recognizance upon which Judgt a Capias Profine is now in the hands of the sheriff for satisfaction &amp; to relieve said Powers from the payment thereof we would respectfully state. that Mr Powers is a hard working industrious man a good citizen &amp; has ever been -- That he is a Irishman &amp; at the time of the Judgt ignorant of the Laws of the commonwealt &amp; was absent from Kentucky. That is now a Gentleman of Family a wife &amp; three children dependant upon his daily labor for Subsistance and in our Judgt it is a case richly deserving the interposition of your excellency we therefore ask in Justice to the interests of both the Commonwealth and the defendant<pb/>
<lb/>that said fine be remitted -- We Know M<hi rend="sup">r.</hi> Powers personally and Know that his failure to answer at the calling of the cause was an act on his part not wanton. but purely accidentel -- we hope that your Excellency will concur with us in this and forever acquit him (Powers) of al liability under said Judgt</p>
<p>O, D, McManama
<lb/>William Smith
<lb/>N.H. Jeffers
<lb/>J. O. Boswell
<lb/>B H Evans
<lb/>J M Hume
<lb/>M, Burnett
<lb/>J. <unclear/> Miller
<lb/>J. H. Webb Deputy Sheriff in '53
<lb/>O P Hogan
<lb/>E H Smith</p>
<p>Grant Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Remit
<lb/>Powers &amp; sureties
<lb/>$50
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/><date when="1864-09-08">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sept/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
