<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-009-0009"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">E. P. Fyffe to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1164</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR1-5 to BR1-6</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Urbana, Champaign County, Ohio</placeName>
    <date when="1863-10-05">5 October 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Urbana Ohio Oct 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863
<lb/>Gov Bramlette
<lb/>My dear Gov</p>
<p>Your very kind letter of the 30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> ult came to hand Saturday last, for which I thank you. I am under many obligations to you, for your kindness, and the interest you take in my welfare, and I do assure you, it will never be forgotten, by either me or my friends.</p>
<p>I am happy to say, that at this time, there is no man in the country, who stands higher with the people than you do, it is generally understood that from the beginning of our troubles, you were outspoken, and the first man in Kentucky to make a speech to throw off Neutrality. In this part of Ohio<pb/>
<lb/>the great majority of the people are Kentuckians, or the decendents of Kentuckians, and after their own State their affections are with Kentucky -- We were here always Henry Clay whigs, and continue whigs at heart, I am pleased to learn that there is a probability of Kentucky sending you to the U.S. Senate. That to me, is the most exalted position in the United States, I would rather be senator as Henry Clay, than be President of the United States. And I see no reason why you should not be the President of that August body -- and I hope to live to see you occupy that position. Capt Powell delivered to me your Potograph for which I am much obliged, and as soon as I can get a good one of myself I will send it to you in return for yours<pb/></p>
<p>From all I can learn our old Brigade suffered terribly at the last battle. Up to this time, I have not heard from any of my friends in the Army, I believe the Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> will not permit any correspondance from the Army -- the correspondent of of the Cincinnati Gazette said, "The Brigade of Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Wood commanded by Col Buell was torn all to flinders" that report distressed me very much. I am anxius to hear, and I think it strange that Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Wood, and Harker have not written me, I cannot understand it, unless the Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> has stopped all letters, and I suppose that is the case, as no one here, has heard from their friends in the 26<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi>, only through the news papers.</p>
<p>My health, I think is improving, and I hope to be able to join my Command by the time the draft is made,</p>
<p>It does appear to me that the Authorities at Washington are very slow in<pb/>
<lb/>enforcing the draft. The law passed in February, nine months have passed and yet the draft is not made in Ohio. Two hundred thousand men in the center or Rosecrans department would bring this war to a close in a short time in my opinion -- The Confeds expected to crush out Rosecrans at one blow, and to reconquer East &amp; Middle Tennessee, and perhaps Kentucky, but in that they were mistaken for instead of a victory for them, it is a victory for our Arms, as long as we can hold our position on the Tennessee. Our friend Capt James was married two weeks since, he went over to Canada and Captured a Canadian girl -- the Capt wishes me to present his kindest regards, he is one of the best young men I ever knew, and is as you are aware, one of your warmest friends.</p>
<p>My dear Gov you must excuse my long letters, I do not wish to inflict on you too great punishment, or do I wish to take up much of your time, knowing that you are from necessity very busy</p>
<p>God bless and protect you
<lb/>Your friend
<lb/>E P. Fyffe</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
