<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-028-0010"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. Marshall to Grant Green</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7665</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Appointments by the Governor, Military Appointments, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R2-126 to R2-127</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-08-21">21 August 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Covington <date when="1862-08-21">Aug 21<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>Grant Green
<lb/>Dear Sir -- </p>
<p>Excuse me for writing to you but I take the liberty, as there is no one at Frankfort to whom I would sooner apply -- </p>
<p>Last winter as soon as I left the service (we were Discharged) I offered my services to my state through Mr Temple &amp; J W Finnell -- but at the time all appointments were <hi rend="underline">full</hi> since that time I offered them again &amp; no response: why I know not as I can give as good recommendations as would be needed; of being a good officer than of Genl<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Anderson &amp; Mitchell as of all others that have ever seen me drill &amp; take care of my men -- &amp; lastly of Genl G C Smith under whom I commanded the mountain men that were with him through his<pb/>
<lb/>trip after Jno Morgan, I think I have always shown my willingness to serve my state, &amp; should <hi rend="str">G</hi>you Gov give me a place will do so again -- I would prefer a place in a Regt in the <hi rend="underline">Field</hi> as in the formation of a regt there is a great deal of work that would be thrown upon a <hi rend="str">Jn</hi> junior officer but if I am placed in a Regt I will do my best to bring the men to a thorough knowledge of their duty -- </p>
<p>Now Grant I ask of you to see the Gov &amp; ask him to read this &amp; tell him what you know of me -- My Brother is in the service &amp; I am the only one left of our family that is loyal -- </p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J. Marshall</hi><pb/></p>
<p>I have known Mr Marshall for many years, and have no hesitancy in recommending ^him^ for an apppointment in the United States Service. He was educated at the Kentucky Military Institute, is a fine tactician, and would doubtless fill the position of Lt. Colonel or Major with honor to himself and credit to the Service -- His loyalty is beyond question, and I sincerely hope he may get an appointment</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>Grant Green
<lb/><date when="1862-08-23"><hi rend="underline">August 23. 1862</hi></date></p>
<p>To
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> J F Robinson.
<lb/>Frankfort. Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
