<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0579"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Gabriel Weitzel, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4698</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-419</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The defendant asks the court to instruct the jury as follows:</p>
<p>1. That the jury must find the defendant not guilty-</p>
<p><note place="left margin">refused</note></p>
<p>2. That the defendant is Entitled to the benefit of all reasonable doubt as to <hi rend="str">the</hi> his guilt or innocence- and it devolves upon the Com'th to prove him guilty beyond all reasonable doubt-</p>
<p><note place="left margin">allowed</note></p>
<p>3. That unless the jury believe from the evidence that the defendant Weitzel sold to John Berney the spirituous liquors mentioned by the witnesses for the Commonwealth, to be carried of in a vessel or vessels from the place of sale, they must find the defendant ^not^ guilty.</p>
<p><note place="left margin">refused</note></p>
<p>4. That it is no offense against the ^existing^ laws for a licensed tavern keeper to sell, give or loan to a free negro spirituous or vinous liquors, unless they are sold given or loaned to be carried off in a vessel or vessels from the place of sale_</p>
<p><note place="left margin">refused</note></p>
<p>5. That the jury must disregard Entirely the evidence of the witness<hi rend="str">es</hi> Robert Aigie</p>
<p><note place="left margin">refused</note></p>
<p>6. That the jury have the right to <hi rend="str">weigh</hi> consider the whole testimony in the case
<lb/><note place="left margin">allowed</note><pb/>
<lb/>and give such weight thereto as they may deem proper.</p>
<p>7. That if the jury believe from the testimony that the defendant is guilty of the charge contained in the warrant, they shall give him not less than twenty nor more than fifty dollars at their discretion. That in no event can the fine be $100 or exceed $50.</p>
<p><note place="left margin">refused</note></p>
<p>8. That the jury must exclude &amp; disregard entirely the evidence of James Aigie</p>
<p><note place="left margin">refused</note></p>
<p>9. That if they beleave from the evidence that ^witness^ James Aigie is to share with Robert Aigie <hi rend="str">the</hi> part of the penalty given to the informer in such cases as these and that he gave his testimony under the belief that he is to get a part of the penalty if deft is convicted, they must disregard his evidence entirely.</p>
<p><note place="left margin">refused</note></p>
<p>10. The jury <hi rend="str">are not</hi> have the exclusive right to judge of the credibility of the testimony sworn by the two witnesses.</p>
<p><note place="left margin">allowed</note></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
