<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0264"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William H. Chelf to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9732</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-239 to MG17-240</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Greensburg, Green County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-12-22">22 December 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Greensburg Ky <date when="1860-12-22">Dec. 22<hi rend="sup">nd</hi>/60</date>
<lb/>To his Excelency ^the^ Govenor of Ky,
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>Having good reasons to believe that a Petition, or Petitions, will be presented to Your Excellency by Fidella Warren, William S Warren, Mitchell Warren, Fields Skaggs, Henry Skaggs, &amp; Co., all of Green County Ky. for the purpose of getting the fines remitted which were prefered vs them before Gabrel Close a Justice of the Peace for Green County, and knowing that said fines ought not to be remitted, I hereby remonstrate and protest against the remission of any of said fines. I as County Attorney prosecuted, said Gentlemen and I dont think they were fined enough by the Jury. The were fined for shamefully and, cruelly beating &amp; brusing one W C Thompson -- it was proven that, the said Thompson without any provocation on his part was beaten almost to death -- (came very near ding) by the above mentioned Gentlemen, -- that while some of them were, upon him beating him with rocks ^the^ others<pb/>
<lb/>were standing over him with rocks, and one stood over him with his Pistol cocked and Knife drawn, defying any of Thompson's friends to interfere. The fact that I am entitled to 30 per cent on said fines does not prompt me to write, but because I think Justice demands the payment of the <unclear/> cint of said fines, Judgment has been rendered against said parties and of Course your Excellency would, not remit fees &amp; cost. In conclusion I hope your Excellency will disregard any and all Petitions that have or may be offered by said Parties,</p>
<p>Respectfully Your
<lb/>Servant W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H, Chelf<pb/></p>
<p>Remonstrance in Warrens case from Green Co</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
