<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3209"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Unknown to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5328</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-390</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Washington County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>His Excelancey Thomas.E. Bramlette</p>
<p>Governor of Kentucky whereas William Hatchett stands indited in the Washington Circuit Court for the Crime of Robery Commited on the <date when="1864-12-07">7th day of December 1864</date> by taking a pistol from one James Reed said Hatchett was a soldier at the time that the pistol was taken and belonged to Capt James Lawsens Company at the time that he is charged with taking the pistol he dos not deni geting the pistol from Reed but he got the pistol with the understanding that he was to Returne it to Reed but when he presented the pistol back to Reed he wold not take it back but wanted Hatchett to pay him twenty dollars for it which Hatchett Refused to do and he then told hatchett if he did not pay him twenty dollars for the pistol that he wold persent him to the Grand Jury which he did do charged Hatchett with taking the pistol on the <date when="1865-12-01">first day of December 186<hi rend="str">1</hi>5</date> and also on mans sadle for his charge Hatchett was tried and aquted after Reed was beat in that case he then went and presented Hatchett <hi rend="str">and</hi> Milbourn and Terrell we Refur you to the inditement to sho wat he done this all hapend the day that the Gurilers Came thru Washingotn County and kiled Col Hall Isac Butner Young Foster and ^a^ man by the name of Green all of them union soldiers and ^there^ was orders from office to take armes ware ever tha cold get them to persue this Gang of Muders and part of this Co past Reed and got this pistol Hatchett is a nice clever young man and we your petitioners ^believe^ that he is not Guilty as Charged in the inditement and we believe that he is entital to your Executive Clemancy we therefore pray your honor to pardon him</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
