<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0496"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">D. H. Hughes et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4615</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-291 to BR9-292</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned petitioners would Represent unto your Excellency that at the <date when="1860-11">Nov. term 1860</date> of the Crittenden Circuit Court <gap/> Higgins <gap/> Randall and N R Black entered in a recognizance before said court in the sum of six hundred dollars conditioned that James Oakley who was charged with having committed an assault with intent to kill Should appear personally in Said court to answer any Indictment which might be formed against him by the Grand Jury then Impanneled in sd court</p>
<p>And further would Show that the said Oakley in violation of sd Recognizance and the conditions thereof Ran away and absconded, Leaving the state of Kentucky and so concealing himself that neither the sheriff or his said bail have been able since to find him or his whereabouts or to make arrests and bring him into said court although they have made diligent Search and inquiry after him</p>
<p>They would further Show that sd recognizance has been taken as forfeited against sd Bail and the said Black haveing been duly served with process and property<pb/>
<lb/>brought before sd court Judgement has been rendered thereon against him at the <date when="1864-05">May term 1864</date> and he will be compelled to pay the whole of sd Judgement They state that sd Oakley Huggins and Randall are each and all of them Insolvent and out of them nothing can be made</p>
<p>Therefore they ask that the Executive clemency shall be extended to said Black Huggins and Randall and that so much of the aforesaid Judgement be Remitted as the consitution and Law will permit and as May be consistent with property and Justice</p>
<p>D H Hughes atto.
<lb/>Dan. B. Cassidy atty.
<lb/>Robt F Haynes County Atty
<lb/>W. C. Carnahan Sheriff
<lb/>J.. C. Elder D Sheriff
<lb/>J H Walker C C C C
<lb/>M. G. Gilbert
<lb/>H L Leigh
<lb/>S Hodge atto
<lb/>A. H. Cardin
<lb/>R. W. Taylor
<lb/>Paul L. H. Walker
<lb/>R N Walker
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. L. Dean
<lb/>J. W. Rutherford
<lb/>J D Gregory
<lb/>Joshua Orr<pb/></p>
<p>Crittenden Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Black, Higgins &amp; Randall
<lb/>$600
<lb/>Remit
<lb/><date when="1864-02-14">14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Feby/ 64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
