<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2288"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">L. S. Trimble to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6925</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-155 to BR15-156</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Paducah, McCracken County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-08-21">21 August 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Paducah Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-08-21">Aug 21<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Bramlett</p>
<p>Dr Sir some three Months since th<hi rend="str">is</hi>e citizens ha<hi rend="str">s</hi>ve of all parties appealed to Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> C, Calhoun to accept the position of Sheriff of this County that office having been vacant since Genl Payne was here, although Col Bacon was elected last August he refused to qualify owing to the disturbed Condition of the Country and in Compliance with his request M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Calhoun who had held the office for years under the old &amp; new Constitution, having discharged the duties of the office with great Satisfaction to the people and marked fidelity to the state and government He accepted the Office and qualified and was proceeding<pb/>
<lb/>faithfully in the discharge of his duties with the tax books in his hands, together with a large number of executions. he was also a candidate for the unexpired term of the Office When on the Saturday night before the election he was arrested and thrown into the guard house where he remained until after the election (he being elected) when he was released giving bond for $5000 Conditions to appear before any Military Commission, for a violation of your proclamation &amp; Genl Palmers election Order, and further not to leave the limits of the City of Paducah. I have Known M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Calhoun intimately for Many years, and with Confidence assert that no man in this or any other Community has done More to Maintain the public peace and quiet of the Country than he having always been the advocate<pb/>
<lb/>of law and order and I have no idea he has done any thing in violation of yours or Genl Palmers orders of the law.</p>
<p>If Consistent with your views you would request Genl Palmer to release him from this bond, or that part that limits him to the City you would place the good citizens of this County under renewed obligation &amp; oblige your friend</p>
<p>&amp; Obt Servt
<lb/><hi rend="underline">L, S, Trimble</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
