<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0419"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Henry Mitchell to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4538</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-161 to BR9-162</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Todd County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-01-12">12 January 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Ky</p>
<p>The undersigned would represent that at the <date when="1863-11">Oct term of the Todd Circuit Court 1863</date> he was tried upon an indictment for violation of his bond as tavern keeper in said County that on his trial the following witnesses were examined W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Henry John Boley A J Mundy and James Christian William Gressau J H Hunter <hi rend="str">was</hi> who stated in substance that said Mitchel kept a tavern about 8 miles from Elkton at Sharon Grove <hi rend="str">for which he had be</hi> that on the day and at the time the offence was charged to have been committed there was public speaking at Sharon Grove that <hi rend="str">Mit</hi> the undersigned <hi rend="str">kept</hi> had charge of a grocery situated about one hundred &amp; fifty yards from the tavern house which Grocery belonged to a man by the name of Sullivan or that the <hi rend="str">goods wares</hi> packages containing groceries were marked to said Sulivan that some men were drunk at said Grocery that said men were violent &amp; riotous <hi rend="str">that</hi> that a fight occured between them in the grocery that they were immediately expelled from the House &amp; doors closed all of the witnesses states that they saw no liquor drank<pb/></p>
<p>in the Grocery House one of the Witnesses for the Commonwealth W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Henry stated that <hi rend="str">some</hi> one of the men engaged in the fight was drunk or drinking when he came to the grocery James Christian a witness for the Com<hi rend="sup">lth</hi> stated that he saw whiskey brought from the tavern house to the grocery but did not see any of it drank there there were no witnesses examined for defence The above is a full statement of the material part of the testimony given in the case The undersigned feels that his case is one that will clearly justify and calls for the interposition of executive clemency that he did not violate his bond that the fighting occured without his consent and contrary to his express Order The verdict of the Jury found defendant guilty and Judgment was redered on his bond for three hundred Dollars This verdict will be exceedingly appressive on the undersigned wherefore he asks for such relief as may seem proper &amp; right to your Excellency -- </p>
<p>Henry Mitchell</p>
<p>Henry Mitchel says that the above contains a full &amp; fair statement of the material part of the evidence given in the case mentioned and that other statements made are true</p>
<p>Henry Mitchell<pb/></p>
<p>Todd County <date when="1864-01-12">Jany 12 1864</date>
<lb/>Sworn to before me by Henry Mitche</p>
<p>Ben T Perkins C. T. C. C</p>
<p>The undersigned would state that he attended to the trial for Henry Mitchel that the above statement made by him contains a full report of the substance of the testimony given on said trial</p>
<p><date when="1864-01-12">Jany 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>J. A. Russell</p>
<p>Govenor Bramlett
<lb/>Dr Sir</p>
<p>I am well acquainted Henry Mitchell, I have know him well for many years, he is a reliable man. very Poor with a large Family to support I am in hops you may see proper to remit the fine against him if not in whole in part at least</p>
<p>yours Respt
<lb/>Ben T. Perkins</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
