<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2861"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Joseph L. Frost to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7498</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-153 to BR17-154</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lexington, Fayette County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-12">12 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Lexington Ky <date when="1865-12-12">Dec. 12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thomas E. Bramlett
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky -- 
<lb/>Hon. Sir.</p>
<p>I have the honor to state that on or about the <date when="1865-09-02">2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> day of Sept. 1865</date> -- also the <date when="1865-11-04">4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of November 1865</date>. "True Bills" of Indictment were found against me. by the Grand Jury of Fayette County Ky -- upon the several charges mentioned in the accompanying copies of said indictments herewith enclosed I would respectfully state that there is no valid foundation for the charges made and respectfully submit for your consideration the affidavits of the witnesses of the Commonwealth and others, at the same time requesting executive interferience in my behalf. by setting aside said indictments</p>
<p>Should you grant the favors here requested your Kindness will be highly appreciated and gratefully acknowledged.</p>
<p>I have the honor to be, Sir.
<lb/>Very Respectfully
<lb/>Your Obedient Servant
<lb/>Joseph L Frost<pb/></p>
<p>Lexington Ky <date when="1865-12-12">Dec 12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 65</date></p>
<p>Respectfully forwarded to His Excellency, Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E. Bramlett. with a request that the petition of the within named Joseph L. Frost be granted. I am and have been long and intimatley acquainted with Mr Frost. who was formerly Major of the 26<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Regt. Ky. Vols, whilst I was in command as Col. of said Regt. I have always known Mr Frost as a strictly honorable, upright gentleman -- and well worthy of Executive interference.</p>
<p>S. G. Burbridge
<lb/>Maj. Genl. U. S. Vols.</p>
<p>I have examined the affidavits connected with the Petition of Frost which will be presented to your Excellency by Genl Burbridge. I am satisfied after reading them, that there has been a sad mistake in this whole matter, or if not that I should with these statements of Com'th witnesses utterly fail to convict. I did not hear the Testimony before the Grand Jury. I have always regarded Maj Frost as an upright honest gentleman and was confounded when called upon to draw the indictments</p>
<p>W. S. Downey
<lb/>com atty</p>
<p>I concur
<lb/>W C Goodloe
<lb/>Crt Judge</p>
<p>Fayette Cir Ct
<lb/>vs 
<lb/>Joseph Frost
<lb/>3 Indictments
<lb/>Pardoned
<lb/><date when="1865-12-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Dec 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
