<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1911"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Allen Atcherson to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6548</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-22 to BR14-23</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thomas E Bramlett
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> of the Com'th of Ky -- </p>
<p>Your Petitioner Allen Atcherson says that at the <date when="--02">Februray</date> term of the Franklin circuit court by the name of Allen Hutcherson he was indicted, in six several indictments numbered from one to six for setting keeping &amp; exhibiting a faro bank &amp; table</p>
<p>He says that he was jointly interested in a game of faro with some others who really dealt the game and kept the table, and that his partners employed an Att'y to attend to the business for them &amp; himself, in case they should be indicted, and that the Att'y never having seen this petitioner, and having heard his name inaccurately called on the Att'y for the Com'th, and said to him that he was authorized to plead guilty to one indictment for one game of Faro for some gentlemen, giving the names at the request of the Com'th's Att'y, and that thereupon his Att'y was called before the grand Jury and gave in his name as Hutcherson through mistake as the one who should be indicted, and stated that he knew nothing of the game himself -- and that there-upon there were six indictments found against him and as many<pb/>
<lb/>against each of his partners instead of one as it was understood that there would be Wherefore in view of the fact that the one offense has been magnified into six and the further fact that all the proof of his guilt or connection with the affair was obtained by unfair means -- to use no harsher term; -- means that your petitioner from a sense of honor declines fully to state to your Excellency, he prays a release &amp; full pardon of the offense before judgment</p>
<p>Allen Atcherson</p>
<p>We whose names are hereunto subscribed join in the prayer of the petitioner and request that he be pardoned.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>P. U. Major
<lb/>W Rictor. Gist
<lb/>E Larkins
<lb/>N. H. Heffner
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> G. Lobban
<lb/>B. F. Johnson
<lb/>P. Joyce
<lb/>H. R. Powell
<lb/>Jno. L. Neal
<lb/>S.. Korsey
<lb/>D. W. Lindsey
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/>Tho. J. Harris
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. P. O'Hara
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> B Tremere
<lb/>Nelson Alley
<lb/>W H Greenup
<lb/>H. P. Elliis
<lb/>M A Gay
<lb/>A. G. Carrick<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Franklin Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Allen Atcherson
<lb/>indicted as
<lb/>Allen Hutcherson
<lb/><date when="1865-05-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> May 1865</date>
<lb/>Pardon Offense</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
