<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3132"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Pelle Knoop &amp; Co. et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5251</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-310 to BR41-311</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="left margin">I believe this statement drawn up by counsel for Deft &amp; the addition made by M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Dupuy contains the facts presented to the Jury in the trial of the case
<lb/>Geo W Johnston ct Judge</note></p>
<p>a <hi rend="underline">statement</hi> of the <hi rend="underline">facts</hi> in the <hi rend="underline">case</hi> of L E Mayer</p>
<p>About the <date when="--03">middle of march</date> L E Mayer came to the city and around the Court House represented himself to be a lawyer about to locate in practice here. On the <date when="--03-31">31<hi rend="sup">st</hi> day of March</date> he went to the Banking House of Odor Taylor &amp; Co and there deposited for collection a draft upon Mayer Bone &amp; Co of Huntsville Alabama his brother ^in business there^ On the <date when="--04-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of April</date> following having previously ordered a suit of clothes of Merchant tailor Pelle Knoop &amp; Co, he gave them a check upon Odor Taylor &amp; Co for ($72) Seventy two dollars representing that he had money then representing himself to them also as a lawyer they permitted him to take the clothes. In the afternoon of the same day he called on them and requested of them that they would not present the check for payment untill the next day. Late in the evening P K &amp; Co having <hi rend="str">had</hi> heard suspicious <unclear/> out as to the character of Mayer, and it being after banking hours hunted up Mr Meddis teller at the bank and were informed by him that Mayer had no funds on deposit.</p>
<p>Information was given to the police &amp; he was arrested the same evening in the immediate vicinity of the store &amp; of the court<pb/>
<lb/>house having made no attempt to get away. He was placed in jail - two days afterward &amp; had an examination when the <hi rend="str">of</hi> draft upon Huntsville upon his brothers bail returned dishonored, and was issued in the examination against him. The goods upon his arrest were turned over to P K Co and sold by them they sustained no loss. He was under the influence of liquor during the time. He has been in prison ever since.<pb/>
<lb/>We the undersigned in view of all the facts and circumstances in the case recommend L E. Mayer to the clemency of Governor.</p>
<p>Pelle Knoop &amp; Co
<lb/>G S Meddis Teller
<lb/>Henry Davis
<lb/>T.. Neel</p>
<p>As one of the counsel of Meyer I respect fully recommend his pardon. The evidence in addition to the above showed that he was a Lawyer duly licensed in <date when="1865">1865</date>, he is a youth of fine education, and good family, and on his arrival in Louisville got on a bad spree, and was drunk during the above negotations. I am confidant that he believed his brother in Huntsville would cash his draft, and that he had no felonious intention.</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> L Jackson<pb/></p>
<p><note place="left margin">Pell ^&amp; Co^ stated they beleived his statement that he had <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> ^money^ on deposit <hi rend="str">with Odor Taylor &amp; Co</hi> ^in Bank^ or they would not have parted with their property- After the examining trial I gave up the suit of clothes to the owners at their request Mayer appears to be about twenty eight or thirty years of age
<lb/>JR Dupuy
<lb/>Com atty
<lb/>addendm by Cour atty</note></p>
<p>Meyer went to Pell Knoop &amp; Evans, was intoxicated, stated he wanted a suit of clothes, (they were merchant-tailors) said he would call in again &amp; get them, one of the proprietors drank with him <hi rend="underline">twice</hi> that day, in a few days he caled in again, the propreitor drank with him <hi rend="underline">once</hi> this time he called &amp; stated that he was under the influence of liquor but could not state that he was drunk Meyer ordered a suit of clothes to be finished in about two days as he needed them to go to a party= (it was a <hi rend="underline">business</hi> suit he ordered)- the man who took his measure did not discover any intoxication he called for the clothes before they were done &amp; in a few hours ^after^ came &amp; got them giving them a check on Odor Taylor &amp; Co when purchasing &amp; ordering the clothes he stated he had <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> ^money^ deposited with <hi rend="str">Odor Taylor &amp; Co</hi> ^in Bank^ &amp; to his credit- He had previously been to see Odor Taylor &amp; Co &amp; asked them to cash a draft for them, they replied that he must have it indorsed by some responsible person in the city, he asked if Hamilton Pope or Baird &amp; Price would do, the Bankers replied that these men were good- He called the next day stating that Ham Pope was not in town or something to that effect, said nothing about Baird &amp; Price, then drew a check or order on Meyer Boone &amp; Co &amp; left it for collection. The deft proved that Odor Taylor &amp; Co recieved for reply when they sent the draft for collection. <hi rend="underline">"that dft had no authority to draw on them"</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
