<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1283"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George Rhodes et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5920</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-472 to BR11-473</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thomas E. Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your Excellency's petitioners respectfully represent, that Jacob Medard was at the January term of the Jefferson Circuit Court last past, found guilty and convicted of manslaughter and sentenced to five years hard labor in the penitentiary of this Commonwealth. He was charged with suffering his father to die of neglect. Jacob Medard was a very hard working man, a shoemaker and well known by his neighbors, as an honest and sober man. He has a wife and <gap/> children wholly dependent upon his industry. He is totally ignorant of our language, and therefore was but poorly able to prepare his defence. Your petitioners would respectfully call your Excellency's attention to the affidavits herewith filed, showing that the deceased was not sound of mind and also showing that Jacob Medard was to say the least possessed of very little mental capacity. These facts were not known to the witensses, when they testified for the Commonwealth. The jurors who tried the case, after being made acquainted with these facts, not then known have joined in this petition. Your petitioners believe, that if Medard was consciously guilty, he has expiated his guilt by the<pb/>
<lb/>expenses attending his defense and by the punishment he has already undergone. Your petitioners pray for a pardon to Jacob Medard</p>
<p>George Rhodes
<lb/>A Gunter
<lb/>A B Semple
<lb/>Thos P Hughes
<lb/>Thos. H. Crawford
<lb/>W. W. Powers
<lb/>N W Goar
<lb/>Stephen H Edmondson
<lb/>Henry W Wilkes } Jury.</p>
<p>We join in the foregoing petition</p>
<p>Andrew Mason
<lb/>Judge of the County Court</p>
<p>The Petition has been signed by nine of the Jurors who tried the case. one of the remaining three has died, &amp; one lives in Nashville. as they ask a Pardon for the Petitioner; who have heard all the Testimony I unite with them</p>
<p>Geo W. Johnston.
<lb/>W. G. Reasor</p>
<p>I Know nothing of the case above mentioned but sign this Peto from the Statements to me of Mr John Shardein &amp; W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Goepper whom I know to be Respectable &amp; Truthful Gentlemen</p>
<p>T. Jack Conn clk<pb/>
<lb/>Jeff Co Court</p>
<p>I can say the same as Hon Geo W. Johnston has said &amp; hope that you will grant on the petitioner</p>
<p>Phil Tomppert Jr
<lb/>Clerk City Court of
<lb/>Louisville</p>
<p>I as Marshal of this city Join in the petition and corroberate the statement of Hon G W Johnston</p>
<p>W R Hydes
<lb/>W R Thomas</p>
<p>I cheerfully unite in the above petition and hope the Govr. will pardon Medard</p>
<p>N. Wolfe</p>
<p>I respectfully join with the gentlemen whose names appear in the foregoing and ask the pardon of Jacob Medard. I cannot think him a parricide</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Jo. G. Wilson</hi></p>
<p>I. cheerfully unite in the above</p>
<p>Edw. A. Preuss</p>
<p>Witness for the Commonwealth.
<lb/>Conrad <unclear>Durant</unclear>
<lb/>H. Ratterman
<lb/>unter taker<pb/></p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Jacob Medard
<lb/>Manslaughter
<lb/>5 years
<lb/>Pardon
<lb/>granted
<lb/><date when="1864-10-05">5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Oct/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
