<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1318"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Charles Schwartz to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10786</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-214 to MG21-215</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-08-07">7 August 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency The Governor of Kentucky:</p>
<p>Your petitioner, Charles Schwartz, respectfully states that on the <date when="1860-04-03">3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> day of April 1860,</date> being solicited by an old friend, a widow lady the Mother of Fred Wymer, to go bail for her said son (&amp; who was her sole support) in the sum of $200 that he should keep the peace and be of good behavior for the period of three months, as had been required by the Judge of the City Court of Louisville, your petitioner, without fee or reward &amp; purely to accommodate the mother, went on said bond.</p>
<p>Afterwards said Fred Wymer, on the <date when="1860-05-18">18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> May 1860,</date> was brought before the judge of said City Court on a charge of having on that day assaulted one B. Polston, a forfeiture of the bond was therefore Entered &amp; a scire facias issued against said Wymer &amp; your petitioner therefor -- </p>
<p>And on the indictment against Wymer for the assault, he was tried on the <date when="1860-07-03">3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> July 1860</date> &amp; fined five dollars -- </p>
<p>Upon the scire facias aforesaid a judgment was Entered on the <date when="1860-11-07">7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 1860</date> against said Wymer &amp; your petitioner Each for the sum of $200, by the Judge of said City Court of Louisville.</p>
<p>The fine &amp; costs upon the indictment Wymer has paid &amp; has also replevied the $200 judgment against him. But a capias having issued against your petitioner for the aforesaid<pb/>
<lb/>$200 judgment against him, your petitioner, being wholly unable to pay it or any part of it, and having a family to support &amp; no property Except a cart &amp; wood wagon &amp; the team thereto with which he has to Earn his support, has been arrested on said Capias &amp; is now in confinement in the city workhouse &amp;, unless relieved by your Excellency, will be there kept till he shall have worked out his fine and costs by labor at 75 cts per day -- during all of which time your petitioners family will be deprived of his aid &amp; support.</p>
<p>Wherefore, your petitioner respectfully, yet Earnestly prays your Excellency to remit the Commonwealth's part of s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> judgment &amp; as in duty bound he ever will &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi></p>
<p><date when="1861-08-07">Aug 7. 1861</date></p>
<p>Chas ^his X mark^ Schwartz</p>
<p>I am personally acquainted with Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Swartz and know him to be an honest, orderly and know him to be an honest, orderly and hard working man, I beleive the Statements contained in the above petition to be true, and would earnestly join in the petition, as he can give security for the costs if the Comths portion of the fine is remitted</p>
<p>F. B. Jane Deputy Marshal </p>
<p>From the fact of having been prosecuting attorney during the time referred to in the foregoing petition, I can certify to the truth of the statements therein so far as relates to the proceedings in the court. And from the information I have received &amp; which I believe, I am satisfied<pb/>
<lb/>of the truth of the other statements in the petition; &amp;, therefore, recommend the petition to your Excellency's clemency</p>
<p>Robt J. Elliott</p>
<p>I concur with Mr Elliott &amp; Join in asking a remission</p>
<p>Geo W. Johnston
<lb/>M. G Holmes
<lb/>G. W. Ronald</p>
<p>I <hi rend="underline">believe</hi> the statements, in the foregoing petition are true &amp; Petitioner is in the work House. I respectfully Joine in petitioners prayer.</p>
<p>W G Reasor
<lb/>John H. Rodgers
<lb/>Jos Jeans
<lb/><unclear/> Claton<pb/></p>
<p>Louisville City Ct
<lb/>$200 } Recog
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. Schwartz
<lb/>Fred Wyman</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-08-14">Aug 14. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
