<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-079-0022"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">A. D. Hill et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14021</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Enrolled Militia Records 1864 - 1865 ; Adair, Allen, Boyle, Daviess, Garrard, Owen, Pendleton, and Shelby counties</collection>
      <idno>Flat Box 7</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Owensboro, Daviess County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-07-27">27 July 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Owensboro <date when="1864-07-27">July. 27<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date>.
<lb/>His Excellency.
<lb/>Thos. E. Bramlette.
<lb/>Governor of State of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your Petitioners, citizens of the County of Daviess, (Through Their Committee appointed at a meeting held in Owensboro. <date when="1864-07-27">July. 27<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date>) would respectfully represent to your Excellency the grievances and injuries to which they are now exposed, and from which almost without exception they have suffered, by the acts of bands of lawless men claiming to be in the military service of the State of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your Petitioners beg leave to assure your Excellency, that they have been and are, peaceable and law abiding citizens; seeking in their regular business avocations such quiet as the disturbed condition of the country will afford; submitting without murmur to the many hardships imposed by this unfortunate war; ^and^ indisposed at all times to swell the burdens and vexations by which you are harassed, by adding their private sufferings to the public calamities now engrossing your time and energies. Controlled by this last consideration they have heretofore preferred to bear in silence the wrongs and losses of property which have been entailed upon them, rather than disturb you with their complaints. Matters have at length however attain<hi rend="str">t</hi>ed that point, that no man's property is safe, -- no man's life secure; nor is the sanctity of his family circle free from invasion, insult and indignity at the hands of these marauding bands. </p>
<p>They would represent as a few of the many<pb/>
<lb/>grievances to which they are exposed.</p>
<p>1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> That these men are quartering themselves upon the unarmed and defenceless citizens and forcing them musket in hand, and with insulting threats addressed to their wives and families, to feed themselves and their horses.</p>
<p>2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> That they have robbed and plundered citizens of the County, guilty of no offense: and engaged in their daily labors, upon the public highways and at their homes in the country.</p>
<p>3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> That they are daily, forcibly taking horses from peaceable and rightly disposed citizens, under cover of their assumed military character; and in some instances as your Petitioners are informed have conveyed these horses beyond the ^Ohio^ river, and sold them for their own benefit.</p>
<p>4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> and finally, that in two instances, men claiming authority from your Excellency ^to recruit a company for state service^ have opened the doors of the county Jail, -- released, and enlisted or claimed to enlist, men arrested and committed for crimes against the State.</p>
<p>And your Petitioners would further state that altho these men are liable to arrest by the civil authorities, yet as to do so would render it necessary to summon the posse of the county, and might lead to bloodshed, and considering likewise, how easily their acts in this respect might be misconstrued and misrepresented, they have determined to appeal to your Excellency, and earnestly and respectfully request that such measures be adopted as will in your Excellencys opinion, be most likely to relieve them.</p>
<p>With assurances of our high<hi rend="str">est</hi> esteem and regard, we beg leave to subscribe<pb/>
<lb/>ourselves</p>
<p>Very Respectfully,
<lb/>A. D. Hill.
<lb/>John Pope.
<lb/>J. H M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Farland.
<lb/>W. B. Tyler.
<lb/>J. G. Harrison
<lb/>Committee.</p>
<p>John H. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Henry Sr.
<lb/>Ch. of Meeting.
<lb/>E. Ramsey King. Sec.<pb/></p>
<p><hi rend="str">4</hi>^2^
<lb/>Owensboro Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-07-27">July 27<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Wing E. Ramsey
<lb/>Secretary.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Sends to Governor Bramlette a petition signed by Sundry persons of Daviess, setting forth the outrages perpetrated by a party claiming to have authority from you: and pray that the outrage may be corrected.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>See Communication to Geo. H. Yearman on letter book B. Page 13 -- <date when="1865-08-05">Aug. 5 -- 1865</date></p>
<p>2 Inclosures}<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Rec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> A.G O. <date when="1864-08-02">2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Aug 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
