<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3149"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Washington Humphrey to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5268</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-340 to BR41-341</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Burkesville, Cumberland County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excelly. Thomas E. Bramlette
<lb/>Gov of the Comth of Ky.</p>
<p>The undersigned you Petitioner Washington Humphrey, would beg leave to represent that in the year <date when="1865">1865</date>, he obtained a license to sell Liquor in the Town of Burksville, for which he paid the Tax to the Trustees of said Town, and also Government Tax to the U. S. Collector, and when so done he thought he was fully and fairly authorized by law to sell, He states that at the <date when="1865-10">October Term 1865</date>. he was Indicted "for selling to a slave", He was Indicted for selling spirits to officers and soldiers and he was Indicted for keeping a Tipling house, and held to bail on each Indictment. Bench Warrants are now in the hands of the Sheriff of Cumberland County for his arrest. He states that these are the only violations of law that he has ever been charged with that at the time he was Selling Liquors that there was Soldier Stationed in and about Burksville, and for selling to them and their attendant or waiter he has been Indicted. He asks your honor to pardon him for thus offending, pleaing himself to try and never violate the laws again- this favor sought when granted will be remembered by the Petitioner, as he did not know at the time he was selling under the License aforesaid that he was violating the law of Ky.</p>
<p>Washington Humphrey</p>
<p>(over)<pb/>
<lb/>The undersigned Citizens of Cumberland State that they are well acquainted with Washingotn Humphrey that he is a poor man, that the License was paid for as stated by him and join him in asking the Governor to pardon him for said offenses.</p>
<p>A. G. Waggoner
<lb/>Wm ^his x mark^ Eston
<lb/>L. D. Cheathan
<lb/>J. M Boles
<lb/>P. P. Alexander
<lb/>James E. Cole
<lb/>W E Powell
<lb/>J L Mastin
<lb/>C T Check
<lb/>E J. Ellison
<lb/>T S Ellison
<lb/>W. F. Alexander
<lb/>R M Phillips
<lb/>N B Cheatham
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Herreford
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. Haggard
<lb/>Wm. J. Dixon
<lb/>L A Waggoner
<lb/>C. P. Gray<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>Cumberland Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W Humphrey</p>
<p>premature</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
