<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0164"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Nannie Phillips to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9632</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-93 to MG17-94</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Rochester, Butler County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-11-20">20 November 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Rochester Ky <date when="1860-11-20">Nov ^the^20 60</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency Governor Magoffin</p>
<p>Honored Sir last winter when I Saw Your Excellency you give hope that ear many Months roled round You would Restore to Me My unfortunate Husband ten wery Months have gone by and now I pray you to have mercy On two of Your unfortunat fellow creatures</p>
<p>Remember mercy iS a devine attribute I pray that its benign infuence may prompt You to Reconsider my unfortunate huSbands caS turn to these documents that I Brought You last winter</p>
<p>Gentlemen whoeS wordS You cannot doubt tell You that they have known him for yearS yeS Some of them have known him from hiS Infancy they all aS one voice Say to You they are Satisfied thiS iS the first Offence and believe it would be the laSt for they aS well as mySelf know that it iS not his nature<pb/>
<lb/>to do evil that in an ungarded hour he was overtaken AlaS, ^for^ frail humanity he fell Oh let the frailty of human nature plead for him let the Miserable and Stressed condition of his devasted Wife plead for him. Governor You have a kind Wife You can appreciate the feeling of a Wife You have precious Children around You by the love you bore them <hi rend="str">and</hi> by the deSire ^you^ feel for ther Weal by all thats Sacred deal Gently with the erring Knowing that the wiSest and beSt of Our Race have moSt Sadly erred,, There are those here aS well aS elSw^h^ere that would be graifyed to know that Your Ecelency had extended Your clemency to him And You can make glad the heart of her that haS known nought but Sorrow for the laSt two yearS by ReStoring the kindeSt of husbands, I think when I was in Frankfort last winter You told me in the courSe of the Summer or fall my husband might write out hiS own petition if he conducted himSelf well when I waS in Frankfort<pb/>
<lb/>laSt MiSS Eliza South told me that hiS conduct been ordely and unexceptional</p>
<p>Knowing that You have been So immersed in buisneSS I thought to Send You a few lines hopeing to bring thiS more <unclear>forenate</unclear> to You mind believeing that You let mercy prompt You to act I would come and See you but have not two DollarS in the wide World and no way of geting it for I am entirely unfit to contend with adverse fate</p>
<p>Yours ReSpectfully
<lb/>Nannie Phillips</p>
<p>P<hi rend="sup">S</hi> if there iS any thing in thiS world that I can do <hi rend="str">for</hi> to promote My huSband Releace let me konwn and I will try to do it</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
