<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3031"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John H. Price et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5150</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR43-141 to BR43-142</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Harrison County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Thomas E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov of Comth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your petitioner James Harden of this County of Harrison &amp; state of Kentucky would respectfully represent to your Excellency.</p>
<p>That in the year <date when="1861">1861</date>, he had a difficulty with James Slade, his wifes Uncle, in which your petitioner unfortunately wounded, but not seriously ^hurt Slade^ and from which he in a short time entirely recovered, but your petitioner did not shoot until he was first shot at by said James Slade. That your petitioner was at the ^time in^ 18<hi rend="sup">th</hi>" Ky Inft. Vols, as a private soldier That said James Slade born an enemy to your petitioner long after said difficulty, and at the <gap/> Term of the Harrison Circuit Court said Slade presented your petitioner before the grand jury and had him indicted for said wounding and said indictment is still pending. That your petitioner shortly after the commision of said affair was tried for it before a court Martial at Falsmouth Ky on the <gap/> day of <gap/>, and acquitted.</p>
<p>That subsequently in the Fall of <date when="1865">1865</date>, your petitioner being a member of the 53<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Ky Inft. Vols, and being at home in Harrison county, engaged in recruiting for said regiment, he was present near Robertson Station<pb/></p>
<p>on this Cov. Lex R. R. when some negro soldiers who were guarding said R. R. were endeavouring to arrest one Charles Hutchison and mistaking Samuel Slade and this uncle of your petitioners wife for said Huchison, commanded him to halt which command said Slade, refused to obey when he was fired upon and <hi rend="str">kill</hi> wounded by said negro soldiers. From said wound said Slade died in about ten days. Your petitioner and said Samuel Slade did, even then only which persons present at the said shooting of said Slade by said negro soldiers, though one Jake Huthison was a short distance off and ahead of said Slade. Your petitioner did all he could to prevent said shooting of said Samuel Slade, but all his efforts were iniffectual. Some malicious persons enemies of your petitioner have represented that your petitioner aided or abetted in the said shooting of said Samuel Slade did, and have made various threats to have him arrested and tried for said offense. Several Terms of this Harrison Circuit Court &amp; Criminal Court have elapsed since said offense was committed and your petitioner has never been indicted for said offence.<pb/>
<lb/>But your petitioner, having enemies and principally because he was in the Federal service during the war is in constant apprehension lest he be arrested and prosecuted against about this matter:</p>
<p>Whereupon your petitioner in conclusion states that he wounded the said James Slade, in his own proper self defense, and being a soldier was tried by a Court Marshal and acquitted, and that he is wholly innocent of the wounding of said Samuel Slade decd, and said affirm having been committed during this late unfortunate war which is now happily over, he begs that your Excellency would <unclear/> and exert your perogative of mercy and power <unclear>releave</unclear> him from said charges.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>John H. Price
<lb/>A. J Hicks
<lb/>Dan'l Roberts
<lb/>Amos Sparks
<lb/>Richard D King
<lb/>Thomas Chriswell
<lb/>Lawson B. Whiteker
<lb/>William A Lesier
<lb/>James Lany
<lb/>Joseph Beckett
<lb/>Sanford Hill
<lb/>David Chriswell
<lb/>James M Thorp.
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Peter W. Miles
<lb/>David P Whiteker
<lb/>John Criswell
<lb/>William Patten
<lb/>John King
<lb/>Ulrich Garrison
<lb/>Moses Cummins
<lb/>Robert Cummins
<lb/>Joseph Cummins
<lb/>Solomon C Hill
<lb/>AJ Lyons
<lb/>Joseph Beckett
<lb/>Thomas S Beckett<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>S N Whiteker
<lb/>J R Karr
<lb/>John Maddox
<lb/>F. M. Patton
<lb/>James Lyon
<lb/>J. D. Mannin
<lb/>William Craig
<lb/>William. D. Slade
<lb/>J. N. Slade
<lb/>John F Slade
<lb/>John Slade
<lb/>Samuel Slade
<lb/>R S Adams
<lb/>C. Watson
<lb/>E. H. Slade
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J H Day
<lb/>william Day
<lb/>L D Cllifford
<lb/>John B Patton
<lb/>Joe Hase
<lb/>James J Bradley
<lb/>C. B. Cook
<lb/>J. A. Cook
<lb/>Joseph Zoller
<lb/>T J Reuthfort
<lb/>C Leighlley
<lb/>Joseph Eammons
<lb/>C B Halkeant
<lb/>Austin H Eklar</p>
<p>Gov
<lb/>Dear Sir
<lb/>Please direct to Robertson Station
<lb/><hi rend="underline">James Harden</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
