<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-009-0044"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">C. W. Cook to Wiley P. Fowler</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1199</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR1-88</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Dixon, Webster County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-08">8 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Dixon, Ky <date when="1865-10-08">Oct<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865_</date>
<lb/>Judge Fowler
<lb/>Dear Sir,</p>
<p>We are getting into hot work up here. Important disclosures have been made in regard to the band of robbers in this &amp; <hi rend="underline">Critenden</hi> Counties I had what I regarded pretty accurate information in regard to several citizens of this county and I sent them word that developments were being made which would ultimately lead to the detection of every man engaged in it and if they would come up and make full and complete disclosures I would guarantee to them protection Upon this representation two of them have come up &amp; made a full confession They say there are about 45 belonging to the band most of them from <hi rend="underline">Critenden</hi> County. I send you a list of names which embraces all the persons with whom these men are acquainted and they say that they are the active men, the men who do the <hi rend="underline">robing</hi> that the others are citizens who act in the capacity of spies and furnish information in regard to has money and feed and harbor &amp; share the spoils. I have started the Sheriff of the County with 25 or 30 men and directed him to pursue them into Crittenden or any other county to which they may go. If you think it best you can start the Sheriff of Union for I think it likely some of them will make their way into that county. D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Corbett the bearer of this can give you all the particulars in detail<pb/></p>
<p>I want you to write to me by D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Corbett, and advise me as to the best course to pursue -- this is my chief object in writing to you -- </p>
<p>Yours truly
<lb/>C. W. Cook -- </p>
<p>P. S. I send this copy instead of the original</p>
<p>W. P. Fowler</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
