<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1385"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">E. H. Parrish et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6022</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-151 to BR12-152</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-12-01">1 December 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><date when="1864-12-01">December 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>To his excellency the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned would respectfully state that he was foreman of the grand Jury of Scott county Ky at the last term, or rather spring term of this year, and had before us the case of I think five young men, among them was W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> B Newton and John T Carr, indightments were found against all of them for robbing some articles of clothing and for taking a horse and mule, probably from Mrs Johnson, it seemed although they took the horse and mule they were both returned to Mrs Johnsons ^by her^ negro befor they were captured, -- in a very short time after they were taken. -- It, all seemed to be a drunken frolick of the boys -- but one -- the Jury thought ought to be punished, it is due to young Newton, to say he had on his soldier over coat and consequently did not have the stolen clothes on, I am informed and believe that both Newton and Carr <hi rend="str">to say that</hi> were members of Capt Goings Company Artilery <hi rend="str">and</hi> at the time Judgement went against B S Newton on their recognizance bonds of Newton and Carr, each of the young men were on detailed duty at Versailles, and could not be got before the court by any means known to the elder Newton, it may be said in mitigation of young Newton and Carr, that thought ^they^ were in bad company, and at bad business, yet they were never before known to be guilty of a misdemeanor I consequently infer that the other three boys who are known to be thieveish bad boys were guilty of the outbreaks such as stealing clothing &amp;c, I would recommend to your<pb/>
<lb/>clemency the bearer of this who from a fathers instincts went bail ^for his son and carr^ with the full expectation of his son, and Carr, comeing to trial, and not from any intention of shielding them from justice, the elder Newton is a poor man that will be much inconvenience if he should have to pay the bail and has ever bein a Loyal man since the outbreak of this rebelion</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>E H Parrish
<lb/>Q. S. Sinclair
<lb/>one of the Grand Jurors.
<lb/>Elza Thomason
<lb/>H M Bedford
<lb/>H. B. Innes</p>
<p>I am personally acquainted with Messrs Parrish Sinclair and Thomasson. They are highly respectable citizens whose statements may be relied upon -- I am also acquainted with B. S. Newton. He is a clever citizen, in very moderate circumstances -- and I recommend <hi rend="str">John M Harl</hi> him to the kind consideration of the Governor.</p>
<p>John M Harlan<pb/></p>
<p>Scott Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>B. S. Newton &amp; Elijah Thomson for $300</p>
<p><date when="1864-12-05">Decr 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Respited <hi rend="str">until ten days succeeding the next term of Scott Circuit Court</hi> for six months from date to give an opportunity for there being brought before the Court -- which if done and certified to the Executive a remission will be granted</p>
<p>T E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi></p>
<p>also vs
<lb/>B. S. Newton
<lb/>for $300 -- 
<lb/><date when="1864-12-05">5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Dec/64</date></p>
<p>Judgt <date when="1864-11">Novr Term 1864.</date> $</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
