<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2312"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John T. Percival et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9388</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG25-65-1 to MG25-66</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Gov Magoffin</p>
<p>The undersigned petitioners would respectfully represent to your Excellency that James G. Everett was at the present term of the Kenton Circuit Court at Independence convicted of the offence of keeping a tippling house and fined $60 -- The testimony showed that he was the keeper of a grocery in the country, &amp; had license to sell liquor in quantities not less than a quart; that on one occasion in <date when="1859-11">Nov 1859</date>, he sold a quart to one of the witnesses, and a portion of it was drank in the house, but the witness could not say certainly that Everett knew it was being drank there; that on the same day, a man named Jones rode up in front of the grocery and bought a quart of whiskey, a portion of which was drank by him in the road as he sat on his horse; and the witnesses said also that they had on several occassions seen Everetts neighbors drink in the road in front of the house, and at the door, but did not know that the liquor was sold to them -- Everett was in the habit of <hi rend="underline">treating</hi> his neighbors and customers when they came to his house -- It was against Everetts rules to allow drinking in his house, if the liquor was paid for -- </p>
<p>We are satisfied that Mr Everett did not know that it was a violation of the law<pb/>
<lb/>to allow the whiskey to be drank in the public road, and that, as he is now informed upon that point, he will not permit it here after -- </p>
<p>Mr Everett is a peaceable law abiding citizen, and we respectully ask your Excellency to remit his fine</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>G <unclear/>
<lb/>X S J Hume
<lb/>X James Fleming
<lb/>X Whitiny Riley
<lb/>X J L Rich
<lb/>G J Bagley
<lb/>X George Riley
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Fisher
<lb/>S. C Sayers
<lb/>John Cox
<lb/>S F Roberts
<lb/>John N Bridges
<lb/>M Hoffman
<lb/>Wm E. Pool
<lb/>D C Stephens
<lb/>Eli Olerver
<lb/>H. H. Mullins J. P
<lb/>E, W, Coleman
<lb/>A S Stephens
<lb/>D<hi rend="sup">an</hi> M M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Searty
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/>John T. Percival
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> R Rufuss
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> W M James
<lb/>J. S Downard
<lb/>J C Byland
<lb/>Jno A Stephens
<lb/>K. Wells
<lb/>E T. Richards
<lb/>B. F. Bagby
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Trippitt
<lb/>Woodford Stephens
<lb/>E. R. Rouse
<lb/>F Young
<lb/>Lewis Wayman
<lb/>John A, Hall
<lb/>James Havens
<lb/>Patrick Stableton
<lb/>George Spilman
<lb/>James Rust
<lb/>H Wayman
<lb/>John ,J, Stephens<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>Javan Swetman
<lb/>M. West
<lb/>J B Wayman
<lb/>X W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Standers
<lb/>M T Stephens
<lb/>John J. Stephenson
<lb/>John, W, Sanders
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
