<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1032"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John M. Harlan to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10500</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-109 to MG20-110</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-05-08">8 May 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville <date when="1861-05-08">May 8/61</date>
<lb/>Dear Sir:</p>
<p>I take the liberty of addressing you in regard to a matter in which all of our family feel a very deep interest.</p>
<p>M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Caldwell of Columbus Ky a neice of my father's is now in Frankfort for the purpose of effecting if possible, the pardon of her son John William Caldwell charged with the homicide of one Woods. -- of course I have no knowledge of the circumstances attending to this unfortunate affair farther than I have learned from others. But my information from entirely reliable sources induces me to believe that there is not the slightest ground to Suppose that young Caldwell pre-<pb/>
<lb/>meditated the killing of Woods. They were friendly, got into quarrel, no doubt unexpectedly, with each other, Woods got possession of Caldwell's cane, and not till then did Caldwell shoot -- Caldwell no doubt, in the excitement of the moment, believed that he was in great danger, &amp; hence he shot at Woods &amp; unfortunately killed him -- </p>
<p>I know Caldwell well. Naturally there is no cleverer young man -- when he was quite young having no father no control him he fell in with evil associates, and contracted some bad habits -- But he has entirely reformed and now desires to return to his native State, and lead an entirely<pb/>
<lb/>different life. He has been a wanderer for 18 months, being compelled to remain away from his widowed mother, who in her old age, looks alone to him for protection. I think you would do a good act if you would restore him to his mother, who seems almost broken hearted in her present condition. I doubt not if you would inquire of M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Lannom, he could give you all the facts.</p>
<p>Your favorable action in this matter would never be forgotten by any member of our family -- We will never cease to thank you. <hi rend="str">if</hi></p>
<p>With great respect
<lb/>Yr obt servt
<lb/>John M Harlan</p>
<p>To Hon B. Magoffin<pb/></p>
<p>Hickman Eq. &amp; Crim. Ct
<lb/>Jno. W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Caldwell
<lb/>Indictment for Homicide
<lb/>Pardon Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-09-16">Sept 16. 1861</date></p>
<p>Petition
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Caldwell</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
