<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0423"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky vs. Stockwell Clark, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8875</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-180</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Madison County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Madison Circuit Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth
<lb/>Against } Indict for Carry Con Weapon
<lb/>Stockwell Clark</p>
<p>W M Stone says that at the <date when="1860-12">December Term 1860</date> of the Madison Circuit Court the defendant Stockwell Clark was indicted for carrying a concealed weapon and then upon a bench warrant was issued and that he became his surety in the sum of $100 for his appearance &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi></p>
<p>He says that the deft did at all times when required attend to answser said charge until the <date when="1862-06">June term 1862</date>, at which time failing to appear a forfeiture of his bond was entered</p>
<p>The case was continued from time to time by the commonwealth, the deft always appearing in obedience to the process in this case till the time aforesaid stated</p>
<p>He further says that about the <date when="1862-04-15">15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of April 1862</date> the said deft without his knowledge or consent &amp; so far as this matter relates to him <hi rend="str">without</hi> against his <hi rend="str">consent</hi> wishes left the county of Madison &amp; state of Kentucky for the state of Massachusetts &amp; that at the date of <unclear/> departure from said county &amp; state he Stone was living in the town of Barboursville Ky some seventy five miles distant from this point &amp; had been residing there since the middle of <date when="1862-01">January 1862</date> &amp; that he did not return till the <date when="1862-08-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> of August of thereabouts 1862</date> -- </p>
<p>He states that an account of his Stones absence aforesaid he had no knowledge of the departure of said Clark &amp; could not therefore take any steps to prevent it He is perfectly willing that the case should be tried &amp; is willing to abide by the Judgment of the court if the case should go against said Clark<pb/></p>
<p><hi rend="str">Wherefore</hi></p>
<p>He says the forfeiture is rather "tight" upon him &amp; he asks your excellency to <hi rend="underline">remit</hi> the same</p>
<p>W M Stone</p>
<p>W M Stone says the statements in the foregoing paper are true</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J M Shackelford C M C C</hi></p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Madison County would respectfully unite in the petition of W M Stone -- </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J. W. Caperton
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Will J Walker</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Giles Rody</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">C. F. Burnam</hi>
<lb/><cb n="2"/>E. H. Fields
<lb/>D Breck
<lb/>R. G. Burton
<lb/>W. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clanahan
<lb/>E L Shackelford</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Madison Cir. Ct
<lb/>The Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Petition &amp; affidavit of W M Stone
<lb/>Stockwell Clark <hi rend="str">Jr</hi><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>$100. } For.
<lb/>The forfeiture in this case is remitted
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J F Robinson</hi>
<lb/>W. M Stone
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-06-13">June 13. 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
