<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2108"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">G. M. Mulligan to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6745</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-319</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Scottville, Allen County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-07-21">21 July 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Scottville Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-07-21">July 21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Gov Bramlet
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>Enclosed you will please find the petition of Mr Guy a citizen of this county whos "humble prayer is for mercy" at your hands allow me to say that the facts of his case are correctly set forth and that he is truly an object of pity under the circumstances, ignorance of his duty or what the law in such cases required was the cause of his failure to comply with his band The old man's Son is a wild reckless boy and I fear a bad man but the offence with which he is charged grew out of the fact that in a drunken spree he rode one of his neighbors horses to a still house for more whiskey and did not get back untill the horse was missed The endorsement of the old man is by the best men in the County</p>
<p>Yours respectfully
<lb/>G. M. Mulligan</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
