<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0003-092-0130"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">G. W. Bayless, John Matthews, and George Hancock to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14420</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>George W. Johnson Papers</collection>
      <idno>Folder 6</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-04-16">16 April 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville Ky
<lb/><date when="1862-08-16">April 16<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1862</date>.</p>
<p>I have just examined the body of the late Geo. W. Johnson, and can state in positive terms that I am able to identify the body beyond all doubt. I travelled to Virginia with him last <date when="1861-08">August,</date> when he showed me the old injury to his left arm and hand; which I now perceive was damaged. I am also able to recognize the face.</p>
<p>He had two wounds: -- One in the right thigh, a flesh wound, and not mortal:- a second in the abdomen about half way between the navel and pubis a little to right of the median line. This last<pb/>
<lb/>wound was, beyond doubt, the cause of his death. He must have died very soon after receiving this last wound; probably from loss of blood, and with very little suffering.</p>
<p>Both of his wounds were rec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> in front and were apparently from minie balls.</p>
<p>G. W. Bayless
<lb/>John Matthews</p>
<p>Doctors, Bayliss &amp; Matthews, at my request, have been with me in this examination and I have no dificulty in recognising the remains of my friend.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Geo. Hancock</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
