<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3008"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Charles Kirtly et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5127</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR43-110 to BR43-111</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thos E Bramlett
<lb/>Gov of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioners would most respectfully state that about the <gap/> day of <gap/> 186<gap/> Jesse Hicks was arrested on a charge of Horse Stealing being a poor man and unable to give bail He was confined in the jail of Rockcastle County, where He remained for about <gap/> months when the Jail was broken open and said Hicks made His escape</p>
<p>They further state that a short time before the arrest of Hicks. His wife died leaving six small children three girls and 3 Boys the Eldest only 10 or 11 years old (a girl) That at the time Hicks got out of Jail His children were entirely destitute of any thing to Eat and almost naked. They were too young to work, Had no one to provide for them. The officers of the Law were in pursuit of Hicks, and consequently He could not work to support his children. To keep His children from starvation He stole some bacon to feed them. Said Hicks continued to remain as near His children as He could. And was arrested and returned to Jail where He remained until the present term of the Court; when on<pb/>
<lb/>investigation He was found entirely innocent of the alleged crime of Horse stealing and the Indictment against Him for that offence was dismissed He was However indicted for Grand larceny, plead this He was guilty of stealing the Bacon, but that it was done as a mattter of necessity to save His children from starving. He was tried and sentenced for 2 yeras to the Penetentiary</p>
<p>Now your Petitioners would most earnestly ask, that as Mr Hicks was wrongfully confined in Jail for so long,<hi rend="str"> the apparent necessity for Him to take the Bacon</hi> on a charge of which He was innocent. As the motives that urged Him to commit the crime (if a crime) for which He was convicted, were such as would have driven men of Higher standing in the Community to acts as desperate as Hicks resorted to, that your Excellency pardon Mr. Hicks restore Him to His famiy, (His six infant children) who will suffer for the very necessaries of life, unless provided for by the charitible</p>
<p>Mr. Hicks is a Hard working man, and we believe should be pardoned.</p>
<p>Charles Kirtly atto at Law
<lb/>R D Cook Clerk
<lb/>Rockcastle County Court
<lb/>Ashley Owens Jailer
<lb/>G. W. McClure
<lb/>J J Williams<pb/>
<lb/>H. H. Baker
<lb/>M. R. Moore
<lb/>Benj T. Hoharn Atty
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J G Hazlewood</hi>
<lb/>A. J. Moore C. Atty
<lb/>Alred Smith clk
<lb/>Rockcastle circuit
<lb/>M. A. Brooks
<lb/>S. H Thompson
<lb/>Jno J Brown
<lb/>S D moore Atty
<lb/>James M Adams
<lb/>Richard A Brooks
<lb/>Jack Adams
<lb/>W L. Kirtey
<lb/>J. W Moore
<lb/>J E Hocker
<lb/>George Tarkington
<lb/>James G Carter Acting
<lb/>Commonwealth Attorney
<lb/>Josh Dishman
<lb/>Jack Jones Atty at Law
<lb/>William Bowens
<lb/>G. W Roberts Late Capt 3 Ky Infty<pb/>
<lb/><hi rend="str">Referred to Govr Helm</hi>
<lb/>Refered to Govr Helm for Consideration.
<lb/><date when="1867">67</date></p>
<p>Gov Bramblete
<lb/>Dear Sir
<lb/>I hope that you will pardon Hix <hi rend="str">from</hi> for Grand Larceny convct for two years from Robert C Pearl</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
