<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0048"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. P. D. Bush et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14077</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1864</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lewisport, Hancock County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-08-03">3 August 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Lewisport Hancock Co Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-08-03">Aug. 3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> 1864</date>.
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Bramlett
<lb/>Frankfort Ky.
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>This will be handed you by M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> E. Sanford a citizen of this county whom I take pleasure in introducing to your Excellency.</p>
<p>M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> S. will visit Frankfort on a mission from the citizens of this county to your Excellency for the purpose of representing to you the true condition of affiars in this county as well as the almost unanmiious wish of our citizens in reference to a Company of State forces which we understand you have authorized Mason Hedrick to raise for (as he says) the defense of this and adjoining counties.</p>
<p>Mason Hedrick and W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> H. Gregg are now attempting to raise a company (as they say) by your authorities and are enlisting<pb/>
<lb/>men in Spencer County Indiana -- they now have in camp in Spencer Co. Ia they say some 30 or 40 men whom they have enlisted there whom they intend to cross over the river in a few days to be mustered into the Ky State Service </p>
<p>I cannot discover any motion in citizens of Indiana coming into the Ky State Service that could possibly recommind them to your Excellency or the people of Ky.</p>
<p>This county has recently suffered very severely in the loss of negroes nad nearly all the good horses in the county and it is hoped the Govenor will not authorize the raising and mustering into the State service a company of men to be located in our midst whose only object both with the officers and men will be their own private gain as neither officers nor their men will have any permanent interest in the community </p>
<p>I can assure your Excellency that not one in twenty of the Union citizens of this county desire any such force as that<pb/>
<lb/>being raised by Hedrick and Gregg as they feel well satisfied from the character of the officers and their men that their presence in our midst will afford no protection whatever to any one and would in all probability bring much trouble and inconvenience upon our citizens</p>
<p>M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Sanford is a reliable and an unconditional Union man and his statements and representations to the Govenor will be entitled to the highest credit and respect, in reference to all the matters above alluded to.</p>
<p>Respectfully Yours &amp;c
<lb/>W. P. D. Bush
<lb/>Eldred E. Pate clerk
<lb/>Hancock Co &amp; cir ct
<lb/>M. L. Cooper. P, M<pb/></p>
<p>Lewisport Hancock Co
<lb/>Ky <date when="1864-08-03">Aug 3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> 1864</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Bush W. P. D. &amp; others
<lb/>To the Gov<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Introduced Mr <hi rend="underline">E. Sanford</hi> who comes to Frankfort as a Representation for the citizens of this co in case of <hi rend="underline">Mason Hedrick</hi> &amp; <hi rend="underline">William H Gregg</hi> who are authorized by you to recruit a co of State Guards report to have 30 or 40 men who are recruited in Spencer Co Ind</p>
<p>And in a few days to come into Ky to be mustered into the S. Guard service. They protest the Mustering of said <unclear>omen</unclear> as in opinion of the Good citizens of co that the purpose of the capt and men are not for any good purpose &amp; from the <unclear>character</unclear> of <hi rend="underline">Hedrick</hi> and <hi rend="underline">Gregg</hi> are satisfied that they in our midst will be no protection and ask that the organization may be broken up<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>L B N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 5 -- <date when="1864">1864</date> P 371<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Rec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> A G O <date when="1864-08-09">9 Aug 1864</date><pb/></p>
<p><figure type="seal"><ab>UNITED WE STAND DIVIDED WE FALL</ab></figure>
<lb/>Head-Quarters Kentucky Volunteers,
<lb/>ADJUTANT GENERAL'S OFFICE.
<lb/>Louisville, <gap/> 186<gap/></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
