<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1248"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Tuttle and W. J. Crook et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5885</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-420 to BR11-421</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned Petitioners would respectfully represent that at the <date when="1864-08">^last^ August Term</date> of the Laurel Circuit Court They were tried for the offence of gaming and found guilty and fined in the sum of $20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> each They state that the facts as they existed and as proved were that your petitioners and two other men were engaged in a game at cards where ^there was^ liquor <hi rend="str">was</hi> for sale the <hi rend="underline">run</hi> of the game was. that the two that beat were to drink while the other two were not to drink but pay the bill -- in this way the game was played merely for amusement and pass time without your petitioners knowing that such gaming was a violation of law -- as the times are somewhat hard in this section and the means of the undersigned <hi rend="underline">limited</hi> They therefore pray your Excellency to remit said fines</p>
<p>Thomas Tuttle
<lb/>W. J. Crook<pb/></p>
<p>I heard the evidence upon which the above mentioned fines were assessed and know that it was substantially as stated in the foregoing petition Said Crook and Tuttle are poor men and in my Judgment the good of society would not suffer by said fines being remitted</p>
<p>C B Faris Clerk
<lb/>Laurel Cir, Court</p>
<p>The undersigned are citizens of Laurel County and well acquainted with said Crook and Tuttle and believe said fines ought to be remitted</p>
<p>Rholand Hodges
<lb/>S Ewen Jones
<lb/>Wm Lemar
<lb/>Wm. R. Jones Sqr
<lb/>S C Jackson</p>
<p>Laurel Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Tuttle &amp; W. J. Crook
<lb/>$20, each
<lb/>Remit
<lb/><date when="1864-10-04">4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Oct/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
