<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0538"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">F. M. English and A. H. Dudley to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8990</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Hannah M. O'Daniel</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-355</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Princeton, Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863">1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><placeName ref="cwgk:P00002273">Princeton Ky</placeName> <gap/> <date when="1863">1863</date>
<lb/>To the Honorable <persName ref="cwgk:N001004">J. F. Robinson</persName><lb/>Govenor of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O001025">State of Kentucky</orgName><lb/>Respected &amp; Dear Sir,</p>
   <p>Your petitioners would respectfully represent that, at the <date when="--12">December</date> Term of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000412">Lyon County Circuit Court</orgName> the Grand Jury, at the information of D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> <persName ref="cwgk:N00002085">J D Yiezer</persName>, found a true bill against <persName ref="cwgk:N00002080">Uriah Kevil</persName> <persName ref="cwgk:N00003866">J L Satterfield</persName> <persName ref="cwgk:N00003868">Lewis Martin Jr</persName> and <persName ref="cwgk:N00003869">John Gray </persName>for taking on the <date when="--02-01">1 day of February</date> a shot Gun from the said D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> J D Yiezer <hi rend="underline">without</hi> fellonious intent. These four Young men were duly tried for said offence at the late <date when="--06">June</date> Term of the Lyon County Circuit Court -- two of them proved an alibi a third that he was accident<hi rend="str">ly</hi>ally at the said Yiezers on his way to preaching at the time said Gun was taken and were acquitted of the charge But Uriah Kevil was found guilty and fined $50<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> The circumstance that involved him in the finding was this. <persName ref="cwgk:N00003857">Captain Winston</persName> a rebel officer in charge ^of^ 6 small number of men had his camp in the neighbourhood of Princeton Ky And on the day specified went to D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> J. D. Yiezers for the <hi rend="str">p</hi>ostensible purpose of getting medicine and while there inquired of the Doctor if he had a shot gun who replied he had. Whereupon Winston demanded the gun and took<pb/>
<lb/>it away with him The said Uriah Kevil was with <orgName ref="cwgk:O00003858">the Company of Winston</orgName> at the time the Gun was taken and went away with the Company when it left On the trial Kevils attorneys acted with the impression that he was a voluntary member of the said. Capt. Winstons Company and were totally unapprised of the Circumstance under which he was present at the taking of the Gun. and simply pleaded in extenuation -- the Young mans Youth And his previous and subsequent good conduct And the unblemished character of <persName ref="cwgk:N00003856">his Parents</persName> Some days after the trial and finding, Your petitioners w<hi rend="str">as</hi>ere made acquainted with the facts Contained in the Affidavit of <persName ref="cwgk:N00003860">P Conway</persName> which is herein enclosed and marked A -- with the Certificate of the clerk of <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000363">Caldwell Circuit Court</orgName> as to his probity &amp;c Your petitioners <hi rend="str">is</hi>are firmly of the belief. that had the facts of said Conway been before the Jury said Kevil would have been acquitted. We are the stern advocates of executing the laws of our Commonwealth against all offenders. But in this Case we are fully of opinion that the evidence of Conway which was not before the jury would have acquitted him, and as it was not.. The protection of the innocent, and the ends of justice, fully <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>authorise us in this appeal to your prerogative in the Earnest hope that the $35<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> going to the Commonwealth may have<pb/>
<lb/>Your executive remission for which Your petitioners would earnestly pray</p>
   <p><persName ref="cwgk:N00003870">F. M. English</persName>
    <lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00002700">A H Dudly</persName> clk
<lb/>Lyon Circt Court</p>
<p>I am personal acquainted with Uriah Kevil -- Think him a clever Young man and if Consistent with the Governors clemency would be pleased that his fine be remitted</p>
<p>Princeton Ky <date when="1863-08">Augst 1863</date>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00003864">A. P. Watkins</persName><lb/>clerk. C C Court -- <pb/></p>
<p>The Undersigned Jurors, whose verdict was given at the <date when="--06">June</date> Term of the Lyon Circuit Court in favour of the Commonwealth vs. Uriah Kevil. do not hesitate to Sign this petition. as we believe the testimony of P. Conway. had it been before us would have acquitted said Kevil</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00003871">A. Brock
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00003872">Levi Jones</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00003874">Nathan Oliver
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00003875">W H Harris
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00003877">William Vaughn</persName></p>
<p>I A H Dudley Clerk of the Lyon Circuit Court Certify that A Brock &amp; others whose names appear above. were members of the Jury at the <date when="--06">June</date> Term of said Court. and that they were a part of the Jury. whose verdict was in favour of the Commonwealth vs. Uriah Kevil and the amount of fine was Fifty dollars
<lb/><date when="1863-08-24">Aug 24 1863</date></p>
<p>A H Dudley clk.</p>
<p>P S. It would be an easy matter to obtain a heavy list of Petitioners. but. I deem it all sufficient to rely upon those whose names appear The other members of the Jury have not been visited or doubtless their names would have been obtained -- </p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>F. M. English</p>
<p>Remit all except costs &amp;c
<lb/><hi rend="underline">T E Bramlette</hi></p>
<p>Lyon Cir. Ct
<lb/>$50 -- 
<lb/>Uriah Kevil
<lb/>Remitted Iss <date when="1863-09-04">4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sep 1863</date></p>
<p>Uriah Kevil</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
