<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0237"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Shields to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9705</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-202 to MG17-203</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>His Excellency, Beriah Magoffin, Govenor of the State of Kentucky:</p>
<p>Your petitioner, John Shields, would respectfully submit his claims to Executive Clemency. On the <date when="1858-01-28">28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of January 1858</date> W C P Breckinridge Esq missed a box of jewelry from his office. A day or two afterward your petitioner was standing near the Market House in Lexington Kentucky and one John Easmer (whose affidavit is filed as part of this petition) came up to your petitioner and asked him if he had heard anything of a box of jewelry. Your petitioner replied that he had not. Robt Byrns, a witness in this Cause, was standing and had the night previous bought some of this same jewelry from Easmer, said that a little girl had found the box and stated where she lives. Easmer then said that the box and jewelry were his, and if your petitioner would go and get them he (Easmer) would give your pe-<pb/>
<lb/>titioner a part of the same.</p>
<p>Your petitioner went to the house as requested and returned to Easmer and handed him the box in the presence of Robt Byrnes. Easmer then gave your petitioner a gold button for his trouble. This was found to belong to M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Breckinridge and returned to him. Your petitioner then went to M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Breckinridge, stated the circumstances under which he had become possessed of the button, returned to Easmer in company with a witness and requested Easmer to go to M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Breckinridge and give him every thing he had belonging to him.</p>
<p>Afterwarda this same Easmer and Your petitioner were indicted jointly in the Fayette Circuit Court. Your petitioner was tried in <date when="1860-02">February</date> last and sentenced to the Penetentiary for Twelve months. Easmer was afterward tried and cleared. This was in <date when="1860-02">February 1860</date>, and your petitioner has been in the County Jail ever since<pb/>
<lb/>He moved for a new trial which was entertained by the court and then overruled.</p>
<p>He then prayed and appeal which was granted but on examining the papers it was found that the instructions of the Court were lost, and your petitioner is now awaiting its order.</p>
<p>Your petitioner states that he is innocent of the charge against him; has been sorely punished by confinement in the County jail for more than two years; is now quite sick and has been confined to his bed for near two weeks. He earnestly hopes and prays that he may meet with Executive clemency and he be released from damp unhealthy walls which have so long confined him.</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>John Shields</p>
<p>We hope his honour will interpose his clemency in aforesaid case.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>L. P. Young
<lb/>W H Lusby Jailor F C
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Bryan H Allen
<lb/><hi rend="underline">R Pindell</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">James B Beck</hi><pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>I wrote to the Governor some months ago -- to which letter I now refer -- recommending a pardon for this Petitioner. I now reiterate that recommendation. I could not sign the above petition, as my recollection differs from that statement of facts.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> C P Breckinridge</hi>
<lb/>Lexington <date when="1860-12-17">Dec 17<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1860</date></p>
<p>We earnestly recommend Petitioner to Executive Clemency</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="3"/><cb n="1"/>Speed. S. Goodloe
<lb/>G W Davis
<lb/>R W Woolley
<lb/>John B Payne Jr.
<lb/>John T. Thomas
<lb/>H Rees
<lb/>W, C, Fox
<lb/>H C Sims
<lb/><hi rend="underline">M. L. Keith</hi>
<lb/>J W Harcourt
<lb/>M, M, Miller
<lb/>Jno C Young
<lb/>M C Forrhee
<lb/>C S Wossham
<lb/>J. R, Henesey
<lb/>James M. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clelland
<lb/>W H Marriott
<lb/>G W Foster
<lb/>J J Wilson
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Jno C Hansbro.
<lb/>H. P. Hitchcock
<lb/>J. L. Semler
<lb/>J<hi rend="underline">no.</hi> W. Alexander
<lb/>Benj F Graves
<lb/>J. M. Taylor
<lb/>F. T Erd
<lb/>S. N. Meyer
<lb/><cb n="3"/>B C, <hi rend="underline">Wood</hi>
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Wheatly</p>
<p><hi rend="str">Pardo</hi></p>
<p>Issue pardon &amp; file the other Pet<hi rend="sup">n</hi> &amp;c with this } B. M.</p>
<p>J W Pate</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
