<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2708"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">G. C. Ingram and L. P. Baker to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7345</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-354 to BR16-355</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-11-02">2 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thos E Bramlette Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned Granville C. Ingram and Levi P Baker, would respectfully beg leave to represent unto Your Excellancy that at the last <date when="--10">October</date> term of the Wayne Circuit Court, a judgment in favor of Said Commonwealth was rendered against them by the Wayne Circuit Court for a fine of One Hundred dollars each on <hi rend="str">an</hi> <hi rend="str">Indictment</hi> ^Saparate indictments against them^ for Tipling. They state that they applied to and obtained from the Government of the United States a license in due form and paid the tax thereon as may be seen by the enclosed license ^one of which through mistake of the Collector was found in the name of Baker &amp; Bobbit.^ That they Would also have obtained a license from the Trustees of Monticello and paid the tax thereon to the Corporation and to the state, but during the time they operated under the license from the general government, there were no Trustees in Office, and Consequently they were unable to procure Corporation license, They state that they had no inteniton of violating any law or defrauding the State or Corporate authority, And moreover they carried on the business at the time of the invasion of this portion of the State by the Rebels, and at the time when law and Order was unknown in this section of Country. Your petitioners would therefore most respectfully ask your Excellency to release them from the payment of that portion of the fines to which the State is entitled, and they will promise that they will not annoy your Excellency with such importunities for the future, and in duty bound they will ever pray and petition</p>
<p><date when="1865-11-02">Nov 2 1865</date>
<lb/>G C Ingram
<lb/>L. P. Baker<pb/></p>
<p>Under the Circumstances set forth in the foregoing petition, the undersinged most cordially unite with the petitioners in asking Executive interpositon and clemency in their behalf</p>
<p>Nov 2. 1865
<lb/>W. Simpson
<lb/>W A Buster
<lb/>H W Tuttle
<lb/>H, B, Carter
<lb/>C H Buster
<lb/>H Huffaker
<lb/>L. J. Stephenson
<lb/>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> L Sallee</p>
<p>There can be no doubt but the remission asked is proper &amp; should be granted</p>
<p>Jno. S. Van Winkle<pb/></p>
<p>To</p>
<p>Wayne Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>G. C Ingram &amp; L. B. Baker
<lb/>$100. each
<lb/>Tipling
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-11-13">13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
