<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1748"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John C. Harding to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6385</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-253 to BR13-254</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-04-01">1 April 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency T E Bramlett
<lb/>Govenor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner John Harding a citizen of Marion County Ky would respectfully State to your Excellency that from the Commencement of the present war that he has been an active Union Man and that he has devoted much of his time in rendering assistance to the Union forces Stationed in Marion County Your Petitioner further States that he had authority from the various commanders of the Post at Lebanon Ky to arrest all Suspicious persons who might be passing through the County and to render Such other assistance to the Military authorities as might be required Your Petitioner states that he commanded a company of home Guards in Said County and that he did render all the assistance in his power to Union forces Your Petitioner States that with 25 of Said home Guards that he fought John Morgans Command at the Roling fork Bridge for more than two hours &amp; that he has arrested and dilivered over to the proper authorities a number of horse thieves who have been Committing thefts through that portion of the Country Your Petitioner States that Some time about the <date when="1863-02-07">7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of February 1863</date> that he was at Raywick in Marion County and that while there he was informed that there was in said Town a Suspicious individual who gave his name as John R Redman Your Petitioner states that Joseph Short (a member of the home guard Company) and himself arrested Said John R Redman and took charge of his pocket book and other property which he had and that they told<pb/>
<lb/>Said Redman that if he could give Satisfactory evidence that he had legitimate business that they would release him and deliver back to him his Pocket Book &amp;c otherwise they would take him to Lebanon &amp; deliver him &amp; his property to the Provo Marshal Your Petitioner States that Said Redman agreed and promised to meet your Petitioner on the next morning at his house for the purpose of proving his loyalty &amp; to prove that he was transacting business in that portion of the County Your Petitioner States that Said Redman failed to meet ^him^ as above Stated and that on the Second day after Said Redman ^was arrested^ your Petitioner went to Lebanon to deliver to the Provo Marshall the money &amp;c which he had taken from said Redman your Petitioner States that he did deliver the same to the Provo Marshall Your Petitioner states that while in Lebanon he with George Short was arrested Charged with robbing Said Redman and that they were required to give Bail for their appearance at the next term of the Marion circuit court Your Petitioner states that he is not guilty of the alledged offense That he had no intention of the kind &amp; that he was acting in good faith in the whole transaction and that he was only doing what he deemed to be his duty under the authority which he then had from Col Spalding the commander of the Post at Lebanon Your Petitioner States that at the last term of the Marion Circuit Court that he was tried for said alledged offense and Sentenced to to hard labor in the Penitentiary of the State for the term of three years Your Petitioner states that the only evidence of any importance against him<pb/>
<lb/>was the Statements of this man John R Redman who was the only witness who Stated any thing that would Sustain the allegation Your Petitioner States that said John R Redman is looked upon as a Suspicious character and ought not to be believed That he for some time before the alledged Offense was said to have been Committed made his home at one Frank Beachamps in Green County who has served a term in the Penitentiary of Indiana for passing Counterfeit money and that he associated with the Daniel &amp; Beachamp all of whom are looked upon as being connected with the bands of Guerrillas which infest that portion of the state That Said John R Redman is a Stragling Stranger who roamed over the country without any apparent business or occupation and that Suspicion has rested upon him for several offences which have been committed in Green County as is shown by the Statement of E M Angel Dep Pro M for Green County &amp; others citizens of ^said county^ Your Petitioner states that he has always tried to live an honest man and that he has always sustained that character as is shown by the statements of his County-men who know him Your Petitioner further States that he has a large &amp; helpless family &amp; that he acted in good faith believing that Said Redman was a Spie or Guerrilla and that he ought to be arrested your Petitioner again declares most Solemnly that he is not guilty of the offense alleged against him &amp; that ^in <hi rend="str">in</hi>^ all he did that he acted in good faith &amp; desired only to serve his country wherefore your Petitioner prays your Excellency to grant him &amp; pardon &amp;c and as in duty bound he will every pray &amp;c</p>
<p>John C Harding<pb/></p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">W D
<lb/><date when="1865-04-01">April 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1865</date></note></p>
<p> -- Sworn to and Subscribed before me by John C. Harding on this <date when="1865-04-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of April 1865</date></p>
<p>W Dearen J. P. T. C</p>
<p>John C Harding indicted as John March term of Marion Circuit court convicted by verdict of Jury to 3 years confinement in Penitentiary for Robbery<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Pardon<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><date when="1865-04-05">5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> April 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
