<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1761"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. N. Turner, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6398</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-273 to BR13-274</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-05-12">12 May 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">J. N. T.
<lb/><date when="1865-05-12">May 12 1865</date></note>
<lb/><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">J C B
<lb/><date when="1865-05-12">May 12/65</date></note></p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Caldwell County</p>
<p>The affiant J. N. Turner States that he is now and has allways been true &amp; loyal to the United States Government, a Citizen of the Town of Princeton Ky that he has been well and intimately acquainted with B. T. Gray <hi rend="str">fr</hi>since his infancy until up to the time of his engaging in the Rebellion that his deportment was good his family large and Respectable That he was induced &amp; influenced to Join the Rebel Army when in his (18) year and the forces under the Command of One Rebel Col Woodward Whose Command he Gray had Joined were as they represented ordered to procure from the stores of our Town Blankets &amp;c that he Gray was Sent in with the squad who pressed the Goods that he Gray did not directly or indirectly participate in the takeing the Goods but used all means in his power as a private to diswade ^(&amp; discourage)^ others from the taking of them, That ^the^ witnesses for the Commonwealth marked at the foot of the Indictment have ^all^ left the State that on a live bill one Joseph Garrett &amp; he Says he knows nothing of either Gray or Charles Hooper of his own knowledge having participated in the taking of the Goods<pb/>
<lb/>This affiant States further that Young Gray Served (12) months in the Rebel army and went in and surrendered himself to the Federal authorities at Knoxville Tenessee some (15) or (18) months since and a very short time after Joined one of the Indiana Cavelry Regiments, &amp; has been with the Regiment ever since was in the Battle in front of Nashville Ten under Command of Gen Thomas and is now or when last herd with the Gen<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Command, This affiant states that Charl. Hooper was a peacible and quiet boy when he enlisted in the Rebel Cause and left then and Repented himself at Louisville &amp; took the oath, and has Conducted himself well as I am informed Since that time, and affiant believes if the two young men Gray &amp; Hooper Could be Releived from the The pending Indictments they would make &amp; become good and permanent citizens when ^if ever^ he Gray <hi rend="str">if</hi> should <hi rend="str">ever</hi> live to return home</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J. N. Turner</hi></p>
<p>Subscribed &amp; Sworn to before me by J. N. Turner this <date when="1865-05-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of May 1865"</date></p>
<p>J. C. Barnes clk c c c<pb/></p>
<p>J. N. Turner
<lb/>Affidavit</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
