<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0390"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Samuel Berry et al. to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8842</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-129 to R4-130</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Greenup County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To the Honorable James F. Robinson.
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Greenupsburgh and Greenup County, would respectfully represent unto your Excellency that at the present <date when="--05">May</date> Term of the Greenup Circuit Court, Alexander ^Hauner^ was tried &amp; found guilty of a breach of his tavern keeper's bond, and adjudgement under the statute rendered against him. Mr Hauner is a peaceable, quiet citizen, of respectable standing, orderly and law abiding, &amp; would be as far from violating any law wilfully as any man, The sentence against him, was of a conflicting character; some witnesses testified in the case had stopped at his tavern for a year or more and had never seen any disorder, or drinking more than was necessary, others who resided in his neighborhood had heard on some occasions boisterous &amp; profane language, &amp; had seen drunken men in front of his house, but did not know where they got the liquor which intoxicated them, and all agreed that Mr Hauner tried to keep a good order, The greatest complaint seemed to be at the time &amp; some recruiting stations were opened in Greenupsburgh when the whole tavern over filled with drunken men, and a grand Saturnalia was held; and no power could have kept order &amp; quiet <pb/>
<lb/>Mr Hauner's tavern was in view of the most public places in the Town, and when the people were in the habit of congregating in great numbers, and when from the situation of the house, the most noise would be made -- from those who had become intoxicated at other public houses, Under all the circumstances we do think this presents a fair case for the interposition of Executive clemency, as the amount of costs, and the Commonwealth's attorney portion of the fine, will be a severe punishment to Mr Hauner, who is a hard working, industrious man, We therefore hope your Excellency will relieve Mr Hauner from the payment of this Exceedingly heavy &amp; oppressive fine and as is duty will ever pray</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Samuel Berry
<lb/>Samuel B. Valane
<lb/>Jesse Corum
<lb/>Junes Sutherland
<lb/>Lexius Ripple
<lb/>H J M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Allester
<lb/>Joseph Ricey
<lb/>G. W Brodshow
<lb/>Joseph Gray
<lb/>Jacob Barney
<lb/>William Hornluckel
<lb/>C A Jossling
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Geo W Childersen
<lb/>C T. Kehoe
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Z Richards</hi>
<lb/>John Mcalcaistear
<lb/>John Thomas
<lb/>Harvey Vallance
<lb/>Jesse Davidson }
<lb/>James Anderson } of the Jury
<lb/>William Smith
<lb/>Nathan Mefford
<lb/>C Hunt
<lb/>Q Smith one of the Jury<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>J, K, Poynter
<lb/>B. B. Nichols
<lb/>Richard Littence
<lb/>B,, B,, Roberts
<lb/>George Dorch
<lb/>Henry Harwilk
<lb/>Allen Myers
<lb/>Elisha Ferguson
<lb/>Savel Montgomery
<lb/>Manuel Patrick
<lb/>John R Tanner
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> G Woodrow
<lb/>Jacob Howe
<lb/>James M Craycraft
<lb/>John G Stewart one of the Jury
<lb/>Martin Morris
<lb/>M L Thompson
<lb/>Alex Green
<lb/>John Breedbowen
<lb/>Edward Bush
<lb/>W A Womack
<lb/>D. C. Callihan one of the Jury
<lb/>Hiram Kiser
<lb/>R Galbreath
<lb/>James Worthington
<lb/>A J Rasor
<lb/>S. Reed
<lb/>William Web
<lb/>J, M, Robb
<lb/>Harrison Hern
<lb/>H C Tufts
<lb/>A. S. Rind
<lb/>Samuel Paull one of the Jury
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H Dougherty
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Ed F Dulin</p>
<p>L. B. Hornluckle
<lb/>J N Lysard
<lb/>Jas F Richards } of the of this Jury<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Greenup Cir. Ct.
<lb/>Pettn to remit fine agst Alex. Hauer of Greenupsburg
<lb/>$ } Forfeiture Tav. Bond
<lb/>Fine in this case remitted
<lb/>J F Robinson
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-05-30">May 30. 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
