<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2227"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Micager Bottom et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6864</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-43 to BR15-44</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>Thomas. E. Bramlette
<lb/>Govener of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioners Citizens of Adair, Taylor &amp; Marion Counties, would respectfully represent to your Excellency, that Milton. B. Cox was convicted at the <date when="1865-06">June called term of the Adair Circuit Court, 1865</date>, for the robbing of George. W. Walkins a Citizen of Adair County, and sentenced to the penitentiary for five years, in pursuance to the finding of the jury in the case,</p>
<p>Your petitioners state that they do not believe that said Cox, had a fair and impartial trial, on account of the feeling excitement and prejudice against him, they state said Cox proved upon Trial by three reliable, and unimpeached witnesses that said Cox was not within twenty three miles of the house of said Walker <hi rend="str">watkins</hi>, when the robbery was proven to have been committed, it was also<pb/>
<lb/>proven by three creditable unimpeached witnesses, Walker said on the next day after seeing said Cox, that he was not the man that robbed him, Therefore the state believes that the finding of the Jury and judgment of the Court was against the evidence in the case, They therefore pray your Excellency to pardon said Cox &amp; release him from his confinement</p>
<p>MiCager Bottom
<lb/>G L Eades
<lb/>J T Bottom
<lb/>Armsted Shelf
<lb/>Dr Jonathan ,R, Huff
<lb/>Samuel W Harden
<lb/>Milton Weatherford
<lb/>Lewis M Christie
<lb/>Harry Dunn
<lb/>James W Hardwick
<lb/>Curtis Lard
<lb/>Isaac R Ford
<lb/>J W M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Whorter Lieut
<lb/>John S Cozine Capt<pb/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Pardon</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
