<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3325"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas H. Ferguson and J. M. Rice to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5444</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-161</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Guyandotte, Cabell County, West Virginia</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner, of Guiandott West, Va, States, in the <date when="1864">fall of 1864</date> he was in the town of Ironton Ohio, and and got on Board the steamer Telegraph to go home, he says before he left Ironton; with his friends he indulged in too freely Drinking, he states that he has no recollection of what took place on the, boat; only as he has since learned, by what is told him; he knows that he is indicted, in the boyd circuit court, for Larceny, in stealing the carpet, sack and overcoat of John M. Burns; and when he learned the indictment was against him, he voluntarily came from Va to the county of Boyd and gave, a recognizance, to appear, and answer said charge he states, that the courts in Boyd Kentucky, and Wayne County, Va, con<pb/>
<lb/>flict, and he will have to incur great Loss, if compilled to attend the Boyd Court, owing to the Loss of practice, in the Wayne court, at the approaching term; feeling innocent of the crime imputed to him, and not being able to loose the practice of the Wayne approaching court; is the reason why; he asks your excellency's interference and clemency, he asks for a pardon.</p>
<p>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H. Ferguson</p>
<p>I did not see, the petitioner on the trip he made on the steamer, but from conversing with men who saw, him, I am satisfied, that, he was, intoxicating and so beleiving, I hope you will favorably act in his case.</p>
<p>J. M. Rice</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
