<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1252"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Nancy Woodward to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10720</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-120 to MG21-121</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-07-17">17 July 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky Your Petitioner Nancy Woodware would state that at the last <date when="1861-05">May</date> term of the Marion Circuit Court Ky She by the judgement of said Court was ordered to be imprisoned in the County jail of Marion County for thirty days and fined the sum of one hundred dollars under the alledged charge of keeping a Bawdy house. Now Your Petitioner would state that she is a widowed woman agaed about 60 years and very poor and not by any means stout and she cannot pay the fine nor has she friends that will pay it for her and if imprissioned would certainly produce her death and would further state that the charge made against her is not true says she does not nor never has kept a Bawdy house tho with shame and mortification she admists that her two daughters are not as discreet and prudent as she would wish them tho by no means does this conduct justify the charge of a Bawdy house and if she could have been present at the trial she could have presented a judgement the same having been procured by her default and she was not present having mistaken the day of trial<pb/>
<lb/>and having no friends she cannot give security and therefore cannot appeal if that could do her any good so that unless Your Excellency interpose &amp; remit the fine and imprissonment she will be imprissioned for thirty days and then imprissoned until death to pay the fine as she cannot do it and she has no friends able &amp; willing and therefore she is compelled to perpetual imprissionment upon a charge unfounded &amp; that could not have been substantiated Therefore Your Excellency is most earnestly invoked to interpose and relieve Your Petitioner</p>
<p>Nancy ^her X mark^ Woodward</p>
<p>Nancy Woodward says she believes the statements made in the foregoing petition are true</p>
<p>Nancy ^her X mark^ Woodward</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Nancy Woodward <date when="1861-07-17">July 17<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>H. H. Goode J. P. M. C</p>
<p>We join in the foregoing petition &amp; pray your Excellency to remit the fine &amp; pardon the alledged offence_</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>B Spalding
<lb/>J G Phillips Jr
<lb/>H. Johnston
<lb/>Felix Smith
<lb/>N. J. Ray
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John F Wills
<lb/>N P Berry
<lb/>J. R. Thomas
<lb/>H. T. Jackson S M C
<lb/>T. H. Chandler C. S.
<lb/>D. W. Phillips,<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>John Shuck
<lb/>Thos C Woods
<lb/>H. W. Purdy
<lb/>A Corley
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Savage
<lb/><hi rend="underline">F. B. Merimee</hi>
<lb/>J. C. Maxwell
<lb/>A. J Jenkins
<lb/>Jas H Miller
<lb/>W. C. Jasboe
<lb/>J B Wather
<lb/>Wm Bigger
<lb/><cb n="2"/>H H Clark
<lb/>John Yocom
<lb/>JaS S Gaither
<lb/>L. H. Noble
<lb/>D. W. Karne
<lb/>A. P. Smith
<lb/>John H. Tucker
<lb/>N. M. A. Withrow
<lb/>James Crowders
<lb/>Q. M. Chandler
<lb/>James M Fogle
<lb/>R. H. Rountree<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Respite 12 Mo
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Is<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1861-07-30">July 30</date></p>
<p>Marion Cir. Ct
<lb/>$100 &amp; 30 day Imprisonment
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Nancy Woodward</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
