<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0739"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James Harris to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10207</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-151 to MG19-152</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-03-27">27 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>Beriah Magoffin Governor State of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioners, respectfully state that on the <date when="1861-03-26">26<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of March 1861</date>, at the <date when="--03">March term</date> of the Ballard Circuit Court. Henry Call was convicted for having stabed a man by the name of Durham in this county, Call is a weak lame man &amp; he Durham &amp; <hi rend="str">that has witnesses that testified in the case</hi> Call were intoxicated somewhat but not ^to^ say drunk, Durham having give Call the darn lies he in a passion stuck his pen knife in Durhams arm. The wound was very slight &amp; within a very short time Durham was entirely well Your Petitioners consisting principally of Grand Jurry &amp; Pettit Juryman that found both Indictments &amp; verdict say that according to the Law &amp; Evidence Calls case &amp; in consequence of the sanction of their Oath. They were compelled to find him guilty. But they think that if ever there was a pardoning act that came within your power his case is one, Accompanying this Petition you here will find a Letter from James M. Ogden of this county who claims to be a personal acquaintance of you honor &amp; has been acquainted with Call for several years &amp; will write you to Knowled he has of Calls general Character</p>
<p>James Harris
<lb/><date when="1861-03-27">March 27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J M Ogden <unclear/>
<lb/>John Pennebaker
<lb/>John L Smedley
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Rudd
<lb/>D. H. Buskaye
<lb/>L. R. Ritch</p>
<p>C Whinthicum clk of the Grand Jury together with the members
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John Armistead
<lb/>H. F Jennings
<lb/>A. Hogancamp
<lb/>John D Mason
<lb/>E Hogancamp
<lb/>W R Becaes
<lb/>Augustin Woolford<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>C. S. Marshall Atty at Law
<lb/>members of the Petit Jury that tried Calls case
<lb/>1 J C Depoyster Forman
<lb/>2 John Alexander
<lb/>3 L. Hilton
<lb/>4 Noah Turk
<lb/>5 Henry <unclear/>
<lb/>6 W C Hendricks I Agreed to the Virdict with great reluctance
<lb/><hi rend="str">The Virdict w</hi>
<lb/>7 Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> A Pease
<lb/>8 S. <unclear/>
<lb/>9 C N. B. Ralling
<lb/>10 Uriah Flarper
<lb/>11 george.W. Stovall
<lb/>12 James McGanly<pb/>
<lb/>Blandville <date when="1861-03-27">March the 27<hi rend="sup">th</hi>/61</date></p>
<p>Dear g.o.v this is to invite Your attention to the case of Henry Call whoo has been convicted one Year to the pententiary at this term of the Ballard Circuit Court &amp;c now dear g.o.v permit me to say that I have known Call for some 9 years and it was truly with surprise that I heard of his difficulty for I was satisfied that he Call was since and inoffensive would not become a child &amp; c. he is also a cripple with a perished leg &amp;c- also a member of the baptist chruch and an ungarded moment drank drank too mutch all of whitch could excite Your clemency would verry mutch comport with the Judgment and wishes of Your humble servent and friend &amp;</p>
<p>J M Ogden<pb/>
<lb/>Persons present at Calls trial.
<lb/>William T Hay
<lb/>P H Keen
<lb/>G. H Pollock
<lb/>D M Johnson
<lb/>Lafayett Rich
<lb/>Adain Coil</p>
<p>Call's case
<lb/>Ballard Co Penty</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
