<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2376"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. W. Haybrook et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9452</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG25-163</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin Governor of the state of Kentucky this Petition sheweth that at the Present Term of the Davies Circuit Court W. T. Hawkins was convicted of the offense of Carrying concealed Weapons ^and fined $50^ -- The proof on the trial of the case was that the said Hawkins had become engaged in a quarrel with several parties one of whom called him a thief and used others taunting words and also threatened the said Hawkins that he would whip him or mash him up if he would leave the town -- After these threats Hawkins was advised by several of his friends to arm himself, which he did and the parties meeting the same evening on the Road in the country and be coming engaged in a difficulty Hawkins exhibited the weapon, but did not use it -- No person was hurt &amp; the proof did not show that Hawkins had ever before or afterwards carried concealed Weapons. Hawkins is a small man and the party who threatened him was a large, stout, determined man, and fully able to carry his threat into effect and could have inflicted great bodily<pb/>
<lb/>harm upon Hawkins in an ordinary fist fight. Your Petitioners would respectfully urge that this is a case for the interposition of Executive Clemency -- Hawkins is a young man of sober habits and industrious -- We pray your Excellency to remit the fine save costs &amp;c</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>R W Haybrook
<lb/>Jno. J. Daviess
<lb/>A M Hathaway
<lb/>James M. Hughes
<lb/>James M. Cox
<lb/>C R Moorman
<lb/>James Stuart
<lb/>Circuit Judge
<lb/>W. B Wall
<lb/>Jno P. Thompson C D C C
<lb/>Douglass McCoy
<lb/><hi rend="str">Hugh</hi>P T Watkins.
<lb/>Clinton M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clarty
<lb/>W A Sweeney
<lb/>John D. Green
<lb/>G, W, Ray
<lb/>Jas R S<unclear/>man
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John
<lb/>John Getty <unclear/>
<lb/>W W Shoemaker
<lb/>Tom Morland D C
<lb/>A F Bayely
<lb/>R. Hawes Taylor
<lb/>David Webb M D
<lb/>James, W, Gregory..Police
<lb/>J R Allen
<lb/>W. B Pegram
<lb/>John Locke S. D. C
<lb/>M. L. Ogden Clk D. C. C.
<lb/>Tapley Maddox
<lb/>F L Hall
<lb/>Jno H M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Henry Jr
<lb/>J, R, Claybrook</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
