<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1587"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Azro Dyer et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11055</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-227 to MG22-228</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Calhoun, McLean County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-11-22">22 November 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Calhoon Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1861-11-22">22nd November 1861</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency Gov Magoffin
<lb/>Frankfort Ky.
<lb/>Dear Sir,</p>
<p>There is a case on the docket of our M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Lean Circuit Court to which I ask your attention for a few moment. It is <hi rend="str">the</hi> a case of Commonwealth against John Baggett for murder. An Indictment was found against him at the <date when="1858-09">September Term of M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Lean Circuit Court in 1858.</date> He was admitted to Bail by the circuit Court for 3 thousand dollars. He made his appearance at the <date when="1859-03">March Term following</date> but the case was continued by the Commonwealth, again at the <date when="--09">september</date> Term &amp; at the <date when="--03">march</date> Term the same order was made, the Deft urging a trial, but the Commonwealth continuing At the <date when="1860-09">September Term 1860</date> a trial was had and the Jury hung all of the Jury except two in favor of acquittal.</p>
<p>The Deft again renewed his Bail Bond for his appearance at the March Term. Soon afterwards Deft moved to Butler County Missouri but returned here ^in march^ for the sole purpose of meeting his trial. He urged a trial but the case was again continued by the Commonwealth, and Deft again renewed his Bond to reappear at <date when="--09">September</date> Term</p>
<p>At this Term he failed to make his appearance owing no doubt to the difficulty<pb/>
<lb/>if not impossibility of travelling from Missouri. If he ha<hi rend="str">s</hi>d joined the army as his friends suppose -- it would not only have<hi rend="str">be</hi> ^been^ difficult for him to leave that, but it would have been dangerous and unsafe for him to have come to so <hi rend="underline">loyal</hi> a County as this. But <hi rend="str">of</hi> with the peculiar state of things now surrounding us your Excellency is familiar.</p>
<p>At the calling of the case <hi rend="str">in</hi>at the <date when="--09">September</date> the Bail Bond was forfeited and summons ordered against the surities &amp;c.</p>
<p>At March Term a Judgment will be rendered against them unless Your Excellency will remit the forfeiture. It seems to me that it is a case well worthy to Executive clemency. The Bail who are the Brothers and Father of the Defendant are William Baggett, Etheldred Baggett Sr and Etheldred Baggertt Jr.</p>
<p>They are poor men and a Judgment for the amount would ruin them.</p>
<p>They have not heard a word from defendant since <date when="--08">August</date> at which time he wrote that he would if living be present at Court, but owing to the condition of the Country every thing was uncertain.</p>
<p>Of the cause of his absence his sureties know nothing, It may be the proclamation of President Davis forbidding communication, it may be military law, it may be death. We have had no mails from that quarter. And even now his Bail<pb/>
<lb/>would start at once in search of him, but on their return they would be subject to the charge of "aiding the <hi rend="str">E</hi> Rebellion".</p>
<p>Of one thing I am convinced that he <hi rend="str">is</hi>was not absent of his free will for he has always been ready and anxious to try and on a former occasion came the whole distance for no other purpose than to dispose of this case.</p>
<p>Hoping that you will think proper to remit the forfeiture -- I remain </p>
<p>Your Respectfully
<lb/>Azro Dyer.</p>
<p>I am familiar with the facts of the case refered to above, and am satisfied that the case is worthy of your Executive clemency</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J. W. Bickers</hi></p>
<p>P. S. Your Excellency will please direct your letter to Alf C. Tanner clk of M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Lean Circuit Court -- at Calhoon Ky</p>
<p> -- A. D.<pb/></p>
<p>McLean Cir. Ct
<lb/>$3000. } Forfeiture
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Baggett &amp; others
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi>. <date when="1861-12-18">Decr. 18. 1861</date></p>
<p><hi rend="str">Issue</hi> Remitted 
<lb/>B. M.<pb/></p>
<p>Resin Price. fined justly. Foreman Maysville</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
