<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1459"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John W. Crockett to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10927</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-30 to MG22-31</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency 
<lb/>B Magoffin
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>Mr A H Talbott was fined at the last June term, of the Henderson Circuit fifty dollars, for selling whiskey to a slave. The proof in the case was in substance as follows Mr Talbott is a dealer in groceries of all discriptions, There was considerable excitement in the county at the time from apprehension of negro insurrection, in consequence of which there was a strong night police, a little after day light two negro<hi rend="sup">s</hi> were discovered standing not far from Mr Talbotts front door by the deputy marshall. Mr Talbott's house is on a corner, and the negroes broke as soon as they saw the deputy Marshall, one of them passing through<hi rend="str">t</hi> Talbotts house and leaving at the back door, The Marshall pursued caught the negro &amp; found upon ^one^ a bottle of Whisky, There <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>are ^on^ the square with Talbot several other grocery establishments all dealing in whisky --.</p>
<p>Mr Talbott is a highly respected<pb/>
<lb/>citizen and as far from violations of law as any in our community</p>
<p>For his standing and character we refer you to Grant Green &amp; Judge Young -- I do not believe he was guilty, but upon the proof he was so found, but as I believe because of an universal feeling in thir community against the offense, It is but due to candour that I should say to you I was of course for Mr T. but I am ^not^ influenced in the least by that fact in thus writing to you</p>
<p>I honestly believe he was innocent &amp; therefore ask a remmission</p>
<p>Yours Truly
<lb/>Jno W Crockett</p>
<p>I ask your Excellency to regard &amp; treat the above letter as my petition to have the fine referred to remitted, assuring your Excellency of my innocence</p>
<p>A. H. Talbott<pb/></p>
<p>Henderson Cir. Ct
<lb/>$50 } liquor to a slave
<lb/>A. H. Talbott
<lb/>Iss. <date when="1861-10-10">Octo 10. 1861</date></p>
<p><hi rend="str">Refer to Judge Young</hi></p>
<p>Remitted B. M.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
