<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0546"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John W. Brookover to Richard Brookover</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4665</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-363 to BR9-364</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Pine Bluff, Jefferson County, Arkansas</placeName>
    <date when="1864-05-28">28 May 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Pine Bluff, Ark. <date when="1864-05-28">May 28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Dear Father</p>
<p>I have waited So long with Sad disappointment in not receiving any letter from any of you that I have concluded to write myself and wait no longer. The last letter I wrote was to Margaret, but have had no answer. My health is much improved Since I last wrote to you I have been out of the Hospital now for nearly four weeks. The Doctors though have refused to let me do duty, yet I am feeling quite well but Still rather weak to do much. I hope that these few lines may find you, and mother and the Rest of My Relatives well. My term of Service is growing Short I have two months, and twelve days to Serve yet. I had hoped that by the time that I got out of the Service that matters would have been arranged So that I could have come home to see you<pb/>
<lb/>without incuring any risk to myself and others. As great as my anxiety is to see you, and my old mother I Still feel Loth to come; without I could do so in a manner agreeable to my feelings But to come in the way my affairs are Situated there Seems to me that Such a visit would render but Little Satisfaction either to you or me. I have Strugled hard and long for the last three years in this Service hoping that I could come home, and See you at least once more before I die; as undutiful as I may have been toward you, you do not and cannot know ^how^ my heart yearns to see my parents once again life, and to visit the home of my childhood.</p>
<p>But the question is with me can I come or Shall I linger out my life among Strangers; Such Seems to be my destiny. I want you to write, and Say what I shall do. I will await with Patience until I hear from you. I do not ever expect to become great but as Little as I feel I would be glad to see you.<pb/></p>
<p>If my health would permit it, I would Remain in the Service, but I am afraid I am not able to Stand another campaign. I could now get the Position that I would have had long ago if my captain had not been killed. I could get a Lieutenants position, but in excepting it, I am tied to the Service three years, So under the circumstances I feel rather indisposed to accept a position that would in all Probability end my life. I think there is a Strong probability That this army will move Soon We have received at Little Rock about eighteen thousand reinforcements If a movement is made I think our Regiment will go with the expedition as our cavalry forces are very Scarce in this department. While the Rebel cavalry is pretty Strong. If our Regt goes I expect to go with it, If I feel as well, as I do now. We have had Some pretty hard fighting in this department but you have Seen the accounts in the papers no doubt.<pb/></p>
<p>I will close by asking you to write Soon give my love to all</p>
<p>I Remain your dutiful Son
<lb/>John. W. Brookover</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
