<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1534"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. L. Simmons et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11002</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-138 to MG22-139</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Grant County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency. The Governor of the commonwealth of Kentucky The undersigned would most respectfully represent and State to your Excellency that at the <date when="1859-05">May term 1859</date> of the Grant circuit court a judgement was rendered in favor of the Commonwealth V<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> John D Duncan &amp; William Duncan on a Recognisance Bond for the appearance of Isaac Duncan their Brother who was charged with Stealing a small quantity of Bacon -- They would further state that William Duncan has no property and can in no way assisting in satisfying the aforesaid judgment and that to require John D Duncan to pay said judgement would take all the property in his possession and would leave himself and family in destitute circumstances John D Duncan is living upon rented land The say that if there ever was a case which commended itself to Executive Clemency this is one which in an eminent degree deserves the favorable consideration of his excellency -- The said judgement was for the sum of $250<hi rend="sup">00/100</hi> They have no hesitancy in Saying that if your Excellency will remit so much of said judgement as in Your power to do that it would approved by all good men who know the circumstances -- </p>
<p>W. L. Simmons
<lb/>T. M Combs Deputy Sheriff
<lb/>T Stroud J G C
<lb/>W Smith Clk G c ct
<lb/>H Hall P J G C C
<lb/>O. D. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>manama atto for Grant County
<lb/>E T Nuttall Judge
<lb/>P. U. Major Comth Atty<pb/></p>
<p>Grant Cir. Ct
<lb/>Petition for John D Duncan from Garret County<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M. </p>
<p>$200 } Recog
<lb/>Jno. D &amp; W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Duncan
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-11-02">Nov 2. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
