<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0186"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">C. D. Baker to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9654</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-126 to MG17-127</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Trigg County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-11-27">27 November 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Govenor of Kenty</p>
<p>Your Petitioner C D Baker, would respectfully state, that at the last <date when="--08">August term</date> of the Trigg Circuit Court, there were two Indictments found against him; copies of each are hereto appended. -- He will now state that he is a very young man, with but little means -- and that up to the time of the occurrences charged in Said Indictments, his character had been good and that this was his first violation of the laws. -- He now most Solemnly avows, that he had been <hi rend="str">an be</hi> drinking for several days and at the time he is charged with having stabbed James Buckner and with having made an assault upon Laura Baker, his mind was so much under the influence of and besotted with Strong drink, that he was unconscious of what he was doing. -- He and James Buckner the young man he is charged with stabbing had known each other for years, had been up to the day the offence is charged, intimate and warm friends and have so continued ever Since -- He did not<pb/>
<lb/>injure either of the parties, The wound inflicted upon Buckner was a mere Scratch, did not cause him to suspend his business atall. -- He now Solemnly avers that he had no malice toward either one of them and but for the madness produced by whiskey, No inducement could have caused him to have offered either one of them violence or to have injured a hair of their heads. -- These occurrences all took place in the town of Cadiz where your Petitioner has been raised and by reference to the petition Sent herewith you will find that James Buckner's name is one of the first upon said petition. -- Your Petioner prays that under the circumstances, Your Excellency, will pardon him. and as in duty bound he will ever pray &amp;c &amp;c</p>
<p>C D Baker</p>
<p>Subscribed and Sworn to before my by C. D. Baker this <date when="1860-11-27">27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Novr 1860</date></p>
<p>Jno R Grace P. J. T Ct Ct<pb/></p>
<p>C. D. Bakers case
<lb/>Trigg co
<lb/>no Judgment</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
