<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0701"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. John Doyle, Warrant</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4820</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-73</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Harrison County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Harrison Circuit Court Sct</p>
<p>I certify that the following are copies of the warrant and bail bond. filed in the case of the Commonlth vs Jno Doyle for Petit. lately pending in said Court
<lb/>To wit</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Warrant</note> "The Commonwealth of Ky. To any Constable of Harrison County</p>
<p>It appearing that there are reasonable grounds for believing that John Doyle has committed a felony by stealing plank. This is therefore to command you to arrest the said J. Doyle and bring him forthwith before some Magistrate in your County to be dealt with according to law Given under my hand this <date when="1861-03-26">26<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of March 1861</date>.</p>
<p>W A Walker J. P."
<lb/>Endorsed</p>
<p>"Executed on Jno Doyle <date when="1861-03-27">March 27 1861</date> &amp; Set for trial at Leeslick same day before T J Furnish &amp; W A Walker. Esqrs</p>
<p>Thos B Arnett C H C"</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Bail Bond {</note> "John Doyle being in custody charged with the offence of petit larceny and being admitted to bail<pb/></p>
<p>in the sum of Fifty Dollars. Now we John Doyle and James Carrell of Harrison County Kentucky undertake that the above named Jno Doyle will appear in the Harrison Circuit Court on the first day of its <date when="--05">next May Term</date> to answer said charge and will at all times under himself amenable to the orders and process of said Court in the prosecution of said charge and if convicted will render himself in execution thereof, or if he shall fail to perform Either of these conditions, that we will pay the Commonwealth of Kentucky the sum of Fifty dollars</p>
<p>Witness our hands this <date when="1861-03-29">29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of March 1861</date>.</p>
<p>Jno ^his x mark^ Doyle</p>
<p>Test
<lb/>J R Curry</p>
<p>James Carrell Surety by W W Trimble atty in fact"</p>
<p>Attest J F Ware
<lb/><hi rend="underline">C. H. C.</hi> C</p>
<p>Commonlth
<lb/>vs } Copy Warrant &amp; Bond
<lb/>Jno Doyle</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
