<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1358"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. L. Martin et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5995</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-113 to BR12-114</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Gov Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Bramlette -- </p>
<p>Your petitioners represent that they were jurors in the case of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O001025">Commonwealth</orgName> against John Patterson tried at the <date when="1864-11">November Term 1864</date> of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000424">Mercer Circuit Court</orgName> on a charge of maliciously shooting &amp; wounding <persName ref="cwgk:N00002275">A G Kyle</persName> and as such under the instructions of the Court they gave &amp; rendered a verdict of guilty against the said Patterson &amp; affixed his punishment at confinement in the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000266">Penitentiary</orgName> at one year -- </p>
<p>They allege that three reputable witnesses (Towit) <persName ref="cwgk:N00002276">James Taylor</persName>, D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Wallace and <persName ref="cwgk:N00002281">Elijah Gabbert</persName> stated on the trial of said cause, that they saw the prisoner at the time the alleged shooting was done, and they each stated they believed and were satisfied that the prisoner had not shot A G Kyle, nor had the prisoner fired at the said Kyle, And the said Kyle testified on trial of said cause that no ill feeling or bad blood had ever existed so far as he had reason to know or beleive between himself &amp; the prisoner,</p>
<p>But as jurors in the said cause they state that they beleive the case presents strong reasons for Executive clemency and they therefore pray your Excellency to grant him a full pardon for the commission of the above offence and they will ever pray &amp; c<pb/></p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00002324">J L. Martin
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00002325">Jonas Robb</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00002319">A Q Sims</persName><lb/>J C M Daniel
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00002322">H W Mitchell</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00002326">Joseph yeast</persName><lb/>Dan<hi rend="sup">l</hi> F James
<lb/>George Raney
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00002323">J H Adams</persName><lb/>W B Semones
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00002320">Cornelius Donovan</persName></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
