<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1142"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James L. Henderson et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10610</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-286 to MG20-287</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Ballard County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-26">26 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Ballard County Ky <date when="1861-06-26">June 26th 61</date></p>
<p>To His Honor B Magoffin Govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky Your Petitioner James.L. Henderson would respectfully represent to your Excellency that at the Last <date when="1861-06">June</date> term of the Ballard Equity &amp; Criminal Court there was rendered a Judgment aganst this Petitioner in favor of the Commonwealth of Ky for one Hundred Dollars Your petitioner further states that he became the Bail of one <hi rend="str">John</hi> Henry Gambrell an and Indictment for <hi rend="str">keeping a tipling house</hi> Breach of the Peace that said Gambrell failed to appear as required by said Bond and consequently this petitioner became liable Now petitioner will state that he has used all the means in his power to compell the attendence of said Gambrell he states that said Gambrell has moved to the state of Missouri and as petitioner as since been informed died before the forfeiture ^of^ said Bond petitioner states that he is a very poor man not having the means to go after Gambrell and Bring him if he was Living that to course payment of the Judgement out of petitioner would be the means of Bringing petitioner and<pb/>
<lb/>Family to want petitioner states that he has a wife &amp; ten children all of which children are small and dependent upon petitioner <hi rend="str">of</hi> for a support petitioner states that to pay said debt would very nearly take all the Property owned by petitioner now your petitioner Prays your Excellency to remit said Judgement and he will Ever feel in duty Bond</p>
<p>James. L. Henderson</p>
<p>I concur in the above statement in prayer -- </p>
<p>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H Corbett</p>
<p>We the undersigned <hi rend="str">Petitioner</hi> Citizens of Ballard County concur in the above statement and recommend the Govenor to remit said Judgement</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>H T Ganass
<lb/>Thos Stralct
<lb/>N. R. Thomas
<lb/>Jacob Edwards
<lb/>W. H. Watson
<lb/>W. S. Watson
<lb/>W. H. Vaugh
<lb/>Noah Turk
<lb/>J Corbett
<lb/>C. S. Marshall
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J. D. White
<lb/>L. W. Weaver
<lb/>Henry Ellwid
<lb/>T. N. Luain
<lb/>S. B. Coil
<lb/>T. F Roberts
<lb/>T. F. Clardy
<lb/>D. P. Juett
<lb/>J. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Cauley
<lb/>J F Blake<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>C Belt
<lb/>Asa Richardson
<lb/>B H Howall
<lb/>E. B. Stuttan<pb/></p>
<p>Ballard Eq. Ct
<lb/>$100
<lb/>Jas. L. Henderson</p>
<p>Iss <date when="1861-07-18">July 18. 1861</date></p>
<p>Respite 12 Mo
<lb/>B. M</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
