<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0781"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Rodman et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4900</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-201 to BR10-202</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excelency B. Magoffin Governor of Kentucky-</p>
<p>Your petitioners the undersigned citizens of Grant county pray your Excellency to grant a pardon to E. T. Herndon who was convicted of having counterfeit money in his posession with intent to pass the same. at the <date when="1859-11">November term 1859</date> of the Grant Circuit Court and Sent to the Kentucky Penitentiary on two Indictments for the space of two years and four months on each indictment-</p>
<p>Signed-</p>
<p>I acted as Judge at the Court on Grant County at which E T Herndon was convicted as above stated and cheerfully sign this Petition</p>
<p>Jno Rodman
<lb/>W D Congers
<lb/>R Burnvows
<lb/>R. H. Lucas
<lb/>John James
<lb/>E. H. Conrad
<lb/>Thomas H Tandy
<lb/>William Vanlandingham
<lb/>Tilford Metcalf
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> S Dickerson
<lb/>John Baker</p>
<p>I defended Herndon- He was shown to have counterfeit money in his posession. There was no proof that he had passed any according<pb/>
<lb/>to my recollection</p>
<p>His family in this county are respectable people and Herndon at the time of his conviction was ^in^ very feeble ^health^ I do not know his state of health now</p>
<p>I believe he might be pardoned with out the law or public justice being at all violated</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Th N Lindsay</hi></p>
<p>One of the indictments on which Herndon was convicted was for having in his posession some fifteen hundred or two thousand dollars of counterfeit money. Knowing it to be counterfeit with the intent to pass it, to which he plead guilty, and the other was for passing one or two one dollars bills with the knowledge that they were counterfeit to which he likewise plead guilty. Herndon was raised in Franklin. I have known him since I was a child always liked him, and in view of those facts join in the prayer for his pardon-</p>
<p>P. U. Major Comths
<lb/>Atty, who prosecuted<pb/></p>
<p>This petition was presented to Gov Magoffin soon after Herndons conviction, but not acted upon. It is again presented with accompanying papers, under the hope that Herndon's good conduct while in prison, may <hi rend="str"><unclear/> a pardon</hi> authorize a pardon. He has but a few months to serve; and is anxious to be placed in a position where he can do better in future.</p>
<p>James Harlan Jr
<lb/>Petition for Pardon of E. T. Herndon</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
