<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0207"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. Lam et al. to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8659</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-314</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-02-06">6 February 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>Gov J. F. Robinson of Ky</p>
<p>Being well acquainted with A. K. Johnston for the last Eighteen months or more who was convicted at the last term of the Jefferson Circuit Court for Stealing, for the Term of one years</p>
<p>We the undersigned are perfectly Satisfied in our minds That he has been frequently not in his right mind and his conduct previous to that Act was uniformly that of a Gentleman and Honest man he lived and boarded with a portion of us during That time And from all we can or ever did learn he is of respectable parentage We Therefore Ask and pray your Excellancy will pardon him as you may not know the undersigned we refer you to the Signers below as to our Credibility and standing</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/><unclear>With to home in boarding</unclear>
<lb/><cb n="2"/>W. Lam
<lb/>Amanda T. Lynn
<lb/>Geo. E. Lynn
<lb/>M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> Mercy R. Shanks
<lb/>A. J. Ray
<lb/>C P Merriman
<lb/>C Duvall</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>I believe him not to be always in his right mind</p>
<p>D. M. Gazlay</p>
<p>John H. Merwin
<lb/>the prosecutor in the case</p>
<p>Subscribed and Sworn to before me, by W. Lynn, Amanda Lynn, Geo. S. Lynn, Mrs. M. R. Shanks A J Ray, D. M. Gazlay and C. F. Merwin &amp; C Duvall John H Herman, this <date when="1863-02-06">sixth day of February 1863</date>.</p>
<p>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Mitchelll J P J C<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned Jurors in the case of the Commonwealth against A. K. Johnston convicted of Felony at the last Term of ^the Jefferson Circut^ <hi rend="str">C</hi>. <hi rend="str">S</hi>. Court and sentenced to the Penitentiary for one year, do cheerfully recommend him to the clemency of the Governor for pardon</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">John H. Rosske</hi>
<lb/>M. S. Gross
<lb/>Henry Deppen
<lb/>William Talbut
<lb/>J Crabb
<lb/>Wm R Gray
<lb/>Geo M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kinney
<lb/>V, C, Kendall
<lb/><hi rend="underline">James Simmons</hi>
<lb/>A. J. Oldham</p>
<p>I, James P Chambers clerk of the Jefferson Circuit Court in the State of Ky, do certify that the above named Jurors, are the same who tried and convicted (in said Court at its <date when="1863-01">January term 1863</date>.) the above named A K Johnston, for one year</p>
<p>In testimony whereof I hereunto set my hand this <date when="1863-02-16">16<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of February 1863</date>.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">James P. Chambers</hi><pb/></p>
<p>State of Kentucky.
<lb/>Jefferson County. } Sct</p>
<p>This day personally appeared before me Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Mitchell, a Justice of the peace, for said county, Nathan, White <hi rend="str">Kennedy</hi> who being of lawful age, well known to me, and duly Sworn, Stated that he was well acquainted with the signers of the within petition, and to the best of his knowledge and belief, were persons in which every reliance might be placed on their veracety and intelligence.</p>
<p>Nathan White</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me, by Nathan White this <date when="1863-02-07">7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of February, 1863</date>.</p>
<p>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Mitchell J. P. J. C.</p>
<p>I have no hesitation in endorsing what M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Lynn &amp; others have sworn too in the above and would recommed the pardon of A. K. Johnston</p>
<p>Tho Reaugh
<lb/>day Watchman of the 4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ward of the City Louisville</p>
<p>I know many of these signers, and they are reliable men</p>
<p>J P Harney</p>
<p>We who sat on the Jury to try A K Johnston Recomend him to to your mercy for pardon -- <pb/></p>
<p>Pettn of A. R. John
<lb/>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>Pardon granted
<lb/><date when="1863-02-27">27 Feby 1863</date>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J F Robinson</hi>
<lb/>Is<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-02-27">Feby 27. 1863</date>
<lb/>Send to Hon J. H. Karm</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
