<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2795"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Moses Preston, Jr. and Frank K. Preston to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7432</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-60</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Paintsville, Johnson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-22">22 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Paintsville Ky, <date when="1865-12-22">December 22<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>To his Excelency
<lb/>Thos, E, Bramlett Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> of Ky
<lb/>Frankfort Ky</p>
<p>Dear, Sir the undersigned states that at the Present Term <hi rend="str">of</hi> <date when="1865-12">December 1865</date> of <hi rend="str">the</hi> Johnson Circuit Court was find One hundred and ten Dollars -- Sixty Dollars tipling &amp; fifty Dollars for Selling Liquor to <hi rend="underline">Minor</hi> -- they State that they Did not <hi rend="underline">Wantonly</hi> violate any Law -- as they have always been obedient to Law -- but that the offences occured -- During the Confusion in this county Growing out of the Rebellion -- when an absolute state of <hi rend="underline">anarchy</hi> existed -- And the Condition of the County was Such as to render it impossible to follow ordinary asocations of life ^in safety^ -- And they was often Compelled to let Soldiers have Spirits -- and of that, Laid in for family use -- and at other times -- Sold it when they Could not get Licins to sell on account of there being no Courts -- to grant Same -- They Present themselves for Executive Clemency -- and ask that the Said fines be Remitted -- They hereunto Present the statement<pb/>
<lb/>of the Commonwealths, atty -- who took the Judgment Against them who Recommends its remission</p>
<p>Moses Preston Jr
<lb/>Frank K. Preston</p>
<p>We, the undersigned Join in the above Petition -- </p>
<p>James E Stewart
<lb/>J C Castle
<lb/>A W Nickell
<lb/>E. H. Conly
<lb/>John Hawes
<lb/>Charles Q Hawes</p>
<p>Johnson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs,
<lb/>Mos F. Preston
<lb/>to } Petition to Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi>
<lb/>For Remit<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>2 Judgts tipling house
<lb/>$60 Keeping
<lb/>$50, Selling to Minor
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Remit</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
