<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0295"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">B. Grinstead et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4414</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-468</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1863-11-25">25 November 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>The Governor of Ky</p>
<p>Your petitioner who are all Loyal citizens of Kentucky and Warren County would respectfully represent to your Excellency that James Brown of This county was fined the Sum of Twenty five Dollars at the last <date when="--08">August term</date> of the Equity and criminal court for Warren county for Tipling or retailing Spiritous liquors We know Mr Brown is not in the true Sense of the term a tipler of Spirious liquors but was on this ocasion Induced to get a Jug of Whiskey and to carry it to a Sale by some friends</p>
<p>We further State Mr Brown to be a civil Steedy and industrious man of Good morral character but verry poor and has a wife and Seven children dependant on him for Support. Therfor we pray your interposition</p>
<p><date when="1863-11-25">Nov<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. 25" 1863</date> -- 
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>B. Grinsted
<lb/>Leonard Harris
<lb/>E. W. Grinsted
<lb/>Richard H Caplinger
<lb/>H Y Gardner
<lb/>Thomas S. Elrod
<lb/>B C Grubbs
<lb/><cb n="2"/>H Grider
<lb/>P W Potter
<lb/>Ivy Gardner
<lb/>Wm M Arnold<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Warren Equity &amp; Crim Court
<lb/>vs
<lb/>James Brown
<lb/>Tipling $20 -- 
<lb/><date when="1863-12-21">21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Dec/ 63</date></p>
<p>I cannot understand could he <unclear>assessed</unclear> The amt does not accord with any law upon the subject of tippling. -- </p>
<p>T. E. B</p>
<p>This fine according to law should have been $20 -- it is in excess all above that sum. Remit all except fees &amp; costs which will reduce the penalty to the legal amount or nearly so.</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
