<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0398"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. M. Samuels et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4517</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-128 to BR9-129</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>The Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>The undersigned, your petitioners, respectfully represent that at the <date when="1861-05">May term 1861</date> of the Hickman Equity &amp; Criminal Court the bond of R. W. Walker, J. W. Lockridge, W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Lindsay, John D. Harlan &amp; M. L. Stoner, for the appearance of John Sanders to answer a charge of larceny, was taken for forfeited; and at the <date when="1863-08">August term 1863</date> ^of the Hickman Circuit Court^ judgment on said forfeiture was taken against R. W. Walker &amp; M. L. Stoner jointly for the amount of said bond, viz: two hundred and fifty dollar -- the other obligor on the bond not having been served with summons in time for said <date when="--08">August term</date>. R. W. Walker &amp; M. L. Stoner will have to pay to the Commonwealth one hundred and seventy five dollars upon said judgment, (they having already paid to P. D. Yeiser the Commonwealth's Atty, seventy five dollars, his thirty per centum upon said judgment) unless releived by interposition of executive clemency.</p>
<p>Petitioners will now state that John Sanders was a boy of 14 or 15 years of age whose parents then and now are residents of East Tennessee, but<pb/>
<lb/>having friends and relatives at Clinton Hickman County Ky (a portion of whom are on the bond aforesaid) John, the boy, was left at Clinton to go to school. While at school he stole from a playmate an old silver watch and for this offense was by an examining court held to bail in the sum of $250 for his appearance at the Equity &amp; criminal Court. After giving the bond John remained at Clinton some weeks but being twitted and jeered by his playmates with theft he ran away and went home, as we presume. The boy's mother, M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> Sanders, informed her friends at Clinton before the theft occurred that John from early childhood had been afflicted with a monomania for stealing -- that he always readily gave up whatever he might take when called upon to do so and always seemed unable to comprehend the serious nature of his offenses. He was a liberal hearted and affectionate boy, with no unusual defect of character or dispotition save his innate and unconquaerable propensity to steal.</p>
<p>Before the <date when="1861-05">May term 1861</date> of the Hickman Equity &amp; Criminal Court, at which Sanders was to appear, the Great Rebellion which has afflicted our<pb/>
<lb/>County with so many evils broke out and up to the <date when="1863-08">August 1863</date> the obligors upon said bond have had no opportunity or chance to go to East Tennessee to compel the attendance of John Sanders. His parents, highly repectable people and good citizens have, as petitioners are informed, been broken up &amp; ruined, by the rebellion which has raged around their home in East Tennessee and will be ill able to reimburse those who have befriended their son to the amount of $250. Upon these facts &amp; representations your petitioners respectfully pray your Excellency to remit the one hundred and seventy five dollars due to the Commonwealth upon said judgment of the Hickman Circuit Court.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/> W M Samuels S H C
<lb/>Jos Kennedy
<lb/>A R Boon
<lb/>Thomas G Poore Clerk Hickman Cir Ct
<lb/>Geo B Moss
<lb/>H. C. Baker of Columbia Ky
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J. M. Bigger
<lb/>E. J Bullock
<lb/>A. S. Arnold
<lb/>Wiley C. Griffey
<lb/>W F Boon
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Hales
<lb/>W. White P. J. H. C. C.<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Hickman Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Walker &amp; Stoner
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/>$250
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1864-01-29">29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Jany/ 64</date></p>
<p>Petition of Stoner &amp; others<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
