<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1593"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Green Self et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11061</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-236 to MG22-237</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-12-04">4 December 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Beriah Magoffin Governor &amp;c</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Green Self respectfully States, That at the <date when="1861-05">May term 1861</date> of the Jefferson Circuit Court he bound himself as Recognisor, for the appearance of his Son Henry Self, at the next term of said Court to answer an indictment for Felony, Said Recognizance was in the Sum of $500,00 Said Henry made default and a Scire facias has been ordered against your Petitioner requiring him to Shew Cause why judgement Shall not be rendered against him for Said Sum All of which appears from a copy of the order of Said court which is Presented herewith, and judgement will be rendered against Petitioner for said Sum as he is also lately unable to Shew any<pb/>
<lb/>cause why it Should not</p>
<p>He States that in consequence of reverses in business, and the Suspension of trade he is utterly unable to pay said Sum, He has a wife and five Children who are entirely dependent on him for their daily bread and to exact the money or imprison him for its non Payment would result in nothing but the suffering of his family He therefore asks your Excellency to remit said forfeiture so far as he is concerned,</p>
<p>Green Self</p>
<p>Jefferson County Sct.</p>
<p>Subscribed &amp; sworn to by Green Self before me, this <date when="1861-12-04">4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Dec<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. 1861.</date></p>
<p>J. S. Dozier Examiner for Jefferson County, Ky.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>R H Rousseau</p>
<p>I ask that the prayer of the petititoner be granted</p>
<p>Hamilton Pope</p>
<p><cb n="2"/>I sincerely hope the prayer of the petitioner will be granted</p>
<p>P. B. Muir
<lb/>Geo. W. Johnston
<lb/>W. G. Reasor<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Henry Self and William Burn were arrested charged with stealing a small lot of cigars, and held to answer us above stated, His father &amp; mother became his <hi rend="str">bail</hi> suretys, Young Self joined a military company &amp; went in the Confederate Army -- Burns remained at home &amp; was tried and acquitted, or a nol pros entered in his case, The facts in his case were those attending Self's, His father &amp; mother are very poor, industrious people &amp; are unable to pay the amt of forfeited bond</p>
<p>W G Reasor
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Ro</hi>. F. <hi rend="underline">Baird</hi><pb/> </p>
<p>Jefferson Cir. Ct</p>
<p>Remitted 
<lb/>B. M.</p>
<p>$500. } Recog.
<lb/>Green and Susan Self
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-12-05">Dec<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. 5. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
