<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1417"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">L. O. Murray to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10885</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-378</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Brooksville, Bracken County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-09-02">2 September 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Brooksville Bracken Co Ky
<lb/>To his Excellency Governor B Magoffin</p>
<p>Your affiant L O Murray humbly praying would state, that at the February term of the Bracken Circuit Court, the Grand Jury of said County indicted him for Selling Spiritous liquors by the small for more than three months -- at the <date when="1861-08">August Term 1861</date> of said Court he was tried and it was proven by one witness that he had bought liquor of him by the Gallon and half gallon, but never in quantities less, that he had on two or three occations drunk some of the liquor so purchased while on the premises, but that said Murray had always, requested him not to drink any, while on or near his premises, and that he never drunk any there by the permission of said Murray, but when he did drink it was always against his will. The commonwealth introduced another witness who stated he lived very near your affiant, that he had bought liquor of him a few times, but never bought, it in less quantities than a half gallon, never saw him sell any by the small, he stated that he was very frequently at the house of affiants, and he recollected on one or two occasions, when he bought liquor he drew it himself, and had once or twice drunk from the measure before he poured it into his jug, he did not know whether Murray knew it or not, and did not think there any harm in it. </p>
<p>This was all the testimony that was introduced, and upon which the jury found a verdict of keeping a tippling house, and was fined by the court Sixty Dollars.</p>
<p>Your affiant would most respectfully state, that<pb/>
<lb/>he has never violated the law intentionally, that he has not made it a practice of selling liquor in any quantities, but happened to have some at the time the witnesses speak of, and let his neighbors have some, more as a matter of accom^m^odation than otherwise -- he would most humbly represent, that he is poor, that he has a large family, that are dependent upon his daily labor for their bread -- your affiant does not possibly see how he can pay said fine and provide his family with the necessaries of life -- if he has to lay in jail, it takes that much bread from his children, which must suffer for food, and the approaching inclemency of the coming winter: he is now about sixty years old, and has lived a quiet and peacable citizen, never having been indicted for any offense before. Your affiant would most respectfully and earnestly pray that your Excellency would interpose his clemency, and save him from the rigor of the law, and remit so far as in your power the fine thus imposed upon me. </p>
<p>L O Murray</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by L O Murray this <date when="1861-09-02">2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> day of September 1861.</date></p>
<p>C. H. Lee P J B C C</p>
<p>I would state that I was the lawyer that attended to the case for L O Murray, and believe the above facts are substantially true. Given under my hand this <date when="1861-09-02">2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> day of September 1861</date></p>
<p>C. H. Lee</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
