<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2945"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. H. Randall to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7582</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR43-15 to BR43-16</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Gov. Thomas E Bramlette
<lb/>Sir.</p>
<p>I feel that have not been troublesome in urging the pardon of persons charged or convicted of crimes or offences and hence I take the liberty of making the following Statement. Before commencement of the late rebellion, James Johnson was indicted in the Harlan Circuit Court, charged with maliciously Stabbing William Howard, during the war, business in the Court was pretty well suspended, and there was very little effort made for a trial, &amp; since the war the parties have not at any time been ready, for the last two terms the case has been continued, because of the abscence of Howard from the state, the witnesses for the defense live at a distance from the Court House &amp; it will be with great difficulty and expense that Johnson will be able to procure their attendance, if indeed he can procure them at all, he is a poor young man of peacable quit habits, and at the time of the difficulty he had reasons to believe, that his father was in danger of great bodily harm from Howard, he has since married and is making an industrious peacable Citizen.</p>
<p>Last fall before leaving home <hi rend="str">for</hi> <hi rend="str">washington</hi>, I drew up a petition for a pardon with the intention of presenting it to you in person as I came on to washington, the petition was numerously Signed by many of the best and most prominent Citizens of Harlan County who were acquainted with the parties and Cognizant of the facts, -- It had the approval of Judge Pearl who made and endorsement<pb/>
<lb/>expressing the hope that you would grant the pardon, by some casualty I lost the petition, and what I now ask is that you will accept this statement in lieu of it. The petition Substantially set forth the facts as stated in this, and was Sworn to by Johnson. It is an <hi rend="underline">old</hi> case, Howard recovered directly, and has been absent for the last two terms of the Court &amp; may not return</p>
<p>It will be too late after I return to get up another petition and have action on it before the next Term of the Court.</p>
<p>I hope therefore you will grant a pardon</p>
<p>Respectfully &amp;c
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W. H Randall</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Harlan Cir. Court
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Johnson</p>
<p>Refused</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
