<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1193"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John McCarthy to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5830</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-333 to BR11-335</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Carthy would respectfully state that on the <date when="1864-09-16">16th day of september</date> the wife of one John Rich caused him to be arrested on the alleged ground of intoxication &amp; abuse to her and had said John placed in the city watch house, that after said arrest was made -- (doubtless she felt sorry for having done so) that at hir insistance your petitioner was induced to did enter into a recognizance in the City Court of Louisville for the appearance of Said Rich on the <date when="1864-09-17">17th day of that month.</date> Rich instead of making his appearance without the knowledge or consent of your petitioner as he is informed hid himself or at any rate did not make his appearance at the calling of the case on said <date when="1864-09-17">17th day of Septr. 1864.</date> at the instance &amp; upon the motion of the City attorney a forfeiture of said recognizance was taken, upon which a sci fa issued against the parties the process was served on your petitioner and was set for trial on the <date when="1864-10-04">4th day of October</date> at the regular term of said court but was not reached for two or three days, upon the caling of the Case it was Submitted to a jury &amp; a verdict rendered against the party alone and when process was served to wit your petitioner<pb/>
<lb/>that he should pay the amount for which he was bound to wit one hundred dollars for which said sum of one hundred dollars &amp; costs judgment was rendered against your petitioner, upon which s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> judgment or verdict and execution will issue in a few days. Your petitioner further states that he is informed that said Rich after the recognizance aforesaid was forfeited went to his house &amp; took some of his clothes &amp; absented himself from home the night of the <date when="1864-08-17">17th of august 1864</date> &amp; left the city and the <date when="1864-08-18">next day sunday the 18th</date> for Cincinnati &amp; has not returned to Louisville, in fact your petitioner has neither seen nor heard any thing of S<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Rich except as stated as aforesaid. Your petitioner would respectfully state that in view of all the facts it would be very hard that he should have to pay s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> judgment. He therefore asks your Excellency to remit the same or so much thereof as in your judgment would be right and proper. And as in duty bound will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p>John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Carthy -- </p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Jefferson County } sec</p>
<p>Personally appeared before me the undersigned a Justice of the Peace in &amp; for the county aforesaid John Mc Carthy who^se^ <hi rend="str">being</hi> signature is affixed to the foregoing<pb/>
<lb/>and annexed petition &amp; made oath that the statements therein Contained are true</p>
<p>Jos,, Clement. Justice
<lb/>of the peace Jeff Co Ky.</p>
<p>To his Excellency the Governor of Ky</p>
<p>M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> Mary Rich states that she has read the petition of M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> John McCarthy that the statements therein contained are true so far as relates to the arrest of her husband Jno Rich, her inducing M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Carthy to en-<unclear/> a recognizance for the appearance of her <unclear/> th of <date when="1864-08">August 1864</date> before the <unclear/> also so far as relates <unclear/> having left the state of Ky <unclear/> husband deceived her as to where he was going when he got his clothes and did not for a moment suspect that he would stay away from home as he did on the night of the <date when="1864-09-17">17th of <hi rend="str">August</hi> september</date> &amp; leave her as he has done that he has abandoned her as she believes from the fact that she has neither seen nor heard of him since then except that he left on the Cincinnati boat on Sunday the <date when="1864-09-18">18th</date> she feels that she has gotten M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> John M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Carthy into a difficulty by inducing him to enter into the recognisance stated in his petition. She feels that she ought not to let him pay the amount of the judgment rendered against him, that her husband has left her without any means whatever<pb/>
<lb/>therefore your petitioner unites with Mr McCarthy in the prayer that your Excellency would remit the Same in as much as he may have (unless your Excellancy interposes) to pay that amount for an act of persuasion on her part and an act of kindness towards her &amp; her husband</p>
<p>Mary Rich</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Jefferson County } sec</p>
<p>Personally appeared before me the undersigned Mary Rich whose signature is annexed to the foregoing petition who states on oath that the statements therein contained are true</p>
<p>Jos,, Clement Justice of the peace Jeff Co, Ky<pb/></p>
<p>To his Excellancy the Governor of Ky</p>
<p>We the undersigned Citizens of Louisville state that we are personally acquainted with John Mc Carthy, that from our acquaintance with him that he is entitled to the relief he asks at the hand of your Excellancy &amp; that in view of all the facts in the case, we hope your Excellancy will give it a favorable consideration</p>
<p>Mrs Rich had a warrant issued against her Husband on which he was arrested &amp; placed in the watch House, soon after she came to me in Company with M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Carthy &amp; asked to have her Husband released. I told her he could only be released on giving a bond to appear the next day. She Said she did not Intend to prosecute the warrant against her Husband &amp; applyed to M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Carthy to become his Security He consented &amp; Executed the bond. The Husband failed to appear &amp; forfeiture was entered. I stated to the parties that not=<pb/>
<lb/>-withstanding the Expressed determination of the wife not to prosecute the case against her Husband. Yet it was necessary to appear. The Husband when he was released in a day or Two left his wife &amp; has Ever Since I believe been absent from the city. The wife did not appear to prosecute the case &amp; her warrant was dismissed. Under all the circumstances I think It would be proper to release Petitioner from the payment of the Commonwealths portion of the Judgment</p>
<p>Geo. W. Johnston J. C. C. L
<lb/>E, S, Craig
<lb/>Jos, Clement, J P.
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Mix.
<lb/>C. T. Taylor
<lb/>James W Osborne
<lb/>John M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Atear
<lb/>M OConnell
<lb/>John Doyle</p>
<p>Louisville City Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Carthy
<lb/>$100,
<lb/>Remit
<lb/><date when="1864-11-08">8th Nov/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
