<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2601"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Logan Coffey to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7238</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-158</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Russell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-10">10 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To Thomas E. Bramlette Esqr Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. Your petitioner Logan Coffey respectfully States that he was tried and fined before the County Judge of Russell county for a breach of the peace and was fined therefor $25. He states that the facts are these. One William Kimbler (while your petitioner was absent from his home) took occasion to slander and abuse your petitioner in an uncalled for manner, without any Cause or provocation and upon his return upon meeting said Kimbler and while in a passion he did give him a decent thrashing. after which he surrendered himself up to the civil authority. and was tried -- He states that after the above occurence and when he became <hi rend="str">Cool</hi> Cool he was satisfied that he had done wrong and this was the reason he so readily and voluntarily surrendered himself up to the county Judge -- The premises considered Your petitioner respectfully asks that said fine be remitted and as &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi></p>
<p>Logan Coffey</p>
<p>The petitioner Logan Coffey says he believes that the statements of the foregoing petition are true</p>
<p>Logan Coffey</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed by Logan Coffey before me this <date when="1865-10-10">10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day Oct. 1865</date></p>
<p>George Bryan Examr R C</p>
<p>We the undersigned residents of Russell County join in the prayer of the foregoing petition and we state that we are acquainted with the petitioner Logan Coffey -- that he is a quiet and peaceable citizen<pb/>
<lb/>in his neighbor hood</p>
<p>G W Twidwell
<lb/>N G Wells
<lb/>Lieut W H Walker
<lb/>W. T. Jackman S. R. C
<lb/>Abner Jones
<lb/>W Jones
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Lucy
<lb/>A, P, Simpson
<lb/>J. P. Satterfield
<lb/>R. H Walker
<lb/>John Johnson D S S R C
<lb/>Reuben Payne
<lb/>Jessee Lawless
<lb/>James M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kinney
<lb/>David Blankenship
<lb/>A, C, Wells
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> P. Payne
<lb/>G P <unclear/>
<lb/>F S Carter
<lb/>S P Collins
<lb/>Jas. L. Willoughby
<lb/>George Bryan</p>
<p>Russell County Judge
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Logan Coffey
<lb/>$25
<lb/>Breach Peace
<lb/><date when="1865-10-17">17 Oct 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
