<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2069"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Jacob Hauserman to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9145</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-99 to MG24-102</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency, Beriah Magoffin Governor of Kentucky:</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Jacob Hauserman respectfully &amp; humbly states that at the <date when="--05">May</date> Term of the criminal court of Jefferson county he was convicted of Grand Larceny and sentenced to two years imprisonment in the state Penitentiary. He is innocent of the crime for which he was tried, convicted and sentenced He never stole any thing in his life and has a sense of honor which renders him incapable of knowingly committing ^such^ a crime. He is now rappidly approaching Sixty years of age and during the almost three score years that he has lived in this country and his native Germany the crime for which he is now convicted is the only offense against the laws of any land with which he has ever been charged.</p>
<p>Your petitioner is a dyer by trade and is in the habit of searching over the city of Louisville for old pieces of iron from which to gather the rust to be used in coloring. In one of these searches he came across a lot of Jewelry ^on the bank of the River among some rubbish^ which to all appearances had been for some time lost. Being unacquainted with the laws and customs and even the language of this his adopted country he thought the articles found became his<pb/>
<lb/>by the finding and he therefore appropriated them to himself, for his poverty and many wants forbade him from doing otherwise than appropriate what he thought was his own by finding -- as much his own indeed by the act of finding as if he had acquired them by purchase.</p>
<p>It turned out however that the articles he found were stolen the store of a M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Robertson of Louisville had been entered &amp; robbed of the articles in question This robbery however was unknown to Your petitioner and had your petitioner <unclear/> dreamed that the articles in question were stolen he would have restored them to the owner or had nothing whatever to <unclear/> done with them</p>
<p>It is not the purpose of your petitioner to argue the question of his guilt or innocense &amp; as he cannot forbear stating that so soon as he found this Jewelry in question he ^took^ <hi rend="str">sent</hi> more of it to the auction room of C C. Spencer in this city to be sold; &amp; it was left with the auctioneer with the private marks of M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Robertson the owner upon cash article. If your petitioner had been guilty of the theft he would<pb/>
<lb/>certainly have erased these marks to present identification But feeling guilty of no wrong and suspecting nothing but his own good title to the articles found he sent them to the auction room as he found them for the purpose of turning them into money.</p>
<p>Your petitioner thus being found in possession of the stolen goods and having no testimony but his own as to the finding of them was charged, tried, convicted and sentenced as a felon. Not supposing that any harm would really come of the trial he took no steps to prove the good character which he feels entitled to state that he has always born both in this and his native country Your petitioner repeats that he is incapable of committing such a crime as that with which he has been charged and prays that your Excellency with that Mercy which often heals the wounds of the law's rigidity may pardon him and set him again at liberty. He has lived half a century in honor &amp; <hi rend="str">industry</hi> prays an opportunity to end his days not in a prison where he must be honest from necessity but at<pb/>
<lb/>liberty where he may be honest from the prompting of an honest heart.</p>
<p>Your petitioner appends hereto the the signatures of some of his countrymen who know him well and have well known him for many years and the signatures of some of his adopted countrymen who wish better of him than the felon's fate which has been assigned him. He <hi rend="str">Louisville Ky <unclear/></hi> ^also adds the signatures of as many of they Jury that^ convicted him as could conveniently be seen, Some of the Jury ^residing in the country and not^ <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> having been asked to sign this petition.</p>
<p>Jacob Hauserman</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Louisville respectfully state to His Excellency, Gov Magoffin that they are well acquainted with Jacob Hauserman whose petition appears preceeding this; that the said Hauserman is in their opinion an honest man in the strictest sense of the term and utterly incapable in their estimation of committing larceny of any thing. on the the property of any person; that they do not believe he stole the articles for which he has been convicted or had anything to do with the getting of them in any other way than that named in the<pb/>
<lb/>petition, which is that he found them on the river bank and took possession of them in the honest belief that they were his own by the finding. They state further that Hauserman is a man turned of fifty years whose long life up to this act has not the blemish of a charge of violated law. They think he is a fit subject for Executive Clemency and humbly join in the petitioner's prayer for a pardon.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/> Dr. T. K Shite
<lb/>B Waylon
<lb/>A M체ller
<lb/>Eng. <hi rend="underline">Michot</hi>
<lb/>Ls <hi rend="underline">Michot</hi>
<lb/>Albert Chryeler.
<lb/>B. Duer
<lb/>J. J Beserman
<lb/>F Holl
<lb/>Geo W Doam
<lb/>John L체tzelschwab
<lb/>Jos Rendhaar
<lb/>Henry Fink
<lb/>Sam<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Sulzer
<lb/>Joseph Rendhaar.
<lb/>Conrad Lealhz
<lb/>G Fred Deoky
<lb/>John G: <unclear/>
<lb/>John Lyan
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Vincent Fricker
<lb/>M Jeriel
<lb/>T. V Kermet
<lb/>J. Holzer
<lb/>G Aebly
<lb/>C Aebly
<lb/>Ch: May^un^flar
<lb/>T. W. Calenger
<lb/>J Aebly
<lb/>john Loran
<lb/>Anton Trauth
<lb/>John F Sch채fer
<lb/>Wm. Schafer
<lb/>Jacob Ruffra.
<lb/>A. Lehnder.
<lb/>Dom. Lehnder.
<lb/>John K채klin.
<lb/>T. Denzinger.
<lb/>A. Bissig.<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>A. Kamer.
<lb/>M. Miller
<lb/>Painter Kindast
<lb/>Sigment Schmirt
<lb/>Lhale William
<lb/>Anton <unclear/>
<lb/>David Blumer
<lb/>Conrad Haeberlin
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>Daniel. Arnold
<lb/>Samuel Rothenbuehler<pb/></p>
<p>C C. Spencer states that he has for many years been an auctioneer in Louisville, that he has had many dealings and business transactions with Jacob Hauserman the party named in the foregoing petition and allways found him straight and honest; that he was the auctioneer a when Hauserman brought the articles for sale which he was charged with stealing; that the <unclear/> marks of ^the owner^ the articles were upon them <hi rend="str">that transaction was <unclear/> <unclear/> <unclear/> for</hi>^so conspicously as to forbid the ideas of their having been stolen by Hauserman who would have erased the marks by which this could be identified if he had stolen them; that he his auction room is very near to^ the place of the theft; and that the whole manner conduct and bearing of Hauserman in relation to the articles stolen left no doubt upon his mind ^and there is no doubt in his mind now'^ that Hauserman came by them honestly or at least that Hauserman thought he got them honestly. He joins in the petition for a pardon and respectfully recommends Hauserman to His Excellency as a worthy recipient of executive clemency.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">C. C. Spencer</hi><pb/></p>
<p>The undersigned Jurymen who sat in the case of the commonwealth against Jacob Hauserman are of the opinion that Hauserman through ignorance of the law and not through crime became possessed of the articles for which he was convicted and <hi rend="str">we</hi> recommend him to <hi rend="str">the</hi> His Excelleny Governor Magoffin as a fitting subject for Executive Clemency &amp; pardon.</p>
<p>Thos. A. Crawford
<lb/>W. R. Coleman
<lb/>B. Miller
<lb/>Lewis Shafer
<lb/>A J Oldham
<lb/>T Enders</p>
<p>Jacob Hauserman
<lb/>To } Petition for Pardon
<lb/>Gov Magoffin</p>
<p>Pardon issued <date when="--07-03">July 3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi></date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
