<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1244"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Patrick Dalaney to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10712</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-104 to MG21-105</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-07-13">13 July 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville <date when="1861-07-13">July 3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>B. Magoffin</p>
<p>The undersigned states that at the <date when="1861-06">June Term 1861</date> of the City court of Louisville a fine of Fifty dollars was imposed on him for an alledged assault committed by him upon one Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Namara Now the true facts of the case these "He says at the trail it is charged that he committed the assault that the said Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Namara Met the undersigned in the City of Louisville and commenced abusing him in a verry violent manner useing evry abusive epithet towards the petitioner that it was possable for him to use, petitioner done all he could to avoid a difaculty with said Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Namara implored him to resist from his abusive language &amp;c and finally when the petitioner could not endure the abuse of said Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Namara any longer He did strike him twice, or thrice with his fist doing no injury whatever. Now your petitioner states that no man is more opposed to a violation of the law than he is<pb/>
<lb/>That he done all in his power for peace -- That he is a law abiding Citizen. That he is very poor with a large family to support by his daily labor and that because of the hard times caused by the political crises and other disarangements in afairs he canot procure work and has not the money to pay the afforesaid fine of Fifty dollars. He trusts in our of the afforsaid facts of the case that your Exclency will review the matter and futher prays Your Excelency will remit said fine of Fifty dollars -- </p>
<p>Patrick Dalaney<pb/></p>
<p>The undersigned Citizens of Louisville take pleasure in stating that they are acquainted with the within petitioner Pat Delaney that they know him to be a man of truth and a good law abiding citizen and from what they have learned of the facts of his case they beleive hi<hi rend="str">m</hi>s is a case that demands Executive clemency and they therefore unite with said petitioner in asking Your Exclency to remit the fine</p>
<p>Robt A Hamilton
<lb/>J W Allen D. C
<lb/>W C Price
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Shyrock
<lb/>Frank B. Jones D. M.
<lb/>H. S. Johnston D. M
<lb/>J M Rogers
<lb/>James W. Osborne
<lb/>Chas Duffield
<lb/>A. G. Schmidt
<lb/><hi rend="underline">A.</hi> <hi rend="underline">Bacon</hi>
<lb/>Geo Doyle
<lb/>Richard H Rudd
<lb/>J. C. Johnston M. D. 
<lb/>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> W. Barr</p>
<p>I cordially unite in the above petition, and I hope that your Excellency will grant the relief asked for</p>
<p>Nat Wolfe<pb/></p>
<p>Louisville City Ct
<lb/>Petition to Gov Magoffin
<lb/>in favor of Pat Delaney
<lb/>$50 } <hi rend="underline">assault</hi></p>
<p>Remitted B. M</p>
<p>Is<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-07-12">July 12. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
