<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-022-0040"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">H. G. V. Wintersmith to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11965</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>37th - 76th Regiments Enrolled Militia Primary Source Documents (1861-1866)</collection>
      <idno>Box 80, Folder 864 HARDIN COUNTY Correspondence - Drafted Men 49th Rgt. Ky. Militia</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Elizabethtown, Hardin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-10-24">24 October 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>ElizabethTown Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-10-24">Oct 24 1864.</date>
<lb/>Friend <unclear/></p>
<p>I write you to suggest to you the propriety and even necesssity of calling the attention of Gov Bramlette to the recent decision of Genl Fry. Pro Mar Genl U S requiring the Deficit for Draft Men who have Left the country or failed to Report to be made up out of The Names in the original <hi rend="str">Draft</hi> enrollment out of which the Draft was made.</p>
<p>Our citizens who have had a chance to be drafted reard this a violation of law and a great injustice to them the U S Law holds all Drafted men as in Service from the time of draft and publishes them as Deserters:</p>
<p>I wish you also to call attention of the Governor to recent order of<pb/>
<lb/>Gen Fry allowing to 2nd Cong Dist Ky credits for negroes who have been run off to other states and also credits for men conscriptied by the Rebels and request the Gen to procure an extension of the Same order to the whole state.</p>
<p>It is a matter of great Doubt with me whether the U S Army has gained by the Draft in our county so many have gone off probably to Southern army A farther Draft might have the the effect to fill the woods with guerillas.</p>
<p>Enquire How we can obtain Credits for our county for those who have enlisted in Indiana Regiments If it is necessary for me to come up to Frankfort in regard to these matters you can Telegraph me at my Expense. Tuesday Eving I will go to Louisville &amp; will be U S Hotel in next Wednesday &amp; Thursday<pb/>
<lb/>Please ascertain whether our Dist Pro Mar has returned to Adj Gen office the no of negro recruits for <date when="--08">Aug</date>, <date when="--09">Sept</date> &amp; <date when="--10">Oct</date> -- also whether any have been reported from offices of Recruiting in Louisville.</p>
<p>Please answer as soon as possible &amp; oblige Yours Truly</p>
<p>H. G. V. Wintersmith<pb/></p>
<p>Elizabethtown Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-10-24">Oct 24" 1864 -- </date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Wintersmith H. G. V -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>His citizens regard the recent order of Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Fry Pro. Mar. Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> U. S. requiring deficit for drafted men, who have left the country or failed to report to be made up from original enrollment as unjust How can they obtain credits for those who enlisted in Indiana regts. Has his Dist. Pro. Mar- returned the N<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi> of Negro regts for <date when="--08">Aug</date>, <date when="--09">sept</date> &amp; <date when="--10">Oct</date> -- have any been reported from Louisville_ Will his presence at Frankfort in regard to these matters be necessary -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Rec<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> A. G. O. <date when="1864-10-27">Oct 27. 1864-</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
