<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-023-0023"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Edward Everett et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG2936</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG1-197</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Boston, Suffolk County, Massachusetts</placeName>
    <date when="1861-01-03">3 January 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>BOSTON, <date when="1861-01-03">JANUARY 3, 1861</date>.</p>
<p>MR. HENRY DEXTER, of Cambridge, Mass., a Sculptor of distinguished merit, has, in the course of the past year, executed a series of busts of the several Governors of the United States. They have, with the exception of those of California and Oregon, all been modelled from life. Those of which the originals are known to us, are excellent likenesses, and, from Mr. Dexter's skill as an artist, the same is no doubt true of the rest. </p>
<p>The idea of forming a collection of this kind is believed to be original with Mr. Dexter, and he has displayed much enterprise in carrying it into effect. It has requied the devotion of much time and labor, extensive journeys, and no inconsiderable expense. The result is a collection of the busts of the Chief Magistrates of thirty-three States, for the year <date when="1860">1860</date>. Several of them are persons of national reputation, and all of them entitled to be considered representative men for the time being, in their respective Commonwealths.</p>
<p>Mr. Dexter's original intention, was to offer the entire series to Congress, to be placed in the Capitol. The state of public affairs at the present time, being deemed unfavorable to an application to Congress, he has determined to propose to the several States, to purchase each, the bust of its Governor, to be placed either in its own Capitol, or in that of the United States. The price at which Mr. Dexter will furnish the busts in marble, viz. Five Hundred Dollars each, we deem quite moderate, and we sincerely hope that he may receive the patronage to which his talent, industry, and zeal in the cultivation of his art, are richly entitled.</p>
<p>EDWARD EVERETT,
<lb/>W. A. STEARNS,
<lb/>C. C. FELTON,
<lb/>JACOB BIGELOW,
<lb/>SAMUEL A. ELIOT,
<lb/>G. S. HILLARD,
<lb/>ROB'T C. WINTHROP,
<lb/>GEORGE S. BOUTWELL,
<lb/>CHARLES HALE,
<lb/>EZRA LINCOLN,
<lb/>PELEG W. CHANDLER,
<lb/>GEORGE TYLER BIGELOW.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
