<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2627"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. L. Simmons to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7264</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-201 to BR16-202</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Grant County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Honor Thomas E Bramlet
<lb/>Governor of the commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned does most respectfully represent and state to your Honor ^that^ Hughey Limbroke stands Indicted in the Grant circuit court for the murder of G W Jamison and also for Shooting and wounding J R Jamison, That he is Indicted with Shryock Oder &amp; Jo Simpson. The undersigned further states that the Provost Marshall of Grant "to wit" W N Simpson had summoned some ten or twelve men to go with him to arrest some persons who had Shot at and wounded G W &amp; A Simpson <unclear>from</unclear> Ambush. That said G W &amp; A Simpson belonged at the time they were so Shot and wounded to the Provost Guard of Grant county -- That while they were out in search of the Gerrillas The said Provost Marshall caused the said Jamisons to be arrested and while they were being conveyed to Williamstown G W Jamison was shot by the Guard and Killed and J R Jamison severely wounded That Hughey Lumbrick was sumined<pb/>
<lb/>by the Provost Marshall and did go with the Possee -- The undersigned states that he has been informed by persons who were in the company that Limbrick had nothing to do with the shooting That he was so far behind the Jamisons that he could not have taken part in the shooting -- That this was the proof before the coroner -- That Shryock and ^Jo^ Simpson were the leaders in the shooting -- That Jo Simpson has been pardoned -- He now states that said Limbrick is a very Poor man -- that he has a wife and nine small children -- That he is a cripple. That he has a school now made up and is about to commence Teaching but that on account of these Indictments he can do nothing for his support or that of his family -- Now a Petition with any No of signers could be obtained asking your Hon to Pardon said Hughey Limbrick but I have deemed it unnecessary as that Jo Simpson the <hi rend="str">s</hi>Liader has been pardonid &amp; as they all were under the<lb/>
<lb/>control and direction of the Provost Marshall -- you are now asked to pardon said hughey Limbrick <hi rend="str">with</hi> in the two indictments aforesaid That it would be a proper exercise of Executive Clemency and it is sincerely hoped that you will pardon the said Limbrick -- Copies of the Indictments are filed herewith</p>
<p>I am your obt Servt
<lb/>W, L, Simmons<pb/></p>
<p>Grant Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Petition for the Pardon of <hi rend="underline">H^uey^ughey Limbrick</hi><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Indicted
<lb/>1 for Murder
<lb/>1 for Malicious Shooting
<lb/>Pardon
<lb/>W. L. Simmons
<lb/>Williamstown
<lb/>Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
