<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0242"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">C. Blanton et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9710</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-208 to MG17-209</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Fulton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Exelency Govenor M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioners would State that at the <date when="1860-12">December term 1860</date> of the Fulton Criminal &amp; Equity Court, Micheal M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Ginney was found Guilty of Larceny &amp; Sentenced to the penitentiary for one year under the following circumstances. Viz Some time in the Early part of the year <date when="1860">1860</date> a Large fire occured in Hickman Ky at which goods &amp; merchandize were in Large quantities thrown out into the Street &amp; Some of the Same was Stolen &amp; removed. The morning after the fire Some of Said Goods were found upon the premise of the Said M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Ginney &amp; he was thereupon commited &amp; held to trial at the court above stated. Now because of the unexplained circumstances of the goods being So found the Jury found said M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Ginny guilty as Stated. Now your petitioners State that the reason why Said circumstance could not be Explained was because his wife (who is a simple &amp; almost idiotic creature) without his knowledge or consent took Said goods &amp; Left them on the premises. This could not be proved by the wife for obvious &amp; Legal reasons -- She has admited the fact &amp; did so from the first but could not be convicted because she has Scarcely intellect to be in any way responsible &amp; hence incompetent to commit crime -- As afarther fact your<pb/>
<lb/>Petitioners would State that the facts above could have been proven as they are informed &amp; believe, had not the only witness of the above facts Left this State for parts unknown &amp; hence it was impossible to procure his attendance -- Your petitioners would State that Said M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Ginney has always borne the character of an honest hard working man &amp; was So proved upon trial.</p>
<p>Therefore Your Petition most respectfully Suggest that this is a case calling for the Exercise of the Executive clemency, so wisely by the wisdom of our Laws vested in your Exelency</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>C Blanton
<lb/>Thos W M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Mahan
<lb/>Dr J F Gourley
<lb/>W. J. Thompson
<lb/>Mont Wilson
<lb/>H F Cheatham
<lb/>Patrick Gaffney
<lb/>Jas Kirkpatrick
<lb/>A D Kingman
<lb/>Sam<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Landrum
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Arthur Brent</hi>
<lb/>C. A. Holcombe jr
<lb/>Jno. C. Bailey
<lb/>Isaac Winston
<lb/>B, Ramage
<lb/>J. A. Overton
<lb/>Dr. W, A, Thomson
<lb/>A Goodhart
<lb/><cb n="2"/>W. D. Isbell
<lb/>J m Kirk
<lb/>Isaac Barnett
<lb/>W R Huffman
<lb/>Eli Aperton
<lb/>E Davis
<lb/>T. V. Gibbs } Jury.
<lb/>T M Corbett } Coms Atty
<lb/>J M Bigger } Judge
<lb/>Joe Roulhac
<lb/>R C Prather
<lb/>B R Walker L. B.
<lb/>C. L. Randle L L D
<lb/>A G Payne
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W. C. Field</hi>
<lb/>Wm C Drury
<lb/>Julon Nail
<lb/>Juno Burchett<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>B H Willis.
<lb/>Ed K Warren<pb/></p>
<p>M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Ginney<hi rend="sup">s</hi> case
<lb/>Fulton Co -- </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
