<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1225"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William B. Jones to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5862</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-381 to BR11-382</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Franklin, Simpson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-10-06">6 October 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Franklin Ky <date when="1864-10-06">6 October 1864</date>
<lb/>Gov Bramlette
<lb/>Frankfort Ky
<lb/>Dear Sir,</p>
<p>At the <date when="1864-01">January term 1864</date> of the Allen Equity, and Criminal Court, a Judgment was rendered in favor of the Commonwealth, Against Robinson Brown, Thos Fisher and Thos Cockrill, (I may not have the given names exactly Correct) on a forfeited bail bond, they being the Sureties or bail of John C Wray,</p>
<p>John C Wray in the Spring of <date when="1862">1862,</date> was prosecuted before an examining Court in Allen County charged with Treason, The result of that prosecution, was that he was committed for further trial, and executed bond for his appearance before the Allen Equity &amp; Criminal Court, at its <date when="1862-07">July term 1862</date> to Answer the charge &amp;C, At said term <date when="1862-07">(July 1862)</date> he was Indicted for the treason and failing to appear on being called after the finding of the Indictment his -- bail bond with Brown, Fisher, &amp; Cockrill ^sureties^ was regularly forfeited, The action pending on the forfeited bond was continued until the <date when="1864-01">January Term 1864,</date> when the Judgment was rendered against<pb/>
<lb/>his bail for $5000.. the penalty of the bond, Mr Wray was as I learn in Tennessee at the time the bond was forfeited, and soon after the forfeiture and before the Judgment, died in Tennessee, Such is the information his relatives have and they regard the Information reliable. He was a decided rebel and as I learn a headstrong man, and his bail had not the power on account of his absense to Surrender him at the times they had the right under the Code of practice to have done So.</p>
<p>My Information is that on account of the pecuniary Condition of Fisher &amp; Cockrill, Mr Brown will be compelled to shoulder, the responsibility alone, and that to pay the amount would probably ruin him pecuniarily.</p>
<p>In view of the facts and circumstances connected with the Case, a portion only of which are herein Stated, I am satisfied it would be right, and Just, that the arm of the executive be interposed in their behalf, and I recommend it, I know that Judge Graham is of opinion that the case is one Justifying executive Clemency.</p>
<p>Respectfully W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> B Jones Atty
<lb/>for the Comth</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
