<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0208"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">H. C. Lilly et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9676</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-162 to MG17-163</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jackson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-11-13">13 November 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioners Citizens of Jackson County Ky Respectfully sheweth that at the present term of the Jackson Circuit Court Newton J Hews a citizen of said county was found gulty under an Indictment in said Court for driving along the public road in said County for more than Eight miles fifty sheep without having them marked &amp; branded as required by law &amp; fined one hundred Dollars &amp; cost,</p>
<p>They state that from the proof in the Case no person was injured by reason of said sheep being drove along the road as stated they further state they are satisfied that said Hughes &amp; the persons engaged in driving said sheep for him did not know that it was Contrary to law to drive said sheep the distance named ^without marking or branding^ &amp; consequently no intention to violate the law was intended, that Hughes is comparatively a poor man ^and hard run^ &amp; if he is compelled to pay said fine he will be seriously injured, that he is a good citizen and ought to be relieved from the payment of the fine, wherefore in view of the whole case they ask your excellency to remit said fine they really think that the payment<pb/>
<lb/>of the fees &amp; cost in the case will be a sufficient punishment against Hughes -- &amp; the example made of him will be a sufficient warning to others in this County to compel them to observe the law in such cases</p>
<p><date when="1860-11-13">November 13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1860</date>.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>H. C. Lilly Estill
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H Carson
<lb/>W. H Wilson
<lb/>Franklin Faubus
<lb/><cb n="2"/>R Runyon
<lb/>Harrison Fleming
<lb/>H J Clark
<lb/>J. Newcum
<lb/>John Stephens J P J C
<lb/>Hardin Alsan
<lb/>John Farmer
<lb/>Robert Hays
<lb/>John Reece
<lb/>Isaac Hacker
<lb/>T I Cornelisen
<lb/>R E Nichols
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Wood
<lb/>J, H, Durham
<lb/>M Cehron
<lb/>Milton Pigg
<lb/>Mathias Seaborn
<lb/>J K Seal
<lb/>Robt Ramsey
<lb/>Cornelius Moor
<lb/>gotfrey Isaacks
<lb/>J C Morriss
<lb/>Henry Faubus<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Andrew Isaacs
<lb/>D. S. Jones
<lb/>Calvin Mchafery
<lb/>Spielman Isaacs
<lb/>Hugh ODonnell
<lb/>A G Ward
<lb/>will isaacs
<lb/>W H Randall<pb/></p>
<p>M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee <date when="1860-11-15">Nov 15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1860</date>
<lb/>Gov Magoffin </p>
<p>I have no doubt but N J Hugh acted ignorantly in driving his lot of sheep upon a public road in this county with out putting the point on Said markers upon them as required by the revised statutes if he had known what was required I have no doubt but he would have complied with it there are but few who know the provision and the penalty is very severe I hope you will remit the fine yours respt</p>
<p>Granville Pearl
<lb/>Sam J Fanley
<lb/>John Dishman</p>
<p>Citizens of Jackson County Kentucky
<lb/>To } Petition for Remission of fine of $100 agst N. J. Hughes
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Jackson Cir. Ct
<lb/>Respite 12 mo
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>$100 } Midsemeanor
<lb/>H. J. Hews
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1860-12-01">Decr 1. 1860</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
