<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1481"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William H. Hagans et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6118</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-297 to BR12-298</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Nashville, Davidson County, Tennessee</placeName>
    <date when="1865-01-18">18 January 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Bramlett Governor of Kentucky
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>We beg leave, to introduce to your acquaintance, M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. &amp; M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi>. Danl Miller, of Nashville Tenn. They go to you, on a sad mission, imploring the liberty, of their suffering son. They are natives of Ky, and have resided in this City, about thirty years. By their sterling integrity gentlemanly &amp; lady-like deportment combined with their other excellenct qualities, they have ever occupied a high position in Society. They have a large, and respectable family of Children. George, their eldest, grew up in our midst, an industrious impulsive youth, of good reputation, except an occasional indulgence, in strong drink. We are informed and believe, that while under its influence, in your State, he became the victim, of older and vastly worse men, than himself. That he committed errors, we dont controvert, but the idea of deliberate crime, as attached to George W Miller, we totally discard.</p>
<p>For a young man, of his high toned sensibilities, to arouse to soberness, in a strange city, without friends or money, to be arrested, charged, tried, pronounced guilty of a crime, incarerated in the Penitentiary, and there remain, eight long, dreary, months, ought to expiate a high crime, of an old offender. Then how much more abundantly, will they atone, for this inconsiderate error, of a dashing, good hearted youth. In adition to all this, we are told, his deep anguish, and accumulated sorrows, are rapidly undermining his hitherto feeble health. </p>
<p>We submit to your Excellency, that the objects of<pb/>
<lb/>punishment, have been attained in his case. </p>
<p>We, therefore, the premises considered, do most earnestly, and urgently, invoke Executive clemency, in his behalf. </p>
<p>We pray you, to restore him to liberty, to citizenship, to the embraces, of his afflicted sorrowing Family</p>
<p>Most Respectfully yours
<lb/>Nashville Ten
<lb/><date when="1865-01-18">Jany 18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi>. H. Hagans
<lb/>T M Patterson
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Will</hi> K <hi rend="underline">Turner</hi>.
<lb/>Nathaniel Baxter
<lb/>J. B. White
<lb/>T W Maxey
<lb/>W H Culkin
<lb/>G C Canhitt
<lb/>A Cunningham
<lb/>W. Mat. Brown
<lb/>Phinehas Garrett
<lb/>J C Pentecost
<lb/><cb n="2"/>F O Hurt
<lb/>W W Curper
<lb/>P G. Breen
<lb/>B N Dodd
<lb/>P H Park
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Clay. Bosworth
<lb/>C. W. Nance
<lb/>Eli. L. Woods
<lb/>J L Nichol
<lb/>C Anason
<lb/>Isaac Paul<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>George W Miller<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Petition of Judge Baxter &amp; other citizens of Nashville for his pardon from Penitentiary -- </p>
<p>Convicted of Larceny at the <gap/> Term <date when="1865">1865</date> of Jefferson Cir Court<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>James Harlan Jr, atto:</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
