<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2024"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">G. P. Cosby, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6661</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-186</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Webster County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-06-24">24 June 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Kentucky Webster County Sct</p>
<p>G P Cosby Says that he is a Citizen of Dixon the County seat of Webster County Kentucky that he is well acquainted with John R Brooks late of said town That said Brooks is said now to be in the Territory of Colorado. That said Brooks has a wife &amp; child now living in Dixon. That Brooks was a practising lawyer of the Webster Circuit Court -- That he was said to be a Commissioned lieutentant in the Regiment of C<hi rend="underline">o</hi>l A R Johnson of the army of the so Called Confederate States during the year <date when="1862">1862</date> or a part there of That during the early part of the year <date when="1863">1863</date> he took the oath of allegiance gave bond &amp; was released by C<hi rend="underline">ol</hi> Foster commanding Post at Henderson That he returned to his home in Dixon and behaved himself well and peaceably during the time he remained &amp; attended to his practice as a lawyer -- but that during the <date when="1864">Summer of 1864</date> ^some officers &amp;^ Soldiers of the 52<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Ky. Regiment passed through Dixon &amp; it is said with out any apparent Cause threated to Shoot said Brooks and ordered him to leave the Country which he did and Which in affiants opinion it was prudent for him to do=there was at the time a great prejudice in the minds of the federal soldiery against those Who had been in the Rebel army especialy those under the said A R Johnson</p>
<p>G. P. Cosby<pb/></p>
<p>Subscribed and Sworn to before <hi rend="str">my</hi> me by G P Cosby the <date when="1865-06-24">24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of June 1865</date></p>
<p>W. W. Gentry J. P</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
