<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1055"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John C. Strong to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10523</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-145 to MG20-146</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-05-22">22 May 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky your Petitioner John. C. Strong states that at the <date when="1860-10">october Term of the Breathitt Circuit Court 1860</date> your Petitioner states that he was prescuten for Keeping a Tipling house, &amp; at the present <date when="1861-05">May</date> Term of said court he was found $20 -- for said offence, or for one single act of Retailing your petitioner states that he was a Distiller that he made. &amp; Distilled apple brandy last fall &amp; on one accasion while your petitioner was from home his wife sold one half pint of brandy for 5 cnts this was not done at the aprobation of your petitioner -- your petitioner says that he did not sell by retail his brandy that he made about 50 gallons of Brandy &amp; that he gave it all away to his poor neighbours &amp; the sick -- in the neighbourhood that he never got one cent of money for any portion of the brandy he made &amp; in trooth he did not get the 5 cnts he thinks it hard to pay 20$ &amp; give all the brandy away he says he in Justice ought not to pay the fine for what he has Stated is the ungarnished trooth Just as it is -- your petitioners under these Circumstances &amp; from the hard times your petitioners asks your Excellency to Remit said fine <date when="1861-05-22">22 may 1861</date></p>
<p>John C Strong</p>
<p>we Join in the above petition
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Isaac N. Cardwell.
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> L Hurst
<lb/>J D Cooley
<lb/>O. W. Hart
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi>. w Hazelipp
<lb/>Thos Munger
<lb/>John Deaten
<lb/>W. Chiles<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>John W Car^d^well
<lb/>W. G. Haddix
<lb/>Morgan R. Puckett
<lb/>James Combs
<lb/>J. W. Moore
<lb/>George Frazier
<lb/>John Little
<lb/>S P Frazier
<lb/>A B Patrick<pb/></p>
<p>Gov Magoffin
<lb/>Dear
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>I hope you will remit this fine I know that it aught to be remited</p>
<p>yours truly
<lb/>Granville Pearl</p>
<p>I agree in the above</p>
<p>John Dishman<pb/></p>
<p>J. C Strongs
<lb/>Petition</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1861-06-24">June 24</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
