<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2944"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Matthew H. Morison to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7581</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR43-14</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To the Honorable Thomas E. Brambett, Esq. Govenor of Kentucky Your Petitioner, Matthew H. Morrison would respectfully state, that he has always heretofore borne a good name for honesty and probity until the charge hereinafter mentioned -- that he has been employed for several months in the capacity of Clerk and Salesman at the house of Baird &amp; Bros wholesale millenery establishment in the city of Louisville Ky. wherein he conceived he had the right to take out at wholesale prices such articles as his wife might need charging himself at wholesale prices -- that this had been the uniform custom of their clerks heretofore -- that often certain articles had been thus taken and given to his wife, she needing others of a different stamp proposed exchanging them, when the said Baird &amp; Bros said they had sold no such articles, which fact <hi rend="str">came</hi> coming to the mind of the officers of the law caused him to be arrested and held over for trial -- He positively asserts that there was not the slightest felonious intent on his part, but the articles taken were in the usual and customary way accorded to other clerks and salesmen He prays the Executive clemency. He states that he is a very poor man dependant entirety upon his daily labor for his support, and the further defense of the same is expensive when he is unable to bear it, and attaches further <unclear/> to his name by hanging on him, thus preventing employment He prays for pardon &amp; he will ever pray <hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi></p>
<p>Mathew H. Morrison<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned Citizens <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>of Jefferson County Kentucky, believe that the foregoing petition of Matthew H. Morrison presents a a fair representation and statement of his case, and that We heartily join with him in recommendation for Executive clemency -- We think that his case is one entitled to it.</p>
<p>Jeff Brown
<lb/>Enos Kern
<lb/>J. B. Russell
<lb/>W. P. Shepard
<lb/>Oliver A Patton
<lb/>M. W. La Rue
<lb/>W. O. Cunningham
<lb/>F G Danneker
<lb/>S A Atchison <unclear>jr</unclear>
<lb/>Rowan Buchanon
<lb/>Jack Fry
<lb/>Jno M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Carthy
<lb/>T. L. Burnett
<lb/><hi rend="str">H. E. Read</hi>
<lb/>F } <hi rend="underline">Attorneys</hi> <hi rend="underline">at Law</hi></p>
<p>Rejected</p>
<p>Jefferson C. Ct
<lb/>Louisville
<lb/>vs
<lb/>M H Morrison</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
