<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-002-0012"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">S. F. Johnson et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG0876</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Jacob A Glover</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Appointments by the Governor, Military Appointments, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR5-327 to BR5-328</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Franklin, Simpson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-01-23">23 January 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Franklin Ky <date when="1864-01-23">Jany 23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency Thos E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Ky -- </p>
<p>The undersigned officers of the 52<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Regiment Ky Vol Infty, would most Respectfully represent to your honor that they have learned with deep regret that Lieut Col John, H, Grider is under arrest and that in consequence of the charges against him objections are urged against his being Commissioned as Co<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> of the 52<hi rend="sup">d</hi>. Regmt. what the charges are against him we cannot tell, But would suggest that if it is not inconssistant with public public service that he be assigned the position of Col, of the 52<hi rend="sup">d</hi>. Regmt. In making this request we are not actuated by any personal feelings, But a high sense of Justice to a brave man and a tried Soldier, that Co<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Grider has his faults and imperfections we admit, But let him that is without Sin cast the first Stone, at great Expense and a vast amount of hard labor, to have raised we think the best Regmt, in the United States Service, And we think we Express the sentiments of every member of the Regmt. when we say that every officer &amp; Soldier in the Regmt. wishes to see John. H. Grider Commissioned as <hi rend="underline">Col</hi> of the 52 Regmt. <pb/>
<lb/>that there are outsiders &amp; hangers on who Expect to be Identified with the Regmt <hi rend="underline">provided</hi> they can secure the <hi rend="underline">position</hi> they desire who are opposed to Co<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Grider, we admit, But we are assured that your high sense of Justice will not permit you to thrust aside the men who have earned their position by their <hi rend="underline">hard</hi> <hi rend="underline">labor</hi> and sacrifices to make room for men seeking for and willing to receive positions at the sacrifice of men who have staked their life and their all upon the Alter of their Country. And in Conclusion we Respectfully ask that if the charges against Co<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Grider are of such a nature as to render it nessary to select another Man for Col, of our Regmt, that we be allowed the privilege of designating who shall be our leader.</p>
<p>S. F. Johnson. Major. 52. Regt Ky Vols
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H. Murrell adjutant 52" K. Regt
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Wo, Besen 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Lieut Co, D, " " "
<lb/>J. W. Underhill 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Lieut. Co E 52<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> Rgt.
<lb/>S. J. Richards capt co A 52 Regt
<lb/>W, H, Walker, 1st, Lieut. co, A 52 Regt
<lb/>James. M. Childress Capt 52 Reg
<lb/>L, P, Arnald 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Lieu<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> 52. Reg<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi>
<lb/>Alexander Dockery 2<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Lieut 52 Ky
<lb/>F Houchin Capt 52 Regt
<lb/>P Willis 2st Lieut<pb/>
<lb/><hi rend="str">D</hi> D, C, Parish 2<hi rend="sup">and</hi> Lieut
<lb/>R. N. Taylor 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Lieut
<lb/>Ed Hartee Cpt Comn Co (G) 52 reg
<lb/>N S Scott 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Lieut Com 52
<lb/>James H Lile 2 " " "
<lb/>1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Lieut W, P, King 52 Ky, Co, F,
<lb/>G W Meyer Surgeon 52 KY Infty vols
<lb/>John D Gilliam Capt. 52<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Ky Regt
<lb/>John, W, Arnett, 2 Lieut Co. D
<lb/>Will, H, Johnson, R,Q,M, 52,<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi>, Ky, Vols, M, I,
<lb/>John B Tyler Capt 52 Ky
<lb/>H. C. Watkins Capt " "
<lb/>Lewis Buckner Captain 52<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> Ky Vols
<lb/>GW Hay Capt.</p>
<p>There are other officers whose names would appear but from the fact that they are absent on duty</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
