<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0074"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William J. Wadlington, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9542</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17A-149</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-08-18">18 August 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Caldwell County</p>
<p>W J Wadlington states that on the <date when="1860-01-17">17<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of January 1860</date> That M. A. Cartwright J Prince and J Blaylock came to where my Father Thomas B Wadlington Myself and Slaves were at work, when Cartwright approached to within about 30 paces. My Father commanded him to stop, Cartwright still advancing in the direction of my Father. my Father commanding him to stop t<hi rend="str">w</hi>hree times -- Cartwright Still approaching came up and took his seat on the boddy of a tree that my Father had cut down at the time Cartwright took his seat my Father was standing on the opposite side of the same two or three steps from cartwright, cartwright asked Father if he was going to cut up that tree, and Father told cartwright that he was, Cartwright then told Father that he would kill him before he should cut said tree up, Father then directed me to cut a log off the tree, and Father marked the place on the tree where he wanted it cut when he had marked it Cartwright got up from where he was sitting on the tree, and came and sit and the place that <hi rend="underline">father</hi> marked for me to cut the tree -- I started to the place where I was directed by Father to cut the tree, and was about to get upon the tree to cut it, when Cartwright rose from the tree and drew his pistol and stepped<pb/>
<lb/>towards Father, and Father retreated back and as Father retreated Cartwright fired his pistol at Father, and Father fired on Cartwright with his shot gun -- at this time the partis were about eight paces apart Father then drew his Revolver and advanced on cartwright and fired at him as he advanced, one time, and when he got near enough he took hold of cartwright and commenced beating him over the head with his pistol -- At this time J Prince came up and Jumped on the back of Father and took him by the shoulders and attempted to pull Father from cartwright as I thought, Then I ran in and took hold of Prince and pulled him off of Father, When I pulled Prince loose from Father he ran off a peace then returned towards me, and at that time the Slave Jorden offered me an axe to defend myself with, but I did not take it, Prince when he saw the slave offer to hand me the axe ran off down towards Eli Nichols and did not return again. Father shot cartwright in the head about this time in the head and he fell, Cartwright started to get up ^agan^ and Fa<hi rend="str">r</hi>ther hit him two strokes with an axe on the head which ended the fight</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi>, J, Wadlington</p>
<p>Subscribed and Sworn to before me by W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> J. Wadlington
<lb/>This <date when="1862-08-18">18 day of August 1862</date>.</p>
<p>E. P Watkins Clerk.
<lb/>Caldwell Circuit Court.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
