<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1736"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">H. R. Littell et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6373</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-239 to BR13-240</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hopkinsville, Christian County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-04-21">21 April 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Hopkinsville Ky <date when="1865-04-21">Apl 21' 1865</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency Governor Bramlette</p>
<p>The undersigned Citizens of Christian County Respectfully represent, that, on yesterday their fellow-Citizen Louis Elb, was fined by the Police Judge of the town of Hopkinsville Ten ($10) Dollars in each of three prosecutions in the name of the Commonwealth, &amp; at the instance of the Board of Trustees of said town, for alleged violations of an ordinance passed by said Board <hi rend="underline">in</hi> <date when="1858-06"><hi rend="underline">June</hi> <hi rend="underline">1858</hi>,</date> prohibiting the opening of stores &amp; the sale of goods therein <hi rend="str">on</hi> <hi rend="str">the</hi> on Sunday in said town</p>
<p>Your Petitioners admit that a few goods were proved to have been sold by said Elb on each of the three Sundays as alleged in said prosecutions, but that said Sales were made, as well to accommodate his Customers as to profit himself, &amp; Said sales Conducted in a very quiet manner &amp; privately,</p>
<p>They state that it is a notorious fact that said Board of Trustees have silently acquies^c^ed in &amp; permitted the violation of said ordinance for <hi rend="underline">a</hi> <hi rend="underline">number</hi> <hi rend="underline">of</hi> <hi rend="underline">years</hi>, not merely in the Sale in a quiet manner of dry-goods -- as in the Case of said Elb -- but in allowin Allowing Grog-Shops &amp; drinking saloons to be opened &amp; ardent spirits vended on the Sabbath day; Corrupting the Youth of the town to say nothing of its general evil tendencies,</p>
<p>Therefore Your petitioners would respectfully Submit, if, under these Circumstances, said Elb had not a right to presume, that said Ordinance had been abrogated by said Board, in effect, if not by direct repeal, After their long acquiescence in its open violation had they a right, an equitable, moral right to sue upon its violation without a re-enactment? and they would further submit, if <hi rend="str">they</hi> said Board should be permitted to single out said Elb, because, perhaps, of some prejudice against him, making a victim of him &amp; allowing the entire escape from prosecution of those saloon keeprs,?<pb/></p>
<p>Your Petitioners, therefore, respectfully &amp; earnestly solicit the intervention of Executive Clemency, &amp; ask that Your Excellency interpose &amp; remit each of said fines of Ten ($10) each amounting to thirty ($30) Dollars or so much thereof as you see proper,</p>
<p>Very Respectfully</p>
<p>H. R. Littell County Judge
<lb/>A H Clark
<lb/>Joab Clark clk. cir court.
<lb/>G. H. Lawson " Co Ct.
<lb/>D. M. Claggett
<lb/>John Feland
<lb/>Wm. M. Buell Surveyor C. C
<lb/>D. S. Hays
<lb/>W <hi rend="underline">Evans</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Christian Co
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Louis Elb
<lb/>refused</p>
<p>Refused
<lb/>Richard T. Jacob
<lb/>Lt. &amp; act. Gov
<lb/><hi rend="str">Chr</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
