<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0480"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Caleb Townly to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9948</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-244 to MG18-245</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-01-14">14 January 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency, Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Caleb Townly, respectfully states, That at the <date when="1861-01">January Term (1861)</date> of the city court of Louisville, he was fined fifty dollars for carrying concealed a pistol. He admitted the fact and confessed Judgment. He states that he had a pistol on Christmans day and was using it as boys usually do on that day loading the same with powder only and firing it off. A young Gentleman who was with him was also arrested. because he had a pistol, made defense, upon the Ground that he was only firing off the pistol to celebrate Christmas day -- and the Jury acquitted him, No man could have proved against your petitioner.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner, is young, not of age, and is poor and unable to pay the fine. The costs in the case amounting to about $20, which is about as much as he can pay -- He assures your Excellency that he did not have said Weapon, for the purpose of injuring any person, -- that is not in the habit of carrying weapons -- and his only intention was to use it as above mentioned </p>
<p>Wherefore he most respectfully asks your Excellency to remit said fine, promising never to offend in like manner again.</p>
<p>Louisville <date when="1861-01-14">Jan, 14th 1861</date>,
<lb/>Caleb Townly</p>
<p>I defended for young friend of Mr Townly in the case -- mentioned above -- &amp; he was acquitted on the grounds above stated, Mr Townly had a pistol on the same day but he confessed Judgment. Doubtless he could have been acquitted, as was his friend.</p>
<p>W, G, Reasor</p>
<p>I know the petitioner, he is young &amp; is a resident of my portion of the city &amp; my acquaintance with him Justifies me in saying that he is a well behaved orderly &amp; industrious young man,</p>
<p>J Connell J P J C<pb/></p>
<p>Names
<lb/><hi rend="underline">James</hi>. W. <hi rend="underline">Osborn</hi>
<lb/>G T May
<lb/>John L. Henning
<lb/>F,, B,, Boyce
<lb/>Joseph Kampf
<lb/><hi rend="underline">A. Kohlhop</hi>p
<lb/>Philipp Gernertz
<lb/>Alex Gilmore
<lb/>Jesse Tolbert<pb/></p>
<p>Louisville city ct
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>$50 } Weapons
<lb/>Is<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1861-01-19">Jany 19 '61</date>
<lb/>Caleb Townley</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
