<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0196"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. V. Veach, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8648</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-296 to R3-297</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Henry County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-01-22">22 January 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Henry County</p>
<p>J. V. Veach says that just before the Rebels came into the state perhaps about a week or so before they came to Ky and 5 or six days before the fight between the Federals and Rebels in NewCastle, I was on my way from Louisville the cars stoped at Lagrange when Fleet Goodrich Jr. asked me if I had seen W D Mitchell, but first he came up to my back and said is this you Mitchell. I turned around and said No -- and asked why -- He replied that Mitchell was a damned scoundrel and He was hunting him -- He said if you see or hear of him on the carrs, will you let me know, or write me word. I replied I will not. He replied I will give five Hundred dollars to find him and if I do I intend to take his life and ^Goodrich said^ that way what He had been hunting him for a good while.</p>
<p>J V ^his X mark^ Veach 
<lb/>Test 
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> A Perry</p>
<p>James Deering says that on the day of the Killing of Fleet Goodrich Jr by W D Mitchell, that in company with Capt Sparks Lieut Armstronog and Liet Mitchell. <hi rend="str">th</hi> He went from New Castle with the intention of arresting said Goodrich. That when they got to Smithfield that he <hi rend="str">Goodrich</hi>Dearing in company with said Mitchell went into the Guthre's house and there found Goodrich. That Mitchell said to <hi rend="str">him</hi> ^Goodrich^ to step <hi rend="str">thru</hi> out he wish to see him. Goodrich replied damn him he would follow him wherever he wanted him<pb/>
<lb/>We then went out of the house, Goodrich following, and went across the street where Capt Sparks was <hi rend="str">and</hi> Mitchell remarked Captain at the same time looked around and saw Goodrich drawing his pistol. Mitchell then fired and Goodrich fell. He was standing near by and saw Goodrich attempting to draw his pistol before Mitchell fired or made any attempt to do so.</p>
<p>James Deering</p>
<p>David FitzGerald says that He knew young Goodrich for some time before the Confederates came into the state and knew him as a verry violent young man. He was in several difficulties in New Castle Cursing and abusing the Union party saying that He would slay them as Sampson slew the Philisteens &amp;c. With his pistol drawn -- I have heard numerous persons say that he was such a terror to the community, that they believed he would never die in his bed that some body would kill him</p>
<p>David Fitzgerald</p>
<p>William Buckley say that He was present at Eminence some time ago when young Goodrich without provecation took up a board and broke the scull of a young man, That this was done without saying a word to the young man. He further says that He knew young Goodrich as a terror to the Country on account of his being constantly loaded down with arms and his reckless habits. I also saw Goodrich in New Castle, draw his pistol and threaten to kill Union men, this was in the summer of <date when="1861">1861</date></p>
<p>W, W, Buckley<pb/></p>
<p>John Robertson says that he was present in New Castle on the day of the Pickick party at Mr Roberts some time ago. where Fleet Goodric <hi rend="str">of <date when="1861">1861</date></hi> was conducting himself in a very boistrous manner. Hurrahing for Jeff Davis with his pistol drawn</p>
<p>J R Robertson</p>
<p>State of Ky
<lb/>Henry County</p>
<p>I W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> A Perry. Justice of the Peace in and for the County of Henry cerefy that the foregoing Depositions of J V Veach, James Deering, David FitzGerald, W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> M Buckley and J R Robertson in relation to the killing of Fleet Goodrich Jr by W D Mitchell and the character of said Goodrich, were sworn to and subscribed by them this <date when="1863-01-22">22 day of January 1863</date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> A. Perry</hi> J P H C<pb/></p>
<p>Deposition of 
<lb/>J V Veach 
<lb/>Jas Deering
<lb/>D FitzGerald
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> W Buckley
<lb/>J R Robertson</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
