<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2127"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">D. R. Haggard to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6764</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-348 to BR14-349</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-07-10">10 July 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville <date when="1865">10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> T. E. Bramlette
<lb/>D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Sir</p>
<p>You will see the petition of Barton &amp; Link,, Mr. Gilbert was Employed by myself to go to Tennessee to lease oil lands for a Company <hi rend="str">of us</hi> organized in this City, and it was not because He wanted to Evade Any responsibility. But to make $100 -- per month, and have 1/8, of the proffits arising from the yeald of the oil, This was <hi rend="underline">the</hi> Cause of his absence, from Ky -- His family needed Bread, &amp; He wanted to make it as I think honestly, These vultures, are still after him, and his securities, they are mad because you cut off their fees. Some time Since -- and they are trying to annoy him &amp; his friends, They Cant reach, you but can, make Gilberts path, a little rugid, just now "<hi rend="underline">Bartons Statement</hi>, is reliable no doubt" Gilbert is now ready to return to his field of operations in Tennessee<pb/>
<lb/>if he can be released from this flock of Blood Suckers -- Give him a <unclear/> to date. So far as <hi rend="underline">Faro dealing</hi> is Concerned He has not been engaged in the business since You released him some months ago, as He &amp; his securities say, and I have no doubt they tell the truth about it imagine -- for a moment, the condition of the inocent man -- ignorant of the law, and Knows that He is inocent of doing rong, but knowing that He is liable to be annoyed by men who will take pleasure in doing So,, and the only thing that He has don, was to deal Faro -- for which offence, He asked pardon and you did pardon him -- Has not delt Faro Since but has been -- as the petion shows required to give Bail, &amp; greatly troubled, wipe the whole affair out, so for as you ^can^ release the Securities, &amp; Let Gilbert up. all right, on that Subject, to date, &amp; then I will go his bail -- &amp; not ask you to interpose in his favour -- </p>
<p>Yr friend
<lb/>D R Haggard<pb/></p>
<p>Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> we want this remission to bear date, the <date when="1865-07-10">10th of July, 1865</date></p>
<p>D, R, Haggard</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
