<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2811"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">G. W. Gwin to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7448</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-80</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E. Bramlett Governor of Kentucky -- The undersigned a Justice of the peace for Franklin County would respectfully represent that at the <date when="1865-12">Decr. Term 1865</date>. of his Court there was adjudged against Richard Crutcher and Washington Crutcher fines amounting to $20 exclusive of Costs for failing to work on road in precinct N<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi> 2 in this County two days with their hands -- Altho I felt bound from the testimony to inflict the fine, yet there are some extenuating Circumstances -- these Can be related to your excellency by Mr. Crutcher the bearer of this petition who respectfully requests and desires a remission of the fines by your honor -- Whatever representation Mr Crutcher may make to you may be Strictly relied on -- </p>
<p>Respy
<lb/>G W Gwin J. P.<pb/></p>
<p>Franklin Co
<lb/>Justice Court
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Rich<hi rend="sup">d</hi> &amp; Washington Crutcher
<lb/>for $20,
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-12-15">15 Dec /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
