<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2517"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">L. Dressel to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7154</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-25 to BR16-26</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Pendleton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-10">10 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Tho E Bramlett
<lb/>Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Louis Dressel Citizen of Pendleton Co. Ky do respectfully represent that he some short time since was served with a notice to appear before Robt Colvin Justice of the Peace of his <gap/> district to answer certain charges preferd against him by a Certain Andy Shela for having performed Labour on the Sabath day <hi rend="str">during</hi> During the past harvest your Petitioner does not deny. that he as a Farmer had a crop of wheat out in the field cut &amp; shocked in the usual way the weather being very wet the shocks were sprouting he had to open the wheat at a time suited to the occasion say on saturday the sabath came h<hi rend="str">is</hi>e thought it his duty to try and save his crop which was in part done on the sabath Your Petitioner did not do it as an immoral act but thought duty<pb/>
<lb/>required him to do so Your Petitoner being of German Birth and not comprehending but little of our Language has caled upon you Humble St -- Geo Keith of his neighborhood to make out his case in plain unsophisticated manner In the proceding before the Justice I doubt that he had Jurisdiction In the case, but this he presumed to Have and assessed damages to the amt 6$ as small as the amt is your petiioner is unable to pay having recently come to the U, S. and having a young Family unable to help him also Brother &amp; Sister in Law of imbecile condition The writer of this is knowing to the facts of the case in the latter clause M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Louis Dressel is a Law abiding man Industrious citizen and submits his case to your Clemency &amp;c</p>
<p><date when="1865-10-10">Oct 10 1865</date>
<lb/>Very Respectfully L. Dressel.
<lb/>Subscribers Names on following page<pb/></p>
<p>We the Subscribers do cherfully subscribe our Names to this foregoing Petition in Behalf of Louis Dressel</p>
<p>Geo Keith
<lb/>B. L. Colvin
<lb/>Birkett Colvin
<lb/>Jas A. Watson
<lb/>P. W. Colvin
<lb/>Henry Trost
<lb/>S Tho Hauser</p>
<p>Pendleton Co Justice Court
<lb/>vs
<lb/>L. Dressel
<lb/>$6.
<lb/>violating Sab
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-11-01">1 Nov 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
