<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2383"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. M. Davidsson et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9459</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG25-177 to MG25-178</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Govenor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioners would Respectfully Represent that at the <date when="1859-05">May Term of the Morgan Circuit Court in the year 1859</date>. one L. C. Adams was fined by the virdict of a Jury in Said Court in three different cases, Two cases for illegal gaming Twenty dollars in each case and in the other case for disturbing Religious Worship, ten dollars, making in all fifty dollars, and the Said Adams was required to Pay, or Replevy said amount or go to Jail, and being unable to do so at that time was committed to Jail. and the said Adams being a young and Respectable man, though a little dissipated two of our best citizens, Towit T. N. Perry &amp; James Barber through their sympathy for said Adams went his security for Said fines and had him released from Prison and restored to his young wife who he had married a few months Previous to Said Term of the Court, and <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>the <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>Sheriff of said county is now about to compel the said Perry and Barber to ay said fines, the said Adams being unable to do so. We therefore ask your Excellency to Release said Perry &amp; Barber as Scurity for said Adams, believing that this is one of<pb/>
<lb/>the cases in which the clemency of your Excellency ought to interveen to protect our citizens, and release them from the payment of a Sum though small would be at this time oppressive on them and which is Respectfully submitted to your Excellency's consideration</p>
<p>I very Earnestly request the Governer to act as petioned in the above Messrs Perry &amp; Barber are both "<hi rend="underline">good fellows</hi>" And are devoted to the "Constitution and the Equality of the States"</p>
<p>Yours &amp;c
<lb/>J M Davidsson
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Jn</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> W Hazelrigg</hi></p>
<p>S. J. Filson
<lb/>John T williams cong
<lb/>W H Cartwill Dr
<lb/>P H. Dyers D S
<lb/>Cyris Ally D. C 
<lb/>Luther F Warden
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Miles Rash</hi>
<lb/>John Mynheir
<lb/>W H Sandlin
<lb/>M M Cox
<lb/>A J Parker
<lb/>J H M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clure
<lb/>R. C. Day
<lb/><unclear>E Mclure</unclear> S M C
<lb/>A. J. May
<lb/>G W Kendall
<lb/>W. McClue
<lb/>Ben F Perry P M</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
