<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-038-0010"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Daniel W. Lindsey to Edwin M. Stanton</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG12494</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Union Artillery, Navy and Marines Primary Source Documents ; Misc U.S.C.T. Primary Source Documents</collection>
      <idno>Box 15, Folder 865-66 CIVIL WAR Corresponence on Freedmen's Bureau (wives &amp; children of veterans to be furnished Freedom certificates)</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-06-09">9 June 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Headquarters Kentucky Volunteers,
<lb/>Adjutant=General's Office,
<lb/>Frankfort, <date when="1865-06-09">June 9<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi>, 1865</date>.
<lb/>Hon E M. Stanton
<lb/>Secty of War
<lb/>Washington D. C
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>I have the honor to represent that daily applications are made to me, by the wives of colored soldiers for Evidence of their husbands -- Enlistment in the army, and I request that in order to facilitate their Endeavors to procure the necessary papers as Evidence of their freedom, that the inclosed blank form of a certificate to be issued by me, be acknowledged by the authorities as sufficient proof of the Enlistment and muster into U S service, of their husbands.</p>
<p>I am not advised as to the proper person to whom to make this request, and if you are not the proper authority to address, I Earnestly request that you will refer it with such Endorsement as you may deem best to secure a speedy reply..</p>
<p><note place="footer">over</note><pb/>
<lb/>His Excellency Gov Bramlette is absent, or he would have made this application himself.</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>Your Obdt Serv<hi rend="sup">t</hi>
<lb/>D, W, Lindsey
<lb/>Adjutatn Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> of Ky.</p>
<p>P. S. 
<lb/>If the form of certificate is approved please telegraph me. -- <pb/></p>
<p>K. 128. <unclear/>. <unclear/>. <date when="1865">1865</date>.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Kentucky
<lb/>D, W, Lindsey
<lb/>Adj Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi>
<lb/>Frankfort
<lb/><date when="1865-06-09">June 9, 1865</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>K. 3 RF&amp;AL <date when="1865"><hi rend="underline">1865</hi></date></p>
<p>Request that the enclosed Form be acknowledged as sufficient Evidence of Enlistment of colored soldiers to procure their freedom, &amp;c -- <figure type="hr"/>
<lb/><unclear>Such</unclear>
<lb/>K. 565 <date when="1865-06-14">June 14"/65</date>
<lb/>Adj<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Col<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Troops
<lb/>Recd back A G O <date when="1865-06-20">June 20, 1865</date>
<lb/>Rec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Freedmans Bureau <date when="1865-06-19">June 19/65</date>
<lb/>Recd A G O <date when="1865-06-15">June 15, 1865</date></p>
<p>War Dept. A. G. Office.
<lb/><date when="1865-06-16">June 16", 1865</date>.</p>
<p>Respectfully referred to Major General <hi rend="underline">O. O. Howard</hi> Chief of Bureau for Freedmen, &amp;c.</p>
<p>The Adjutant General of the State of Kentucky asks that the enclosed form of certificate when properly filled up and signed by him, be acknowledged by the authorities (War Department?) as sufficient proof of the enlistment and Muster into service of the persons named in such certificate, and as a consequence the right of the wives and children of such persons to their freedom in accordance with the Act of Congress Approved <date when="1865-03-03">March 3" 1865</date>.</p>
<p>The Adjutant General of Kentucky has been furnished from this office with copies of the Muster-in Rolls of all the colored men enlisted in that State, and he is therefore the competent and proper authority to issue such certificates.</p>
<p>The matter involved is one of the very highest importance, and although the proposed certificate is very well as far as it goes, I doubt very much whether it would be regarded by those disposed to disregard or evade the law referred to.</p>
<p>With these remarks the question is respectfully referred to Major General <hi rend="underline">Howard</hi> in the belief that the freedom of the wives and children of colored soldiers properly pertains to his Bureau.</p>
<p>C. W. Foster
<lb/>A. A. Genl. Vols.
<lb/>E. B. Vol. 3. @ P. 307.<pb/></p>
<p>War Department
<lb/>Bureau of Refugees Freedmen &amp;c 
<lb/>Washingotn <date when="1865-06-19">June 19. 1865</date></p>
<p>Respectfully returned to Col. <hi rend="underline">C W Foster</hi>, A. A. Gen'l The certificate herewith enclosed in approved; but in order to secure the results desired, the Adjutant General of Kentucky had better communicate with Brig Gen'l <hi rend="underline">C. B. Fisk</hi> Ass't Com'g of this Bureau for the States of Kentucky &amp; Tennessee, Hd. Qrs. at Nashville Tenn.</p>
<p>O. O. Howard
<lb/>Major General
<lb/>Commissioner</p>
<p>E. B.
<lb/>p. 8.
<lb/><date when="1865">1865</date><pb/>
<lb/>Headquarters Kentucky Volunteers,
<lb/>Adjutant=General's Office,
<lb/>Frankfort, <gap/>, 186<gap/>.</p>
<p>I hereby certify, that it appears form the U. S. Muster in Rolls on file in this Office, that <gap/> was enrolled on the <gap/> day of <gap/> 186<gap/> at <gap/> by<gap/> and mustered into the U. S. service on the <gap/> day of<gap/> 186<gap/> at <gap/> by <gap/> to serve <gap/> years or during the War <gap/></p>
<p>In testimony whereof I have hereunto set my hand, and affixed my Official Seal, this <gap/> day of <gap/> 186<gap/>.</p>
<p><gap/>
<lb/>Adjutant General of Kentucky
<lb/><figure type="seal"/><pb/>
<lb/>K. 565 <date when="1865-06">June/65</date></p>
<p>K. 128. Vols. <unclear/> <unclear/>. <date when="1865">1865</date>.
<lb/><hi rend="underline">K. 3</hi> RF &amp; AL <date when="1865"><hi rend="underline">1865</hi></date><pb/></p>
<p>War Dept. A. G. Office,
<lb/><date when="1865-06-21">June 21", 1865</date>.</p>
<p>Respectfully returned to Brig. General <hi rend="underline">D. W. Lindsay</hi> Adjutant General State of Kentucky, Frankfort, Ky. and attention invited to the endorsement of Major General <hi rend="underline">Howard</hi> thereon.</p>
<p>By order of the Secretary of War:
<lb/>C. W. Foster
<lb/>A. A. Genl. Vols.
<lb/>E. B. Vol. 3 @ Page 349,</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
