<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3168"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">L. A. Wood et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5287</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-209 to BR41-210</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thos E Bramlette Gov. State of Ky.</p>
<p>Your petitioners, would respectfully present, that one Josiah Eaton is now in your State prison under a Sentence for four years; that he has already Served over two years of that time; and in as much as the law has been vindicated, and as we learn that at the time of his conviction and ever since he has evinced the plainest proof of Sorrow and repentance for the past, and of a determination to endeavor to live honestly in the future; and as we learn that it is the almost unanimous desire of the citizens of New Albany Ind, the place of his residence to have him pardoned and released that he may return to his family; we do most earnestly entreat your excellency to pardon him. We learn that he has a wife and 5 helpless children in New Albany; that his wife is a most excellent, amiable, and industrious woman; that She has for about 3 years Supported herself and children, mainly, by washing and laboring by days work; that She has struggled along with her hard lot manifesting a courage, fortitude, <hi rend="str">and</hi> a heroism and rectitude of purpose most prais-worthy<pb/>
<lb/>indeed; all of which has won the esteem and Sympathy of her acquaintances and enlisted them in her behalf. And it is mainly on her account and that of her children, and because we learn that it is the desire ^of^ the citizens there, that we pray you to pardon him. He is a good mechanic and can, and we trust he doubtless will make a good living for his family if permitted to return to them.</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>L. A. Wood
<lb/>Phil Tomppert Jr
<lb/>Rd. F. Baird
<lb/>Ed Meg Curry
<lb/>J L Duncan
<lb/>James R. W. Smith
<lb/>Ben M. Harney
<lb/>A M Stout
<lb/>D. M. Rodman</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
