<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1691"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">H. W. Goode et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6328</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-174</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency the Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>We the undersigned petitioners would respectfully represent that our County man James. B. Lee was found guilty under an Indictment at the Equity &amp; Criminal Court of Warren County at its <date when="1863-08">August Term 1863,</date> of the offense of permitting Spiritous Liquors on his premises ^to be sold^ and a fine assessed against him in the sum of $60 -- </p>
<p>The fine assessed against him is not contrary to the cause of the Law, under the facts in <hi rend="str">the</hi> his case but as we believe that when the resulting concequences, in enforcing this penalty, upon M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Lee in this case, is presented to your Excellency, that the executive clemency will be extended to him -- The principal fact in his case is about this: -- There was a large gathering at spring near his house for the purpose of having a Barbacue &amp; a Union meeting, while M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Lee was rejoicing with his friends, others were selling Liquir -- at his house -- we do not believe that M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Lee was engaged in or had any thing to do with the selling</p>
<p>M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Lee is a poor man with a large family -- and, physically a cripple and is a Law abiding citizen. If the fine is enforced upon him. the result will be hard upon him &amp; his family. In All obedience we ask that your Excellency pardon him of this fine</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>signed
<lb/>H W Goode
<lb/>Joseph Miller
<lb/>Jacob Miller
<lb/>B F harrison
<lb/>James Miller<pb/>
<lb/>C H Crabb
<lb/>Isaac miller
<lb/>Wm H Jones
<lb/>A C Floyd
<lb/>William H Miller
<lb/>James T Graham
<lb/>N C young
<lb/>W Brutcher
<lb/>W E Floyd
<lb/>W T Watt
<lb/>J. L. Watt
<lb/>A. D. Roberts
<lb/><unclear/><unclear/>
<lb/>C H Lewis
<lb/>James A Jones
<lb/>N W. M. Lewis
<lb/>John G Lewis
<lb/>F E Lewis
<lb/>W <hi rend="underline">T</hi> Davis</p>
<p><hi rend="str">Wm</hi> <hi rend="str">H Jones</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
