<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0997"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Q. Roberts to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10465</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-58 to MG20-59</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-04-05">5 April 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville <date when="1861-04-05">april 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>B. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin Esqr.
<lb/>Govr of Ky</p>
<p>Dear sir Mr John Doyle who Keeps a Grocery store second Door East of my residence &amp; on the Corner of Green &amp; 5th sts informs me He has been fined for selling spirits without License, His license to sell Groceries entitles entitles Him to sell spirits by the quart or Gallen, He has been in ^the^ practice of Crediting some &amp; Had been selling Groseries &amp;C to some one who at last become bad pay &amp; ^refused to Cret Him &amp; He^ took umbrage at it &amp; (as I am informed) informed on Him making statements that some time or times He took money of Him for Drinks one thing I know and am Certain of, He Keeps a verry respectable Grocery store Keeps a quality and orderly House &amp; is an <hi rend="underline">Honest man</hi> &amp; a Good Citizen &amp; if He has violated the law He (I think) did not the spirit of the law. for I understand that it was not his wish to retail spirits by the small quantity, &amp; once or twice doing even if he did is not in my mind a violation of the spirit of the law at any rate he is an industrious worthy Honest Irishman &amp; I do beleave he aught not to ^be^ fined He is ^a^ poor man exerting Himself to suppor Himself &amp; family, I do wish you may think with me &amp; Remit His fine &amp; oblige an</p>
<p>old Friend
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Tho</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> Q Roberts</hi><pb/></p>
<p>P. S. M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Doyle is a popular man with all who know him he got his start as I understand from His good honest principals &amp; I do realy Hope you will releave him of this fine</p>
<p>T Q R<pb/></p>
<p>Louisville City Cy
<lb/>$60 } Tipling
<lb/>Jno. Doyle
<lb/>Remission
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-04-09">Apr 9. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
