<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0483"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Mark R. Boyd and Nathaniel Wilmot to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9951</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-250 to MG18-251</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Rockcastle County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-07-01">1 July 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>B Magoffin</p>
<p>Sir, your petitioners Mark R. Boyd and Nathaniel Wilmot respectfully state to your Excellency that on the <gap/> day of <gap/> 18 <gap/> one Reobert Altum of this county was arrested by Robert Capps Constable of Rockcastle County for an assault and, that they signed a bond for said Altums appearance before Milton Hurst a Justice of the peace and that on the day specified in said Bond, they appeared with said Altum at the office of said Hurst -- but the said Capps as Constable afsd Returned the case before one Tolbert Bowman a justice of the peace -- and in consequence of said Altum not appearing at the said Bowmans, the Bond was returned to the Circuit Court <hi rend="str">&amp; <unclear/></hi> forfeited and judgement rendered agst them for the sum of $100 -- &amp; costs at the <date when="1860-07">July ^Term afsaid court 1860^</date> </p>
<p>Now they state that they have paid off the <hi rend="str">Commonwealths</hi> entire costs and there is nothing remains unpaid but the Commonwealths part of said fine -- which they ask<pb/>
<lb/>your Excellency to remit they state that they are poor men; and not able to pay the full amt, besides they think that they were unjustly dealt with by the Court -- from the fact that they took the man to the place stipulated in their bond -- M<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Vernon Ky <date when="1861-07-01">July 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1861</date>. ^The state that Execution is now in hands of the sheriff &amp; their property levied upon wherefore they pray speedily relief^</p>
<p>M R Boyd
<lb/>N. Wilmot</p>
<p>Sworn to before m by M R Boyd this <date when="1861-07-01">1<hi rend="sup">st </hi>July 1861</date></p>
<p>E. F. Fisk <hi rend="underline">c R c c</hi></p>
<p>We the undersigned believe the statements made in the foregoing petition are true &amp; hope relief will be granted</p>
<p>W H Rictly
<lb/>E T Fisk
<lb/>J. G. <hi rend="underline">Hazlewood</hi></p>
<p>I think the fine ought to be remitted by all means</p>
<p>J, Newcum</p>
<p>I heard the trial upon which the forgoing Judgment was rendered &amp; honestly believe the Judgment was an error of the court &amp; therefore &amp; because of hard times &amp; the petitioners being poore hope &amp; believe that Your exelency will remit the fine</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">E. F. Fisk. C. R. c. c</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Rockcastle Cir. ct
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/>$100 } Forfeited Recognizance
<lb/>M. R. Boyd &amp; Nath<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Wilmot
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-01-14">Jany 14 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
