<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0291"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">T. J. Jenkins et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9759</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-284</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Ballard County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excllency Hon<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> B Magoffin</p>
<p>John Benyer of Ballard County Ky Keeps a Ferry across the ohio river. and in connection with it has pleasure Garden on the Kentucky side Where the young &amp; gay frequently visit &amp; Swing dance &amp; indulge in other innocent amusements, One day whilst a company were there enjoying themselves a Gentleman in the company Said to Benyer he must have some brandy. Benyer politely asked him in, set out some brandy. the Gentlman drank three down a dime &amp; went out Benyer telling him to take his money that he did not <hi rend="str">Sell</hi> want it &amp; did not Sell his brandy &amp; refused to take it under the above State of facts Benyer was taken before the county Judge of Ballard County &amp; by him fined Sixty dollars wrongfully &amp; as we fear maliciously. We the undersigned citizens of Ballard county Ky Know Said Benyer &amp; take pleasure in bearing testamony to his good ^character^ &amp; do not beleave that he would intentionally violate the laws of his country,</p>
<p>We recommend him to your Executive clemency &amp; hope that you will remit the fine so unjustly imposed upon<pb/>
<lb/>him</p>
<p>T. J. Jenkins
<lb/>F D. Bailey
<lb/>W H Russell
<lb/>G W Boyd
<lb/>C. Rollings
<lb/>J H Bishop
<lb/>V A M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cutchen
<lb/>D. F. Fraser
<lb/>W, L, Skinner
<lb/>J M Tisdal
<lb/>Jno E Henderson
<lb/>M. L. Christian
<lb/>W A. Jefferson
<lb/>J. P. Jones
<lb/>R Frost</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
