<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0492"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William B. Jones to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4611</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-283 to BR9-284</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-02-02">2 February 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Bowling Green Ky <date when="1864-02-02">2 Febry 1864</date>
<lb/>Gov Thos E Bramlette
<lb/>Frankfort Ky.
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>Your predecessor Gov Robinson on or about the <date when="--07-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of July</date> last, remitted two fines which had been assessed against D R Hendrick in the Warren Equity and Criminal Court, in each case for keeping a Tippling house. The remission as I learn described the Judgements as being for $60.. each.</p>
<p>There is a mistake in the matter, as the only two Judgments in Said Court against MR Hendrick for keeping Tippling house was for $200.. ^each^ rendered an Indictments, charging him with the offense in each case of keeping a Tippling house for three months at one time.</p>
<p>I know that <hi rend="str">the</hi> it was intended in the petition forwarded to Gov Robinson to embrace and ask a remission of the Judgments in the two Judgments of $200.. each, as the petition was presented to me, and my endorsement Sought of the project. I refused to sign or endorse it, principally on account of the rule I have adopted, never to recommend any thing of the kind, unless it be a case presenting considerably more than ordinary reasons for executive clemency.<pb/></p>
<p>As it is, Mr H desires no benefit from the remission. And I think now, that as it was doubtless the intention of the Governor to remit the two Judgments which still stand in full force against Mr Hendrick, it would be Just, and proper that you remit the two Judgements of $200.. each. For these reasons I ask that it be done. Send the remissions to me at <hi rend="underline">Franklin</hi> Ky.</p>
<p>I will ask you to remit another Judgt so far as you have power. I believe the only case in which I have interceded, for three years, but regarding it a meritorious case. I make the request. The facts briefly are these.</p>
<p>George H Bell became the bail of Wesley Brown in the Simpson Equity &amp; Criminal Court (Just before the rebellion) for $500.. Brown went off, and joined the rebellian, and his band was forfeited. Bell died in the fall or early in the winter of <date when="1861">1861</date>, and Since then I have taken Judgment against his Administrator on Said forfeited bond for $500.. Mr Bell was killed at his own house, by a mob a portion of whom were Commited with Buckners Army then located at Bowling Green, and on the Same night that he was killed his dwelling house a valuable new brick mansion was burned and<pb/></p>
<p>destroyed by the same mob. Since then and very recently, during a considerable conflagration in our town (Franklin) Bell's heirs, lost a valuable house on the public Square, not insured. Their losses from the two fires were quite heavy. Bells heirs are a widow and several children ^most of whom are infants^ Same of the children afflicted permanently, and incurably, mentally, and physically. Bell's estate although entirely Solvent, is much reduced, in value by Said fires, and from other consideration. His Slaves having become under the operation of the rebellian almost valueless.</p>
<p>For the foregoing reasons, I think it Just that so much of Said Judgment as your have power over, Should be remitted</p>
<p>I therefore ask, that the Judgment of the Simpson Equity, and Criminal Court rendered against the Administrator of George H Bell deceased on a forfeited bail bond be remitted. Send the remission to me at <hi rend="underline">Franklin Ky</hi>. This application is made with the knowledge &amp; consent of the Admr &amp; heirs.</p>
<p>Respectfully &amp;c.
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> B Jones Atty
<lb/>for the Comth
<lb/>4th District<pb/></p>
<p>Warren Equity &amp; Crim Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>D. R. Hendrick</p>
<p>Send the Tipling Remissions as requested by Mr Jones Atty for Com<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi>
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette</p>
<p>Simpson Equity &amp; c
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Admr of
<lb/>Geo. H. Bell
<lb/>$500 -- 
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/><date when="1864-02-04">4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Feby 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
