<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2573"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Timothy King, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7210</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-113 to BR16-114</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>At the <date when="1865-05">May Term 1865</date> of the Jefferson Circuit Court, Timothy King was Indicted for Murder, at the same term he was tried &amp; convicted, upon the following testimony</p>
<p>Jas Gill Coronor</p>
<p>The pistol shot wound caused the death of deceased.</p>
<p>Bridget Casey. I am sixteen years of age.</p>
<p>I came to the house of Bradlies about 7 Oclock in the evening of the illumination. I saw King the accused there. I left in a short time in company with deceased to view the illumination &amp; remained about an hour, &amp; then returned to Bradlies, While at Bradlies deceased invited the accused to drink &amp; he declined pleasantly,</p>
<p>I then left Bradlies in company with deceased for my home, we went up Bullit street to main up main to third where deceased<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">2</note>
<lb/>was Killed.</p>
<p>Between Bullit &amp; fourth streets I met King Comming <hi rend="str">coming</hi> down main street half way between Bullit &amp; fourth streets,</p>
<p>As deceased &amp; my Self was crossing third street. I heard the report of a pistol &amp; <hi rend="str">accused</hi> deceased said he was shot, I turned immediately &amp; recognized King who ran down third street,</p>
<p>Accused had on a Blouse Coat &amp; white hat at Bradlies &amp; also on main street,</p>
<p>I did not see any one near at the time of the shooting except accused,</p>
<p>Neither accused nor deceased had any claims on me I was not the sweet heart of either, there was no cause for Jealousy, when we left the house of Bradlies we left King talking to Mrs Bradley, we walked at an ordinary g<hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>ait from the time we left Bradlies untill deceased was shot on the corner of third &amp; main, we did not stop on the way,</p>
<p>My father &amp; Mother live in shepardsville. Ky, but for the last three years I have<pb/>
<lb/>lived away from home, &amp; for nearly all this time I have resided in Cincinnati Ohio.</p>
<p><note place="header">3</note>
<lb/><note place="left margin">2</note>
<lb/>Peters Tassa</p>
<p>I was near the person when he fired the pistol that caused the death of the deceased, as soon as he fired he ran down third street. I can not say that the accused resembled in size the person that did the shooting, he had on a blouse coat &amp; white hat, I do not recognize accused as the one that shot deceased</p>
<p><note place="left margin">3</note>
<lb/>Mrs Story.</p>
<p>I was walking up main street in company with Miss Davis &amp; we were very near only a few feet distant from the person that fired the pistol, I do not recognize the accused as the person that fired the pistol. As soon as the pistol was fired the person ran down Third Street. At the time of the shooting a man was standing on the north east corner of third &amp; main.<pb/></p>
<p><note place="header">4</note>
<lb/>Mary Cummins</p>
<p>I saw accused at the house of Bradlies on the night of the murder, &amp; he said he would be revenged on some one that was somthing to me in less than two weeks. when Miss casey &amp; deceased were viewing the illumination accused fired a pistol, I heard the report of a great many pistols that night as it was the illumination.</p>
<p>I was examined in the city court when King had his examining trial but I did not make this statement there, The deceased was nothing to me. Accused did not leave the house of Bradlies untill deceased &amp; Bridget Casey had time to get on to main street, I have been living at the same place <hi rend="str">with</hi> with Miss Casey for four days before the trial, I have a home of my own &amp; I cant tell what made me go to the house of Bridget Casey. Bridget Casey was a Servant in the house</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
