<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0478"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John F. Fisk to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4597</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-257 to BR9-258</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="--01-04">4 January </date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Cov Ky <date when="--01-04">Jany 4<hi rend="sup">th</hi></date> <hi rend="str">1863</hi>
<lb/>Gov Bramlette,
<lb/>Sir,</p>
<p>I have known Mr Wertz for many years, as a hard working honorable law abiding man. I was present at the trial, one witness only was called, who testified that he had seen Wertz sell by the half Gallon, but never less, I am satisfied he thought he had authority to sell by the half gallon. Perhaps you may have noticed that the law is a little confused on that point. Some lawyers here were of that opinion, but the Judge ruled differently I was not an<hi rend="str">y</hi> atty in the case. I willingly hoever make this statement in behalf of an honorable man with a large family struggling to support them. I hope you will grant his prayer</p>
<p>Respectfully Yours
<lb/>John F. Fisk</p>
<p>I was present at the trial and heard the evidence, and arguments upon the law, and believe the Executive clemency would properly be exercised in this case. There is a difference in opinion among the bar as to the right to sell by the half gallon or more, and a wide spread belief in the community that no license is required to sell liquor in such quantities.</p>
<p>John P. Harrison<pb/></p>
<p>L. Wertz
<lb/>Petition
<lb/>Gov. of Kentucky<figure type="hr"/><pb/></p>
<p>To his his Excellency -- 
<lb/>Governor Bramlette</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Leonard Wertz would respectfully reprepresent to your Honor that at the present term of the Kenton County Circuit Court he was fined Sixty dollars for selling Whiskey, that he sold twice to his neighbors one half gallon Each time and thought that the had a right to do so but under the instruction of the Court the Jury found him guilty and he was fined as above, he says that he is law abiding man, and that if he had known he was violating the law he would not have done so, He further states that he is poor having an affected Wife and six (6) small children and if he has to pay said fine it will nearly break him up.</p>
<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays your honor to Exercise your Clemency, remit so much of said fine as you can and your petitioner will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p>Leonard Wietz</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Covington Ky are acquainted With Leonard Wietz the foregoing petitioner and will state the we beleive the statements in the petition are true</p>
<p>S. C Perrin<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Petitioners names
<lb/>H. Crout
<lb/>P Weinde
<lb/>Philipps Lowes
<lb/>John Cleby
<lb/>H. W. Schleutker
<lb/>T. G. Brinkmann
<lb/>L <unclear/>
<lb/>John H. Heingehold
<lb/>Henry Ortmann
<lb/>Martin Nordoff
<lb/>G Frerker
<lb/>Johny S Trinton
<lb/>Robards <unclear/>
<lb/>J C Howard
<lb/><unclear/> Butts
<lb/>W W Mosher
<lb/>R. Richardson
<lb/>J. G. Carlisle
<lb/>Geo G Perkins
<lb/>A H Herod
<lb/>W. E. Arthur
<lb/>W. H. Tarvin
<lb/>B. Vaghan
<lb/>Berry Moore
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Petitioners names<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>I am not conversant with the facts in this case yet I know the petitioner and take pleasure in saying that he is an honest industrious man, striving hard to 
<lb/>support his family I trust therefore that his prayer may be granted</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>B. D. Foley</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
