<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0726"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Matthew Wilson, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10194</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-130</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-03-18">18 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Mat Wilson States that he was well acquainted with Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> S Dawson the accused he was very young had no education, and naturally of weak mind He never heard him suspected of crime before and from all the information that he could get in regrard ^his character^ <hi rend="str">to <unclear/></hi> he believed that ^he was^ honest, and thinks if he had Stood his trial he would been acquited. He says the Sister who Baild him are very poor and humble, their only property being an <unclear/> interest in a small tract of land of about thirty five acres, and five or six <unclear/> They are orphans their Father and Mother both are dead and they had no one to protect or aid them, and they are unable to pay this Judgment without the Sale of their land, which will be <unclear/> him I would consider it an act of great clemency in your excellency to remit this Judgment and believe under the circumstances that it ought to be done.</p>
<p>Matthew Wilson</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Mat Wilson on the the <date when="1861-03-18">18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of March 1861</date>.</p>
<p>W. W. Howard D C</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
