<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0957"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Edwin S. Craig, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5076</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-474</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>New Albany, Floyd County, Indiana</placeName>
    <date when="1864-06-01">1 June 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The Commonwealth
<lb/>vs }
<lb/>Wright, Thomas &amp;c</p>
<p>The Evidence Substantially in the above case Showed that Wright was located in New Albany Ia: and the two men implicated with him by name Thomas &amp; Henry appeared early in the morning at the Store of M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Ullman on Main Street when a boy was sweeping the said store house and had swept out the trash on to the Street. one of them asked him if they could buy some goods: He replied that Mr Ullman was away an <unclear>else</unclear> had came down to the store; but they could examine the goods and when the Sales men Should come in they could make their purchase: One of the parties remained below and the other went up stairs and whilst up there he managed to place in the pockets of an amount He wore a number of pieces of silk; the pockets were large &amp; opened under the skirt-like a hunting coat: the parties took a hack and even troad to New Albany and Wright who in New Albany (and not with them on this side of the river) sold several of the pieces of silk to Merchants in New Albany. Wright was taken to<pb/>
<lb/>New Albany to be tried there for receiveing stolen property, the other two men were arrested here, for stealing the goods; Wright was well known to the Police of this City to be an experienced thief; and there can be but little doubt that He planned the Larceny &amp; induced the other two men to carry it out: this is my recollection of the matter and I believe to be substantially correct: I do not know which of the two men made the proposition to buy goods <unclear/> which of them went upstair; I make this statement from the <unclear/>, of this little boy:</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/><hi rend="underline">E. S. Craig</hi></p>
<p>Mr Craig was the Commonwealth's Attorney at the time of the trial referred to in the above statement, The indictment on which Geo Thomas was convicted &amp; sent to the penetentiary, was for stealing goods from Ulman. Said Thomas true name as, I now learn, <hi rend="str">was</hi> is Silas S. Greenman. I was present at the trial &amp; defended him &amp; am thus enabled to state as I now do, that s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Thomas or Greenman was the party who remained down stairs as spoke of by M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Craig.</p>
<p><date when="1864-06-01">June 1 1864</date>
<lb/>Robert F Baird</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
