<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2510"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Ben S. Griffin et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7147</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-17 to BR16-18</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thomas E Bramlet, Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Ben S Griffin would respectfully represent to you that William Swincher was held to bail by the Judge of the Police Court for the City of Louisville, to answer for a felony. at the <date when="1865-09">September term of the Jefferson Circuit Court 1865</date> in the sum of three hundred dollars. and security in the like amount.</p>
<p>Your petitioner was induced by the constant importunities of the mother of said Swincher, (an aged and infirm widow who was mainly dependent upon him her said sons labor for support) to become bail for him (said Wm Swincher) for his appearance at the <date when="1865-09">September</date> term of the Court aforesaid, at the term aforesaid.</p>
<p>Your petitioner being well acquainted with the family of said Swincher, and assured by them that said William Swincher would appear in said Court at the term aforesaid, acted in the premises through charitable motives alone in becoming Bail aforesaid.</p>
<p>At the seting of the Court aforesaid in <date when="1865-09">September 1865</date> as aforesaid the said William Swincher failed to appear to answer. -- a forfeiture of said Bond was therefore taken and your petitioner made liable therefor. A Judgment was at the last term of said Court rendered against your petitioner for three hundred dollars, the amount of said Bond.</p>
<p>Your petitioner is man upwards of sixty years old, and a Cripple, -- makes his living by labor as a Carpenter, and if Compelled to pay the amount of aforesaid will be seriously injured. He therefore in view of the forgoing facts, Prays <hi rend="underline">your</hi> Excellency to exorcise the Clemency pertaining<pb/>
<lb/>to your perogative, by remetting all that portion of said forfeiture and Judgment you have the power to remit, and your petitioner will ever pray &amp;</p>
<p>B S Griffin
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>William G. Reasor
<lb/>attorney for the City of Louisville Ky
<lb/>Jos. Clement Justice of the peace Jeff Co Ky
<lb/>James Harris
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W F Barret</hi>
<lb/>Will, P, Thomasson
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Sam Matlock</hi>. J. P. J. C
<lb/><hi rend="underline">C. Ripley</hi>
<lb/>W. R. Thompson</p>
<p>I do not Know any thing the facts stated, except that M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Griffin is a lame man who lives by his work, and is not as well off as he once was. I shall be glad if he can be let off.</p>
<p>Henry Pirtle
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J. B Gaither att
<lb/>A V Walker
<lb/>Philip Tomppert Mayor<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Ben S. Griffin
<lb/>$300
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Remit</hi>
<lb/><date when="1865-10-24">24 Oct /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
