<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-003-0120"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">H. Taylor to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1637</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR5-207 to BR5-208</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Maysville, Mason County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-20">20 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Maysville Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-09-20">Septr. 20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>.
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Bramlette.</p>
<p>Allow me to refer you to two resolutions of the Ky Legislature the 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> approved <date when="1860-02-11">Feby 11 1860</date> Act <date when="1859">1859</date>'<date when="1860">60</date> Vol 1. page 180 -- the other approved <date when="1861-01-29">Jany 29<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861</date>, Acts called Session <date when="1861">1861</date> page 49, providing Gold medals for the surviving officers and soldiers of the Ky Volunteers ^who were^ present and participated in the battle of Lake Erie. These resolutions have not yet been executed.</p>
<p>I am perhaps somewhat to blame for the delay as Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Magoffin once gave me a commission to procure the medals. At the time the resolution were passed there were three survivors of the Ky Vol engaged in that battle to wit:</p>
<p>James Artus Esq<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> living in the vicinity of this city.<pb/></p>
<p>D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> William T. Taliaferro formerly of Ky now a resident of Cin. Ohio.</p>
<p>John Tucker formerly of this County removed to Ohio -- and since died.</p>
<p>I am personally acquainted with all three, knew them well and there can be no doubt of their <hi rend="str">being</hi>having been present, and engaged in the battle -- </p>
<p>At the passage of the resolution then three were supposed to be the only survivors -- About a year afterward Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Magoffin delivered to me a letter from John Norris at Petersburg Boone Cty Ky claiming that he was in the battle also -- which I enclose herewith -- as also a letter form James Artus in relation to Norris.</p>
<p>James Artus was a Sergeant of his company and was wounded.</p>
<p>D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> T. Taliaferro was a corporal in his Company -- Tucker &amp; Norris were privates I take the liberty of enclosing a letter from D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Taliaferro to myself upon the subject of the medals= I should have executed<pb/>
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Magoffins commission, but for the troubles which came upon the country, and as in many other instances drew my attention from it.</p>
<p>One of these men James Artus is my neighbor and is now quite an old man of great worth, and I should be gratified if he could get his as early as possible.</p>
<p>D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Taliaferro is a younger man than Artus, a personal friend -- and a physician of high repute in Cin -- We will see from his letter the interest he takes in it.</p>
<p>Tucker is dead -- I have heard many anecdotes related of his brave conduct in that battle -- His family reside just across the river in Ohio, and will be gratified at this memorial of their father.</p>
<p>I am not acquainted with Norris. Such appropriate desires as your taste may dictate, inscribed with the name of the source, presented by the state of Ky. &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi><pb/>
<lb/>in suitable language as may suggest itself to you -- Perry's celebrated dispatch to the secretary of war, "We have met the enemy, and they are ours" might be appropriatly inscribed -- though I never was <unclear>struck</unclear> the good taste of the dispatch. I would be greatly pleased if your excellency could find time to have the medals prepared, as early as possilbe for fear some of the others should die.</p>
<p>I am Very Respectfully
<lb/>Your Obt Sert
<lb/><hi rend="underline">H,, Taylor</hi>.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
