<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-003-0073"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">A. Bradshaw to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1590</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR5-130 to BR5-131</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Paducah, McCracken County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-02-09">9 February 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>No one here seems to know the extent of authority given by the sec. of War. to the officer recruiting this sable Regiment, whether by impressment or voluntary enlistment and whether or not it is left to the discretion of the officer, whose slaves shall and whose shall not be taken, in fine to loose and bind whom he pleases, Indeed it little signifies whether the means resorted to for filling up this Regiment be strictly coercive or not, The artifices employed in the way of threats, promises &amp;c. &amp;c. Toward an ignorant and timid class through instrumentality of the most vicious (always the most active and forward in such cases, are equivalent to compulsion. Possibly cupidity and avarice may be a strong motive, We do not know what sum (if any) is is allowed for each recruit, This is true the encampment and vicinity is fast filling up with Women, babies, boys and girls of all ages, the wives children kindred &amp;c of the enlisted soldiers, all of whom living in squalor and idleness are to be supported from some quarter. Not unfrequently a squad of these semi-baboons driving a Gov. Waggon up to some house either in the city or country and in the most insolent manner proceed to pack up whatever they may choose to claim as theirs, and return in triumph to the rendezvous of the Nations defenders -- </p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>Your Obt Servt
<lb/>A. Bradshaw<pb/></p>
<p>Paducah Ky <date when="1864-02-09">Feby 9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Gov. Bramlette</p>
<p>Sir In connection with or in confirmation of the facts and representations made by D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> S. P. Cope in a communication of this date to your Excellency, setting forth one example of many wrongs and grievances to which the Citizens of this section are subjected, in regard to the impressment of their slaves into the military service of the U. S. A work which has just begun, and thus far seems to be conducted without any respect whatever to the status of parties, I. E. their loyalty or disloyalty, I would respectfully state that on yesterday I met a Boy belonging to D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Cope, only a few hours after he had been sworn in and donned the uniform of the Regiment, D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Cope being present stated to him distinctly, that if he had taken this step of his own accord and free will, without intimidation threats of compulsion in any form or degree, then he had no more to say on the subject, but if otherwise, he felt it his duty and his right to seek redress in the best practicable way, The Boy disclaimed any disposition or wish to leave him or his service and stated that he was approached on the market square<pb/>
<lb/>while engaged in his ordinary duties) by several armed Negro soldiers and forced into the encampment against his will and consent and there compelled to take the necessary oath as an enlisted soldier, and if he did not take it voluntariy, he would be compelled.</p>
<p>Then, lest he might feel under some restraint or disinclined to communicate his sincere feelings on the subject in the presence of D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Cope because of the decided stand heretofore taken by him, notwithstanding the many, (I might say) almost daily opportunities for the past 2 or 3 years of deserting his home with perfect impunity, I called him aside and assured him he had nothing to apprehend from a frank full nad candid statement of all the motives and reasons that prompted him to the course he had taken. He reiterated all that he had said to D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Cope and others present and to the question put to him by me, whether if left to his choice he would remain in the army or return to his home, He replied that <hi rend="underline">he would return to his home</hi> -- </p>
<p>Very Respectfully &amp;c
<lb/><hi rend="underline">A. Bradshaw</hi> </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
