<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3321"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. H. Covington et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5440</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-156 to BR42-157</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Calloway County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned neighbors and countymen of W A &amp; &amp; Thos L M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>quiston ^of Calloway County^ would represent that Thos L Mcquiston in the year <date when="1861">1861</date> being young and a mere boy seeing his neighbors and comrads joining the Rebel Service and being persuaded to do so did join the regular Rebel army and remained with it and fought at the front and that in the course of discharging his duties as such soldier he was detailed to go with Captain Wainwright to capture horses clothing &amp;c in <date when="1865-03">March 1865</date> and in executing that order Some <unclear/> and other things necessary for the use and comfort of the army and nothing whatever for private gain by him and that after the surrender which occurred some after the capture or impressment of said articles the same not having been used owing to the surrender such of said articles as were on hand were returned.</p>
<p>That afterwards one of the shopkeepers from which the goods were taken at Leesburg in Harrison County Ky provoked a difficulty with said Thomas and not making any advantage he got but a Summary proceeding in examining court had him bound in a bond of $500 which was afterwards<pb/>
<lb/>reduced to $250.</p>
<p>That R L Ellison of this county at the instance of W A Mcquiston the father of Thomas went and bailed him out as said Thomas had no means to deposit in lieu of bail. That no indictment was found agaisnt him at the last term of the Circuit Court for that county but the bond was taken for forteited and Summons ordered and unless relief can be had the securities R L Ellison and J S Boyd will have the same to pay.</p>
<p>That both W A Mcquiston and his said son were before during and Since the war honorable and restectable persons the young man having nothing not even a horse to ride to Cynthiana in discharge of his bond ^distance^ about 500 miles That said W A Mcquiston's means were before limited and living near fort Heiman Ky while the Rebels occupied the place they were much reduced by said troops.</p>
<p>That he has a large family who need his attention and all the means he can raise and the reason Thos did not appear in discharge of his bond was that his friends<pb/>
<lb/>could not go to assist him and he had no means either of conveyance or to procure counsel and assistance and at the time said court was held the said Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi>. L. Mcquiston had a severe carbuncle and several Boils upon his body and labouring under severe cold and was unable to travel to attend said circuit court We therefore humbly and respectfully petition your Excellency to remit the amount claimed on said forfeited recognizance, and that the said Thos L Mcquiston be also pardon from any or the supposed offence with which he is so charged believing as <hi rend="str">the</hi> we do that the interests fo the Commonwealth adn the good citizens will not be injured thereby</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W H Covington Rep
<lb/>Joshua Z Sledd
<lb/>J C Span
<lb/>J C M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Elrath
<lb/>P M. Boaz
<lb/>H F Bowman
<lb/>Isaac Keys
<lb/>A B Stubblefield
<lb/>Saml M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Knight
<lb/>J. B. England
<lb/>W J Stubblefield
<lb/>H Hardy
<lb/>E. H. Covington
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi>. H. Curd
<lb/>D Mathewson
<lb/>M Clayton
<lb/>P. C. Linn
<lb/>J. W. Fergeson
<lb/><cb n="2"/>P. A. Stilly
<lb/>John M Stilley
<lb/>Cyrus Owen
<lb/>J H Nest
<lb/>John Forrest
<lb/>G W Beely
<lb/>A. B. Kinley
<lb/>R. M. Owen
<lb/>A. F. Stilly
<lb/>J. M. Beucy
<lb/>W L Stubblefield
<lb/>T. M. Stilly
<lb/>J M Mooney
<lb/>O. H. Bucy
<lb/>W C Bailley
<lb/>F P Crabtree
<lb/>George Wilson
<lb/>J J Waters<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Levi Campbell
<lb/>S. H. Wilson
<lb/>J. Wilson
<lb/>J. P. Wilson
<lb/>W.. H.. Bucy
<lb/>A. B. Sparkes
<lb/>J. A. Bucy
<lb/>J. M. Bucy
<lb/>C.H. Bucy
<lb/>B C Rowlett
<lb/>R C Shackleford
<lb/>R. N. Shackleford
<lb/>John ^his X mark^ Bucy
<lb/>G. D. Backus
<lb/>W. P. Stublefield
<lb/>J B Davidson
<lb/>J.. H Whitworth
<lb/>R. C. Stubblefield Jr
<lb/>J. T. Stubblefield
<lb/>G. T. Lawson
<lb/>G. G. Oury
<lb/>R. F. Nix
<lb/>D L Brandon
<lb/>Isaac Wesson
<lb/>B. Allbritten
<lb/>John S Oury
<lb/>A. J. Outland
<lb/>William Durham
<lb/>H Baburn
<lb/>J. H. Gocke
<lb/>B J Wesson
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J. W. Hutcheson
<lb/>P. P Worsham
<lb/>P F Lovins
<lb/>A Brannon
<lb/>John, G. Forrest
<lb/>J. S. Stubblefield
<lb/>M Hutchens
<lb/>Edmund Cook
<lb/>J. T. Thermon
<lb/>W C Stubblefield
<lb/>C. W. Almond
<lb/>J. S. Waters
<lb/>W. M. Cook
<lb/>S G Fakes
<lb/>Samuel Morgan
<lb/>J R Brinn
<lb/>John W Whitworth
<lb/>L B Lassiter
<lb/>Simeon Knight
<lb/>W. W. Bucy
<lb/>Jesse B.. Lassiter
<lb/>A J Elkins
<lb/>G. G. Morris
<lb/>J. J. Stubblefield
<lb/>B. F. Wilson
<lb/>R C Stubblefield
<lb/>R. M. Montgomery
<lb/>B B Stubblefield
<lb/>Jas Jones</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
