<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-007-0077"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas E. Bramlette, Justice of the Peace, Robert Jones</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1742</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Appointments by the Governor, Civil Appointments, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR1-469</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-12-08">8 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Commission/Appointment</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>IN THE NAME AND BY THE AUTHORITY OF
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky,
<lb/><figure type="seal"><ab>KENTUCKY
<lb/>UNITED WE STAND DIVIDED WE FALL</ab></figure>
<lb/>THOMAS E. BRAMLETTE,
<lb/>GOVERNOR OF SAID COMMONWEALTH.</p>
<p>To all whom these Presents shall come, Greeting:
<lb/>Know Ye, That Robert Jones having been duly appointed JUSTICE OF THE PEACE, for Owen County, in District, No. 9 In the place of Robert Garvey refused to qualify, I hereby invest him with full power and authority to execute and discharge the duties of the said office according to law: And to have and to hold the same, with all the rights and emoluments thereunto legally appertaining, until his successor is duly qualified according to law.</p>
<p><figure type="seal"/>In Testimony Whereof, I have caused these letters to be made patent and the Seal of the Commonwealth to be hereunto affixed. Done at Frankfort, the <date when="1863-12-08">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Dec, in the year of our Lord, one thousand eight hundred and 63</date>, and in the 72<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> year of the Commonwealth.</p>
<p>Tho. E. Bramlette
<lb/>BY THE GOVERNOR:
<lb/>E. L. VanWinkle, Secretary of State.
<lb/>By Jas R Page
<lb/>Asst Sec</p>
<p>Commonwealth Office -- WM. E. HUGHES, State Printer.<pb/>
<lb/>Kentucky Owen County Sct
<lb/>To His Excellency Gov Bramlette</p>
<p>The undersigned would respectfully state that owing to old age ill health and <hi rend="str">other</hi> pressing personal engagements he is unable to attend to the duties of the office of Justice of the Peace in District No 9 in Owen county -- he therefore most respectfully declines to accept of said office <date when="1864-04-11">April 11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date></p>
<p>Robert Jones</p>
<p>Owen Co
<lb/>Resignation of R. Jones
<lb/>J P.
<lb/>&amp;
<lb/>appointed
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> W. Stewart
<lb/><date when="1864-04-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Apl/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
