<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2211"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Hudson Johnson et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9287</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-340</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To Bariah M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin
<lb/>Govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioners respectfully represent that at the <date when="--05">May Term</date> of the Hickman Criminal and Equity Court, John W. Long was indicted for the Murder of his Father William Long, the indictment was found at said Term and the defendent placed upon trial upon the fourth day after the finding of the Indictment by the Grand Jury.</p>
<p>During that time defendent was confined in the Jail of the County without any means to procure Counsel and without friends to assist him in his preperation for a trial; that Counsel was assigned the Defendent by the court, but owing to other professional engagements in said court they were prevented from giving such attention to the case as the importance of the case demanded.</p>
<p>Your petitioners state that there are several circumstances in this case which within opinion will recommend the case to Executive clemency -- these are, that, at the time of the killing both defendent and the deceased were very drunk and the finding of the Jury were upon the instructions of the court based entirely upon <hi rend="underline">implied malice</hi> that the defendent is without any means to remove his case to the court of appeals and is now under the Judgment of the court<pb/>
<lb/>sentenced to be hung upon the <date when="1860-08-10">10th day of August 1860</date>, Your petitioners therefore respectfully pray your interposition of clemency in his behalf, and that a commutation of his punishment be made to imprisonment in the Penitentiary for a Term of years. &amp; your petitioners will ever pray &amp;</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>Hudson Johnson
<lb/>E P Riley
<lb/>S W Owens
<lb/>T H Owens
<lb/>J. Oneal
<lb/>W. H. Courtney
<lb/>H v Hobbs
<lb/>B F Jackson
<lb/>R.. R.. Jackson
<lb/>R George
<lb/>John Gorge
<lb/>W. W. Jackson
<lb/>Wm George
<lb/>J. J. Walker
<lb/>J A Bellamy
<lb/>Joseph G Marspita
<lb/>J. C. Bery
<lb/>B F Zook
<lb/>E S Rollinson
<lb/>G W <unclear>Heinz</unclear>
<lb/>J C. Williams
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/>B. W. Sharp
<lb/>E. G. Farmer
<lb/>G. W. Hines
<lb/>Les Courteny
<lb/>H,, Jackson
<lb/>C. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kinney
<lb/>W Kennedy
<lb/>R M Ferguson
<lb/>T A Ferguson
<lb/>N Boswell
<lb/>E. E. Thomas william by
<lb/>W J Pennibaker
<lb/>R T. Milburn
<lb/>S N Calvert
<lb/>J N Tate
<lb/>J. Cook
<lb/>Alfred Allen
<lb/>David Harp
<lb/>J. A. M Ternon
<lb/>W S Jordan
<lb/>J. D Peebles<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>To the Govner of the Commonwealth of Ky
<lb/>Petition of citizens of Hickman County</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
