<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3039"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. J. Stubblefield et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5158</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR43-150 to BR43-151</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Calloway County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency. Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E. Bramlette
<lb/>Gov. of the Commonwealth of Kentucky:</p>
<p>Your petitioners, citizens, of Calloway County would most respectfully represent that Samuel Heast, a citizen of said County, was some twelve or eighteen months ago indicted in our Calloway Circuit Court for stealing W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi>" Hutchins Mule another citzen of said county.- That just before the present term of our circuit court now seting. he had discovered that he could make by a witness living in Illinois important proof. that by the witness he could prove an alibi. The Comlth Attorney discovered in the indictment against Said Heast Some mistake as to the ownership of said Mule, and that he had the Same dismissed. and a new bill formed against him for stealing Roland Hutchins mule at the present term of said court. Embracing one of Heasts witnesses and in a few minutes placed him on trial and while we do most earnestly protest against such hasty proceedings in cases of such vital importance and interest Still we have no words of censure for Either the jury in the case of the officers of the law. -In view of these facts and that M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Heast is a very poor man- has an<pb/>
<lb/>Excellent wife and Seven helpless children all of whom are dependent upon him for a support, and if deprived of his service must suffer. We also state that M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Hart has many Excellent qualitites therefore We most respectfully ask your Excellency to pardon, Mr Hart and restore him to his helpless family</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>W J Stubblefield
<lb/>R. Martin
<lb/>P. W. Evans Jury
<lb/>W C Bufford Jury
<lb/>T E Seatt Jury
<lb/>J F Walker Jury
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Wells Jury
<lb/>S. B. Parber
<lb/>E P Chandler
<lb/>J. P. Burbun
<lb/>W. M. Chandler
<lb/>John Odum
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi>" Odum
<lb/>N. G. Sate
<lb/>James Grasham
<lb/>A. B. Stubbs
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/>T. S. Gutent
<lb/>G. W. haynes
<lb/>Joel Gross
<lb/>W.H. Easlye
<lb/>B. F. henslee
<lb/>A. Ellett
<lb/>Jury
<lb/>O Willam Weather^ford^
<lb/>T. H. Stamps
<lb/>J H Morgan
<lb/>A. Henslee
<lb/>J H Mason
<lb/>C. Barnett
<lb/>G. W. Burnt
<lb/>J. A. Miller</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
