<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0981"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Smith Wingate, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5100</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-19 to BR11-20</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Owen County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="left margin">(1)</note> Please before James Pryor Judge of the Owen Circuit Court at the Court house in Owenton on the <date when="1853-11-14">14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Novr 1853</date>.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth of Ky Plff
<lb/>vs } Indictment
<lb/>Smith Wingate Deft</p>
<p>Be it remembered that heretofore to wit on the <date when="1853-05-04">4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of May 1853</date> came the Grand Jury Empannelled and sworn for Owen County and returned into Court an Indictment which is in the words and figures following to wit:</p>
<p>Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>Owen County &amp; Circuit } S. S</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of the Commonwealth of Ky impanneled Sworn &amp; charged as a grand inquest to enquire in and for the county of Owen upon their oath present that Smith Wingate gentleman late of Owen County did from the <date when="1853-01-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> day of January (A D) 1853</date>. thru months &amp; more in the county of Owen aforesaid Keep a tipling house by then and there selling whiskey and other spirituous liquors in said tippling house to be drank therein. he the said Wingate not then and there having license therefor: contrary to the form of the Statute in such case made and provided &amp; against the peac &amp; dignity of the commonwealth of Kentucky, and the Jurors aforesaid upon their oath<pb/>
<lb/><note place="left margin">(2)</note> aforesaid, do further present, that the afs<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Smith Wingate on the <date when="1853-01-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> day of January (A D) 1853</date>. in the county of Owen aforesaid, did keep a tippling house by then and there selling Whiskey and other spirituous liquors in said tippling house to be drank therein and did continue the keeping of said tippling house from that time until the <date when="1853-05-01">first day of may (A D) 1853</date>. being three months &amp; more he the said Wingate not then &amp; there having during any of that time a license therefor as by law required contrary to the form of the statute in such case made and provided &amp; against the peace &amp; dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>And the Jurors aforesaid upon their oath aforesaid do further present that the aforesaid Smith Wingate on the <date when="1853-03-01">1st day of March (A. D.) 1853</date>. in the county of Owen aforesaid did keep a tippling house by then and there selling Whiskey &amp; other spirituous liquors in said tippling house to be drank therein he the said Wingate not having then &amp; there license there for as by law required contrary to the form of the Statute in such case made &amp; provided &amp; against the peace &amp; dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>And the Jurors aforesaid upon their oath aforesaid do further present that the afs<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Smith Wingate in the County of Owen aforesaid on the <date when="1853-04-01">first day of April AD 1853</date>.<pb/>
<lb/><note place="left margin">(3)</note> did keep a tippling house without having a license therefor<hi rend="sup">s</hi> contrary to the form of the Statute in such case made &amp; provided and against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Ky.</p>
<p>Ro. Hutchinson C. Atty</p>
<p>Afterwards to wit at a circuit court held for Owen County at the courthouse in Owenton the following Judgement was rendered in this cause to wit;</p>
<p>"Came parties by their attornies and the defendant confessed Judgement on the first count of the Indictment herein, It is therefore considered by the court that the defendant make his fine to the Commonwealth by the payment of two Hundred dollars toegether with the costs by the Commonwealth in this behalf expended and that he be taken &amp;c On motion of atto for plff it is ordered that the indictment herein be dismissed as to the 2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> &amp; 3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> counts-</p>
<p>Kentucky Owent Circuit Ct Sct</p>
<p>I W H Sandford clerk of the Circuit Court for the county afs<hi rend="sup">d</hi> do certify that the foregoing 3 pages contain a true and complete transcript of the record and proceedings had in the <unclear>Court</unclear> therein named</p>
<p>W H Sandford Clk<pb/></p>
<p>Owen Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Smith Wingate
<lb/>$200.
<lb/>Remit
<lb/><date when="1865-01-03">3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Jany/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
