<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2146"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Josh Gamblin and Boon Hicks, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6783</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-374</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Graves County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Graves Circuit Court.
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>Against
<lb/>Josh Gamblin &amp; Boon Hicks</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Graves County in the name &amp; by the authority of the Commonwealth of the Kentucky accuse Joshua Gamblin &amp; Boon Hicks of the crime of Robbery committed as follows, Viz. the said Joshua Gamblin &amp; Boon Hicks on the <date when="1865-11-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of November 1865</date> in the County aforesaid did feloniously steal take &amp; carry away one mare of the value of One Hundred and twenty five dollars the property of John Pryor from the possession &amp; in the presence of the said John Pryor and against his will by putting him in fear of some immediate injury to his person against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>W. W. Tice Attorney for the Commonwealth of 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> J D</p>
<p>Information by John Pryor Thomas Hicks
<lb/>Endorsed</p>
<p>"Bail is fixed in the indictment at $500.<hi rend="sup">00</hi> for each defendant"</p>
<p>C S Marshall</p>
<p>"A True Bill Thomas Carman foreman</p>
<p>Filed <date when="1865-11-28">Nov. 28th 1865</date>. &amp; process issd <date when="1866-01-02">2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Jany 1866</date></p>
<p>W A Turner c g c c</p>
<p>A Copy attest W A Turner c g c c<pb/></p>
<p>This day J F Sayre Calvin Nance B N Stone B B Rhodes &amp; Frank Sayre made oath before me in person <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> that they were well acquainted with Boon Hicks. Whilst he was a Soldier in the Federal Army of the United States, that he belonged to the 15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Regiment Cavalry, that said Hicks made a good Soldier and was honorably discharged &amp; they know that he was acting under the orders of Federal Commanders when he was acting with parties Sent out to take horses guns &amp;C in this part of the State we do not know that he himself had engaged in the taking but he was frequently with persons as Soldiers who were Sent out for the purposes afsd <unclear/> J F &amp; Frank Sayre being in S<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Regiment</p>
<p>Commwlth
<lb/>vs } Robbery
<lb/>Hicks et al
<lb/>(Copy)</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
