<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1293"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Alford W. Picherell, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10761</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-181 to MG21-182</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Marion County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-01-28">28 January 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Alford Picherl being in custody charged with the offence of larceny and being admitted to bail in the Sum of one hundred dollars. Now we Elias Cundiff of Larue County Ky &amp; Hatten Harris &amp; John D Alvey &amp; Alexander Millen James Thompson of Larue County Thomas J Sweets for Nelson County Thomas Kincade of Larue county Ky hearby undertake that the above Alford Picherl will appear in the Marion circuit court on the first day of its next <date when="1861-08">august</date> term to answer Said charge and will at all times render himself amenable to the order and process of Said court in the prossecution of Said charge and if convicted will render himself <hi rend="str">amenable</hi> in execution thereof or if he Shall fail to perform either of these conditions that we will pay to the commonwealth of Kentucky the Sum of one hundred dollars</p>
<p>witness our hands this <date when="1861-07-19">19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of July 1861</date></p>
<p>A. W. Picherell
<lb/>Elias ^his X mark^ Cundiff
<lb/>J D Alvey
<lb/>Alexander Millen
<lb/>Hatten Harris
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Kincade
<lb/>Thomas J Sweets
<lb/>James Thompson</p>
<p>Sworn and subscribed before me as Justice of the peace of Marion County</p>
<p>A Bichet J P M C</p>
<p>And at a regular term of the marion circuit court towit <date when="1861-08-21">August 21<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1861.</date> there was made<pb/>
<lb/>the following order towit:</p>
<p>Commonwealth Plff
<lb/>vs } Larceny
<lb/>A W Picherell Deft</p>
<p>This day came the attorney for the Commonwealth and at appearing to the court that the defendant Picherill executed a bond before the examining Court for his appearance in this court at its present term in the Sum of one hundred dollars with Elias Cundiff J D Alvey Alexander Millen Hatten Harris Thomas Kincade Thomas J Sweets &amp; James Thompson his Sureties and he failing to appear the court declares Said bond forfeited and orders that a Summons issue on Said forfeiture returnable to the next term of this court.</p>
<p>The Summons was duly issued and returned by the Sheriff of Marion County <hi rend="underline">Exectued</hi> <hi rend="underline">on</hi> <hi rend="underline">Hatten</hi> <hi rend="underline">Harris</hi> the rest not found.</p>
<p>And at a further term of Said court towit <date when="1861-11-28">November the 28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861.</date> there was made the following order.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth Plff
<lb/>vs } On forfeiture
<lb/>A W Picherell &amp;c Defts</p>
<p>This day came the attorney for the commonwealth and the defendant Hatten Harris being Summoned and failing to answer it is adjudged that he pay to the Commonwealth<pb/>
<lb/>the Sum of one hundred dollars the amount of the forfeiture herein and also the costs herein expended. And the defindents A W Picharell Elias Cundiff J D Alvey Thomas Kincade Thomas J Sweets &amp; James Thompson not having been Summoned this cause is continued as to them and an alias is awarded against them and the death of Alexander Millen being Suggested this case is abated as to him.</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Marion circuit court } Sct</p>
<p>I N T Berry clerk of the Marion circuit court certify that the foregoing two and a half pages contain a true copy of the bail bond. The order forfeiting the Same and the Judgment on the forfeiture in the case in Said court of the commonwealth against A W Picherell Given under my hand as clerk aforesaid this <date when="1862-01-28">28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Day of January 1862</date></p>
<p>N T Berry cK<pb/></p>
<p>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Transcript
<lb/>A W Picherell</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
