<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1064"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John W. Christin to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10532</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-159 to MG20-160</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Adair County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-05-28">28 May 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><date when="1861-05-28">May 28<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>Beriah MaGoffin
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>At the <date when="1861-05">May term 1861</date> (just past) I was fined <hi rend="str">fifty</hi> Sixty dollars "for Keeping a tipling house"</p>
<p>I was not guilty, but did not make my defence because Mr. William Stewart ^an atty &amp; counsillor at law^ advised me that it was not necessary for me to attend Court. The names of two persons named Curry &amp; one named Orr were put down on the indictment ^as witnesses for the Comwth^ The two Currys had left the State &amp; gone into parts unknown to the petitioner.</p>
<p>Mr. Stewart failed to observe that Orrs name was endorsed as a witness, &amp; therfor believed that ther would be no trial. of the Case. The case was tried in my absence &amp; I was fi<hi rend="str">l</hi>ned $60. because no defence was made against the charge.</p>
<p>I Kept a little store in this (Adair) County. I never sold spiritous liquors upon the recomendation of Dr. Hector Owens I bought a Keg (ten gallons) of ginger wine. I never sold that wine except once &amp; then to a man whose wife was sick.</p>
<p>I stat to Your Excellency that I never Kept a tippling house &amp; never ^sold^ a gile of spiritous liquors<pb/>
<lb/>unless the ginger wine containd it.</p>
<p>These are the facts. I ask to be released from a fine for a offence which I have not commited.</p>
<p>John W Christin</p>
<p>We state that we <hi rend="str">are</hi>were the nearest of neighbours of John W. Christin while he resided at the house in this county in which he has been convicted of keeping a tipling house. We certify that we were often at his Store &amp; that so far as we <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>know or could observe he kept an orderly house -- that he did not keep a tipling house. He did not keep disorderly company about him. We earnestly join in his prayer</p>
<p><date when="1861-05-28">May 28. 1861</date></p>
<p>Hector Owens
<lb/>Benjamin,, Grant
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi>. H. Arnold
<lb/>N A Thomas
<lb/>Wm T Smith
<lb/>A F Harden
<lb/>N R Thomas
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Stewart<pb/></p>
<p>Kentucky Adair County
<lb/>John W. Christin states that he believes the statement of his petition are true.</p>
<p>E S Willis, P, J, A, C, C</p>
<p>To <hi rend="underline">Gov</hi>' Magoffin -- </p>
<p>I know the gentlemen whose names are affixed hereto as men of honor and perfect reliance can be placed in their statements, From what I have heard I believe this is a meritorious case -- </p>
<p>Truly Your Obdt Servant
<lb/>Nat Gaither<pb/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Petition</hi></p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1861-06-24">June 24</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
