<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2454"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Jessee Carrico et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7091</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-408 to BR15-409</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Hon T. E. Bramblette.
<lb/>Governer of Ky</p>
<p>The undersigned your petitioners citizens of Carroll County would respectfully represent that Jessee Carrico a citizen of said county by certain proceedings had before -- Johnson a justice of the peace in Carroll County, was fined // One cent and costs for a breach of the peace. Said fine and costs was paid by said Carrico That afterwards by proceedings had before Samuel Carlisle another justice in said county said Carrico was fined $20, and costs for the <hi rend="underline">same</hi> offense. That fifteen days after the rendition of said judgment, when execution had issued, He applied to said justice for an appeal and was informed by said Carlisle that no appeal could be granted <hi rend="underline">15 days</hi> after judgment. Said Carrico is now advised that he can not be tried twice for the <hi rend="underline">same</hi> <hi rend="underline">offense</hi> and that he had <hi rend="underline">60</hi> days to take<pb/>
<lb/>an appeal from said judgment Your petitioners believing it would be unjust for said Carrico to pay sad fine, Through his ignorance of his legal rights -- and their being now no other redress except an appeal to the executive: respectfully request your excellency to remit said fine.</p>
<p>Jessee Carrico
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W. Corn</hi>
<lb/>J H Mershon
<lb/>A H Ball
<lb/>M. Brown
<lb/>William Gelfins
<lb/>Prentis Meade
<lb/>B B Elston
<lb/>S A Berry
<lb/>G Hish
<lb/>W Madcaf
<lb/>S. E. Vancleave
<lb/>J, W, Ball
<lb/>John Myrick</p>
<p>We recommend that the request of the petitioners be granted.</p>
<p>W. M. Fisher
<lb/>H, S, Wright <hi rend="underline">rep</hi> <hi rend="underline">elect</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Carroll Co
<lb/>Justice Peace
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Jesse Carrico
<lb/>$20.
<lb/>Breach Peace
<lb/>Remit
<lb/><date when="1865-10-23">23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Oct 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
