<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-003-0106"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Samuel G. Suddarth to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1623</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR5-176 to BR5-181</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-04-20">20 April 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>STATE OF KENTUCKY.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Office of Quarter-Master General,
<lb/>Frankfort, Ky., <date when="1865-04-20">April 20, 1865</date>.
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>T. E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Ky.</p>
<p>The accompanying correspondence upon the subject of the conditions of the papers referring to the accounts between the State of Ky and the United States having been referred to this office, is now respectfully returned, with the following remarks -- viz -- </p>
<p>I am, of course, unable to speak of the present conditions of the papers forwarded to Washington from this office. Those sent forward once I have had the honor to preside over this Department even prepared exactly as those had been, which were sent forward by my predesessors -- They, the papers, were arranged and "<hi rend="underline">classified</hi>" and "<hi rend="underline">abstracted</hi>", according to the manner, understood to be acceptable and necessary at Washington.</p>
<p>The first portion of this settlement, &amp; as I understand, the only portion yet examined, required no "<hi rend="underline">classification</hi>" nor "<hi rend="underline">abstracting</hi>", for the reason that they were memorandum pay rolls, an im<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">2</note>
<lb/><note place="header">STATE OF KENTUCKY.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Office of Quarter-Master General,
<lb/>Frankfort, Ky., <gap/>, 186<gap/>.</note>
<lb/>-perfect in form -- but the difficutly is of such a character that it cannot be remedied at Washington or Elsewhere, unless the parties signing the originals, could be found to sign new and regular rolls. For a more explicit statement of this matter I refer Your Excellency to the extract from my last Report, herewith accompanying -- </p>
<p>In regard to the difficulties in the way of settling the State accounts for Quarter Master Stores &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi> &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi> I understand from the accompanying correspondence that the 3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Auditor requires formal returns, the same as a Quarter Master in the Regular Army would make to the Chief at Washington -- this I understand is the meaning of "<hi rend="underline">Abstracts</hi>" and classifications. To a limited extent this could be done, but, as Your Excellency well knows, during the earlier period of the War every thing connected with Military matters was done in haste, and regardless of form or <hi rend="underline">regulations</hi>, consequently there is no <hi rend="underline">data</hi> upon which<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header"><hi rend="underline">3</hi></note>
<lb/><note place="header">STATE OF KENTUCKY.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Office of Quarter-Master General,
<lb/>Frankfort, Ky., <gap/>, 186<gap/>.</note>
<lb/>to base such a report as seems to be required.</p>
<p>It may be that I am not advised of the proper requirements made by the 3r<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Auditor -- and that Washington is the proper place to rearrange these papers -- if so -- the originals of many, and duplicates of all the papers in Washington are in my office, and any arrangement different from the present form, should have a corresponding copy on file in the State Military Department -- but -- if I understand what is required to make this settlement present able to the Auditing Officer at Washington, I am clearly of opinion that the operation should be performed at the point where is collected all the historical records of the War &amp; all the Auxilliary papers considered with the Settlement, for if any thing is wanting to complete the record at Washington, it must be obtained through this office -- </p>
<p>Still, I am not prepared to say that nothing could be done at Washington,<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">4</note>
<lb/><note place="header">STATE OF KENTUCKY.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Office of Quarter-Master General,
<lb/>Frankfort, Ky., <gap/>, 186<gap/>.</note>
<lb/>to facilitate the settlement, how much the settlement could be facilitated there, or the clerical force necessary to accomplish what can be done, is not within my power to state. Since the first papers were sent to Washington there has been a change in the incumbancy of the 3rd Auditorship, &amp; the views of the present officer in that Department may differ from those of his pre decessor. The latter named officer, made no objection to the <hi rend="underline">form</hi> of the accounts, but to the substance, and as far as possible this suggestion as to the delinquencies, were promptly adopted and the required evidence supplied. this, no doubt was the result of an understanding with the Secretary of War, that the Government at Washington, in its settlements with the States, for advancements for War purposes, would make an "<hi rend="underline">equitable</hi>" settlement, without requiring <hi rend="underline">regulation</hi> forms -- </p>
<p>If the Washington agency of the State of<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">5</note>
<lb/><note place="header">STATE OF KENTUCKY.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Office of Quarter-Master General,
<lb/>Frankfort, Ky., <gap/>, 186<gap/>.</note>
<lb/>Kentucky can prepare this settlement, in a manner more satisfactory to the 3r<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Aud. &amp; thereby facilitate the transaction to a more speedy close, than can this Department, there is where the work should be done, but, as before remarked, as at present advised, I cannot see what greater facilities can be had at Washington than at Frankfort, unless the immediate process of the agent, will enable him to learn from time to time what may be wanting; if facts, they must come from here -- if change of arrangements it may be done there, but this office at the same time, must be advised of any change in such arrangment, that the files of this Department may correspond with those at Washington, in which event my clerical force must be increased in proportion as the labors of my office are increased; as the same amount of labor done at Washington, must be repeated<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">6</note>
<lb/><note place="header">STATE OF KENTUCKY.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Office of Quarter-Master General,
<lb/>Frankfort, Ky., <gap/>, 186<gap/>.</note>
<lb/>here in order to preserve a perfect record.</p>
<p>I have the honor to be
<lb/>Very Resply
<lb/>Your Obdt Svt
<lb/>S. G. Suddarth
<lb/>Q. M Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> of Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
