<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0583"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John F. Fisk to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4702</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-426 to BR9-427</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-03-09">9 March 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Covington Ky <date when="1864-03-09">March 9/64</date>
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>Gov Bramlitte
<lb/>Sir,</p>
<p>I most respectfully ask you to carefully examine the papers enclosed. I am impressed with the idea that this case, comes up to your idea of the time when &amp; the case in which, Executive clemency out to be exercised.</p>
<p>I begin with the fact that the prosecutive was a pregnant prostitute, then the statement made before Hon E. W. Hawkins Mayor that Kennedy only had connection with her but he had <hi rend="underline">two</hi>, within <hi rend="underline">two</hi> or <hi rend="underline">three</hi> moments of each other. In the course of <hi rend="underline">nature</hi> that was impossible and false.</p>
<p>Then before the petit jury the to issued this story, said both Kennedy &amp; White<pb/>
<lb/>had connection with her- but this discripancy the jurors state was not brought home to them, but if it had they say they would not have convicted Whites. Then again the improbability of the whole affair. Why Rape-a woman-when the article sought could be bought at a low price. As to Kennedy I know nothing, but White positively denies having had connection with the woman- and any conflicting with, or knowledge of any such thing by Kennedy. A youth just above Eighteen of good habits and character, when convicted, he has now served two years. Mr Arthur, the Atty who prosecuted, writes you that this case presents a clear case meriting in his opinion executive clemency. All the jury, living and accessible_ say the same thing. The jailor writes that she ^the <unclear/>^ had had a <hi rend="underline">child</hi> <hi rend="underline">previous</hi> to this trial- at which time she was again pregnant- that she had been confined<pb/>
<lb/>in his jail charged with theft that she was of <hi rend="underline">general</hi> <hi rend="underline">bad</hi> character. Forty eight of the most respectable business men of Newport, where the woman lived, and the trial was, ask a pardon. The list includes the city clerk-Jailor-Deputy Sheriff-Member of the present Legislature-lawyers. owner of the Ferry-Clerk of the County Court-City Marshall Assessor of the County_Members of the City Council-Mayor of the City-Leuit Col J. P. Jackson. and other eminent gentlemen, who have been soliticted because of their weight of character. It is indeed a petition that ought to command great respect and consideration from the fact that White is a poor young man without power and influence. It is the intrinsic merit of the case that has caused there eminent citizens to take the intent they have in the case. From the doutbful<pb/>
<lb/>character of the <unclear>prosecutive</unclear> they fear a great wrong has been done and for that reason and interest general in its character, is manifested in the case. They say even if the offence, was committed on this woman, the punishment endured is quite sufficient but the great doubt- that hangs over the whole matter is <unclear/> as a good and sufficient reason for liberating the young man. I hope Governor you will give the papers a favorable examination and the case a favorable decision. His aged parents are quite afflicted about the case. Please inform me of the result</p>
<p>Respectfully Yours
<lb/>John F. Fisk</p>
<p>The other son is now in the Federal army-</p>
<p>F</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
