<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2113"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. M. Vaughan et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9189</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-172 to MG24-173</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned Petitioners will respectfully represent that at the <date when="1858-01">January Term 1858</date> of the Jefferson Circuit Court Adam Schweitzer was tried on an Indictment charging him with having committed a Felony &amp; he was found Guilty &amp; sentenced to five years Imprisonment in the Kentucky Penitentiary. Your Petitioners will state the facts as detailed to them upon which the prosecution was Instituted. Adam Schweitzer and one Joseph DeMarsh who was Jointly Indicted with him but who was never arrested made a trip on a coal boat to New Orleans and returned on a Steamer, leaving New Orleans together; on the trip up a watch was stolen from one of the passengers and the Testimony on the trial of accused showed that a man answering the description of DeMarsh was seen in the state room of the Passenger who lost the watch. DeMarsh left the boat before she arrived at Louisville &amp; accused as we presume because he was the travelling companion of DeMarsh was arrested &amp; altho no watch or stolen property of any description was found upon him he was tried &amp; found guilty as above stated. He has now been confined over two years in the Penitentiary at hard labor and we believe under the circumstances he should be discharged, he is a man who before the above charge was made against him labored for the support of himself &amp; his aged father &amp; mother who have been mainly dependent<pb/>
<lb/>on him, and he has always before sustained a good character, never haveing before been charged with crime, He is a German, Ignorant of our laws, poor &amp; was consequently not able to make such a defense as might have been made in his case. We believe that his punishment has been sufficient to produce the proper Effect, If it be admitted that he was Guilty; which we cannot believe and for the sake of his aged parents and that their old age may no longer be Embittered by the recollection of the unhappy condition of their son. We respectfully ask your Excellency to Pardon the said Adam Schweitzer &amp; we as in duty bound will &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J. M Vaughan
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J. B. Ehuchs</hi>
<lb/>N. L. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clelland
<lb/>F. B. Jones
<lb/>Geo W Doaner
<lb/>H C Russell
<lb/>D Forsyth
<lb/>P. M. Moore
<lb/>J C Baird
<lb/>James Sucker
<lb/>C. C. Henry
<lb/>J A Bayne
<lb/>Jeff Brown
<lb/>C D Pennebaker
<lb/>S. H Punzer
<lb/>Geo W. Johnston.
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Isaac R. Greene
<lb/><hi rend="underline">C. T Taylor</hi>
<lb/>Sam<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Matluck
<lb/>S. B Lancaster.
<lb/>Jo<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Clement J P U
<lb/>J. R. Davis</p>
<p>If the above facts are true and from the character of the gentlemen who have signed the above Petition they are I join in this petition</p>
<p>John Roberts<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>To His Excellency
<lb/>The Govenor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Captain Sweitzer who hands me the above petition, I have known well since the Mexican War. I was not aware until now that Adam Sweitzer the young man to whom the petition refers was in any way related to him. DeMarsh escaped in Straw Bail and has now been taken and I am inclined to believe that young Sweitzer may have been ^led^ into the difficulty by the one who was man <unclear/>, seen under the hope, that the punishment which Sweitzer has received, may cause him to turn away from such associates and Acts, if Violation of Law. the watch was of little value. it is true but the case was made out by the Witnesses Yet the Young man was not defended by any Counsel. believing that He has suffered a great deal I join in the petition</p>
<p>E S Craig Atto
<lb/>For Com<hi rend="sup">wth</hi> 7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> <unclear>Justice</unclear><pb/></p>
<p>Adam Schweitzer
<lb/>case -- Pen<hi rend="sup">y</hi>
<lb/>Louisville -- </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
