<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0311"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. P. Sparks to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8763</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-9</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Pleasureville, Shelby County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-04-18">18 April 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Pleasureville Ky. <date when="1863-04-18">April 18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>.
<lb/>Governor Robinson
<lb/>Frankfort Ky
<lb/>Dear Sir -- </p>
<p>I Received a paper from you this evening Remiting one half of the Fines against all of the parties of the peace for this County. I am very thankful to you for so doing Although it is nothing to me. But I think that one half and the costs will be sufficient to give them and their successors a morning in the future to make their -- Returns Promptly when Notified to do so,</p>
<p>Last summer they was Some Horse thieves came into our County and Shelby and Staled 5 very valuable Horses from R. L. Tinsley &amp; others near eminence Ky. And crossed the Ohio River with the Horses, Tinsley &amp; others pursued the thieves and captured one Myers in the State of indiana, And brought said Myers to New Castle Ky. where he was tried before an examining court and found guilty And Bail was then fixed at $1,000 And Myers could not give Bail then and he was put in jail, Before our Circuit Court (a short time) last Septr. -- one C. M. Mathews a lawyer -- of New Castle went on the Bond with said Myers And permitted Myers to escape for parts
<lb/><note place="left margin">Mr. Sparks<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Horses of <unclear/></note><pb/>
<lb/>unknown, At the Cir -- cuit Court in Septr. -- last I understood Mattews got the Bail lowered to $750= It is almost universally throught and Believed by all persons who are Phamilior with the case that Myers has deposited money with Mathews or Mortgage property in the State of Indiana to make him safe in the Case, for it appeared from the evidence in the case that there was a Band of horsethieves over-there and $750= would be a very small Amount for a Band of thieves to make up these times,</p>
<p>,At our last session of the legislature we passsed and act for the Benefit of R. L. Tinsley &amp; others giving of them $500= to compensate them for the expenses incured and the money expended in Bringing of said Myers to New Castle, when the aforesaid Bond was collected. My object in writing this letter to you is to put you on your guard Against any petition of C. M. Mathews or any other -- person in order to get you to <hi rend="underline">Remit</hi> <hi rend="underline">the</hi> <hi rend="underline">aforesaid</hi> <hi rend="underline">Bond</hi>, I want the same collected (and I think that I speak the sentiments of the most of our honest and law abiding citizen about here) And paid over to R. L. Tinsley &amp; others as cited in the prea^m^ble of the act,</p>
<p>Yours very Respectfully 
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J' P' Sparks </hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
