<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0960"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William M. Rector et al., to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10428</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-1 to MG20-2</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-04-01">1 April 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The undersigned citizens of warren County Ky most respectfully begs leave to offer a few Suggestions to His Excellency Gov Magoffin, why Rufus Jones convicted of Manslaughter for killing Henry Jenkins Should not be pardoned,</p>
<p>In the first place it is useless to have laws unless they are execute -- The general evil of one day is that all laws and obligations, Morel &amp; <hi rend="str">Just</hi> Legal are relaxed.</p>
<p>In the 2' place ther is nothing in the case certainly not in the testimony to Show that Jones had got any more punishment than his case demands Indeed it is almost the universal opinion that he got off very well with four years imprisonment and he ought to be glad of that -- and sofare as we know his friends have not complaind of the Jury for finding that length of time,</p>
<p>In the 3rd place if Jones is pardend we dont See why the whole lot of prisoners in the prison at Frankfort may not be turned out on the same principal.</p>
<p>In the 4" place if Jones is discharged it will amt to a general motivation to all violators of The Law to Repeat this offence and the design of the Law will <hi rend="str">will</hi> not be met.</p>
<p>while then we do not go into any Specific <hi rend="str">case</hi> Personal charge we basely Say that the Govner cant read a copy of the testimony before the Examing court or on final trial to Say an oath or conscience that Jones ought to be discharged</p>
<p><date when="1861-04-01">April 1the 1861</date><pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> M.. Rector
<lb/>G. W. Grow
<lb/>Josiah Os<hi rend="underline">born</hi>
<lb/>John W Weaver
<lb/>A, Hewitt
<lb/>Jas H Casaday
<lb/>Benjamin Hewitt
<lb/>John Satterfield
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H Moody
<lb/>S. L. Hewitt
<lb/>W. J. Resnick
<lb/>N. W. Jordan
<lb/>J. T. Lee
<lb/>T. W. Mitchell
<lb/>A. J. Claypool
<lb/>E. T. Claypol
<lb/>W. H. H. Claypool
<lb/>W. M. Claypool
<lb/>G G Roarner
<lb/>J R Claypool
<lb/>H. W. Motley
<lb/>Ab Liles
<lb/>Thoma D <unclear/>
<lb/>Sampson. Jenkins
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
