<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-003-0097"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Schofield, General Orders No. 89</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1614</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR5-160 to BR5-161</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Knoxville, Knox County, Tennessee</placeName>
    <date when="1864-10-20">20 October 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Head Quarters Department of the ohio
<lb/>Knoxville Tenn. <date when="1864-10-20">October 20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>General Orders
<lb/>No. 89
<lb/>Extract.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>II Before a General Court Martial which convened at Louisville Kentucky <date when="1864-01-11">January 11<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date> pursuant to Special orders Nos. 9. 16. 25. 27 and 31, dated Assistant Adjutant General's office. Department of the ohio Lexington, Kentucky, <date when="1864-01-08">January 8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi></date> <date when="1864-01-08">15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi></date> <date when="1864-01-24">24<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi></date> <date when="1864-01-26">26<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi></date> and <date when="1864-01-30">30<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date> respectively, and of which Lieutenant Colonel B. F. orcutt 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Regiment Michigan Volunters Infantry, was President, was arraigned and tried.</p>
<p>2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> Lieutenant <hi rend="underline">Charles Helton</hi> Company I 39<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Regiment Kentucky Volunteer Mounted Infantry.
<lb/>Charge I
<lb/><hi rend="underline">"assult and Battery. with intent to commit rape"</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Specification</hi> -- "In this: that he, Lt <hi rend="underline">Charles Helton</hi> Co. "I" 39<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Regiment Ky. Vols. Mounted Infantry did, on or about the <date when="1864-12-14">14<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of December 1864</date> go to the house of Capt Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Russell of the 45<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky. Vols. Inft U. S. army. and did rudely assult the wife of said Capt Russell, saying that he would stay all<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header"><hi rend="underline">2</hi></note>
<lb/>night with her, and on being told that he should not. replied 'By god. I will Stay.' M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi>. Russell then ran into another room, and shut the door. said <hi rend="underline">Helton</hi> kicked the door violently, and said to her, 'If you do not open the door, I will blow your God damned brains out,' and forced the door open, and followed said M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi>. Russell into another room; and caught hold of her and tore her dress open and thrust his hand into her bosom, saying, I have been on a scout fourteen days, and by God I must have you for my purposes now, and the said <hi rend="underline">Helton</hi> did, by force, attempt to throw said M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> Russell on the bed, and was only prevented from so doing by the timely appearance of two countrymen. All this on Rock Castle Creek Lawrence County Kentucky."</p>
<p>Charge II
<lb/><hi rend="underline">"Conduct unbecoming an officer and a Gentleman."</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Specification</hi> -- "In this; that he, 2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> Lieut <hi rend="underline">Charles Helton</hi> Co. I. 39<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Regiment Ky. Vols. Mounted Inft U S Army did. on the <date when="1863-12-14">14<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of December 1863</date> go to the house of Capt Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Russell, of the 45<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Regt. Ky. Vols. U. S. Army and did in a rude and unGentlemanly manner use threatening and insulting Language to the wife and daughter of Capt Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Russell, and did attempt to persuade the daughter aforesaid to accompany him from the house and<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">3</note>
<lb/>upon her refusing to go, he replied, 'By god you shall go or I will kill you.' and drew his pistol. she running off this at Rock Castle. Lawrence County Ky."</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Specification</hi> 2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> -- "In this: that he 2nd Lieut. <hi rend="underline">Charles Helton</hi>. Co. I. 39<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Regt Ky. Vols. Inft U S. Army did on the <date when="1863-12-14">14<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of December 1863</date>. rudely enter the house of Emanuel Spence, and did use insulting Language to the inmates thereof. and did fire his pistol in said house, and by threats compel M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> Zelphina Spence to accompany him one-fourth of a mile from her house, attempting to persuade her to go to camp with him, there to be as a wife to him. All this on Rock Castle Creek, Lawrence county. Kentucky."</p>
<p>Charge III
<lb/><hi rend="underline">"Drunkennes on duty"</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Specification</hi> -- "In this; that he 2nd Lieut <hi rend="underline">Charles Helton</hi> Co "I" 39<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Regt. Ky. Vols. Mounted Inft. U, S. Army did on the <date when="1863-12-14">14<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of December 1863</date> while in command of his company, on a Scout in Lawrence County, Ky,, get intoxicated to such an extent that he was unable to command, and did permit his company to become demoralized and scattered in consequence of said intoxication"</p>
<p>To which charges and specifications the accused pleaded: "Guilty."</p>
<p>Finding.<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header"><hi rend="underline">4</hi></note>
<lb/>The Court, having maturely considered the evidence adduced, finds the accused, 2nd Lieutenant <hi rend="underline">Charles Helton</hi> Co "I." 39<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Regiment Kentucky Volunteer Mounted Infantry, as follows:</p>
<p>Charge I
<lb/>of the <hi rend="underline">Specification</hi>. "Guilty."
<lb/>of the Charge. "Gulty."
<lb/>Charge II
<lb/>of the 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> <hi rend="underline">Specification</hi>. "Guilty."
<lb/>of the 2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> <hi rend="underline">Specification</hi>. "Guilty."
<lb/>of the Charge. "Gulty."
<lb/>Charge III
<lb/>of the <hi rend="underline">Specification</hi>. "Not Guilty"
<lb/>of the Charge "Not Guilty."
<lb/>Sentence.</p>
<p>And the court does therefore sentence him 2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> Lieutenant <hi rend="underline">Charles Helton</hi> Co. "I" 39<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Regiment Kentucky Volunteer Mounted Infantry, "<hi rend="underline">To be reduced to the ranks. and forfeit all pay proper due, and to become due, and that he be confined at hard Labor, with ball and chain attached to his leg, for three years. at such place as shall be designated by the General Commanding, and at the expiration</hi><pb/>
<lb/><note place="header"><hi rend="underline">5</hi></note>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">of his sentence to be dishonorably dismissed from the service."</hi></p>
<p>III.. The proceedings, findings and sentence in the case of 2nd Lieut <hi rend="underline">Charles Helton</hi>. Company I. 39<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Kentucky Mounted Infantry, are approved and confirmed except, so much of the Sentence as reduces him to the ranks. His name, however, will be Stricken from the rolls of his company, and he will be delivered, under guard, into the custody of the Commanding officer of the at Louisville Kentucky, under whose direction the remainder of the Sentence will be executed.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>By Command of
<lb/>Major General Schofield
<lb/>(S'g'd) J. A. Campbell
<lb/>Major and A. A. Genl
<lb/>Official</p>
<p>Capt &amp; A. A. Genl</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
