<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1149"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Suddarth et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5786</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-265 to BR11-266</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lancaster, Garrard County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-08-22">22 August 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Lancaster Ky <date when="1864-08-22">Aug. 22<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency Thos E. Bramlette Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky:</p>
<p>Your petitioner would respectfully state that an indictment having been obtained against him at a former term of the Garrard Circuit Court for the offense of keeping a gaming house he confessed judgment on the same as the <date when="1864-08">present august</date> term of said court for the sum of $200 -- and that he is the proprietor of a respectable hotel in this place and a poor man <hi rend="str">of</hi> with a large family to support. He states that there might have been gaming in his house occasionally as is the usual custom <hi rend="str">through</hi> at most hotels in this county but that he never kept a regular gaming house or any apartments about his house for the special purpose of gaming; and that the prosecution was a malicious one, gotten up by some enemy of your petitioner; and that he has been keeping tavern but a short time and if he has to pay the above fine it will work much detriment to himself and his large family of little children and a widowed sister-in-law with three helpless &amp; infant children who are living with<pb/>
<lb/>him and wholly dependent on him for support. Under this state of facts your petitioner the undersigned would respectfully petition your Excellency to remit the above mentioned fine</p>
<p>William Suddarth</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by William Suddarth this <date when="1864-08-22">22<hi rend="sup">d</hi> dy of August 1864</date></p>
<p>A M <unclear>Merull</unclear> j p g c</p>
<p>The undersigned respectfully represent to your Excellency that they believe the above statements are true and request your Excelency to remit the above fine this the <date when="1864-08-22">22<hi rend="sup">d</hi> of august 1864</date></p>
<p>Joshua F Bell
<lb/>Jno S Vanwinkle -- 
<lb/>M.G. Bushman
<lb/>B M Burdett
<lb/>G. W. Dunlap
<lb/>H. S. Burnam
<lb/>G.E. Hackley</p>
<p>I respectfully request the Governor of Kentucky to grant the prayer of the foregoing Petitioner</p>
<p>Fon. T. Fox
<lb/>Wm Engleman
<lb/>M.L. Rice<pb/></p>
<p>Garrard Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Suddarth
<lb/>$200 -- 
<lb/>Gaming
<lb/>Remit
<lb/><date when="1864-09-08">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sept/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
