<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2935"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. James Brown, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7572</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-269</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Morgan County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Morgan Circuit Court
<lb/>Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against } Indictment
<lb/>James Brown</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Morgan Count in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky Accuse James Brown of the Offense of Horse Stealing Committed as follows to wit The said James Brown on the <date when="1865-05-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> May 1865</date> in the County and Circuit aforsad did willfully and feloniously take Steal and carry off a Certain Horse the personal property of E H Williams of the vaule of more than four Dollars against the Peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Ky</p>
<p>J S Dury Com<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Attorney</p>
<p>A Copy Atteste
<lb/>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> T Hazelrigg<pb/></p>
<p>Colwealth
<lb/>v } Indict
<lb/>James Brown</p>
<p>A True Bill
<lb/>M G Carter Foreman
<lb/>Filed <date when="1866-05-24">May 24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1866</date>
<lb/>Jno T Hazelrigg Clk<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>In this case Brown was then in the service of the U. S in the 39' Regt &amp; was on a scout in morgan county with some others &amp; while he was there a Mrss Yates who Lived at Williams seen Brown &amp; informed him that that Williams had Powder &amp; Lead for the Guerrilas who infested that County &amp; had said he would shoot the first Linconite he came across across &amp; in Blue Brown took a part of his men &amp; went to Williams &amp; made search for Powder Lead &amp;c but Williams had left home one of his men was a <unclear>fool</unclear> &amp; he called on ^Mr<hi rend="sup">s</hi> williams for a horse she refused to Let him Have it he informed her if mr williams was a Loyal man &amp; was clear of the charge he could get his horse &amp; told Mr<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Williams to tell wiliams to come over to the Rock house next day &amp; prove himself clear &amp; get his horse they took the horse &amp; he failed to come the <unclear/> came over to the 39 this are the facts <unclear/> <unclear>the bond</unclear> <unclear/> in the county</p>
<p>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> W Hazelrigg^</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
