<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0057"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James Buford to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14086</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1864</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Salvisa, Mercer County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-11-04">4 November 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Salvisa Mercer County Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-11-04">Nov 4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>Gov Bramlet
<lb/>Honered Sir</p>
<p>In attempting to write you, I hardly know how to begin, but simply wish to apprise you of some things that are going on here, hoping by this means ^to^ do some good,</p>
<p>There are two men in this county that are geting up, as they say and independent company, for the State service, on the order of Cap't Bridgewater's of Lincoln County, They are both very bad men, one of them is the notorious J D. Hail that released a prisner last spring from<pb/>
<lb/>the civil court, as you are aware, The other is Cap't Harvy Burns of the late 9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Cav.</p>
<p>They are men of very bad feelings and they have many enemies in the county, and should they succeed in raising a company, and receive a commission. from you, they will treat many men in this country cruelly, as they <hi rend="str">the</hi> have already done By the way, they are both strong for Lincoln, and will be the cause in the ensuing election. to intimidate many from voting for M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clelland. They have whipped some already about politics, I could write a half day about their miss deeds, and they have a clan that is ready to do any thing they suggest, No man is more desirous of catching these Robers that has committed so many daring outrages than myself, but to start out men of equal stamp, and back them<pb/>
<lb/>by the Goverment as they would think, they would only prey upon certain men they don't like, and let robbers go, they are not the kind of men that should have power, as they are "base tirants" should I use the term, (at the same time I have gotten along with them well) Had they power, they would equal the notorious Pane of Paduca notoriety, I am asstonished at our Provost Mars for encouraging them,</p>
<p>I have given you this few hints for your consideration, and I have done so through the purest of motives, and the good of my countrymen, you must excuse me for requesting you to keep my name should they find it out I would,n't live long -- </p>
<p>Yours with most profound Respect
<lb/>Jas Buford<pb/></p>
<p>Salvisa Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-11-04">Nov 4" 1864</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Buford Jas<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>To The Gov -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Complains of Capt<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> J. D. Hail and Harry Burns -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Rec<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> A. G. O. <date when="1864-11-10">Nov 10" 1864.</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
