<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-009-0031"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Richard J. Oglesby et al., Articles of Association, and By-Laws, Rules and Regulations of the National Lincoln Monument Association</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1186</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR1-55 to BR1-60</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Springfield, Sangamon County, Illinois</placeName>
    <date when="1865-05-11">11 May 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>ARTICLES OF ASSOCIATION,
<lb/>AND
<lb/>BY-LAWS, RULES AND REGULATIONS
<lb/>OF THE
<lb/>National Lincoln Monument Association,<pb/></p>
<p>ARTICLES OF ASSOCIATION,
<lb/>AND
<lb/>BY-LAWS, RULES AND REGULATIONS
<lb/>OF THE
<lb/>National Lincoln Monument Association,<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>ORGANIZED AT SPRINGFIELD, ILL., <date when="1865-05-11">MAY 11, 1865</date>.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>SPRINGFIELD:
<lb/>STEAM PRESS OF BAKER &amp; PHILLIPS.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/><date when="1865">1865</date>.<pb/></p>
<p>ARTICLES OF ASSOCIATION.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>We, Richard J. Oglesby, Sharon Tyndale, O. H. Miner, James H. Beveridge, Newton Bateman, John T. Stuart, Samuel H. Treat, Jesse K. Dubois, O. M. Hatch, James C. Conkling, Thomas J. Dennis, John Williams, Jacob Bunn, S. H. Melvin, David L. Phillips, all being of full age, and citizens of the United States, and the State of Illinois, certify that we do hereby associate ourselves under and by virtue of an act of the General Assembly of the State of Illinois, entitled "An act for the incorporation of Benevolent, Educational, Literary, Musical, Scientific and Missionary Societies, including societies formed for Mutual Improvement, or for the promotion of the Arts," approved February 24, 1859, by the following name and for the purpose herein specified.</p>
<p>ARTICLE I.
<lb/>This association shall be called "The National Lincoln Monument Association," and be located at Springfield, State of Illinois, and shall continue in existence for the term of twenty years.</p>
<p>ARTICLE II.
<lb/>The object of this association shall be to construct a Monument to the memory of ABRAHAM LINCOLN, in the city of Springfield, State of Illinois.</p>
<p>ARTICLE III.
<lb/>The following persons shall be the directors of this association during the first year of its existence: Richard J. Oglesby, Sharon Tyndale, O. H. Miner, James H. Beveridge, Newton Bateman, John T. Stuart, Jesse K. Dubois, O. M. Hatch, James C. Conkling, Thomas J. Dennis, John Williams, Jacob Bunn, S. H. Melvin, Samuel H. Treat, David L. Phillips.<pb/>
<lb/><note>[4]</note></p>
<p>In testimony whereof we have hereunto set our hands and seals, this <date when="1865-05-11">11th day of May, 1865</date>.</p>
<p>RICHARD J. OGLESBY, [SEAL.]
<lb/>SHARON TYNDALE, [SEAL.]
<lb/>ORLIN H. MINER, [SEAL.]
<lb/>NEWTON BATEMAN, [SEAL.]
<lb/>JOHN T. STUART, [SEAL.]
<lb/>S. H. TREAT, [SEAL.]
<lb/>JESSE K. DUBOIS, [SEAL.]
<lb/>O. M. HATCH, [SEAL.]
<lb/>JAMES C. CONKLING, [SEAL.]
<lb/>S. H. MELVIN, [SEAL.]
<lb/>JOHN WILLIAMS, [SEAL.]
<lb/>JAMES H. BEVERIDGE, [SEAL.]
<lb/>JACOB BUNN, [SEAL.]
<lb/>THOMAS J. DENNIS, [SEAL.]
<lb/>DAVID L. PHILLIPS, [SEAL.]</p>
<p>STATE OF ILLINOIS,
<lb/>CITY OF SPRINGFIELD. } SS</p>
<p>Before the undersigned, a Notary Public, within and for the city aforesaid, on this <date when="1865-05-11">11th day of May, A. D. 1865</date>, personally appeared Richard J. Oglesby, Sharon Tyndale, Orlin H. Miner, Newton Bateman, John T. Stuart, Samuel H. Treat, Jesse K. Dubois, Ozias M. Hatch, James C. Conkling, Samuel H. Melvin, John Williams, James H. Beveridge, Jacob Bunn, Thomas J. Dennis, and David L. Phillips, the parties named in the foregoing article of association, and whose genuine signatures were affixed thereto in my presence, and severally acknowledged the execution thereof to be their free and voluntary act and deed for the purpose therein expressed.</p>
<p>[SEAL.]</p>
<p>Witness my hand and seal notarial, the day and year above written.</p>
<p>HALL WILSON, N. P.<pb/></p>
<p>BY-LAWS AND REGULATIONS.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>ARTICLE I.
<lb/>MEETINGS.</p>
<p>SECTION 1. The stated meetings of the association shall be held in the State Library Room on Thursday of each week, at 4 o'clock P. M., until otherwise ordered. Special meetings may be called by the President, or, in his absence, by the Vice President, and by the Executive Committee, of which special meetings all the directors shall be duly notified by the Secretary. A majority of the directors shall be a quorum for business.</p>
<p>SEC. 2. The stated<hi rend="italic"> annual meeting</hi> of the association shall be held on the second Thursay of May in each year.</p>
<p>ARTICLE II.
<lb/>OFFICERS.</p>
<p>SEC. I. The officers of the Association shall be a President, Vice President, Secretary and Treasurer, who shall hold their offices for one year, and until their successors are elected and qualified, unless sooner removed by the Association. All officers shall be elected at the stated annual meeting, and the votes of a majority of the board of corporators shall elect.</p>
<p>SEC. 2. The President shall perform all the duties usually devolving upon a presiding officer. He shall appoint all special committees, unless otherwise ordered by the board of directors. He shall sign all orders upon the Treasurer, when such orders have been authorized by the directors. In his absence the Vice President shall assume the duties and have the powers of the President; and, in the absence of the Vice President, the directors shall appoint a President, <hi rend="italic">pro tempore</hi>, who, in like manner, shall have the powers and perform the duties of President.</p>
<p>SEC. 3. The Secretary shall keep a faithful record of the proceedings of the Association, and shall perform all other duties usually devolving upon<pb/>
<lb/><note>[6]</note>
<lb/>that officer. He shall countersign, and keep a record of all receipts for moneys issued by the Treasurer, and shall also countersign all orders drawn on the Treasurer. In his absence the directors shall appoint a Secretary, <hi rend="italic">pro tempore</hi>, who shall have all the powers and perform all the duties of Seretary.</p>
<p>SEC. 4, The Treasurer shall receive, and have the custody of all funds contributed for the objects of the Association, and shall not pay out any of said funds except upon orders drawn on him by the President, and countersigned by the Secretary. He shall report in writing, the amount of funds received, paid out, and remaining on hand, as often as may be required by the Association. He shall give bond, with such securities as the Association may approve, for the faithful discharge of duties of his office.</p>
<p>ARTICLE III.
<lb/>COMMITTEES.</p>
<p>SEC. 1. The standing committees of the Association shall be as follows: An Executive Committee, of three members; and an Auditing Committee, of three members; and other standing committees may be appointed by the directors, when, in their judgment, the same shall be necessary. The standing committees appointed during the first year, shall hereafter be elected or appointed at the stated annual meeting, in the same manner, and for the same time as the officers of the Association are elected. A majority of each committee shall be a quorum for business.</p>
<p>SEC. 2. No committee of this body shall incur any pecuniary obligation in the name of the Associatiion, without due authority conferred by the corporation.</p>
<p>ARTICLE IV.
<lb/>DUTIES OF COMMITTEES.</p>
<p>SEC. 1. The Executive Committee shall have power, and it shall be their duty, to act in the name and by the authority of the Association, upon all such matters and questions as may arise in the prosecution of, or be necessary to the success of the Lincoln Monument enterprise, except in relation to the disposition or use of the funds of the Association, and such other matters as require the corporate authority and sanction of the Association as such, and which cannot properly be delegated to a committee.</p>
<p>SEC. 2. The Auditing Committee shall examine all bills and accounts against the Association, and shall duly certify such as are found to be correct.</p>
<p>SEC. 3. Each standing committee shall report its transactions in full and in writing, at every stated meeting of the Association.<pb/>
<lb/><note>[7]</note></p>
<p>ARTICLE V.
<lb/>ORDER OF BUSINESS.</p>
<p>SEC. 1. Until otherwise directed, the regular order of business at each stated meeting shall be as follows:
<lb/>1. Reading Minutes.
<lb/>2. Reports of Special Committees.
<lb/>3. Reports of Standing Committees.
<lb/>4. Treasurer's Report.
<lb/>5. Communications.
<lb/>6. Motions and Resolutions.
<lb/>7 Unfinished Business:
<lb/>8. General Business.</p>
<p>ARTICLE VI.
<lb/>HONORARY MEMBERS.</p>
<p>SEC. 1. Any person may become an honorary member of this Association by the payment of ten dollars to its funds, which will entitle him to an appropriate certificate of such membership.</p>
<p>ARTICLE VII.
<lb/>VACANCIES, ETC.</p>
<p>SEC. 1. All vacancies in the offices, directors or corporators, may be filled at any stated meeting by a vote of the Associatiion, a majority of the votes cast being necessary to a choice.</p>
<p>SEC. 2. All resolutions shall be presented in writing, and motions shall be reduced to writing when requested by the President or Secretary.</p>
<p>SEC. 3. These by-laws and regulations may be altered, amended or repealed at any stated meeting, by a votte of two-thirds of all the directors present.<pb/></p>
<p>OFFICERS.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/><table rend="rules">
<row>
	<cell>GOV. RICHARD J. OGLESBY,</cell>
	<cell><hi rend="italic">President</hi>.</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>HON. JESSE K. DUBOIS,</cell>
	<cell><hi rend="italic">Vice President</hi>.</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>HON. JAMES H. BEVERIDGE,</cell>
	<cell><hi rend="italic">Treasurer</hi>.</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>CLINTON L. CONKLING,</cell>
	<cell><hi rend="italic">Secretary</hi>.</cell>
</row>
</table></p>
<p>JOHN WILLIAMS,
<lb/>SAMUEL H. TREAT, } <hi rend="italic">Executive Committee.</hi>
<lb/>JACOB BUNN,</p>
<p>O. H. MINER,
<lb/>O. M. HATCH, } <hi rend="italic">Auditing Committee.</hi>
<lb/>S. H. MELVIN,</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
