<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2738"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Rice to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7375</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-422</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-06-14">14 June 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency</p>
<p>The Governor of Kentucky your Petitioner John Rice states to you that the <date when="1865-05">may Term of the Magoffin Circuit Court in 1865</date> The Grand Jury at that Term Indicted him for Tipling (that is for two acts of selling sprituous Liquor. I was guilty of selling only on one occasion &amp; that in case of Sickness I advised with an attorny who informed me that I had best Confess Judgment &amp; ask your clemency I accordingly confessed Judgment for $60 -- when in fact &amp; in truth I have only been guilty of the one act of selling in violation of the Laws -- we have been Living for several years without Courts or Law &amp; it was a very hard matter for Union men who remained here to sell any way -- I am no Grocer or Tavern Keeper I had a small quantity of Apples which I distilled &amp; had some little apple Brandy on hand this selling that I have Confessed is all that I Sold by the Small have no more on hand -- &amp; will not again be caught I am a Poor man &amp; have a wife &amp; several children to support a small mountain farm to make a Living on for them &amp; if I am Compelled to pay the Judgmt it will deprive my family of actual Comforts of Life &amp; it will not be felt by the State hence I verry Respectfully ask your Excellency to Remit said Fine <date when="1865-06-14">14' June 1865</date></p>
<p>John Rice<pb/></p>
<p>June Term 1864<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Fines in A P Cooprs office as J P M C
<lb/>to
<lb/>Andrew howard for
<lb/>one for -- $20.00
<lb/>one for. -- 5 00
<lb/>one for -- 2.46<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>have them Remited for Howard if it can be done<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>John Rice
<lb/>Petition to the Governor<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>I believe the facts stated in the petition of M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Rice to be correct</p>
<p>J. S. Dury
<lb/>Com<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Atty.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
