<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1319"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Underhill to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10787</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-216 to MG21-217</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>B. Magoffin, Govr of the State of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your subscriber, &amp; petitioner would respectfully represent, that at the Equity &amp; Criminal Court in &amp; for the County of Edmondson, at the <date when="1861-03">march term last past</date> of said Court, he confessed a judgt for the sum of 200$ for gaming in said County <hi rend="underline">Sixty</hi> <hi rend="underline">dollars</hi> of said fine going to the Comths Atty. &amp; which he has made arrangements to pay the remainder to wit $140.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> Soon falls and said judgment having been replevied.</p>
<p>The truth is your petitioner is a <hi rend="underline">novice</hi> in the "art &amp; mystery" of gaming &amp; got into a <hi rend="underline">little</hi> <hi rend="underline">spree</hi> &amp; found himself in the County of Edmondson somewhat out of his "<hi rend="underline">bailiwick</hi>" &amp; very improperly indulged in a game for which he is honestly ashamed &amp; truly penitent &amp; thinks (he being the judge in the case) that the amt. he is compelled to pay the atty. for the State &amp; the costs of the prosecution, is <hi rend="underline">fine Enough</hi> for the <hi rend="underline">initiation fee</hi> for of one who pledges your excellency that he has <hi rend="underline">graduated</hi> &amp; satisfied with his experience in the <hi rend="underline">aforesaid business</hi> &amp; not only willing but <hi rend="underline">determined</hi> to "close business." He respectfully begs your excellency to entertain his vices of the case as to the sufficiency of the amt he should pay <hi rend="str">in</hi> <hi rend="str">the</hi> <hi rend="str">costs</hi>. He asks permission to say further that he is a young man, just <hi rend="underline">entering</hi> on "the battle of life" with a young &amp; interesting wife &amp; one child, &amp; no estate beyond a support for himself &amp; family the premises considered he respectfully prays a remission of the aforesaid fine. </p>
<p><hi rend="underline">John Underhill</hi><pb/></p>
<p>We the subscribers, believing, &amp; some of us, knowing Mr. John Underhill to be a sober industrious &amp; good citizen unite in the prayer of the foregoing petition</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> V. Loving</hi></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="3"/><cb n="1"/>John B. Tyler
<lb/><cb n="2"/>W. R. Dunn
<lb/>Luther Carpenter
<lb/><cb n="3"/>B. C. Grider
<lb/>P. J. Potter
<lb/>C E. <unclear/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>I have enquired ^into^ and I think fully under stand the facts relative to the above named case, The Information I have is I know from Sources fully reliable, and I am Satisfied that his case is one to which the clemency of the executive should be extended, In a remission of his fine the executive, will but do an act of Justice to a poor man who as I am informed and believe has reformed, and who will not in future engage in the violation of the laws. As I remarked he is a poor man with an ^interesting^ family dependent upon him and, and the payment of Said fine would be at the Sacrifice of of many of hte comparts of his family</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> B Garret Atty for the Comth</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="3"/><cb n="1"/>B. R. White
<lb/>S. D. Carpenter
<lb/>S F Johnson
<lb/>H C Ewing
<lb/>W. M. White
<lb/>M O White
<lb/>John L Gary
<lb/>G. A. D<hi rend="sup">e</hi>Long
<lb/><cb n="2"/>N. H. Hewitt
<lb/>J B Clark
<lb/>A B Gardner
<lb/>J H Snider
<lb/>R H Morris
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> E Keel
<lb/>W t White
<lb/>Sed P Smith
<lb/><cb n="3"/>S V Goode
<lb/>W. T. Davis
<lb/>R W Hendrick
<lb/>Robt Davis
<lb/>Thos Killpatrick
<lb/>F. G. Thompson
<lb/>R J Young
<lb/>H Wilson<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Edmonson Eq Ct
<lb/>$200. } Gaming
<lb/>Jno Underhill</p>
<p>Issd <date when="1861-08-15">Aug 15. 1861</date></p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
