<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1253"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James Blakeman to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10721</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-122 to MG21-123</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Green County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-03-02">2 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin Esquire Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner James Blakeman would most respectfully represent that at the <date when="1861-02">February Term of the Green Circuit Court 1861</date> he was fined the Sum of $50 for the alledged offense of Carrying Concealed Weapons. he was fined the further sum of $10. for an alledged assault. making $60 in all and the last thereon</p>
<p>He states to your Excellency that under the evidence in the cause he supposes the Jury could have done nothing else than fine him as he had no witnesses in his behalf Judgement was rendered agianst him without defence, He was unable to have his witnesses at the trial. he denies that he was guilty of the Offenses charged. he admits he had some weapons in his profession at the time charged and he admits he had a Difficulty with the parties mentioned in the Indictment. but he had his weapons merely for Self defence he had been frequently threatened by these parties. that he was to be whipped on Sight. and that if he dared to resist they would kill him. and on this account &amp; in order to protect himself he admits he did on the occasion, have weapons to defend himself but for no other purpose. he was overtaken on the highway by these parties he alone. they began the difficulty with him and greatly abused him. and illtreated him and in self defence he Exhibited his weapons and defended himself the best he could, but<pb/>
<lb/>he did not use his weapons in nay other way he hurt no one and done nothing but defend &amp; try to keep off his assailants.</p>
<p>For this he was brought before the Grand Jury, the parties who had there maltreated him were the only witnesses &amp; upon whose evidence he has been fined</p>
<p>He could have proved the threats agaisnt him and the combination made to beat and kill your petitioenr but he was forced into trial, &amp; a continuance denied him because it was supposed he had not used dilligence to get his witness but he says he did use all reasonable dilligence and had the promise of his witness to attend. but they did not come in in time for the trial</p>
<p>He states to your Excellency that this fine is greivious and hard upon him he has not the means to pay said fines it is unjust &amp; oppressive he is a poor young man he is living with an aged mother who is to a gret Extent dependent upon him for assistance in making a living, his father recently died and left his family in a dependent condition &amp; your petitioner is the chief help of his mother <hi rend="str">&amp;</hi></p>
<p>He prays your Excellency to take his case into your favorable consideration. and release him from the payment of said 2 fines <hi rend="str">H</hi> for which he will be ever grateful and thankful he states that he is a law abiding good citizen and if it were needful he could obtain the evidence &amp;<pb/>
<lb/>approval of all his neighbors and acquaintances</p>
<p>He submits his case to your Excellency
<lb/>James Blakeman</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by James Blakeman this <date when="1861-03-02">2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> March 1861.</date></p>
<p>S A Spencer J P G C</p>
<p>Greensburg Ky <date when="1861-03-07">March 7 1861</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency Governor Magoffin</p>
<p>In behalf of the poor young man I send you his petition. accompanied by ^the petition of^ a respectable portion of his neighbors &amp; acquaintances asking your Excellency to remit &amp; release him form the 2 fines assessed against him one for an alledged assault, of $50 and one for a Breach of the peace for $10. making $60 in all </p>
<p>The Petitioner is a poor young man with no means to pay said fines and if taken to Jail as he will be it will not only, not pay the fine, but will deprive an aged and deserving old Mother from the benefit of his Service Which she now so much needs his father, (<hi rend="str">recently died</hi>) a soldier in the war of 1812 recently did an indigent circumstances leaving his wife the mother of the Petitioner in a helpless condition and dependant upon her children for support</p>
<p>It will be an act of charity &amp; humanity to release this poor fellow from the Judgements &amp; will ever be held in Grateful rememberance by his poor mother</p>
<p>I have the honor to be very respectfully
<lb/>your obt servt
<lb/>S. A Spencer<pb/> </p>
<p>Green Cir Ct
<lb/>James Blakeman
<lb/>To } Petition To Governor
<lb/>B. Magoffin Esqr
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Respite 12 mo
<lb/>B M</p>
<p>Is<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1861-07-30">July 30</date></p>
<p>From Greensburg
<lb/>Green County Ky<figure type="hr"/></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
