<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1351"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Patrick U. Major et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5988</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-103</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excy Gov'r Thos E Bramlett</p>
<p>Your Petitioner would respectfully represent that James Sechrest was indicted at the <date when="1864-05">may term 1864</date> of the Grant circuit for gaming without permission on the premises of another -- and was at the <date when="1864-10">October term 1864</date> fined the sum of seventy dollars $70 <hi rend="sup">00</hi>/<hi rend="sub">100</hi>, therefore -- The facts in the case were these Several gentlemen played a game of Poker in a Hotel -- One of the Party was the temporary occupant of the Room, and told the others that it would be all right for them to play that he had got the permission of the Land Lord for so doing -- and thence for mony played, and all were indicted, the rest of the party who made defense were fined some twenty dollars only, while Sechrest, who was absent, made default and in the absence of any defense was fined the said sum of $70,00, In view of these facts and the further fact that James Sechrest is an old, and poor man, and in fact unable to pay said fine without distressing his family we would respectfully recommend and pray that the said fine, or so much, thereof as your excellency may deem just be remitted and forever forgiven, and in will ever pray &amp; c -- </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/><hi rend="underline">Names</hi>
<lb/>P, U, Major comth Atto
<lb/>pro Tempore
<lb/>J J Landram
<lb/>J M Collins
<lb/>P W Geason
<lb/>Thos L, Dickerson
<lb/>L Brown
<lb/><cb n="2"/><hi rend="underline">names</hi>
<lb/>Wm Franks
<lb/>B. Wilson
<lb/>B, S, Franks
<lb/>J <unclear/>
<lb/>William vanlandingham<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>James Price
<lb/>John E Smith
<lb/>George W Simpson
<lb/>J T Myer
<lb/>J S <unclear/>
<lb/><unclear>Robt</unclear> <unclear/>
<lb/>J. B. Lewis
<lb/>J J. Bromback
<lb/>A Lingenfelter
<lb/>W. Oldham
<lb/>W Beard
<lb/>Thos. gray
<lb/>Aaron Baronett
<lb/>R H Bromback
<lb/>B Stewart,</p>
<p>Grant Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Jas Sechrest
<lb/>Gaming
<lb/>$70,
<lb/>Remit
<lb/><date when="1864-11-19">19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
