<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0386"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Edward P. Campbell et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9854</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-92</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Princeton, Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-01-26">26 January 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Princeton Caldwell Co Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-01-26">Jany 26 1861</date>
<lb/>Hon Beriah M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin
<lb/>Frankfort Ky</p>
<p>D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Sir Petitions have been circulated in Caldwell Trigg, Lyon &amp; Christian counties praying for the pardon of Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> B Wadlington who was convicted at the last term of the Caldwell Circuit Court of the murder of Milton, A, Cartwright -- the said petitions have been gotten up secretely in order to forestall public opinion in Caldwell County, representing that the persons signing said petition are citizens of Caldwell Co when in fact they are citizens of other Counties -- unfamiliar with the facts of the case and circumstances attending the Killing of "Cartwright" we desire to remonstrate against the pardon of T. B. Wadlington and are apprehensive that the Petitions will reach you before<pb/>
<lb/>we can send a remonstrance </p>
<p>We hope therefore you will withhold any action or opinion until we can obtain a remonstrance of the people of <hi rend="underline">Caldwell Co</hi> who are of opinion that, the finding of the Jury and the judgment of the Court are correct and that Wadlington justly deserves the punishment due to his crime we will send a remonstrance in a few days</p>
<p>Yours very Respy
<lb/>E, P,, Campbell Comth atty
<lb/>J, P, Gracey
<lb/>L, J, Cartwright
<lb/>E R Farrow
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> O'Hara
<lb/>A, C, Black
<lb/>R H Lander
<lb/>P, Barnes
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Cash</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
