<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2985"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Wiley Mountjoy et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7622</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR43-79 to BR43-80</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>(To his Exlency Thomas. E. Bramlet 
<lb/>govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky)</p>
<p>The undersigned Citizens of the County of Anderson. Would most Respectfully Represent to your Honor that Willliam gibbens of the county of Anderson was indibted on the <date when="--05-30">30<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of May</date> last by the Grand Jurry of said County. Accused of Stealing four hogs of the valiue of five dollars Each the property of H. Buntin this indibtment is now pending in the anderson Circuit Court.) That William Gibbens was boarn in afforsaid County is a married man and has up to this time boarn a good morrel Carecter and we his immediate nabors believe the charge is unfounded. That the hogs are the property of gibbens and not the property of Bunting and futher that Said Bentin<hi rend="underline">ss</hi> Sons and Son in law took the hogs from the premises of Said gibbens by Being armed with Double Barreled Shot guns and Other deadly weapons) ^suit^ has ^Bin Brought^ for these hogs by gibbens before a Justice of the peace and has bin continnued by Buntin Several times and is Sill pending) and Cannot be tried before the Seting of the <date when="--05">May</date> term of the anderson Circuit Court, the foregoing facts are the true history of this case) Wee tharefore as the nabors of gibbens believe That the charge of gibbens<hi rend="underline">ss</hi> Stealing the hogs to be unfounded and was instigated by malace We therefore most Respectfully ask your Exlency to Release him from the charge in Said indibtment in doing So you will
<lb/><note place="footer">over</note><pb/>
<lb/>comply with the wishes of a portion of your fellow citizens and. The nabors of William gibbens Wee Also believe That The foregoing charge will be attempted to be Supported by men <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> who were in arms against the government of the united states in <date when="1864">1864</date> When the hogs w<hi rend="str">a</hi>ere taken from gibbens and attempted to parole Said gibbens as <hi rend="str">if</hi> <hi rend="str">he</hi>A federal Soldier</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Wiley Mountjoy
<lb/><cb n="2"/>S. Y. Willis
<lb/>W. Moffett
<lb/>J E Willis
<lb/>Robert Catlet
<lb/>J A Cinnamond
<lb/>Peter Parmer
<lb/>John Melias
<lb/>Robert Carlton 
<lb/>James, D, Richy
<lb/>B. V. Hart
<lb/>J, M, Hawkins
<lb/>Francis Catlet
<lb/>Elisha Parmer
<lb/>John grace
<lb/>P. A. Spears
<lb/>W B Searcy
<lb/>R Brown
<lb/>D,, N,, Redmon
<lb/>P,, M,, Nolan
<lb/>Brice Willard
<lb/>S P M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>gaughey
<lb/>Henry grace<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Anderson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs 
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Gibsen</p>
<p>not a proper case ^for^ Consideration of Executive before <hi rend="underline">trial</hi>.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
