<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0662"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Z. Wheat to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4781</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-16</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Shelbyville, Shelby County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-04-19">19 April 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Shelbyville Ky <date when="1864-04-19">Apl. 19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Gov. Bramlette
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>I write to solicit a remission of a fine of $10. imposed on W M Heaton by a verdict &amp; Judgment in the Police Court of this Town.</p>
<p>Heaton is a Poor honest mechanic of this Town &amp; was doubtless improperly dealt with on his trial. Jury not not here, or I think a different result would have been had.</p>
<p>From the best information I can get, Heaton was not at all to blame. He is a Loyal man, Picket is not. The witnesses to the transaction are also secessionists, I could not remember what<pb/>
<lb/>threats Picket made, although he had drawn a pistol &amp; pointed it at Heaton, before Heaton opened his mouth, &amp; Swore he would blow his brains out if he spoke or even batted his eye. Heatons Pistol was in his belt, under his coat, buckled in the case, &amp; he had to wait till Picketts eye was off him, before he could draw in safety. He drew, but Picket shot first &amp; just as Heaton drew his weapon Heaton, made him cower &amp; get out of the way.</p>
<p>The most of the jury who tried the case are secessionists.</p>
<p>This case is a small one, but is an outrage, from which I hope you will redeem Heaton, by remitting the<pb/>
<lb/>fine. You know, I trust, that I would not solicit this, if I did not believe it to be right.</p>
<p>Yours &amp;c
<lb/>Z Wheat</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
