<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1632"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Bell et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11100</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Andrew P Patrick</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-288</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-01-13">13 January 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellincy B. Magoffin
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitiioners John Bell, R Varble, &amp; Patrick Fitzpatrick, state, that at the January term of the city Court of Louisville (1862) they were each fine two hundred dollars, upon an Indictment for permitting Gaming in their house. They are Keepers of Coffee &amp; boarding houses, The Gaming complained of was not for money, but sometimes their boarders &amp; neighbors played Games of "Euchre," "whist" &amp; "seven up" for drinks &amp; cigars, in a sociable &amp; friendly manner, They state that, they never permitted Gaming for money in their houses, So soon as they were advised, that such Gaming were against the law, They appeared in court &amp; confessed, <hi rend="str">with the</hi> and now state that they will hereafter prohibit such violations of the law They are poor and unable to pay said fines Wherefore they respectfully, ask your Exellency to remit said fines &amp; as in duty bound will ever pray&amp; -- </p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>John Bell
<lb/>R Varble
<lb/>Patrick Fitzpatrick</p>
<p>Louisville <date when="1862-01-13">Jan. 13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1862</date></p>
<p>The above petition fairly states the case of petitioners. They live in the same neighborhood, and are clean, industrious and Except in the above instance I know of no violation of the law having been committed by either of them. I am satisfied they will hereafter refrain as promised &amp; considering the circumstances &amp; character of Petitioners, and the nature of the offence, I respectfully unite with them &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi></p>
<p>W, G, Reasor city atto,</p>
<p>The Petitioners confessed Judgement in Each case but from facts stated to me &amp; on which I rely I think the fines should be remitted.</p>
<p>Geo. W. Johnston<pb/></p>
<p>Louisville City Ct
<lb/>$200 each } gaming
<lb/>Jno. Bell &amp; others
<lb/>Resp<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Mo<hi rend="sup">s</hi>
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-01-17">Jany 17. 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
