<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0270"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">S. A. Spencer to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9738</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-247 to MG17-248</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Greensburg, Green County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-12-24">24 December 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Greensburg Ky <date when="1860-12-24">Decr 24/60</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency Governor Magoffin</p>
<p>On behalf of a poor man Fidella Warren a citizen of our county I inclose the written petition to be relieved from the payment of a small fine for the alledged offence of committing a Breach of the public peace. The amt it is true is small, and to one who is able to pay it would be but a trivial matter but to him it will render the present pressure of the times be a great hardship. his little family of children and a wife depend on him for their support and if he is required to pay this fine it will take then little all from them. The neighbors and those who know the man. all concur in respectfully asking your Excellency to remit this fine</p>
<p>All of which is respectfully submitted to your Excellency</p>
<p>I have the honor to be
<lb/>very respectfully
<lb/>your obtdt
<lb/>Servt
<lb/>S A Spencer<pb/></p>
<p>Warren case
<lb/>Green Co -- <pb/></p>
<p>To His Excellency Beriah Magoffin Governer of the state of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your petitioner Fidella Warren would most respectfully state that on the <date when="1860-12-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of th Decr 1860</date>, he was taken before John Bloyd a justice of the Peace for Green County, and there tried for rioting and fined the sum of fifteen Dollars. &amp; Cost</p>
<p>Your petitioner knew he was present at the time the rioting took place and that the only part he took in the matter was to attempt to seperate the rioters and preserve the peace, and supposed that this would certainly be the finding of the jury. knowing his own innocence of any violation of the law, or any part in the riot he employed no counsel, supposing the verdict would acquit him, but the Jury fined him the amount above stated, which though a small sum he cannot pay and if pressed for it will have to lay in jail for it and he has a family <hi rend="str">of wife</hi> consisting of a wife and two small children entirely dependant upon him, and he can scarcely make enough to sustain them by his daily labor, owing to the excessive hard times in this section of the country</p>
<p>fidella warren<pb/></p>
<p>We would respectfully state to your excellency that we earnestly join in with the petitioner in requesting you to remit the fine imposed upon him, as we <hi rend="str">do not</hi> the country is in a most deplorable and miserable condition at this time, we know him and can state that he is poor man having to labor for the support of his wife and little children who would suffer if deprived of his labor. we consider him a fit subject for your clemency and beleive him to be worthy of it.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Ossian T Ward
<lb/>Isaac Garvin
<lb/>John Bloyd
<lb/>W. T Ward
<lb/>Jas. W, Howell
<lb/>L. W. Elmore
<lb/>W B Marshall
<lb/>D T Towles
<lb/>James Barnett
<lb/>G Close Eq
<lb/>David Gwen
<lb/>Jasper Saltsman
<lb/>C D Moore M D
<lb/>Peter Sidebottom
<lb/>John H Vance
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> B Moore
<lb/>F L Sidebottom
<lb/>J C, Gwin
<lb/>J, H Perkins
<lb/>Wm Lee
<lb/>James Elkin
<lb/>James Edwards
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Robert Marshall clerk of Green ^County Court^</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
