<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2064"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">P. P. Baker et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6701</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-254 to BR14-255</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Princeton, Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-07">July 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Princeton Ky <date when="1865-07">July 1865</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>Thos. E. Bramlette</p>
<p>We the undersigned state that we are Union men and citizens of Caldwell County Kentucky and would respectfully represent to your Excellency that at the <date when="1865-06">June Term ^1865^</date>, of the Caldwell Circuit Court, Jas Wilson a youth of this County was presented by the <hi rend="str">g</hi>Grand Jury of this County by three several and distinct Indictments charged with the crime of Larceny. The facts of the case are these. That a lot of young men in and about this place resolved to cast their lot with the Rebellion, and in the spring of <date when="1864">1864</date>, they started forth some of them furnishing their own horses, and others stealing from their neighbors. Jas, Wilson the accused was one of those that furnished his own horse but being afterwards seen <hi rend="str">by</hi> with those who had stolen the horses they were jointly Indicted, But said Jas. Walson the accused only remained with them three or four day's. When he returned to his father's house where he has been working upon his farm and has been demeaning himself in a very orderly manner, ever since<pb/>
<lb/>Jas, Wilson the accused at the time said acts were committed was only about 17 years of age, and is the son of a Union man, and all those that are accused in said Indictment ^<unclear/>^ are Rebels and have effected their escape form justice, by removing to other states, &amp; at the time said Wilson joined <hi rend="str">into</hi> said unlawful enterprise he was away from home attending Princeton ^College^ and from under paternal influence. and we are satisfied that if he had been at home he would not have joined in said illegal enterprise, but being young, and away from home. and the Rebel sympathisers at that time were makeing frantic efforts to rally young men around the Rebel standered, and the accused like many hundred young was inveigled into a course of crime. without being as culpable as the Rebel <unclear/> who goes wholy unwhiped of justice in full view of all these things we earnestly solicit Your Excellency to pardon the said Jas. Wilson from the said three indictments copies of which we will Enclose you,</p>
<p>Respectfully</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>P. P. Baker one of the Grand Jury of the <date when="1865-06">June term of /65</date>
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. B. Johnson
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J. W. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Coy Foreman of grand Jury of <date when="1865-06">June Term 1865</date><pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>John T. Wyatt
<lb/>David Willson
<lb/>William G Glenn
<lb/>S. B. Wigginton
<lb/>J. C. Leeper
<lb/>G. W. Adamson
<lb/>Milton Bird
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> S. Black one of the grand jury of the <date when="1865-06">June term of /65</date>
<lb/>D. L. Black
<lb/>Jno. W. Cook
<lb/>John L. Adamson
<lb/>S. B. Brelsford
<lb/>D, B, Stevenson
<lb/>one of the the Grand jury of the <date when="1865-06"><unclear>June ter</unclear> ^of 65^</date>
<lb/>B Ford one of the grand jurey of the <date when="1865-06">June Term ^of /65^</date>
<lb/>C L Trotter
<lb/>one of the grand jurer
<lb/>Q, A, Mott
<lb/>one of the Grand juery of the <date when="1865-06">June term /65</date>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J. N Turner</hi> P J
<lb/><cb n="2"/>O. Ross Baker Sheriff Caldwell County.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
