<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0371"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Michael Hauze and George Larrison, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4490</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-89 to BR9-90</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Barren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-12-11">11 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Barren Equity &amp; Criminal Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Ky Plff
<lb/>against } Amded Pet
<lb/>John W hauze &amp;c Defts</p>
<p>The defendants John W Hauze and Marion Larrison by Way of amendment to their Petition filed herein State that they belonged to the 41<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Reg 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Indiana Cavalry as Stated in their original answer That at the time that the forces at Hartsville Tenn was attacked &amp; the large porition of them captured by Rebel forces the Reg to which defendants belonged being a porition of the forces &amp; large porition of D Regiment being Captured by sd Rebels it being a Short time before they were imprisoned the defendants were Cut off from their Command That upon returning home as Stated in their original Petition the provost Marshall of the district in Which they lived towit Col Harris Kerny required them to report to him at <unclear/> &amp; refered to suffer them to attend said Court &amp; refused them permission to go to any place except to return to the army.That the defendants Marion Larrison was at the time of said Court &amp; for some time before sick with a disease to which he is subject to wit Sick Stomach &amp; head ache with vomiting &amp; General disibility confining him for Two or Three weeks &amp; was was at that time to ill to leave his home or Travel<pb/>
<lb/>&amp; could not get to S<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Court</p>
<p>That through the interposition of the Father of the Defendant Hauze the provost Marshall aforesaid was prevailed upon to let said defendant remain at home a Short time by his defendant being ready at all times to report at <unclear/> Where he had been arrested and sent to his Regiment July 1863 That at the time said Court was held &amp; the order forfeiting said bond made, on account of the defendant Soldiers and in the Service of the Military authorities by reason of the restrictions thrown around them by said authorities it was uterly impossible for them to appear in Said court</p>
<p>That they could not pass out of their State or County without a pass from said Provost Marshall or Some Military Commander</p>
<p>That they could not obtain such pass &amp; it was impossible for them to attend</p>
<p>That they are now and have been Since July last in the active Service in the army</p>
<p>Wherefore they pray as in their original Petition</p>
<p>Janes &amp; McIntire for Defts</p>
<p>State of Kentucky Barren County</p>
<p>Michael Hauze &amp; George Larrison says they are agents for the Defendants who are<pb/>
<lb/>absent from this County &amp; state &amp; that they beleave the Statements Made in the foregoing answer are ture</p>
<p>George Larrison
<lb/>Michael Hauze</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by George Larrison and Michael Hauze <date when="1863-12-11">Dec 11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date></p>
<p>L H M Minn D. C.
<lb/>A Copy Attest
<lb/>W. L. Poster Clk<pb/></p>
<p>Hauze &amp; Lamer
<lb/>Ans<hi rend="sup">d</hi>. Answer</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
