<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0432"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">H. L. Arnold and H. P. Allen to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8884</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-193 to R4-194</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-06-22">22 June 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Bowling Green Ky
<lb/><date when="1863-06-22">June 22 1863</date>
<lb/>To
<lb/>Gov Jas F Robinson:</p>
<p>The undersigned Citisens of Warren County Ky -- state that at the last <date when="--02">Feby</date> term of the Warren Equity &amp; Criminal Court -- Judgment was rendered agst them as sureties on a bond of Jno Stephens -- which was forfeited at the <date when="1862-08">Augst term 1862</date>, because of the nonappearance of said Stephens to answer a Charge of Murder for killing a soldier in Bowling Green -- belonging to the 9" Tenn -- Reg -- Vols -- </p>
<p>The judgment was for $500 -- </p>
<p>The undersigned represent most respectfully that they became sureties -- out of mere sympathy for said Stephens to keep him out of jail -- inasmuch as they did not believe him guilty of that charge. -- and if said Stephens had not gotten into another difficulty since in Russellville Ky which frightened him from the County, they believe, he would have appeared and stood his trial -- They had no desire to prevent an impartial trial -- and it was not their fault that he escaped from the hands of justice -- </p>
<p>They ask most respectfully to be relieved so far as it can be done by law.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">H. L. Arnold</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">H. P. Allen</hi><pb/></p>
<p>I defended Mr. Stephens before the Court of inquiry &amp; am satisfied from the proof that he acted in self defence, &amp; the Court, in my opinion ^at this time^ only required bail to quiet the excited soldiers who were present at the trial, I therefore unite in the prayer of the petitioners</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> V. Loving</hi></p>
<p>We, the undersigned, unite in the foregoing prayer of the petitioners, Arnold &amp; Allen -- </p>
<p>W H Payne</p>
<p>I was the County Attorney who attended to the prosecution of John Stephens in the Examining Court. I am satisfied from the Testimony that he would have been acquitted on the final trial if he had stood his trial.</p>
<p>J, E, Holsell</p>
<p>I was one of the examining court who tried Stephens &amp; held him to bail upon very slight evidence, which without others corroborative evidence upon the final trial I think would not convict him of any high offense</p>
<p>W H Payne<pb/></p>
<p>I was one of the examing Court who tried Stephens and held him to bail on the sum of five hundred dollars What I done in the primises I done from a sense of duty I have no doubt Stephens would have appeared before the Court had he not got in a seccond difficulty of a more serious nature I would therefore most respectfully ask your honor the Govenor of Kentucky to remit the fine or Judgement against H. L. Arnold &amp; H. P. Allen his securities if consistent with your feelings</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">P. Hines</hi></p>
<p>Govr. Robinson is very respectfully requested to reply to the foregoing petition at his earliest convenience &amp; oblige</p>
<p>Your obt. Svt
<lb/>Arnold &amp; Allen
<lb/><date when="1863-06-23">June 23rd. 1863</date><pb/></p>
<p>Warren Eq. Ct
<lb/>Arnold &amp; Allen Pettn to remit fines in Warren County -- 
<lb/>$500 }Recog.</p>
<p>Remitted except one hundred dollars &amp; costs</p>
<p>J F Robinson
<lb/>Iss <date when="1863-06-26">June 26 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
