<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0962"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John J. Manning et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10430</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-5 to MG20-6</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-04-01">1 April 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The undersigned Citizens of Warren County, Most respectfully beg leave to offer a few Sugestiens to His Excellency Govner Magoffin why Rufus Jones convicted of mans-slaughter for Killing Henry Jinkins Should not be pardoned</p>
<p>In the 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Place it is useless to have laws unless they are executed. The great evil of our<hi rend="str">e</hi> day is that all laws and objectives Moral and Legal are relaxed,</p>
<p>In the 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Place, There is nothing in the case certainly not in the testimony to show that Jones has got any more punishment than his case demands, Indeed it is almost the universal opinion that he got off very well with four years imprisonment and he ought to be glad of that and so far as we know his friends have not complained of the Jury for finding that the length of time.</p>
<p>In the 3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Place If Jones is pardoned we dont see why the whole lot of prisoners in the prison at Frankfort may not be turned out on the Same principal,</p>
<p>In the 4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Place If Jones is discharged it will amount to a general invitation to all violaters of the law to repeat their offenses, And the design of the law will not be met, While then we do not go with any Specific personal charge, we barely Say that the Gov can't read a copy of the testimony before the examining court on the final trial and Say on his oath or concience that Jones ought to be discharged,
<lb/><date when="1861-04-01">April 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>John J. Manning<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>John J Manning
<lb/>S A M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Ginnis
<lb/>A. J. Stewart
<lb/>J W Koons
<lb/>Thos. Richards
<lb/>Wm Stewart
<lb/>J A Stevenson
<lb/>Henry Hester
<lb/>J, H, Hester
<lb/>G G Stewart
<lb/>A. C. Stevenson
<lb/>James Colvin
<lb/>James C. Stewart
<lb/>J. D. Ferguson
<lb/>Moses Taylor
<lb/>James B Taylor
<lb/>John S. Adams
<lb/>P C Romans
<lb/>G. W. Blankinship
<lb/>S.. P.. Sublett
<lb/>Bengamin Ward
<lb/>Jas H Hines
<lb/>W. P. Waddle
<lb/>Thos Alderson
<lb/>James Heard
<lb/>Jas. M. Taylor
<lb/>H. H Cox
<lb/>William Ressner
<lb/>H. J. Nieghbours
<lb/>C. W. Westbrooks
<lb/>J A Cherry
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/>Jas S. Cherry
<lb/>A. A. Cherry
<lb/>J. T. Cherry
<lb/>James J Manning
<lb/>W B Cherry
<lb/>I. A. Simmons
<lb/>Wm L Peak
<lb/>G, W, Stephens
<lb/>David Spencer
<lb/>B F Sublett
<lb/>Hugh Campbell</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
