<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1151"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. D. A. Layman, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10619</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-301 to MG20-302</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>Kenton Circuit Court,
<lb/>Comwth of Kentucky
<lb/>agst } wounding with intent to kill
<lb/>D. A. Layman</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Kenton County in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, accuse D. S. Layman of the crime of wilfully &amp; maliciously, shooting at and wounding one Charles Leonard, so that he did not &amp; has not died thereby, committed as follows_viz -- </p>
<p>The said D. A. Layman on the <gap/> day of <date when="1860-07">July in the year of our Lord, one thousand Eight hundred &amp; Sixty</date> and before the finding of this Indictment, in the county aforesaid, with a Gun Commonly called a pistol, loaded with a leaden bullet, and other hard substances, then and there had &amp; held by said Layman, wilfully maliciously and feloniously did make, and commit an assault in and upon one Charles Leonard, and him the said Leonard, in the manner &amp; form aforesaid, with <hi rend="str">ill</hi> willful malicious and felonious intention then and there to kill and murder, did<pb/>
<lb/>then and there shoot at and wound, against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>W. E. Arthur, atty <hi rend="underline">for the Comwth</hi></p>
<p>witnesses
<lb/>M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> R Buckingham
<lb/>Isabella Robinson
<lb/>Eliza Culvin
<lb/>Anna Cochran
<lb/>W. B. Watts
<lb/>Charles Leonard</p>
<p>copy attest
<lb/><hi rend="underline">N. B. Stephens, clk</hi></p>
<p>Kenton County
<lb/>Examining Court
<lb/>Commonwealth of Ky Pltff
<lb/>agst } Bond
<lb/>D A Sagman Deft</p>
<p>D. A. Layman being in custody, charged with the offence of malicious shooting, and being admitted to Bail in the sum of Six hundred Dollars, $600<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> Now we D. A. Layman &amp; J. C. Thomas hereby undertake, that the above named D. A. Layman, will appear in the Kenton Circuit Court on the first day of its next <date when="1861-09">September</date> Term in Covington<pb/>
<lb/>to answer said charge, and will at all times render himself amenable to the orders and process of said Court, in the prosecution of said charge, and if convicted will render himself in Execution thereof, or if he shall fail to perform, Either of these conditions, That we will pay to the Commonwealth of Kentucky The sum of six hundred Dollars ($600<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi>) witness our hands this <date when="1860-07-20">20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of July 1860</date></p>
<p>D A Layman
<lb/>J. C. Thomas</p>
<p>taken and subscribed before us as Examining Court of Kenton County </p>
<p>J. C. Howard J. P. K C
<lb/>Benj Eggleston J P K C</p>
<p>copy att
<lb/><hi rend="underline">N. B. Stephens clerk</hi></p>
<p>At the <date when="1861-06">June Term 1861,</date> the above named D A. Layman appeared and was try and convicted under the above indictment of shooting in sudden affray and amend his fine at $125 -- I am ac-<pb/>
<lb/>quainted with Layman's circumstances, and believe him unable to pay the fine -- He is now confined in the Jail of Kenton County in difault of payment He had indemnified his surety ^in the Bail bond^ in some measure Most of which has been <hi rend="str">when</hi> exhausted in paying that costs and the attos' part of the forfeiture I heard the trial and believe that the offence was not an agravated one and the question of guilt at least Doubtfull. I was not his attorney, but believe his appeal for executive clemency meritorious he having a wife and three small children wholly Dependant on him for support and he no means except the remains of a broken Down <unclear/> establishment</p>
<p><date when="1861-06-02">June 2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>Kenton Cir Ct
<lb/>Commonwealth
<lb/>agst } Copy Indict &amp; Bail Bond
<lb/>D A Layman<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>$600 } For. Recog
<lb/>Copies</p>
<p>Respite 12 Mos
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-06-21">June 21 1861</date><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Remission Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi>
<lb/><date when="1861-07-09">July 9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Fee 60cts for D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> J. C. Thomas</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
