<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3176"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Joseph M. Cecill to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5295</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-222 to BR41-223</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Wayne County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>Governor. Thos. E. Bramlett</p>
<p>Your Petitioner humbly sheweth unto your Excellency that at the close of the war before Peace had been fully declared and So understood by the citizens of our state There may have been several misdemeanors committed before the majesty of the law had asserted her Judicial authority over the citizens of our Said State. And during Said time your Petitioner would most respectfully state to your Excellency That he has been arrested and Indicted for an Assault &amp; Battery against <hi rend="str">Richard</hi> Rachael Adkins and others And Petitioner states that there was no Serious damage done to the Said Adkins. That it; the prosecution has only been Instituted against him because he has honorably discharged the duties of a Federal Soldier and is now drawing a Pension from the General Government for wounds recieved in Battle for the cause of American Liberty. And further petitioner States That he is not guilty of the offence alledged against ^him^ that if it was done it was in conformity with Military Authority and under military order and<pb/>
<lb/>Petitioner believes that the civil power of the state has no cognizance of offences committed during that time and that all such acts of violence were only subject to the Jurisdiction of County Martial and orders of Military officer in High rank, and petitioner believes if any such act was committed, it was Belligerent in the legal Import of the Term and was not such an offence as was cognizable by the courts of our state. And Petitioner would state that the prosecutor ^has maleciously Prosecuted him^ and <hi rend="str">his</hi> <hi rend="str">friends</hi> <hi rend="str">live in a strong Rebel section of this County</hi> and that he is informed and fully- believes that the aforesaid prosecution is made against him out of the strongest prejudices and Maliciously Instituted in order to gratify the malice of the prosecutor friends and it is needless to say that they are and Have been the Enemies of the Government And farther Petitioner states that some two others were Jointly Indicted with him and have removed from this State and if there was an assault committed it may have been by them and the prosecutor has Said proper to hold petitioner Culpable for their Deeds, and unless your<pb/>
<lb/>Humble petitioner Can Have your Interposition He can find no relief at their Hands But will be involved in great Costs and subject himself to the mercy of the prosecutor. your Petitioner believing in your mercies and charities and Firmness in administering Exact Justice to all your subects of our Said State</p>
<p>Therefore prays that you will Pardon and demand that the state or Commonwealth will no further prosecute this Said cause And Relieve him frm said prosecution and all Such further and General Relief as your Excellency may Grant</p>
<p>Your Humble Petitioner
<lb/>Joseph M. Cecill
<lb/>surveyor Wayne Co</p>
<p>Jno L Sallee Clk ^circuit court^
<lb/>he his a good fellow
<lb/>William Dobbs S W C</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>James Duran
<lb/>S Duncan
<lb/>Smith Barrier
<lb/>B W Dunckin
<lb/>Emuel Sanduskey
<lb/>Julin F. Friels
<lb/>G W Biel
<lb/>P Miller
<lb/><cb n="2"/>F M Supter
<lb/>MarSal of Martin Co
<lb/>I Sertifi that he is a onest man and peaceable
<lb/>Nicoles Sharp
<lb/>James aruck
<lb/>J T Welhite
<lb/><hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi><milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>J John B Drake
<lb/>B.S. <hi rend="underline">Fleming</hi>
<lb/>J. T. Warden
<lb/>P G White
<lb/>William Miller
<lb/>C H Buster
<lb/>William Bartleson
<lb/>William Buster
<lb/>Havey Bartheson</p>
<p>Wayne Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Jos M Cecil</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
