<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2190"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. A. Sinclair et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9266</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-308 to MG24-309</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin Gov of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p><hi rend="str">Respectable</hi> <gap/> Your petitioners would respectfully Represent that at the <date when="--11">Nov Term</date> of Scott Circuit Court Sandford Tomlinson was tried for shooting John Baker with intent to kill and was for Said offence fined the sum of fifty dollars &amp; cost and imprisonment in the County jail for Six months We would further State that we believe that Said Tomblinson shot at Said Baker honestly believing that he would be killed or badly injured by Said Baker. The proof in the case clearly Showing that Said Baker had ^on^ various occasion treated Said Tomblinson in such a manner as would have justified said Tobinson in killing him and that the only thing which could have possibly justified Such a verdict is that Said Tomblison Shot at the wrong time. Notwithstanding we believe he honestly thought he would be attacked He having been abused by Said Baker once or twice the same day. We f<hi rend="str">u</hi>arther State that Sandford Tomblinson So far our intercourse has been, is a good law abiding Citizen It was proven by several witnesses in Court that Baker had threatened to take the life of said Tomblinson on former occasions We would therefore knowing the facts in in the case pray Your Excellency to remit the fine and release Said Tomblinson from the imprisonment. And your petitioners woud ever pray.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/> Mr J. A. Sinclair
<lb/>James S. Gorham
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Sinnett T. Johnson
<lb/>T M Andrew<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>Henry B Fowler
<lb/>Eliza Booce
<lb/>A. C. Alsop
<lb/>P. Calvert
<lb/>V. C Bradley
<lb/>Berry Fugett
<lb/>F. C. Johnson
<lb/>J L Gatewood
<lb/>Richard Thomason
<lb/>Reuben B Seler
<lb/>James Mullen
<lb/>A J Aderson
<lb/>W. D Penderton
<lb/>J N Gatewood
<lb/>J. H. Mcmillin
<lb/>Mason Lucas
<lb/>Sears Burton
<lb/>Samuel Campbell
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> F. Campbell
<lb/>John W. Lucas
<lb/>William Butten
<lb/>John F Fugett
<lb/>William Hockenswith
<lb/>Lloyd R Gayle
<lb/>Samuel T. Gayle
<lb/>Elza Thomason<pb/></p>
<p>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Pet
<lb/>Sanford Tomlinson</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
