<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-007-0242"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">David A. Sayre to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1907</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Appointments by the Governor, Civil Appointments, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR2-110 to BR2-111</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lexington, Fayette County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-07-05">5 July 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Lexington <date when="1864-07-05">July 5/64</date>
<lb/>Hon<hi rend="sup">r</hi> T E Bramlet
<lb/>Resp Friend</p>
<p>You will do A faveur to A Worthy And Loyal Man my friend Joseph B Cooper A Clerk At Camp Nelson to Appoint him A Notary Publik for of that place he is well qualified to fill the office And I am enformed it is An Office that is <hi rend="underline">much Needed</hi> that At this time And he is A Clerk in the Quarter Masters Department there And it is thought <hi rend="str">Ab</hi> he very emportant to<pb/>
<lb/>A Notary thare to transact Government Business And to oblige the Publick</p>
<p>I hope you will be so good As to send Mr. Cooper A Commission to this place for the office And you will oblige your friend And</p>
<p>Obt. Se<hi rend="sup">t</hi>
<lb/>David A. Sayre</p>
<p>P S I hope you can send it to him by return male he is An old citizen of this place And worthy of the appointment</p>
<p>D A S<pb/></p>
<p>Dear Governor.</p>
<p>As I dont suppose that you will be able to decypher Uncle Davy's letter, I will say that it is a recommendation for the appointing of Joseph B Cooper a clerk at Camp Nelson Jessamine County, Notary Public. There is no Notary here and one constantly needed. I have long known Mr. Cooper and heartely join in the recommendation.</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>M C Johnson<pb/></p>
<p>Jessamine Co
<lb/>Notary Public
<lb/>J B Cooper
<lb/>Appt<hi rend="sup">d</hi>.
<lb/><date when="1864-07-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> July/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
