<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2718"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William May to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7355</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-370 to BR16-372</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlette Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner William May states that in the fall of the year <date when="1862">1862</date> and shortly after Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Bragg with his Confederate forces ^left Ky^ one of Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Woolfords Company, John W Gully pressed a horse of Cyrus Saunders of Garrard county to go to his regiment near Stanford Ky. He was pursued by Saunders &amp; others and was taken with a writ for Larceny, and the officer of the regiment gave him up to the Civil authorities and he was brought to and put in the Garrard county jail, where he remained for several weeks, when on a pledge he would go to his regiment and continue in the service, your Petitioner became his bail for $150 for his appearance at court, which he attended once or twice and the case was not ready, and finally without fault on the part of your Petitioner, he failed to attend, and the bail bond was forfieted, and is now in judgment. Your Petitioner in his desire to see<pb/>
<lb/>the Federal service prosper, (being an unconditional Union man) he has involved himself as surety aforesaid, and asks that so much of the judgment above named as is in the power of Executive Clemency be remitted</p>
<p>William May</p>
<p>We the undersigned are well acquainted with the Petitioner, and recommend him to Executive Clemency.</p>
<p>G. W. Dunlap
<lb/>W. H. Whurell
<lb/>N Sandifer
<lb/>John W Letcher
<lb/>W D Hopper clerk Garrard Circuit Court
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H. Kinnaird<pb/></p>
<p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thomas E Bramlette Esq
<lb/>Frankfort
<lb/>Ky.</p>
<p>Garrard Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> May
<lb/>$150
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-11-10">10th Nov/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
