<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2549"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Lewis Colbert et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7186</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-77 to BR16-78</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thomas E Bramlett Govenor of Kentucky The undersigned petitioners citizens of Boyd County would respectfully represent that at the <date when="1865-10">October term of the Boyd circuit court 1865</date> a judgment was rendered against German May for Sixty dollars on an Indictment for Keeping a tippling house, the proof showed that may was licensed to sell by the Quart as a merchant and there was no proof that he sold in any less quantity but the proof was clear that he refused to sell any smaller quantity one witness proved he sold a quart and that he went out of the house with it over in the Rail Road some distance from the place where sold and there he and another man took a drink, upon this proof the jury returned<pb/>
<lb/>a verdict of Guilty we are sure that May has conducted the sale of liquor with more than ordinary care and respect for the law we therefore pray your Excellency to remitt this fine against him</p>
<p>Lewis Colbert
<lb/>T. A. Newman
<lb/>plesant couft
<lb/>I Black
<lb/>W D Creasey
<lb/>Moses Everman
<lb/>John R Hold
<lb/>John Triplet
<lb/>Johnathan Colbert
<lb/>Wil Kibby
<lb/>George Burgraf
<lb/>A. Meyers
<lb/>Georg Sohmer
<lb/>Johnny Long
<lb/>Geo M. Rouse
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Arthur
<lb/>Martin duval
<lb/>J W Pough
<lb/>Greenhill Arthur
<lb/>Samuel, Arthur
<lb/>John P. Brien
<lb/>J, M, Gray<pb/>
<lb/>German May</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
