<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-027-0051"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">I. Stuart to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1284</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R2-82</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Brandenburg, Meade County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-10-08">8 October 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Brandenburg <date when="1862-10-08">Oct<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi> 8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1862.</date>
<lb/>Gov. Robinson</p>
<p>Recent events have demonstrated that one of two classes of population in this state must depart or be expelled from it. Their is not One of all the rebel population who is not covertly at War with the Federal &amp; state authorities I have closely observed their temper ever since the Rebellion began, and in no instance have I known of One of them condemning in any way acts the most atrocious and bloody if done under the rebellion I find all of them ready to endorse murder, Robbery, Rape, to furnish every bad man any amount of their property horses, money, Weapons, to act as spies, &amp; informers, to grudge no pains or expense, in getting newspapers &amp; other information, and going great Journies to bear it to the enemies of the Country I have observed that they long since have abandoned all interest in Government regarding it as their enemy, by their acts <hi rend="str">decl</hi> &amp; professions declaring that they neither hold life or property under the legal system</p>
<p>While this is the case with that class their is the loyal man declaring that his life &amp; all he has are dedicated to the perpetuation of the moral legal &amp; civil system &amp; that he will part with them all before he will leave the ship Now can these two ever come under a common obediance to the same civil Compact<pb/>
<lb/>simply no One or the other must go The invasion was invited is endorsed &amp; sustained by Ky population -- under the protection of Government Men crops, clothing, arms, are all reared trained raised &amp; matured for the ragged ranks of Rebellion &amp; so it will ever be until the Rebel men Women &amp; children and so disposed of that they loose all possible influence within these borders. The Jews &amp; Egyptians must one or the other have perished but for the Exdus so with the people of Ky and we had just as well face the crisis at once This small Community is an example we cant live together they are all of them willing that all of us may die by any means however atrocious &amp; we have determined to <hi rend="str">f</hi>keep the supremacy by dealing death among them I write this to aid the authorities in solving the enormous issues that are upon us as it is you can take 25000. men of the Rebels are baffle 75.000 Federal troops such an instance is now before our eyes I have been as conservative as the best way -- in me Conservatism has degenerated in Cowardice but I would now embrace the remedy of having four fifths of my family expelled from this State with every other person of any age that has professed or been educated in rebellion The rebel President was right when he expelled every hostile element from his rule at least it was the best step toward success. </p>
<p>Pardon the intrusion.
<lb/>obtly &amp;c
<lb/>I. Stuart</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
