<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0570"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas C. Judy et al. to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9022</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Hannah M. O'Daniel</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-403 to R4-404</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Honor <persName ref="cwgk:N001004">The Govenor</persName> of <orgName ref="cwgk:O001025">Kentucky</orgName></p>
   <p>We the citizens of <placeName ref="cwgk:P00001937">Powell County</placeName> beg leave to represent to your Honor That <persName ref="cwgk:N00006972">Bazel Hall</persName> now confined in <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000266">the state prison</orgName> sent their from the <placeName ref="cwgk:P00006506">county of Madison</placeName> was born and reared in this county that we are well acquainted with him and know the familey of which he is desendent the Familey is large and respectable there is Some of them that has not been of mutch benefit to the repetation of the Family tis true yet it remaines true that the familey is respectable The said <persName ref="cwgk:N00006972">Bazel Hall</persName> was young when he commited the crime for which he was confined in prison <persName ref="cwgk:N00006974">his father</persName> had been dead for several years <persName ref="cwgk:N00006973">his Mother</persName> in the state of <placeName ref="cwgk:P00001883">Missouri</placeName> he heare without constraint soon learned some bad habits and earley formed bad associations and out of thees doubtless grue his crime and greate falt more than out of his nature and we are thereby convinced that it grue not out of his earley Education for his parrents was Honest We further beg leave to informe you that he has a Brother now in the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00001186">Federal Armey</orgName> -- <persName ref="cwgk:N00006975">Capt G V Hall</persName> <orgName ref="cwgk:O00006977">Co C 24f<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Ridg Ky Vol</orgName> for his character as a man we can vouch for his bearing as a Soldiel we would refur you to <persName ref="cwgk:N00004947">Col L B Grigsby</persName> and <persName ref="cwgk:N00006976">Lieut Col J S Hurt</persName></p>
<p>Now we do not pretend to represent to you that his crime was insignificant or that his confinement unjust and oppressive we suppose that the Judg and Jury simply done their duty<pb/>
<lb/>But we pleade his age-- a youth without experience without a Father &amp; Mother in a distant state we pleade his Family and above this we pleade the service of his Brother and lastly we pleade our sympathy for his condition and ask and Pray your Honor that you repreave him</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006959">Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> C <unclear>Judy</unclear></persName> Clerk 
<orgName ref="cwgk:O00000680">P. C. C.</orgName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006960">Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> B Hardwick</persName> J. P. C C
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006961">John F Halley</persName> J P C
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006962">Joseph L. Judy</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006963">J. H. Scholl</persName> Ck P cir ct
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006965">Joab Morton</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006966">C D. Creed C P C</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006967">Nasmanres Teartner</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006968">Romulous Snopes</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006969">G M Wood</persName>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006970">Geo M Pettit</persName>. P, M,
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006964">J T Clark</persName>
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Gov Robenson
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>The petitioners who have signed the within paper are the best men in Powell Co. where Basil Hall was raised &amp; lived at the time he was convicted I defended Mr Hall and believe him an honest man and that he <hi rend="str">forged</hi> committed the forgery of which he has been convicted when so drunk he did not understand what he was doing &amp; hope you will parden him He is a brother of Capt G V Hall of the 24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky infty and has as you have learned the full confidence of the <unclear/> of the penitentiary</p>
<p>Yrs
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006971">Thos <unclear>Lunen</unclear></persName><pb/></p>
<p>Pettn for pardon of Basil Hall
<lb/>already granted</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
