<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0943"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James T. Donaldson to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10411</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-493 to MG19-494</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-04-02">2 April 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Bowling Green Ky <date when="1861-04-02">April 2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> 1861.</date>
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>Gov. Mcgoffin
<lb/>D<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Sir</p>
<p>I understand that efforts are being made to obtain executive clemency in behalf of <hi rend="str">Henry</hi>Rufus Jones convicted of manslaughter <hi rend="str">&amp;</hi> Sent from this County to the Penetentairy for five years</p>
<p>At the time the murder occured the act was properly called but by delays in court putting of trial &amp; maneuvering to have an accomplice tried Seperately &amp; cleared; the testimony desired was obtained &amp; by these means no doubt Jones was saved from capital punishment and Since he has been So lienently dealt with by law I, and almost every man I have heard express an opinion think that the young blood Should be Suffered to cool &amp; that he Should not be turned loose upon the community to again perpetrate Some desperate action to be again releaved of punishment designated by the law for Such crimes by the money &amp; influence of his rich Kin, I most Earnestly petition you to give Jones a trade for the full time he was Sentanced for, that he may have the ability to Support himself &amp; have an occupation, the lack of which, may have lead him into disipated company &amp; assosiated him with desperate men who think it <hi rend="underline">brave</hi> to violate the laws of the land &amp; brag that they have Killed their man Hoping that you ^may^ think it proper in this case that the laws be executed According to the Sentence I remain very Resp<hi rend="sup">y</hi> your fr<hi rend="sup">d</hi> &amp; Obt svt</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Jas</hi>,, <hi rend="underline">T Donaldson</hi><pb/></p>
<p><stamp>BOWLING <unclear>GRE</unclear>EN
<lb/>Apr 8
<lb/>1861
<lb/>KY</stamp></p>
<p>His Excellency
<lb/>Gov B Mcgoffin
<lb/>Frankfort
<lb/>Ky</p>
<p>File in Jones Case</p>
<p><figure type="postmark"><listPlace><place><placeName>Bowling <unclear/> KY
<lb/><date when="1861-04-08">Apr 8 1861</date></placeName></place></listPlace></figure></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
