<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-003-0033"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Joseph H. Glover to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1550</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR5-55 to BR5-56</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Glasgow, Barren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-12-05">5 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Glasgow, Barren Co Ky
<lb/><date when="1863-12-05">Dec 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>.
<lb/>Govenor Bramlet,</p>
<p>Sir I Submit for your conSideration a plan for a Battery of Guns, which I consider a very formidable &amp; Destructive wepon</p>
<p>I am Satisfied that with two of these Batteries &amp; twenty five men I could resist an attack of 500 Successfully, for the protection of Depots RailRoad &amp; Bridge it will Surpass all others and if you think it advisable to Submit the plan to the Legislature &amp; ^have^ Some of them Built, I think it would be time &amp; money well Spent,</p>
<p>The Gun is mounted on wheels like other Guns &amp; can be Drawn by Horses in the Same way</p>
<p>it is pited in the Ground or Surrounded By Earth work or other fortification, the Soldiers that work it are also Secure all the time, under the Surface of the Ground &amp; have nothing to do But to Pull Down alternatly Each End of the walking Beam, which Rols the cilinders. Sets the trigers, &amp; fires every time Each End is thrown above the Surface, as you See from the Dotted lines in the Draught, you can take whativer Range that the Locality of the Ground may Require verry Readily, without any fear of Panic or Reckless Shooting it can be carried in the can which would protect them against guerillers Each Battiry can be made with a Single or Double teer of guns, Each Gun is provided with a cilinder containing from 5 to 10 charg<hi rend="str">d</hi>es Each Battery is fired at least 5 times in a minuit making 10 Shots to the minuit, which would <unclear>than</unclear><pb/>
<lb/>from 2 to 5000 Shot to the minuit,</p>
<p>So you See that it would be impossible to Surround me with any hope of Success as the Shootigs is Spirrally</p>
<p>you See from the Draught on forth page that the cilendars are Roled with a cog wheel, I have left off the top plate, so that you could <gap/> See its inside</p>
<p><figure/><pb/>
<lb/>all the triger work is Secure inside of Iron plates</p>
<p>I would like to have the Command of Several of these Guns, &amp; a fiew men &amp; go to the Cumberland Mountains to enduce Hamilton or Ferguson to make an attack on me </p>
<p><figure/>
<lb/>My Health will not Permit me to go into the Regular Service But if the Ligislature will have some of these guns Built I will try it a while with your permision or the presidents</p>
<p>we have Sufered much from the plunderg Bands of Robers we Dont Expect to make or much crop next year unless these Gurrillers Band can be Broken up<pb/>
<lb/>you See from the letter marks the guns &amp; cilinders <hi rend="str">f</hi> for guns &amp; C. for cilinder</p>
<p>Your Resply
<lb/>Joseph.H. Glover</p>
<p><figure/> 
<lb/>I have taken the nessary steps to Secure a pattent. But that wont make the Guns</p>
<p>I will freely give the Right to the State if it will assit in crushing this Damnable Rebellion</p>
<p>I Sometimes talk a little about the Union, &amp; on another Sheet I give you some of my opinions</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
