<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0261"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John W. Woodward to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9729</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-235 to MG17-236</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your petitioner John W Woodward respectfully states, that at the Barren Equity &amp; Criminal Court, he was fined the sum of Two hundred dollars for keeping a Tippling house for three consecutive months. He states that the charge was proven by but one witness, and at the time the charge was made against him, he was a merchant in the town of Edmunton and had a license <hi rend="str">to</hi>from the Barren County Court to retail spirituous liquors by the quart, He states that it was untrue that he ever sold any liquors to be drank on the premises or on the premises adjacent thereto, but was in the habit of giving his customers a dram when they bought liquors by the quart, for the purpose of carrying it away. He states that the evidence by the witness was; during some three months prior to the finding of the indictment, that at some several times during the months prior. (the witness not able to state the number of times) that witness had seen your petitioner sell liquors<pb/>
<lb/>by the quart, and at the same time, he saw the liquor drank in the house by those who brought liquors by the quart. -- saw money passed, but could not state whether it was paid for the liquor which was carried away, or that which was drank in the house. He states that the witness was a man who was in the habit of drinking liquor, and getting drunk, and often made application to your petitioner ^to get liquor^ by the drink, and in consequence of the refusal to sell him liquor by the drink, witness fell out with <hi rend="str">with</hi> petitioner, went before the grand Jury and indicted him.</p>
<p>Your petitioner is a man is very ordinary circumstances, with a large family to maintain ^<hi rend="str">and</hi>^ and ^in very ill health^ relying upon his business for a support,</p>
<p>Your excellency is well aware of the money crisis. Wherefore your petitioner humbly prays that the Executive clemency be extend to him.</p>
<p>Jno, W, Woodward<pb/></p>
<p>James A Rousseau states that he was present at the trial, and the evidence stated in the petition is about the amount of proof that was made and that he is acquainted with John W Woodward, and that the statements in the petition in relation to his condition and family are true, he is of the opinion that his case is one that deserves the clemency of the Executive and therefore recommends that it be extended to him.</p>
<p>J, A, Rousseau</p>
<p>We the undersigned state that we have been acquainted with John W Woodward since the year <date when="1854">1854</date>, and have been about his house since the time he has been doing business in Edmunton, a great deal, and have never known him to sell any liquors to be drank in his house or upon his premises, that we are well acquainted with his circumstanes and know that he has had bad health for the last ten years, and scarcely able to attend to his business. We are fully satisfied that his case is one that deserves the executive<pb/>
<lb/>clemency, and therefore candidly recommend it.</p>
<p>R. H. Young
<lb/>Joseph B Stockton
<lb/>J. W. Compton
<lb/>Charles Yates
<lb/>S, H, Maris
<lb/>W C Pool
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> F. Kiel
<lb/>J R Witty<pb/></p>
<p>Barren E &amp; C Ct
<lb/>Respite 12 Mo
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>$200 } Tipling
<lb/>Jno. W. Woodward
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1860-12-22">Dec 22<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> 1860</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
