<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3022"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William K. McCracking to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5141</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR43-130 to BR43-131</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thomas E Bramlette Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner William K McCracking would respectfully represent that at the <date when="1864-08">August term of the Laurel Circuit Court from 1864</date> His Son W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> G. McCracking was tried found guilty and Sentenced to four years confinement in the State Penitentiary (for the Crime of Grand Larceny he was charged with Stealing one Hundred dollars from John Mardis) He says that in pursuance of said Judgement or Sentence his son the said W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> G. McCracking was taken to the Penitentiary and has been there confined at hard Labor ever since He says that his son was under a good reputation up to the time he was charged with taking the money for the taking of which he was sent to the Penitentiary that he was about nineteen years old at the time he was convicted that he was a weak minded boy far below the average of Boys of his age He says that he thinks that he has suffered Enough already and that he thinks that he will not again be guilty of a Similar crime as he was never before<pb/>
<lb/>charged with having committed an offense or crime against the law your Petitioner is a poor old man having a large family all of whom are of good character save the one which is now confined in the State Penitentiary and he was up to the time he was charged with Stealing as aforesaid.</p>
<p>The premises considered the prayer of your Petitioner is that you Pardon his erring son and restore him to his Parents for which he will ever feel Greatfull</p>
<p>William K McCracking </p>
<p>We have Examined the foregoing Petition and believe the Statements therein contained are true and Earnestly request your Excellency to Pardon Wm G McCracking the Person named therein from further confinement in the Penitentiary</p>
<p>R Boyd
<lb/>C B Faris
<lb/>R L Ewell C L C C
<lb/>M. L. Rice
<lb/>C Pitman
<lb/>J. H. Carrier Jailer
<lb/>J T Brown<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>B. M. Porter
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> H B Wadkins
<lb/>Jesse Bowling
<lb/>Elijah Bowling Sr
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Whorter
<lb/>Noris Black
<lb/>Thomas. C. Patoar
<lb/>Samuel Scoomner
<lb/>Landon G Gains
<lb/>R M Hill
<lb/>James H M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Neill
<lb/>Jeremiah Lawson Jr
<lb/>John Clay S
<lb/>E S M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Neill
<lb/>Levi Rees
<lb/>henry S Slagel
<lb/>James W. Faris
<lb/>Jonathan M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Neill
<lb/>Richard Parley
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John Pitman Clk
<lb/>Laurel Co Court
<lb/>Wm J Moren Judge
<lb/>Laurel county court
<lb/>P. A. Harris. m. d.
<lb/>James B Cloyd
<lb/>William H Porter
<lb/>Riley Wadkins
<lb/>William H Swanner
<lb/>R Swanner
<lb/>H H Cathers
<lb/>John R Lewis
<lb/>James W Cethers
<lb/>L. B. Patton
<lb/>John A Pearl
<lb/>J W Swann
<lb/>E Boling
<lb/>Chap Watkins
<lb/>Georg Watkins
<lb/>James M Parter
<lb/>William T Centers
<lb/>Elisha Bowling
<lb/>Gerge W Patton
<lb/>John W Porter
<lb/>Granvil Black
<lb/>W T. Elza
<lb/>W. B. Estes.
<lb/>C A. Pearl.
<lb/>J B Faris</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
