<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1252"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">F. M. Johnson et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5889</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-425 to BR11-426</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Gov Bramlett Sir your Petitioner F M Johnson would state that he was Indited in the shelby Circuit Court for keeping a tipling house &amp; tryed at the <date when="1864-09">last sept</date> term for said offense &amp; fined the sum of $20 for Retailing with out licens he states that it is wrong that he should pay said fine for the following Reason to wit</p>
<p>he states that at Request of meney of his friends &amp; customers he being a merchant at Consalation Shelby County he bought &amp; Brought on some fine old whiskey for medical purposes that he has never sufered men to tipple about his house Although he has keep whiskey of the above kind for five years &amp; on tryal some five or six of his most Promenent nayhbors was swown &amp; not one had Ever knew of his violating the law made in such cases but a man who lives some 4 miles off stated that he had got a drink of whiskey at one time that he had paid for he states that upon one occasion said Witness was at his Store when your petitioner was bisey &amp; he asked witness to chop him some wood that he but about enough for to make 2 or 3 fires &amp; when he Quit petitioner asked what he charged &amp; witness Replyed to give him a drink of old whiskey &amp; that would pay him &amp; he did so without thinking of violating the law<pb/>
<lb/>but thinking that witness charged him knothing &amp; he would treat him but witness thought outherwise &amp; he was fined for same wherefore he prays that your Excelency will Remit said fine it is not the amount of Judgment or his Inability to pay but he wishes to be put Right upon the Record</p>
<p>F M Johnson</p>
<p>The undersigned say that they are naighbor of F M Johnson &amp; know that he keep an Orderly house &amp; dos not sufer tippling about his house that he keeps a fine Artical of whiskey to sell by the Quantity to take away from his house Also that he offen treats his Customers he is a dry Goods Merchent &amp; has been selling a Large amount of goods we ask that his fine be Remited</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>S. E. Miles
<lb/>C G Kenney
<lb/>A G Roberts
<lb/>T, J, Montgomry
<lb/>J. H. Poore
<lb/>C C Sacrey
<lb/>Lewis Vardiman
<lb/>H. C Vardaman
<lb/>W C Johnson
<lb/>J S Tutler
<lb/>W C Hackett
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J, R Hansbrough
<lb/>J, H, Bohannon</p>
<p>I am the witness upon which F M Johnson was fined for selling whiskey &amp; I have Read the Petition above &amp; the facts are corectly stated</p>
<p>J P tracy<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Shelby Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>F M Johnson
<lb/>vs } On Pet
<lb/>Tipling
<lb/>$20
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Remit</hi>
<lb/><date when="1864-10-11">11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Oct/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
