<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2137"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James H. Mellon et al. to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9213</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-216 to MG24-217</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The Commonwealth 
<lb/>vs } On an indictment in the Madison Circuit Court for the Murder of Woods Caperton
<lb/>Francis Searcy</p>
<p>The undersigned respectfully petition his excellency the Govenor of Ky to pardon the aft in the above named case under the peculiar &amp; oppressive circumstances attending it. The deceased Caperton at the time of the fatal encounter drew a larg Bowie Knife on the dft Searcy &amp; threatened his life &amp; dft persuaded Caperton to put it up which he did. Caperton drew the knife a Second time &amp; was brandishing it at dft being Very near to him whereupon the dft for the first time drew a pistol &amp; shot Caperton firing but once.</p>
<p>The dft was arrested &amp; shortly after tried by an examining Court in the town of Richmond within less than fifty yards ^of^ where ^the^ affray took place &amp; was acquitted by the examining court. The case was at the next term of the Madison Circuit Court brought before &amp; thoroughly examined by the Grand Jury &amp; that Jury refused to find an indictment The case then laid until the next circuit Court when as is generally believed a<pb/>
<lb/>Grand Jury was arranged for the purpose of indicting the dft &amp; an indictment was found which is now pending</p>
<p>Your petitioners do not believe that a Grand Jury fairly empaneled could have been found in the county of Madision which would have found an indictment in the case &amp; they state that the proceedings against the dft are oppressive &amp; unfair The Judge who presided at the time the indictment was found &amp; the foreman of the Grand Jury are both relations of the deceased &amp; Harris ^the foreman.^ divers others of the grand Jury were not selected by the Jury commissioners -- We believe that public Sentiment would sustain your Excellency in pardoning C<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">ol</hi></hi> Searcy the dft who is a poor man Very far from having the means to defend himself properly</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>I certify that I was one of the court who permited Col Seary to bail
<lb/>M B Johnson J P
<lb/>Peter T Shalps J P M C presided in the examing court and acquited ^the^ defendent
<lb/>Green Clay
<lb/>J M Hill S M C at the Time
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> H. Mellon
<lb/>Nathaniel Bonny
<lb/>S R Shaw
<lb/>Edmon dunn
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> G Watts
<lb/>A. P. Wilson
<lb/>D C M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kinney
<lb/>John. keen
<lb/><unclear/> S tuder
<lb/>Stephen Ross<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Zenna Cobb
<lb/>Wm Galdin
<lb/>Wm rolland
<lb/>James S Golden
<lb/>Isaac J. Jett
<lb/>Robert keen
<lb/>Josiah Adams
<lb/>John Jones Jr
<lb/>Calborn Freeman
<lb/>Wm Crus
<lb/>Elder Josiah Collins
<lb/>Charles Searcy
<lb/>John C Bargess
<lb/>Thos M Boone
<lb/>Jno W Carrol
<lb/>Noah C Griggs
<lb/><unclear/> Ward
<lb/>Richard Stevens
<lb/>James.H. Richersens
<lb/>John W Pinketon
<lb/>R M Elkin
<lb/>Allen Douglas
<lb/>J C Williams
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> <unclear>Sparks</unclear>
<lb/>Ephriam Parson
<lb/>James W Owen
<lb/>B J Douthit
<lb/>Jonas S. Griggs
<lb/>E Flenty
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Wm P Dalton
<lb/>Rev. F. T Johns.
<lb/>J. N. Douglas
<lb/>Amareel Tritts
<lb/>James S Potdan
<lb/>G M Webber
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> P Roberts
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> T Moberly
<lb/>H W Right
<lb/>Noah H Tevis
<lb/>William Collins
<lb/>S F Harber
<lb/>John W Green
<lb/>Owen Parish
<lb/>Albert Wagner
<lb/>J J Ford
<lb/>Rice partward one of the first grand Jurors that Refused to find A true bill
<lb/>Austin M Brooksher
<lb/>D. Waller Chenault one of first grand Jury
<lb/>G, C, burn
<lb/>A. T. Chenault
<lb/>Geo Depruatt<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>Searcys case -- Madison</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
