<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2034"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">S. Noland et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6671</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-202 to BR14-203</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jessamine County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-06-19">19 June 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Tho E Bramlette Gov. of Ky.</p>
<p>Your petitioners, citizens of Jessamine County, represent -- </p>
<p>That an Indictment is pending in the Jessamine Circuit Court against two young men formerly citizens of Jessamine County -- viz: John Scott and Joseph Chrisman, charged with Mule Stealing -- The said Scott and Chrisman were raised in this community and had borne good characters up to the itme of the offence aforesaid, and the families to which they belong are as respectable as any in Jessamine County -- We believe considering the circumstances that if the young men were pardoned by your Excellency the strong probability is they would return to their homes and he of good behavior in the future, and considering that they are young, and it being their first offence, we unite in petitioning you to pardon them for the offence aforesaid.</p>
<p><date when="1865-06-19">June 19. 1865</date>.
<lb/>S. Noland clk Jessa. Cir. Ct.
<lb/>K S Ferguson P. J. J. C c
<lb/>James F Barkley
<lb/>T. Woodson
<lb/>N,, Dickerson S. J. C
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Tom K. Seteher
<lb/></hi>Samuel Muir
<lb/>George Brown
<lb/>John A Willis Clerk
<lb/>Jessamine County Court
<lb/>S. S. Mirner
<lb/>J, C, Randolph
<lb/>Late Dep. Marshal Jes. Co. Ky</p>
<p>I take great pleasure in signing the above petition Knowing the young men well, &amp; believing that the offence was more a disipated frolick than any thing else. They have always been honourable &amp; fine young men</p>
<p>Marlan Brown<pb/></p>
<p>Nicholasville Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1865-06-19">June 19 1865</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency Thos E Bramlette Gov of the Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>Sir:</p>
<p>Being Somewhat familiar with the facts in the case of the young men mentioned in the foregoing petition. I deem it nothing more than a matter of duty to make a statement in their behalf. These young men were charged with stealing some Govt. stock and also private stock belonging to Mr. Campbell Wilmore of Jessamine County, and under fear of being prosecuted they left the state and went to Canada. They wrote to me, whilst I was in Command at Camp Nelson, stating that if I were to give them protection they would return and make a full statement of the facts in the case. I wrote to them to return which they did and gave me the promised Statement from which and from other information obtained, I am satisfied they were induced to commit the offence by designing persons and when too very much under the influence of Liquor. They regretted having been in the scrape and seemed exceedingly anxious to do all that was right after their return home. They belong to respectable families and they regret very much the reproach they have brought upon themselves and their friends. I request they be pardoned &amp; allowed to return home</p>
<p>Speed S. Fry
<lb/>Brig. Genl<pb/></p>
<p>Jessamine Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John Scott &amp; Joseph Chrisman
<lb/>Pardon the Offense -- 
<lb/>(<date when="1865-03">March Term 1865</date>)
<lb/><date when="1865-07-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> July 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
