<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0109"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">T. J. Clark to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8561</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-168 to R3-169</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Marion County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-11-18">18 November 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency J. F. Robinson Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky Your Petitioner T. J. Clark would most respectfully state to Your Excellency that at the <date when="1862-05">May term 1862</date> of the Marion Circuit Court a judgement was rendered in favor of the Commonwealth of Ky against your Petitioner for the sum of $200 --  besides costs for the charge of Keeping a gaming house -- Your Petitioner would state that he did ^not^ intend to keep a gaming house nor did he keep a Gaming tho a few of his friends did game for a short time in his house for very small assets tho without his approbation and no knowing the danger or responsibility that rested on him for a <hi rend="underline">small game</hi> at cards. Your Petitioner ^would state that the late Governor^ respited this fine for 12 months and Your Petitioner has paid the costs and did hope to be able to pay the fine before the 12 months expired tho he finds that now it will be impossible to do so as he has a wife and four children to support all young and one that is totally helpless and the business house and dwelling house in Lebanon Ky has been passed and taken from him by the Federal officers and thereby throw him out of business and deprived him of the means to support his family and he cannot pay the fine and putting him in jail would not pay the fine<pb/>
<lb/>and has no friends that are able and willing to advance the payment of the fine therefore Your Petitioner would most respectfully ask a remission of the fine. </p>
<p>T J, Clark</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by T J Clark this <date when="1862-11-18">November 18 1862</date></p>
<p>F B Meriner clerk
<lb/>Marion Circuit Court</p>
<p>The undersigned join in the petition of T. J. Clark and respectfully ask a remission of the fine</p>
<p>The house of T. J. Clark was pressed and taken possession of by the Federal officers while vacated by Mr Clark who was compelled to leave his home on account of his known Loyalty and that the house was not taken for any other cause &amp; sd Clark upon account of his loyalty did &amp; was necessiated to leave and remain from home for over a month during the time the Confederates occupied Lebanon</p>
<p>F, B, Meriner
<lb/>J, W, Tyler
<lb/>N T Berry
<lb/>N. S. Ray
<lb/>Thos. C. Woods
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> M. Fidler Clk<pb/>
<lb/>The undersigned join in the Petition of T J. Clark and respectfully ask a remittance of his fine</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>E R Ames
<lb/><cb n="2"/>L A Spalding
<lb/>E. P. Mahon
<lb/>C. S. Stoy
<lb/>O Ames<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>Clarks Pettn to remit fine</p>
<p>From Marion Ct</p>
<p>Remitted except $50. of fine 12 months respite of ballance</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J F Robinson</hi></p>
<p>Marion Cir Ct
<lb/>$200 } Gaming
<lb/>Hana R, Spaulding
<lb/>T. J. Clark
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-02-09">Feby 9. 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
