<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3275"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Edwards et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5394</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-84 to BR42-85</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Harrodsburg, Mercer County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Gov. Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Bramlette,</p>
<p>Your petitioners represent that W T Davis was by a verdict of a jury fined the sum of Fifteen Dollars for an assault committed in the Town Harrdosburg Mercer County Ky on Basil Davis, The proof in the case represented, that the said Basil Davis and one Madden Duncan at the time of the alleged assault drew pistols on the said W T Davis; used menacing ^language^ &amp; threatening gestures toward the said Davis. The said W T Davis yielded prompt obedience to the command of the peace officer who commanded the peace on the occasion of the alleged assault, the said peace officer being the Town Marshall of Harrodsburg Ky- Your petitioners represent further <hi rend="str">represent</hi> that said Town Marshall although present when the said assault was alleged to have been committed did not arrest the said W T Davis, nor did said Town Marshall cause to ^be^ issued any warrant for the arrest of the said W T Davis, but the same was procured by Basil Davis the prosecution of said warrant<pb/>
<lb/>The ends of justice have been more than satisfied so far as any breach of the laws is concerned by the said W T Davis by his trial and any further prosecution of the matter to the collection of the judgment would be onerous &amp; oppressive -</p>
<p>We therefore pray that the judgment for Fifteen Dollars rendered before his honor <hi rend="str">judgment</hi> Judge Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Edwards P J M C C be remitted that justice may be done in mercy &amp; we will ever pray &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi></p>
<p>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. Edwards P J M C C
<lb/>R. P. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Grath
<lb/>Richard Board C. M. C. C
<lb/>J W. Cardwell
<lb/>M. A. Hoat
<lb/>A James
<lb/>W T Curry
<lb/>W W Edwards<pb/>
<lb/>Mercer County Court
<lb/>VS
<lb/>W. T. Davis</p>
<p>Refused</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
