<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0102"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Harvey Clarke to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8554</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-158 to R3-159</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Marion County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-11-06">6 November 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency the Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky Your Petitioners Harvey Clark would most respectfully state that he was found guilty of manslaughter in the Marion Circuit at the <date when="1860-05">May Term of said Court 1860</date> and he was in Consequence thereof senteced <hi rend="str">f</hi> Confinement in the Jail and Penitentiary of this Commonwealth for the space of ten years -- </p>
<p>He states that he was much intoxicated at the time of said alleged manslaughter and the man killed was also drinking. He was &amp; is poor, had no friends and had not been living <hi rend="str">as</hi> long in the county when the aforesaid occurrence took place -- Says he has always been an industrious man but poor. He has been confined in the Penitentiary now since <date when="1860-06">June 1860</date> -- His family is very poor. He has a wife 4 daughters &amp; three sons one of which is so severly afflicted as to be unable to labour ^but^ verry little -- </p>
<p>Owing to the hardness of the times and the lack of demand for labor his children cannot get employment and are therefore hard run to make a living=</p>
<p>He has suffered greatly in body and mind <hi rend="str">since</hi> since he has been in the penitentiary and he thinks the Keeper will say has served the state faithfully. -- </p>
<p>He is pretty well advanced in life and has all the desire that a husband and father could have to be relieved from the prison and restored to his family=He is greatly wasted in flesh<pb/>
<lb/>and his hair is rapidly growing gray not so much from age as from the sorrows incident to his condition</p>
<p>If the punishment he has endured has been inflicted only to teach him to guard against vice and crime he is satisfied he has endured enough to make him a temperate and discret man the balance of his life and feels sure that if your Excellency will inquire of those who know what his conduct has been since he has been sentenced you will have reason to believe this declaration well grounded=He prays your Excellency most sincerely to pardon his offense and remit the Judgment rendered against him and as in duty bound will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p>Harvey Clarke -- </p>
<p>We the undersigned jurors who sat upon and tried the case of the Commonwealth of Kentucky against Harvey Clarke concur in his petition for reprieve and pardon <date when="1862-11-06">Nov 6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1862</date></p>
<p>John Russel Jureman
<lb/>Robert Belle Juryman
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> R Begley Jury Man
<lb/>Benedick Ford one of the Jury
<lb/>Ben Wheatleay one of the Jurman
<lb/>Loyd Thompson one of the Jury
<lb/>Elias Russell one of the Jury
<lb/>M. J. Cecil one of the Jury
<lb/><note place="footer">11</note><pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned join in the prayer for the pardon of Harvey Clark</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Warren
<lb/>H. W. Purdy
<lb/>C Beiler
<lb/>J. D. Grant
<lb/>J. J. Varen
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Savage
<lb/>Jeb H Bailey
<lb/>William Mattingly
<lb/>Dr. C. H. Porter
<lb/>B Edmonds
<lb/>James N Fogle one of M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Clarks counsel
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John Shuck one of Clarks counsel
<lb/>Thos. C. Woods same
<lb/>N. T. Barry Ck of the court at the time of the trial
<lb/>J. C Maxwell
<lb/>James M Muller
<lb/>A. S. Montgomery
<lb/>Ben Walker
<lb/>Uriah Garton Jr
<lb/>Elias Webb
<lb/>H. Johnton
<lb/>Jno R. Thomas
<lb/>T H Chandler<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Harvey Cla^r^k Pettn for Pardon</p>
<p>Held for further consideration &amp; facts formed upon Jury</p>
<p>Marion Cir Ct
<lb/>Pardon granted <date when="1863-01-17">17 Jany 1863</date>
<lb/>J F Robinson
<lb/>10 yrs. Penty
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-01-17">Jany 17 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
