<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-033-0054"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Henry V. Sundnum, Abstract</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1517</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Apprehension of Fugitives from Justice Papers, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-89</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Jefferson Circuit
<lb/>Commonwealth
<lb/>against } Abstract of Testimony
<lb/>Henry. V. Sundnum</p>
<p>Commonwealth proved that deft &amp; several others were in the house of M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Sower, when a dispute arose between a M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Ould &amp; deft, which was amicably settled. Subsequently deft remarked that he did not insult any one nor did he ^intend to^ insult anyone, one of the witnesses for the comth. however, stated that deft said he had not insulted any one nor did he intend to be insulted, whereupon Gotlip Mosher, said to the deft, that if he had any thing to settle with Mr Ould, that he Mosher would do the settling, Deft then told Mosher he would fight him, &amp; deft started out of the house for that purpose when Mosher steped up to deft &amp; knocked him down deft falling between two barrels, deft rose &amp; clinched Mosher &amp; stabed him with a knife.</p>
<p>Deft is a cooper &amp; stabed Mosher with the knife he used in his business to cut the flagging. Deft proved a good character for industry &amp; peace. Deft is a man of family. Com<hi rend="sup">th</hi> proved that after the first dispute between deft &amp; Mr Ould deft left the house of Sowers &amp; went to his<pb/>
<lb/>own house &amp; returned bringging with him the knife he used at his business &amp; the same with which the cutting was done</p>
<p>The above statement is in substance the Evidence produced at the trial of Sundrum</p>
<p>E S. Craig atto for
<lb/><hi rend="underline">the State pro. Tem</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Comth Evidence
<lb/>vs } Evidence
<lb/>Sundrum</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
