<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-027-0046"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James H. G. Bush to John W. Finnell</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1279</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R2-74 to R2-78</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Maysville, Mason County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-10-03">3 October 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Maysville Ky <date when="1862-10-03">October 3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> 1862</date>.
<lb/>General J W Finnell</p>
<p>Dear Sir I hasten to say, I sent you a letter by Quartermaster Rickets of the 14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky <hi rend="str">Vol</hi> Cavalry.</p>
<p>And as He has returned without having brought any further instruction Concerning the consolidation and organization of the 14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Cavalry, Since that time we have lost some by death -- Captured by the enemy and desertions, So that We now lack about seventy men, of having the number requisite for a Battallion -- Counting Finnells Company as being full, He Having been elected &amp; commissioned heretofore Please send me instructions How to proceed as we have not enough to make a Major's command Cant you send us 70 recruits to fill up the quota. Do send us 2 or 3 Six pound cannon or some Mountain Howitzers. Our Boys in Spite of all are greatly demoralized without some more efficient commander they cannot be controlled they are a perfect Mob stragling out of camp Hoaring &amp; drinking &amp;c &amp;c officers afraid of them as they are elective<pb/>
<lb/>Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> W H Wadsworth has been trying his hand at Cincinatti with Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Wright but it is no go -- He did send <hi rend="underline">Lieut</hi> <hi rend="underline">Col</hi> <hi rend="underline">Wilson</hi> the commander of this posts, two gun-boats (the same that fled from Augusta when Duke attacked that town last Saturday.)</p>
<p>There have <hi rend="str">been</hi> enough able bodied young men passed through here and gone to the state of Ohio, for safety to make Two full Regiments but they could not be prevailed upon to take arms and help us to drive the enemy out of Ky. We have about 60 or 70 good men that we are subsisting for their services. they work well and are quite willing. We appear to be rather a graceless set here and utterly unworthy of help -- or this point is too insignificant to need protection. You have had many rumors concerning the Augusta &amp; Brooksville fights, no doubt; But I must give my version -- On Saturday last a messenger informed me that 60 men had took Flemingsburgh -- our Mounted men about 85 all told were <hi rend="str">on</hi> many of them on Scout duty. L<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Wilson requested me to take what mounted force I could raise &amp; go to<pb/>
<lb/>Flemingsburgh ^Seventeen miles^ and feel of the enemy -- I raised 63 men and marched from camp at <hi rend="sup">1</hi>/<hi rend="sub">2</hi> past two O'clock P. M. for Flemingsburgh in dust from 2 to 4 inches deep, We got to Flemingsburgh at 7 O'clock -- it commenced raining and was very dark I ordered a halt and led a reconnoisance found no enemy in two Miles of the place East or South, I fed and got Supper having first picketed the town closely. at <hi rend="sup">3</hi>/<hi rend="sub">4</hi> past 11 O'clock P M I received by special messenger an order from L<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Co<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Wilson, requiring me to march my command to Germantown a distance of 29 Miles as there was a fight going on at Augusta and Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Marshall &amp; Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Wadsworth were mooveing all the foot troops at Maysville to reinforce at Germantown Lt Co<hi rend="sup">l </hi>Wilson having gone to Ripley for the troop at that place, I was to be at Germantown at 7 O'clock A. M. and I got there -- 3 minutes before the time amid the shouts of our boys -- We got a cup of coffee fed &amp; watered our Jaded Horses &amp; in 20' were on the march we heard that Duke was at Brooksville arresting &amp; paroling Citizens, Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Wilson ordered the Cavalry to double Quick to the Head of the column &amp; look out for<pb/>
<lb/>the enemy -- we plied the spur and were soon in position passing the Ohio 44<hi rend="sup">th</hi> and the 14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Cavalry that were not mounted and some Ohio Volunteers under Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Edwards. When within 2 miles of Brookeville we met a woman bare headed and bare footed crying go fast go fast they are there yet and got the men in the Court-House I sent Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Wadsworth and L<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Col Wilson word that we had a chance &amp; where I was &amp;c The messenger returned with an order from Lt Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Wilson to flank the road &amp; proceed cautiously &amp; He would soon bring up the infantry &amp; artilery. -- </p>
<p>When in less than <hi rend="sup">1</hi>/<hi rend="sub">2</hi> mile of the town but in plain view I Halted and formed the cavalry in a ravine densely covered with timbers ordered a dismount proceeded alone on foot under cover of a hedge of bushes to a point commanding a fine view of Brooksville I supposed our advance had been discovered as the Rebels were forming a line on the Augusta road -- I sent this word to Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Wilson -- who was marching very rapidly and in 3 minutes his advance came up Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Wadsworth was ordered to deploy the infantry and form them into a line of Battle this was done in a trice Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Wilson &amp; Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Wadsworth ^&amp; Col. C. A. Marshall^ went forward to examine the ground -- <pb/></p>
<p>I was ordered to Send forward a squad of Cavalry covered by the fences and Hill to see the exact position of the enemy I throwed forward 30 men to make this reconnoisance, and found the enemy in full retreat. I communicat<hi rend="str">i</hi>ed this fact to Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Wilson and He ordered a charge We darted in; <hi rend="str">i</hi>It would have pleased you to see how willingly 30 fellows pushed forward to attack over 600 well drilled Cavalry We had not gone far when I found Seven of the boys were going at full Speed on a nearer road I ordered a halt intending to keep my hand full of men to-gether charge up to the rear Guard empty our guns and return to the left flank -- but it was too-late They were thundering away -- It only remained for us to change our course and by a flank movement go to their support, The firing commenced When our van Guard got up to the Court House when the balance of the Cavalry was from 300 to 400 yards off the enemy's was a cross fire and Whistled throug our cavalry only killing one Man -- Private Carrington of Capt M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee's company.<pb/>
<lb/>3 of our boys were in front flying after some retreating rebels, at this Juncture Baz Duke with 16 or 18 Men fell upon our boys in their rear but their shots failed, they were hurrying off our boys whom they had captured but one of them <hi rend="str">whiled</hi> wheeled his horse &amp; made his escape, with little Bob Trumbo (a son of Hon<hi rend="sup">l</hi> A. Trumbo of Bath) at my side I proceeded with 2 other's M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Fred Berbower &amp; another I did not know we pressed upon Baz Duke &amp; party so closely we cut off one of their men and took him prisoner We fired upon the rear Guard twice they returned the fire once -- We then found that the main body of cavalry had halted I sent M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Beerbower back to enquire the cause &amp; the other man to inform Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Wilson that they were close at hand. He ordered up the Artilery and commenced shelling the enemy they replied with their little swivel once only -- We captured 4 Horses two guns and one prisoner and paroled for Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Duke about 35 citizens -- We then marched to Augusta and took boat &amp; arrived at Maysville at 9 O'clock P. M We had marched our cavalry<pb/>
<lb/>more than 70 Miles besides skirmishing &amp;c all praise is due to L<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Wilson who exposed himself to the fire of the enemy and was as courageous and as <hi rend="str">coll</hi> cool as our dress parde also Gen Wadsworth He seemed to be delighted at the prospect of a battle all parties have full conficence in him The officers and men all behaved well as far as I could see -- </p>
<p>For several days past the enemy have been threatening an attack on this place and the vigilance of the Post commander Liet Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Wilson for his energy untiring and indefatiguable exertions both by night and day are worthy of all praise He executed his plans in an admirable manner on the <date when="1862-09-30">30 Sept</date> He ordered a complete reconnoisance of all the roads &amp;c at 4 O'clock P M our pickets under M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Campbell were driven in ^two being captured^ I mounted my horse &amp; with 30 men followed the Cavalry of Holladay &amp; Bob Stoner 5 Miles finding they had fallen back upon their reinforcements I returned.^at night^ our whole force Slept on their arms Guarding every entrance to this city -- On the <date when="1862-10-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> October</date> Major Smith with 20 men was ordered to find the enemy &amp; if Practable feel him -- <pb/>
<lb/>about 4 miles from the City on the Flemingsburgh pike the Major came up to the enemy -- He charged and fired upon him the firing was kept up at long range until the major had expended 3 rounds at the enemy. when the ^enemy^ retreated in haste carrying off his wounded one man. ^wound^ in the arm. ^<hi rend="underline">Bully for the Major</hi>.^ The enemy was 230 strong -- there were from 300 to 600 in the vicinity. Show this to Governor Robinson I will do the best I can in your matters do write soon -- </p>
<p>as ever your friend
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Jas H G Bush</hi></p>
<p>P. S. The conduct of Robt Trumbo <hi rend="str">&amp; M</hi> a private in Capt M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee's company -- and Maj Smith is certainly deserving especial praise &amp; I hope you will also commend M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Smart the man who escaped from the rebels at Brooksville after he was taken prisoner to his excellency Gov Robinson and at least send a letter praiseing their conduct in a deserving manner</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J H G Bush</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
