<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-060-0031"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">"Peace" to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG13647</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Active Militia Records - Capital Guards, North Cumberland Btn., and Three Forks Btn.</collection>
      <idno>Box 77, Folder John T Akin of Lincoln Co. &amp; The Rousey's of Boyle Co. - 1865</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lebanon, Marion County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-02-27">27 February 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Lebanon <date when="1865-02-27">Feb 27.65</date>
<lb/>Hon Thomas E. Bramlette.
<lb/>Dear Sir.</p>
<p>Believing as I do that you have deeply at heart the interest peace and welfare of our State, I am prompted to lay before you as <unclear/> as possible a Statement as follows: -- </p>
<p>You are doubtless aware of the difficulty pending between The Akins of Lincoln &amp; the Rowseys of Boyle -- As I understand, the Akin party applied for and obtained a commission to recruit a company for the State Service -- which was probably well enough -- </p>
<p>Shortly afterwards -- the other party (Rowseys) <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>Applied for a commission and was promptly refused, -- which was we think also well enough -- <pb/></p>
<p>Rowseys failing to obtain a commision in their own Name -- Sent forward to you an Uncle from I think Adair County -- One Capt Curry, formerly of the 13. Ky</p>
<p>If I am correctly informed -- both parties are now organizing rapidly and unless your Excelency can do some thing for the people of the immediate country in which they live -- fears are entertained that it will grow into something awful indeed -- </p>
<p>Rest assured there is even now a reign of terror among those people who so well know the material of which the parties are composed -- and especially the Rowseys -- </p>
<p>Wishing that you may be enabled to spare some little time to a careful investigation of this matter -- And act in the case as your good judgment may dictate</p>
<p>I am Sir
<lb/>Your Obedient Servt -- 
<lb/>"<hi rend="underline">Peace</hi>"<pb/></p>
<p>Lebanon Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-02-27">Feby. 27" 1865</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>"Peace" -- <figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>To the Gov.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Asks that a stop be put to the depredating of the Akins of Lincoln &amp; the Rowseys of Boyle Cos.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>an officer will be sent to look after their operations<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Rec<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> A. G. O. Ky <date when="1865-03-01">1 Mar 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
