<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0751"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. H. Savage et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4870</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-146 to BR10-147</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned would respectfully represent that Charles Miller was indicted ^for carrying concealed weapons^ by the Grand Jury of Mason County at its Session of <date when="1863-10">Oct 1863</date>- that the Mason Circuit Court as its present <date when="--04">Apl term</date> fined him $50 &amp; costs this being the lowest sum under the Statutes for that offense. Charles Miller is a boy about 17 or 18 yrs old the son of a very worthy &amp; peaceable &amp; loyal citizen of this County &amp; he ^the father^ will have to pay the fine if it is not remitted -- </p>
<p>At the time the offence was committed like many boys of that age he was a little wild and on a little spree with the ^boys &amp; some of them were^ witnessess against him Since then he has entirely reformed and become a perfectly ^sober^ and upright &amp; manly boy - this offence was committed at the time our county contained some one or two hundred soldiers some of whom <hi rend="str">who</hi> were undisciplined &amp; reckless &amp; dangerous men when no one whatever his opinions or loyalty might be could be regarded as safe. There are other circumstances which would recommend themselves to your Excellency but which would not be proper to mention in a petition. We think this a case worthy of the Execution clemency and would respectfully ask that so much of the fine as does not go to the Commonwealth Atty and the cost be remitted -- (over)<pb/>
<lb/>Signed</p>
<p>W. H. Savage
<lb/>Emery Whitaker
<lb/>F. B. Trussell (Dpty Provost Marshall)
<lb/>Ben W Wood one of the Grand Jury men</p>
<p>I am satisfied from what I have learned since the judgement was rendered that it would be proper to grant the prayer of the petitieonrs</p>
<p><date when="1864-04-07">April 7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Geo M Thomas Cmth atto</p>
<p>This should have been sent before but my absence several times since court and other matters Exciting our community caused me to overlook it. I did not think it necessary to get any more names as ^it is signed by Comlth's Atty.^</p>
<p>W H Savage<pb/></p>
<p>Mason Circuit Court
<lb/>=VS=
<lb/>Charls Miller
<lb/>$50. -- 
<lb/>concealed Weapons
<lb/>Remit
<lb/><date when="1864-07-11">11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> July 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
