<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0668"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Alf Allen to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4787</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-25</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hardinsburg, Breckinridge County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="--04-12">12 April </date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Hardinsburg <date when="--04-12">Apl. 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi></date>
<lb/>Gov Bramlette
<lb/>D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Sir-</p>
<p>Just now I confessed Judgment for $50 in favour of the Comlth against Thomas C South on an Indictment for shooting at (but not killing) a man named Hoskins. The facts are that in the beginning of the rebellion a home guard was organized in upper end of this County of which the Defendant was a sworn member. A contraband trade was carried on from Meade County with the rebels at Bowling green &amp; many recruits went thence from that county. The outlet was directly through the neighborhood in which this home guard was organized and they were ^kept^ pretty constantly on the alert. This home guard procured their guns from A M D M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cook Brig Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Com Central Division at Camp Nevin. The Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> issued an order at the same time directed to the officers &amp; men of the Home guards of Breckinridge &amp; adjoining counties to stop all contraband goods &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi> &amp; to stop all persons having such goods &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. The order winding up in these words. "This authority is absolute and must be carried out even to the taking of life- Also all suspicious persons must be arrested". On the day the shooting took place there was a considerable crowd of home guards &amp; others assembled in the village of Hudsonville to witness the exam inactive of some persons who had been arrested as rebel<pb/>
<lb/>sympathisers &amp; a good deal of excitement had been gotten up by the discharge of some known to be disloyal and the home guards had some talk of rearresting those discharged The County Judge was present &amp; he gave orders to Deft to watch the highway &amp; let no one pass unless known by him to be right. In obedience to these orders Deft took his position on the Big Road in the ouskirts of the Town. Shortly after Hoskins came along and was ordered by Deft to halt <hi rend="str">who</hi> but would not stop &amp; after hailing him as many as three times Def<hi rend="sup">t</hi> fired. This fact altho denied by Hoskins is fully proved by M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Simons a most estimable lady of undoubted truth. We had proof also by one or two of the home guards that they had received even more stringent verbal orders not only from M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cook but Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi>. Rousseau. The Deft. says that he did not know Hoskins at the time he fired on him. Under all the circumstances <hi rend="str">I thought</hi> altho I felt pretty well satisfied that the Deft. would be acquitted I thought it safest to confess judg<hi rend="sup">t</hi> for $50 rather than risk a worse punishment and fully believing that you would remit as much of the judgm<hi rend="sup">t</hi> as the law would permit. This is to urge that remission</p>
<p>Very Resplty &amp;c
<lb/>Alf Allen</p>
<p>I dont send copy of Judg<hi rend="sup">t</hi> as it is not yet entered &amp; we dont wish to wait this petition. Judg<hi rend="sup">t</hi> entered <date when="--04">Apl Term</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
