<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0055"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Jesse Stevens, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9523</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17A-127</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-02-08">8 February 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Caldwell County sct.</p>
<p>Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Jesse Stevens states that he has been acquainted with Thomas B. Wadlington ever since his boyhood, and has always regarded him as a good honest and law abiding citizen, and such he believes to be the general opinion of his neighbors</p>
<p>He states, that on the evening previous to the unfortunate killing of Cartwright, and after said Wadlington had learned, that his son and servant had been driven from their work, he said Wadlington told this affiant about the circumstance of his hands having been driven from their work and in said conversation, Wadlington said he was afraid he would have trouble with Cartwright about it. That he himself wanted to do right about it, but he Cartwright was a dangerous &amp; troublesome young man, and he (Cartwright) had already shot at one man, and he seemed to have apprehensions of his own safety, and seemed very much to regret the circumstance of Cartwrights conduct. In said conversation Wadlington did not seem to manifest any anger or bad feeling, but <hi rend="str">on</hi> ^only^ the feeling of regret.</p>
<p>He further states, that he heard the trial, heard the evidence of Prince and Blalock, and from all he heard and from all that he knows of the whole matter he does firmly believe, that manifest injustice was done to said Wadlington in the verdict of the Jury and he does believe the killing of Cartwright<pb/>
<lb/>was in necessary self defence.</p>
<p>Jesse Stevens</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed before me by Jesse Stevens. This <date when="1861-02-08">8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Feby 1861</date>. <hi rend="str">Jesse Stevens</hi></p>
<p>J. C. Barnes D. C.
<lb/>for E. P Watkins clk</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
