<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1200"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">N. L. Cooke to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10668</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-38 to MG21-39</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Your petitioner would respectfully represent to your excellency that there is now a writ of capias pro fine in the hands of the sheriff of Henderson against him for the sum of $220.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">16</hi></hi> which issued upon a Judgment under the <date when="1857-12">Decr_ Term of the Henderson Circuit court 1857_</date> That said Judgment was upon an indictment against him for permitting gaming upon his premises, That the procecution was set in foot &amp; carried out through the malice of the Eastin Family against your petitioner, that the facts as proved by the only witness W A Eastin, showed your petitioner to have been absent at his home some 3 miles distant &amp; the gaming took place between some of his hired hands at a point where he was waking for coal_ and at a time when he was absent_to well convinced was the commonwelths attorney that malice was at the bottom of it that he dismissed several other inditements upon information given by Eastins. &amp; this verdict was upon technicality of the law, only -- &amp; so contrary to plain justice that the Jury offered to petition<pb/>
<lb/>to your excellency to remit it, &amp; his attorney promised to attend to the matter &amp; endeavor to obtain your executive clemency, &amp; your petition was informed &amp; beleived that it had been done, &amp; that your excellency had remitted the fine, until within the past few days, the Sheriff informed him of the writ before mentioned</p>
<p>Now your petitioner would further state that he is in humble circumstances, with a family to Support_ &amp; that to require him to pay that fine, such times as now exhist, would be impossible, &amp; that to imprisson him, would be, to deprieve his family of their only means of support, Your petitioner did not intend to violate the laws, but through their stringency he has been fined unjustly, He therefore in the name of himself, wife &amp; children appeals to your clemency, to release him of this heavy burden -- </p>
<p>N L Cooke<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned were Jurors who rendered the verdict above &amp; beleive the facts therein stated are true, &amp; think the case is one in which your excellency would do great justice by remitting the fine,</p>
<p>W. R. Lancaster
<lb/>J. B. Rusk
<lb/>Sol. S. Sizemore
<lb/>G W Johnson
<lb/>A. J. Goode
<lb/>T J Hopkins
<lb/>John E Taylor
<lb/>J H Fuluiler
<lb/>W M Ladd</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Henderson Circuit } Sct</p>
<p>I T. J. Hopkins clerk of the Henderson Circuit Court do certify that the foregoing nine signatures are the names of nine of the Jurymen that <hi rend="str">brought</hi> rendered the verdict against him, as the same appears of Record in my office in Order Book "M" Page 449.</p>
<p>Witness my hand this <date when="1861-06-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> June 1861</date></p>
<p>T J Hopkins C. H. C. C
<lb/>By Fred Pentecost D C</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
