<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0991"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">G. S. Kimberly to Thornton F. Marshall</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5110</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-35 to BR11-36</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Foster, Bracken County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-12-01">1 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Foster K.y <date when="1863-12-01">Dec 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>Mr T. F. Marshall</p>
<p>Dear Sir I herewith Send you a Duplicate copy of the petition which you Drew for me after it was signed and Just as sent to the Govenor I send you the Duplicate copy to satisfy you that the statements which I made you are true= in answer to which Petition the Governor sent me a respite of which I also send you a Duplicate copy</p>
<p>Now my reasons for addressing you is this. I do not think he exactly understands the matter or he would have remitted my fine instead of respiting it for 12 months.</p>
<p>I wish you if you please and will be induced to take any further action in the case, to write the Govenor<pb/>
<lb/>with regard to the matter and use your high influence in my behalf to get the Govenor to yet remit said fine for I feel that if you would but aid me by communicating with the govenor that end might yet be accomplished and as I have before stated to you I am as Inocent of the crime as your Honor I have sent you the Duplicate of my Petition to satisfy any doubt you may have upon that matter which is signed entirely by my Neighbors many of whom you are no Doubt acquainted you may think me extremely anxious upon this matter But one in your situation could hardly imagine the feelings of as poor a man as me robed as this will rob me of all that he Posseses with want Stareing his family in the face when he has labored hard and honestly to obtain the little of<pb/>
<lb/>which he has been thus cruely robed. but hopeing that you will be induce to aid me and that the Governor may yet remit it and further hopeing that I may yet be able to liberaly reward you for your trouble in my behalf I remain yours Truely</p>
<p>G. S. Kimberly<pb/></p>
<p>Duplicate Copy
<lb/>Thomas E Bramlette
<lb/>Govenor of the commonwealth of K.y.</p>
<p>To all who shall see these presents Greeting. Whereas a Judgement has been rendered By the Bracken Circuit Court (<date when="--08">August Term</date>) for $200 against George S Kimberly And Whereas it appears from satisfactory Evidence that the case of the said Kimberly presents strong considerations for the interposition and indulgence of the Executive Now know ye that in consideration of the premises, and by virtue of the power vested in me by the constitution I have thought proper to respite and do by these presents stay and respite the collection of said Judgment of the Bracken Circuit Court for the term of twelve months from the Date here of and do hereby enjoin all officers to respect this respite and govern themselves accordingly In testimony whereof I have hereunto set my hand and caused the seal of the Commonwealth to be affixed at Frankfort on the <date when="1863-10-24">24 day of Oct 1863</date> in the 72<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> year of the Common</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
