<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3197"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. William Hatchett, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5316</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-371</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Washington County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against } Washington Circuit Court
<lb/>William Hatchett</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Washington county in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky accuse William Hatchett of the crime of Robbery committed as follows: The Said William Hatchett on the <date when="1865-12-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of December 1865</date> in the County aforesaid <hi rend="str">Washington</hi> did feloniously steal take and cary away one Pistol of the Value of Ten Dollars, One mans Saddle of the Value of Twelve Dollars the personal property goods and chattels of James I. Reed from his person &amp; presence by force and against his will by putting him in fear of Some immediate injury to his person against the peace and dignity of the commonwealth of Ky Witnesses before the Jury</p>
<p>James I. Reed, George Lambert George Baker Morrison Harber Andrew Pinkston John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Millen and H. D. Reed</p>
<p>L. H. Noble Atty for
<lb/>Commonwealth
<lb/>a Copy att
<lb/>W. H. Phillips D. C.<pb/>
<lb/>Comwlth
<lb/>vs } Robbery
<lb/>Wm. Hatchett<figure type="hr"/>a true bill
<lb/>D. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Ilvoy foreman of the Grand Jury
<lb/>a Copy
<lb/>Att.
<lb/>W. H Phillips<figure type="hr"/></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
