<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0454"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Robert Simmons to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9922</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-209 to MG18-210</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-01-10">10 January 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Covington <date when="1861-01-10">Jan 10 1860</date>
<lb/>Gov B. Magoffin
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>You ^will^ receive with the mail that brings this, a petitin from F Hock asking to be released from confinement in the Kenton Jail, &amp; from a fine of fifty dollars which were pronounced against him by a Jury at the present Term of the Kenton circuit. Along with the petition you will also find a recommendation signed by the Jury who tried the case &amp; also numerous letters from the most intiligent citizens of this county asking you to interpose<pb/>
<lb/>&amp; by virtue of the power vested in you, release him from Jail &amp; remit the fine This is asked because all who know the man &amp; the facts of the case, are satisied he had no entention to inflict <unclear/> Injurey upon the man Miller</p>
<p>Thes are times which very <unclear>seriously</unclear> effects all classes &amp; particularly the poore &amp; laboring classes <hi rend="str">of one</hi> Hock is one of this latter class. He is unable to pay the fine, If he ays the fee of the Commonwealths Attorney &amp; clerks fees -- he will have paid more than he is really able to pay. &amp; to be required to pay that amount will be <unclear/><pb/>
<lb/>fully adequate to th offence commited -- </p>
<p>Be assured if you interpose in behalf of this man &amp; remit the fine &amp; the imprisonment you will have confered a great favor on honest &amp; industrous man &amp; one whose life heretofore has been without spot or blame. It would I believe be approved of by th great body of those in this community who know the man &amp; the facts of the case in which he was found guilty. you will see the Jury imposed the smallest fine &amp; the shortest period of imprisonment. allowed by law. If the prayer of the<pb/>
<lb/>petitioner is granted please send immediately the papers showing the remission</p>
<p>your &amp;c
<lb/>Robert Simmons</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
