<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1057"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">L. A. Wood to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5694</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR[11]-130 to BR[11]-131</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-07-14">14 July 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-07-14">July 14 1864</date>
<lb/>Gov. Thomas E Bramlette</p>
<p>Dear Sir: This will be handed you by Mrs Eaton, wife of Josiah Eaton, who is a convict in the Penitentiary. She brings you a petition from nearly if not quite all the county officers of Floyd County, Indiana, and of the city officers of the city of New Albany. These are the old neighbors and acquaintances of Josiah. All the names I think are officers, except Mr Stottenberg who is a law of distinction. This list of petition might have extended to several hundred; but these officers thought it was unnecessary to cumber the petition with such a vast number of names, as they are the county and city officials, and the representative men of the county and city. They advised her to this course.</p>
<p>I could have procured a number of Signers here, in this city; but I thought in as much as, he was not to return here if he got, but was to return New Albany from whence he came, that it would not avail any thing with you. I think in as much as the community in which he lived, and to which purposes to return<pb/>
<lb/>through their representative men have petitioned for his release and return to them, that this is a Sufficient call to Justify you in exercising the pardoning power in his behalf.</p>
<p>There are other reasons which are Set forth in the petition; by the petitioners themselves; to which I refer you.</p>
<p>But the principal reason, which I urge most earnestly, is the helpless condition of his family. I have known Mrs Eaton well ever since <date when="1863-01">January 1863,</date> about 18 months ago. It was about this time that her husband was arrested and lodged in Jail on the charge upon which he was convicted. I was her husbands counsel He lay in Jail from then until the <date when="--10">October</date> term afterwards before he had a trial. He got his finger Shot off at the time he was arrested; and he was Sick nearly the whole time he lay in Jail. He has already Suffered a great deal, and has experienced the truth of that Scripture Saying, "that the way of the transgressor is hard". The law has been vindicated, and the demands of Justice Satisfied; and he Seemed at the time of his conviction thoroughly penitent; and determined if he could get restored to his family that he would live an honest life.</p>
<p>Mrs Eaton has 5 Small children, and by washing out by days work, and struggling &amp; econemizing she has supported herself and chil<pb/>
<lb/>dren for about 18. months. She is a good Kind-hearted clever woman, devoted to her husband. She has Struggled like a heroine to maintain herself &amp; children; and She has been able to do it. <hi rend="str">for</hi> until now. But she has bought no clothes for herself or children, except Some Shoes. And now that the clothing she had for herself and children are pretty well worn out, it will be impossible for her to feed and clothe them both.</p>
<p>Under all these circumstances I cannot ^help^ thinking that to restore to this helpless and distressed family their only Stay <hi rend="str">of</hi> and Support, would be an act of charity and humanity, highly commendable. Nor can I see how the public good would suffer by it;</p>
<p>I do hope Governor, you <hi rend="str">will</hi> can find it, consistent with your views of propriety to restore him to his helpless and dependant family.</p>
<p>your friend &amp; obt Servant
<lb/>L. A. Wood.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
