<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2425"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Charles Mitchell to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7062</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-369 to BR15-370</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-22">22 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Covington Ky <date when="1865-09-22">Sept 22<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>Governor Bramlette</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Charles Mitchell would respectfully represent to your Honour that he was This day Convicted in the Kenton Circuit Court in Covington Ky for Taking Some $9 <hi rend="sup">17</hi>/<hi rend="sub">100</hi> cents in Postage Currency on last saturday Evening in the Makit in Covington ^and sentanced to the Penatentiary for five years^ he says he has no doubts but what he did take money for it was proven positively upon him in said Court on the trial and the only Excuse he has to offer which was also proven on the trial that he was drunk the taking was done in the presence of the Owners of the Money She &amp; he had it as she swore in a quarter Peck measure on her stand and there was Many persons present, and She and her Husband were both attending to the Stand in market he says he would not have done so if he had been sober never done any thing of the kind before he says that he has served 3 years in the army of the United States and had just been discharged that all the Money he had was stolen or taken from him the same Evening and he has not heard any thing of it since</p>
<p>He therefore prays your Honor to use your Executive Clemency and Grant him a pardon and your Petitioner will Ever pray &amp;C</p>
<p>Charles Mitchell</p>
<p>We whose names hereto subscribed join in the foregoing Petition and pray<pb/>
<lb/>Your Honour to pardon the said Charles Mitchell and we will Ever pray &amp;C,</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Petitioners Names
<lb/>J. C. Howard
<lb/>W, T Hill
<lb/>H. S. Wally Foreman Jury
<lb/>J H Easton
<lb/><hi rend="underline">James G Arnold</hi>
<lb/>Thos.. L.. Laris
<lb/>H, S, Wilson Juro</p>
<p>I am satisfied that this case presents as good reasen for the exercise of Executive Clemency as any case if drunken faithfully can <hi rend="underline">C H Hoover</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J. Battersby</hi>
<lb/><unclear>B,, Peytin</unclear> Main
<lb/>Robert M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Vay
<lb/>M, Ashford
<lb/>J H Bloomer
<lb/>H Hardelebeck
<lb/>Joseph Havekemp
<lb/>J, H, Berkius
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Petitioners names
<lb/>James and nelly Donavan
<lb/>prosecutieing
<lb/>Wittnesses</p>
<p>We have become Satisfied Since <hi rend="str">Wittness</hi> the triall that the Said Charles Mitchell is not the Man that <hi rend="str">G</hi> Got our money<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>I am acquainted with most of the persons whose names are to this petiton and they respectable Citizens of Covington Ten of the Jury that convicted him &amp; the prossecuter the woman who made charge now say, by her certificate here that she was mistaken that he was not the man of which she is now satisfied you will please answer without delay as the Court has committed to keep him here till next monday. 15th Int</p>
<p><date when="1865-10-10">Octr 10<hi rend="sup">th</hi>' 65</date></p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>James G Arnold</p>
<p>His Excellency
<lb/>Governor Bramlette
<lb/>Frankfort
<lb/>Ky</p>
<p>Kenton Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi> B. Mitchell
<lb/>Pardoned <date when="1865-10-13">13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Oct /65</date></p>
<p>Charles B Mitchell
<lb/>Petition</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
