<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0277"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. C. Moore to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9745</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-260 to MG17-261</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-12-30">30 December 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville <date when="1860-12-30">Decb<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 30. 60</date>
<lb/>D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Sir</p>
<p>I hope you will pardon me for troubling you in this instance, but forbearance ceases to be a virtue beyond a certain point and I think I have been fleeced by the Knownothing party and its police officers, untill I am not willing to be fleeced any longer. I have been an uncompromising democrat for thirty years and twenty five of that time I have been an active working democrat of this City and for which I have been proscribed in my business, and Since Know nothingism I have been hunted on all occasions and more especially by the police of the City for every little ordinance while the Same ordinance was violated by at most every Business man in the City with impunity=about one year since I overlooked my store license a Summons was served on me by the marshall. I told him to enter the smallest fine $5 -- <pb/>
<lb/>and make up the Costs and I would pay it as I did wish to be troubled with it. this he promised should be done but instead of doing so=I was tried By a Jury always ready on Such occasions and fined $50 and costs $25 without being heard in person or By attorney=to this I remonstrated with the Judge and he set it aside the next Case was the day after the great Bill demonstration=I was viewing the procession and casually remarked that it was a Beautifull affair headed By one of the City police on one of the City horses as marshall of the night and lo I was must be <unclear/> for it So by 9 oclock the next morning I was summoned for violating an ordinance which my entire neighborhood and the whole City violated with impunity=and now I am once more fined for overlooking the time that my car license expired and the City owing me money at the Same time=the fine $5.00 &amp; Costs $4.<hi rend="sup">90</hi>/<hi rend="sub">100</hi> and feeling that I have been<pb/>
<lb/>taxed and outraged enough. I have sought your Clemency to remit this last fine of $5.00 which was imposed on me on the <date when="1860-12-20">20th day of this month</date> and for which I shall be most gratefull not so much for the amt as to teach the police officers that there is a higher power that will not permit such wrongs to her Citizens=with my warmest regards I remain Yours Truly</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">W, C, Moore</hi></p>
<p>To his Excellency Gov Magoffin
<lb/>Frankfort Ky</p>
<p>not having the honor of your acquaintance I have enclosed a letter from one of personal friends -- <pb/></p>
<p>Louisville City ct
<lb/>$50 } Misdemeanor
<lb/>W. C. Moore
<lb/>Remission Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi>
<lb/><date when="1860-01-03">Jany 3. 1860</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
