<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-023-0129"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James M. Rice to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG3042</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG1-366 to MG1-367</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Cincinnati, Hamilton County, Ohio</placeName>
    <date when="1862-04-04">4 April 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>MADISON HOUSE,
<lb/>Main Street, Between Front &amp; Second,
<lb/>CINCINNATI, O.,
<lb/>J. W. GARRISON, PROPRIETOR.
<lb/><date when="1862-04-04">Ap<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> 4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1862</date>,
<lb/>Gover, Magoffin</p>
<p>When, I left home on Tuesday last, my intention was to visit you, and other of my friends in Frankfort, but I have from pressure of matters and being worn down with travel, to forego the pleasure it would afford me, to see you, and content myself, as best I can, on this day I returned here from, <hi rend="underline">Columbus</hi>, spending almost 2 days &amp; nights there and at, camp; most of my time at latter, place, doing what I could, to <hi rend="underline">assist</hi> and relieve Suffering humanity, and complying<pb/>
<lb/>with the christian duty, of visiting the sick, and those that are imprisoned &amp;c; and administering to them, (I have Sympathy large, for those that are, imprisoned.) by experience men can be taught, as I have learned -- Governor, all men, are not made to See and feel alike; yet I have a hope that you will, feel, inclined favorably, in regard to the petitions, I Send you, it would under the circumstances truly oppressive to enfor the forfeitures, against Sureties, where all travel has been cut off, or at least, very Dangerous to get where the parties<pb/>
<lb/>formerly resided; there is no need of enumerating, reasons, march up and <hi rend="underline">intervene</hi>, do not, force us to wait, until after Judgement; and then apply for releif, and compel the sureties to pay 30. perct, to have done in good conscience what should have ^been^ granted at first -- you will see in pencil, are the petitions <hi rend="underline">Manard</hi> &amp;c also Davidson &amp;c, <hi rend="str">derecting</hi> admitti<hi rend="str">d</hi>ng, the Constitu^tion^al power of the governor to remit a forfeiture, as asked for in the above cases; then came up to the work; I have been more, troubled, in the last, 6 months, than all my life beside, withal<pb/>
<lb/>I have lost, property, the distress, still hangs over our region of the State I would delight to meet you and have an old timed Kentucky, talk, and hope, it not be a great while before I can &amp; will have that pleasure again -- I shall remain here until I hear from, you in regard to the petitions sent; do act; <hi rend="underline">prompt</hi>, So that, I may, return home, my respects, to, Gaither </p>
<p>I am dear Sir as ever your most obedient Servn<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi>,
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> M, Rice,</p>
<p>&amp;#9758; answer at this place care Keepers, <hi rend="underline">Madison House</hi>.</p>
<p>p s, look to your journal where you respited a Judgement against Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> C. Frazier, and also one against Granville Frazier, they ought to be remitted, I know &amp; hope you will so act, very &amp;c</p>
<p>J, M, Rice</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
