<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2991"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Barber, Jr. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7628</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR43-87 to BR43-88</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bath County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>J,, B,, <unclear>Sarnell</unclear> C B C</p>
<p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E Bramlett</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Thomas Barber Jr says that he is indicted in the Bath Circuit Court for the alledged offence of "Stabbing with intent to kill"</p>
<p>A Copy of said Indict<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">mt</hi></hi> is in the following language (viz)</p>
<p>"Bath Circuit Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against } Indictment
<lb/>Thomas Barber Jr</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Bath County in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky accuse Thomas Barber Jr of the offense of Stabbing with intent to kill Committed as follows to wit The said Thomas Barber Jr on the <date when="1865-07-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of July 1865</date> in the County and circuit aforesaid did willfully &amp; feloniously &amp; without previous malice &amp; in sudden heat &amp; passion Stab and wound Charles Daniel in the back with a knife which he then &amp; there held in his hand with the intention of wounding &amp; killing him but of which wounding he did not die<pb/>
<lb/>Against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>J S Dury Comms Aty</p>
<p>Your petitioner States that it is true he and the said Charles Daniel did have a little difficulty in which Said Daniel got a little cut and there the matter ended It was done upon a misunderstanding &amp; as petitioner thought to prevent injury to himself but which he found out upon explanation to be unfounded and after an explination took place between the parties the matter was amicably adjusted &amp; settled by them and they are now the best of Friends and have been ever since the difficulty which ^difficulty^ no person regrets more than your petitioner It is the wish <hi rend="str">that</hi>of the said Charles Daniel that your Excellency should interpose and pardon your petitioner from the Consequences of the offence as your Excellency<pb/>
<lb/>will see by the statement which He makes which I suffix to this petition This is the 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> offense of the kind alledged against your petitioner and he hopes it will never become necessary for him to resort to measures of the like sort again --  -- </p>
<p>Thomas Barber Jr</p>
<p>I Charles Daniel of Bath County in the state of Kentucky hereby state that it is my desire that your Excellency pardon <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>Thomas Barber Jr of the offence as alleged in the forgoing Indictment we had a little difficulty in which I got slight cut in the Back and it may be that I was in fault as well as he Indeed we were both in fault we are now friends and hope your Excellency will pardon him Mr Barber is a good Citizen peacable man and had we both been properly at ourselves the<pb/>
<lb/>difficulty would never have occured Mr Barber is honestly striving to make an honest living for his wife and a family of Small and dependent children and any fine imposed upon him now would hinder in the Education and maintenance of the children I therefore on his account and on the account of his interesting little Family ask you to parden him</p>
<p>Charles ^his X mark^ Daniel</p>
<p>Attest
<lb/>H H <unclear>Lewis</unclear></p>
<p>We the undersigned Citizens of Bath County Ky Concur in the statements requesting the Governor of Kentucky to pardon Thomas Barber Jr of the offence charged in the forgoing indictment -- requesting the Governor to send said pardon to said Barber at Owingsville Ky to the Care of Nesbitt and Gudgell Attys at Law -- *</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>R Gudgell
<lb/>R. Coulthard
<lb/>Fred K <unclear/>
<lb/><cb n="2"/>H H Lewis
<lb/>James Johnson
<lb/>C A Williams
<lb/>Seth Wright J. P. B. C</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/><note place="left margin">Bath Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Thos Barber</note></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
