<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2727"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George W. Johnston to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7364</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-384</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-11-03">3 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville Ky <date when="1865-11-03">Novr 3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi>
<lb/>Dear sir</p>
<p>I take the Liberty to call your attention to the case of Joseph Shearer now confined in the Jail of this city. at the <date when="1865-05">May Term 1865</date> of the Jefferson circuit court he was tried upon an Indictment, charging an assault with Intent to Kill &amp; a verdict returned, Guilty of a Misdemeanor &amp; Sentenced to six Months Imprisonment in the county Jail and to pay a fine of $200= He has served out the Imprisonment of six months and is still in Jail to pay the fine of $200 under the Judgment at the rate of Two dollars per day which will continue his Imprisonment yet for 100 days at a cost to the commonwealth of 75.¢ per day or $75. for the whole time, Shearer is a poor young man has no means &amp; no Friends, who served three years in the 4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Kenty cavalry &amp; has always denied having made the assault, another party has since his conviction been Indicted &amp; the case now stands for Trial, as a matter of Economy it would be proper to remit the fine, and as Mercy to a faithful young Soldier it would be<pb/>
<lb/>altogether proper &amp; I respectfully ask that it may be done. I have talked with M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Thomas the Jailor &amp; others who fully concur with me, my Sympathies for the young man &amp; a desire to save the Expense of his Jail fees for the 100 days are the sole reason Influencing me to address your Excellency in relation to the matter. If your Excellency agrees with me as to his Pardon, you can cause it to be forwarded to me, &amp; I will see that he is released.</p>
<p>Most respectfully
<lb/>your obt Serv<hi rend="sup">t</hi> &amp; Friend
<lb/>Geo. W. Johnston</p>
<p>Joseph Shearer states that the foregoing letter has been read to him &amp; that the statements therein are True &amp; he Humbly asks his Excellency Gov Bramlette to grant him a remission of the fine of $200. assessed against him in the letter set forth</p>
<p>Joseph Sherer</p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Jos Shearer
<lb/>$200.
<lb/>&amp; 6 mos Imprisonment</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
