<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2507"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Unknown et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7144</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-11 to BR16-12</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Thomas. E. Bramlette -- 
<lb/>Govenor of Kentucky</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Washington County desire to call your attention to the case of Nathan Lawson. who has had judgement rendered against him in the Sum of five hundred dollars ($500.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi>) on a bail bond in the case of the Commonwealth vs -- John S. Davis in the Lincoln circuit Court and desire you to interpose executive clemency in his behalf, for the following reasons John. S. Davis had been indicted for Stealing a horse in Lincoln county, Nathan Lawson became his Security in a bail bond -- The accused Davis returned home quickly in Washington county and as we believe would have remained there and have rendered himself amenable to the judgement of the said court but from the fact that a body of armed citizens of Washington county went to his house, calling them selves home guards and ordered him to leave the country within three days or, that, they would hang him, within the three days they did again go to his house with a rope to execute their <hi rend="str">theat</hi> threat, for fear of these men J Davis has left the country, and as we believe not through fear of the law -- in this way his bond has been forfeited, and judgement has been rendered against <hi rend="str">him</hi> <hi rend="str">and</hi> <hi rend="str">his</hi> his Security Nathan Lawson in the above named Sum -- We humbly petition your Excellency to remit the penalty -- for which he would as we believe never ^have^ been liable but for the lawless acts of these men<pb/>
<lb/>over whom he had no control -- </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>William <unclear/>
<lb/>Henry Brown
<lb/>W, H, Kimberlin
<lb/>James. T. Call
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> C Milton
<lb/>Jeremiah Lowe
<lb/>H P <unclear/>
<lb/>T W Anderson
<lb/>M M Pope
<lb/>F. S. Anderson
<lb/>Davis Bettoe
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi>. F. Jones
<lb/>Michael Yankee
<lb/>Uriah Shoemaker
<lb/>Robert S Mitchell
<lb/>John Lambert
<lb/>D M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Ilvoy
<lb/>C, F, Bosley
<lb/>C. R. Craycroft
<lb/>Jas P Barbour
<lb/>Alexander Smith
<lb/>M. L. Chatham
<lb/>B. C. Palmer
<lb/><unclear>D M Thompson</unclear>
<lb/>E L Davison
<lb/>D. R Hays
<lb/><hi rend="underline">L R Thurman</hi>
<lb/>R. G. M Schell
<lb/>P G Lanham
<lb/>M A Brady
<lb/><cb n="2"/><hi rend="str">I</hi>
<lb/>James D Hanlin of Mercer County
<lb/>M D Hall
<lb/>J. W. Cardwell
<lb/>E. J. Polk
<lb/>C. S. Abell
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Edwards P J M C C
<lb/>W. A Mooe
<lb/>Nat Gaither
<lb/>S. M Bryan</p>
<p>I Know nearly all of the forgoing persons personally &amp; I have heard <hi rend="str">of</hi> a statement of the facts from Capt F. S Hill, late of the 10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Infy &amp; have no doubt that -- the prayer of the petition should be granted</p>
<p>John M Harlan<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Lincoln Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Nathan Lawson
<lb/>$500,
<lb/>Bail Bond
<lb/>Remit -- <date when="1865-10-31">31<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Oct 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
