<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1270"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Taylor et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5907</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-453 to BR11-454</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-10-09">9 October 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thomas E Bamlette</p>
<p>Governor of the commonwealth of Kentucky your Petitioner William Taylor would respectfully represent that on the <date when="1861-09-02">2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> day of September 1861</date> an Isam Faddis of Whitley county was in the county Jail of said county charged with Larceny &amp; was held to Bail in the sum of five Hundred dollars &amp; your Petitioner Entered into a Bail Bond as the Security of Said Faddis at his earnest Solicitation &amp; by him the Said Faddis volunteering into the Service of the united States for the period of three years &amp; Solemnly pledging his honor as a man that he would Serve his country faithfully for said period which he did for a considerable period but has since deserted &amp; the Bond aforesaid for five hundred has since been forfeited at the <date when="1864-08">last August</date> Term of the Whitley circuit Court Judgment went against him for five hundred dollars the amount of said forfeiture your Petitioner would further represent that before Judgment he tried in every possible manner to bring said Faddis before the court to answer said charge but <pb/>
<lb/>was unable to do so your petitioner was actuated by the purest motives in Bailing said Faddis out ^of Jail^ That it was done for pure love of Country He thought &amp; was advised by his neighbors that Faddis would make a number one Soldier &amp; He himself was unable on account of age &amp; infirmity to go in &amp; fight for his Country &amp; thought it his highest duty to procure others to do so &amp; being<hi rend="str">s</hi> moved by such motives &amp; such only he undertook as the bail of said Faddis and was told by his friends that he was in no danger that his bond would not be forfeited if Faddis went into the Service which he did &amp; made a good Soldier for a long time your Petitioner would further represent that he is a very poor man and cannot pay said bond without Striping his family &amp; himself of all that he has &amp; their hard Earnings for years to come come that he has a Large &amp; dependant family</p>
<p>The premises considered the prayer of your Petitioner is that<pb/>
<lb/>you Exercising your Executive Clemency will remit said fine or Judgment &amp; thereby relieve himself &amp; family from distress &amp; Suffering for which he will ever feel grateful</p>
<p>William Taylor</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Wiliam Taylor <date when="1864-10-09">Oct. 9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date></p>
<p>John, G, Sharp J. P</p>
<p>Gov Bramlette the Petitioner is a poor man it will take all or nearly so that he has to pay the fine &amp; think the fine ought to be remitted</p>
<p>H F Finley</p>
<p>We believe the Statements in the foregoing Petition are true &amp; join in the prayer thereof</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W. T. King
<lb/>J, C. Watkins clk
<lb/>W.C. Gilliss
<lb/>H, L, Fye
<lb/>E H Adkins
<lb/>W C Murphy
<lb/>J..L M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Carty
<lb/>John Smith
<lb/>C. L. Creekmore
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Robt Boyd
<lb/>Jas M Chishom
<lb/>M E White
<lb/>T. M Chisom
<lb/>P. C. Berry
<lb/>E D Wilders
<lb/>A J Curd
<lb/>P Mead Jr
<lb/>J. S. Curd
<lb/>T. D. Sutton
<lb/>S P Brawner<pb/></p>
<p>I have no objection to this fine being remited if the Gov sees proper to do so</p>
<p>G. Pearl</p>
<p><unclear/>
<lb/>Vs } <unclear/>for Remission of forfeiture $500 as Bail for Isam Faddis
<lb/>William Taylor<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Crime Larciny<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Remit
<lb/><date when="1864-11-08">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
