<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0918"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Woodson Woods to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10386</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-458 to MG19-459</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Morgan County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Morgan Circuit Court</p>
<p>The commonwealth of Kentucky against Woodrow Woods The Grandjurors of morgan County in the name &amp; by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky accuse Woodrow Woods of the offense of <hi rend="underline">Adultery</hi> Committed as follows towit the said woodrow woods on the <date when="1858-12-01">1<hi rend="sup">s</hi> day of Decr 1858</date> in the county &amp; circuit aforesaid being free white married man did copulate with Jane <unclear/> a free white married woman but thay not being maried to Each other agnst the peace &amp; dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky Signed a true Bill &amp; filed <date when="1859-05-19">19" May 1859 -- </date></p>
<p>To the Govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky Your Petitioner Woodrow Woods would most respsectfully represent unto your Excellency that at the <date when="1859-05">May</date> Term of the morgan Circuit court he was indicted for Audltery a copy of which Indictment is above &amp; at the <date when="1859-11">November Term of said court in 1859.</date> There was a fine of $10= assessed against him for said charge he states that since that time towit on the <date when="1860-04-20">20' day of April 1860</date> he &amp; the said Jane <unclear/> have introduced a copy of the License &amp; certificate of marriage is here filed &amp; presented to Your Excellency your petitioner Says that he is a poor man &amp; had reason for mercy in these days of distress that he is now married and the object of the Law caused out &amp; that the costs he thinks under the circumstances a sufficnt punishment<pb/>
<lb/>which he will pay as the whole is now replived he in all Kindness &amp; Confidence asks your Excellency to Remit said fine your petitioner has a former family of small &amp; motherless children to support &amp; has but a small &amp; poor mountain farm to support them on &amp; that not all paid for as yet with all this in view &amp; the dificulty to get the money Your petitioner would <unclear/> most respectfully ask your Excellency to Remit said fine your petioner dose not deem it necessary to procure a Long list of petitioners as he thinks it would not amount to any thing with the <unclear/> now before you as to the cause of the fine &amp; the marrage certificate Suffer me again to ask Your Excellency to remit said fine &amp; <unclear/> the frailty of mortal man</p>
<p>yours most Respectfully
<lb/>Woodrow Woods.</p>
<p>Mr. Woods is an industrious man poor with a Large family &amp; his condition is truly state in his petitn &amp; hope your Excellency will remit the fine</p>
<p>John W Haydress<pb/></p>
<p>Morgan Cir. Ct
<lb/>$10 } Adultery
<lb/>W. Woods
<lb/>Remission Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi>
<lb/><date when="1861-04-17">Apr. 17. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
