<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0744"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. Standeffer to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4863</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-135</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-04-24">24 April 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Frankfort Ky <date when="1864-04-24">April 24<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E. Bramlett
<lb/>Gov State of Kentucky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>Thinking that you have forgotten me I take this method of recalling to your mind who I am. I take the oath of allegiance at Jonseboro Ill <date when="1861-06-13">June 13<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861</date> and Joined the 18<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Illinois Reg'<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Vols Commandid by Col M. K. Loller for three years if not sooner discharged. Was a recruiting officer with the promise of a commission at the time of my arrest I left the 18<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Regt in <date when="1862-08">August 1862</date> and went to the 8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Tenn with the promise that if I would help to recruit the Reg'<hi rend="sup">t</hi> that I should receive a commission as 2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> Lieut -- Was in a skirmish near Burkesville Ky and lost my horse and I had to report to my Reg'<hi rend="sup">t</hi> once every month and my time had almost run out when I should report and to reach my Reg'<hi rend="sup">t</hi> was compelled to take this horse, but not with the intention of appropriating it to my benefit but to the benefit of the service for a few days with the full intention of returning it to the owner which you know as you was my counsel at the examining trial.</p>
<p>I left my house in the South, came North and take up arms in the service of the "Glorious old Union" which I felt was my duty. And am I to suffer for a thing that my government uphold<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> If you will release me I will return to the service and fight for my country until this rebellion is quelled. My family all live in the Southern<pb/>
<lb/>states so I have no chance of writing to them but am here friendless and penniless</p>
<p><hi rend="str">Hoping you will give me a hearing on this</hi></p>
<p>I was tried at Columbia <date when="1863-02-16">Feb 16<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1863</date> for pressing a horse beloing to W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Ray's and riding it to any Reg'<hi rend="sup">t</hi></p>
<p>Hoping you will give me a hearing on this</p>
<p>I Remain
<lb/>Your Ob't Servant
<lb/>J. Standeffer<pb/></p>
<p>Adair Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Petition of
<lb/>J Standeffer
<lb/>4 years
<lb/>Horse Stealing
<lb/>Pardoned
<lb/><date when="1865-01-23">23 Jany/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
