<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-005-0027"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John W. Debaum, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG0916</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Apprehension of Fugitives from Justice Papers, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR7-51 to BR7-52</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mercer County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-04-28">28 April 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/><hi rend="str">John W. Debaum</hi> Mercer County
<lb/>State of Kentucky } sct
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Affidavit</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>John W. Debaum states that Martin B. Debaum now confined in the Jail of Franklin County, was indicted at the <date when="1862-04">April term 1862</date> of the Mercer Circuit Court, in conjunction with one W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Crasslow, for malicious &amp; wilfull Shooting at John Alexander without wounding, and that the said Shooting -- affiant occurred on the first day of said month &amp; year -- Affiant States that he was present when the Said difficulty arose, and saw it all the facts &amp; circumstances of which are about these; the Said W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Crasslow and one Wesly Robards got into a heated political discussion arising from the fact that they Said Crasslow <hi rend="str">who</hi> was a member of the home guards and the Said Robards was a returned rebel Soldier and had before that time belonged to the command of John H Morgan -- The Said disputants progressed in their quarrel until they got into a fist fight, and ^both^ had fallen to the ground in the Struggle, when the Said John Alexander urged by his political sympathies for the rebel Soldier ^despite the said Crasslow <unclear/> Robards^ fired on the Said Crasslow &amp; Struck him in the leg -- At this time Martin B. Debaum, who was a member of the Same home-guard company with Crasslow, and who thought that there was a <unclear/> &amp; purpose to kill said Crasslow, who was also a brother-in-law of Said M. B. Debaum picked up a pistol which the Said Robards had dropped in the fight, &amp; Shot at the Said Alexander Without Striking him or any one else -- Affiant States that the Said M. B. Debaum enlisted about two months ago into the Federal Service, and before he was<pb/>
<lb/>confined in jail, and that he now belongs to the 4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky Mounted infantry. He says the Statements in the foregoing affidavit are true and the facts were witnessed by this affiant.</p>
<p>John W Debaum</p>
<p>Sworn to before me this <date when="1864-04-28">28 day of April, 1864</date>.</p>
<p>John C. Kyle
<lb/>Police Judge of Harrodsburg</p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/> </p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Mercer County Sct } Affidavit</p>
<p>Richard Board States that he is the clerk of the Mercer Circuit Court and that he was present on the <date when="1862-04-01">first day of April, 1862</date>, when the difficulty &amp; fight occured for which M. B. Debaum was indicted at the <date when="1862-04">April Term, 1862</date>, of Said Court. He Says he has read the foregoing affidavit of Jno. W. Debaum and that the Statements contained therein are true, and the circumstances as narrated therein were witnessed by this affiant -- </p>
<p>Richard Board</p>
<p>Sworn to before me this <date when="1864-04-28">28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of April, 1864</date> -- </p>
<p>John G. Kyle P. J. H -- </p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><pb/></p>
<p>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Affidavits
<lb/>M. B. Debaum</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
