<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0179"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">E. B. Davis et al. to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8631</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-273</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Grayson, Carter County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Grayson Carter County Ky
<lb/>To his Excellency James F Robertson
<lb/>Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>The under signed petitioners would respectfully represent to you that Stephen H. Young was fined before P, B Hord a Justice of the peace for said Co. the sum of $19.50 ^cts^ for a breach of the peace Now Mr Young is a sober man and this is the first case of the kind he ever was charged with and that he committed ^it^ when he was aggrevated to do the same Now Mr Young is a poor man with a family to rase and Educate; and this of fall the Rebels passed through this county and stoled all of the horses he had which was one in number they took and destroyed all of his beading and clothes for himself and family destroyed all of his cupboard ware such as tea cups saucers plates knives and forks and all of his cooking utencels besides salt Bacon &amp; Beef and fed out a quantity of corn &amp;c and upon the whole he was Litterally destroyed as a house Keeper; and he was taken a prisoner by the Rebels and taken away from home at the same time -- Now under these circumstances we petition your Excellency to remit Said fine and for such relief we shall ever pray</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>E B Davis -- 
<lb/>Wm Neithercutt
<lb/>R. P. Hyrne
<lb/>J. B. Ward
<lb/>Jn<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi> M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Guire
<lb/>Jas N Barnes
<lb/>Jordan Neithercutt, Captain
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Jonathan Davis
<lb/>Larken Dawson
<lb/>J<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">as</hi></hi> M Thompson
<lb/>Boon Finaley
<lb/>William Womack
<lb/>Ira Jacobs
<lb/>Bewrel Burtchet<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>S, S, Greer
<lb/>Philip M Hardy
<lb/>C S Counts
<lb/>John Golihue
<lb/>Joseph, M, Plummer
<lb/>Allen Duncan
<lb/>Joseph Morrill
<lb/>E John Hoggs
<lb/>James L. Hackett
<lb/>James Burtchett
<lb/>C P. McGuire
<lb/>E Boggs
<lb/><cb n="2"/>
<lb/>Stephen H. Young is a Union man, has been robbed by the rebels. I join with the petitioners in the desire that his fine be remitted</p>
<p>W. C. Grier Senator</p>
<p><hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>
<lb/>I prosecuted the within case of the Commonwealth vs Stephen H. Young as county attorney of Carter county, I refused to sign the within petition for the reason that I had prosecuted the case -- I have no objection to the fine being remitted by the Governor and think it ought to be remitted (Except fees and costs) I am fully satisfied that the statements in the petition are true, Mr Young is a good union man.</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> Bowling</hi></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Carter J. P. Ct.
<lb/>Fine Remitted
<lb/><date when="1863-01-21">21 Jany 1863</date>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J F Robinson</hi>
<lb/>$19.50 } Breach
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-01-21">Jan 21. 1863</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>S. H. Young</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
