<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-023-0150"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">G. A. Flannery to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG3063</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG1-296 to MG1-298</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Paducah, McCracken County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-05-22">22 May 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Paducah Ky <date when="1862-05-22">May 22<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>Hon. B Magoffin
<lb/>Gov. of Ky.
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>Col. Noble the Commandant of the U S forces at this Post, has ordered me not to exercise the functions of Judge of the M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracken County Court unless I volunteerly take the oath of allegiance to the government of the United States. I told him I had taken the oath to support the Constitution of the U. S. and of this State &amp; all the oaths of office required by the laws of Ky and that I could not nor would not submit to take any other, nor would I resign the office. I am in the midst of his Soldiers and appeal to you as chief Magistrate of Ky to know whether my course is right or wrong and what course I ought to pursue. The oath is not merely an allegiance to the U S but also requires that I should agree voluntarily to surrender the right of trial by jury and agree to be tried by a Court Marshall and suffer any penalty it may inflict even unto death. Hoping to<pb/>
<lb/>hear from you soon</p>
<p>I Remain
<lb/>Yr Most Obt
<lb/>G. A. Flannery
<lb/>Judge M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Cracken Co. Court</p>
<p>As Clerk of the County Court I would resepectfully state to your Excellency that I have rec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> the same orders for the same reasons, have pursued the same course as stated by Judge Flannery, I am not permitted to exercise any of the functions of my office, in fact my office is closed to business. I join <hi rend="str">in</hi>with the Judge in his appeal as to what I shall do</p>
<p>Yrs Resptly
<lb/>Tho. D. Grundy
<lb/>Clerk of the County Court M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracken County Ky</p>
<p>Executive Department
<lb/>Frankfort Ky <date when="1862-05-25">May 25. 1862</date></p>
<p>Hon J. J. Crittenden
<lb/>Washington City D. C.
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>You will see from the enclosed<pb/>
<lb/>paper just rec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> by me that another outrage has been committed upon the civil authorities at Paducah Ky, by Col Noble the Commandant at the Post. I hope you will Pardon me from troubling you again, to lay this matter before the Secretary of War believing he will redress the wrong without delay, I will only add that these interferences by the military with the Civil authorities and the numerous arrests of our citizens by them which are being daily made, without warrant, charges, Judicial authority, or investigation by the proper tribunals, with what is daily transpiring in Congress, will if persisted in greatly weaken if it does not extinguish the Union Sentiment in the State</p>
<p>With great Respt Your Friend
<lb/>&amp; obt Sevt
<lb/><hi rend="underline">B. Magoffin</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Copy of letters of Judge G. A. Flannery &amp; Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> D. Grundy of Paducah Ky to Gov. Magoffin &amp; his letter to Hon. J. J. Crittenden
<lb/><date when="1862-05-25">May 25. 1862</date><figure type="hr"/><pb/></p>
<p>Letters &amp; c of Hon. W. P. Fowler to Governor Magoffin</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
