<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3143"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Jesse Underwoord and David C. Underwood to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5262</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-329 to BR41-330</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bath County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Governor Thomas E Bramlett
<lb/>Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Jesse Underwood and David C Underwood would most respectfully represent unto your Excellency that at the <date when="1865-09">Sept Term 1865</date> of the Bath Circuit Court that they were Indicted for Killing one Geo Trumbo in a drunken spree They would most respectfully represent that at the beginning of the war they were in the service of the United States and that they continued in the service aforesaid until the close of the war and that while they were in the service aforesaid there was animosities <unclear/> and which is not fully alleged yet, that this Killing of said Trumbo at said time was occasioned by the war or difficulties caused by said war. We would respectfully represent that your Excellency having adopted the only wise and statesmanship policy of wiping out as far as lies in your power the last 5 years of domestic war and trouble and teaching the people moderation and to exercise Christian forebearace &amp; forgiveness to all of your wayward and prodigal sons and in order to do this you have been engaged in the holy mission of as far as has in your power of forgiveness and saying to us all to sin no more We ask your Excellency to extend to us the same executive clemency that you have shown to all of those who have applied for mercy at your hands<pb/>
<lb/>We ask it in the name of ourselves who have regretted more than words can tell the necessity that compelled us to <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> so the deed we have suffered now more than the law can inflict upon us We ask it in the name of a tender mother and a grief stricken father whose faltering <unclear/> life and fast leading him to the grave. We ask it in the name of our wives and helpless little children whose food and <unclear/> depend upon our daily labor. And lastly we ask it in the name of Justice and in the name of thousands of our fellow soldiers whose bones be bleaching upon the battle fields of the South, who went forth with us to <unclear/> the Union preserve the Constitution and to <unclear/> our <unclear/> the laws of <unclear/> <unclear/> <unclear/> while faithfully laboring in the discharge of the duty <hi rend="str">necessity</hi> we were so unfortunate as to <unclear/> the hatred and the displeasure of a man that it became necessary afterwards to take his life We ask your Excellency that in view of all of these facts to extend to us the same executive clemency by pardoning said offenses and we will every pray &amp;c</p>
<p>Jesse Underwood
<lb/>David C Underwood</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of the Countie of Bath &amp; Rowan Counties Ky unite in the above I aver and would ask your Excellency to pardon<pb/>
<lb/>said Jesse &amp; David C Underwood and we would also state that we are fully acquainted with the facts set forth and that they are correct as set forth in the foregoing petition are true</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>S Ecfort
<lb/>C J True
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Elias P Davis</hi>
<lb/>B. S. Shepherd
<lb/><cb n="2"/>V.B. Young C B C C
<lb/>Cyrus Alley clk
<lb/>Rowan Cir't County Court
<lb/>John H. Steele
<lb/>J. E. Clarke prosecuting atty for Rowan Co. &amp; Asst.
<lb/>U. S. Assesser
<lb/>Doc J. T Sellards
<lb/>H H Lends
<lb/>C W Richards
<lb/>P M Lewis
<lb/>H. C. Humphries
<lb/>Alexander Locker
<lb/>James R. Manley
<lb/>James W James
<lb/>J. H. Arnold
<lb/>Jesse Atchison
<lb/>P. O. Collins
<lb/>G. L. Atchison
<lb/>B T Haden Sherif of rowan ^Co^
<lb/>N. B. Literal
<lb/>James <unclear/>
<lb/>Marion Muncy<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>Bath Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>D C Underwood
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Rejected</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
