<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2076"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Purdon to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6713</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-272 to BR14-273</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Stanford, Lincoln County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-07-20">20 July 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Stanford Kenty <date when="1865-07-20">20<hi rend="underline">"</hi> July 1865</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency Tho E Bramlette -- </p>
<p>Your Petitioner Thomas Purdon would respectfully represent that in the fall of 1864, he was residing in the Town of Stanford where he was borned, and Just after dark it was announced, on the streets that horse theives were in a pasture adjoining the Town of Stanford attempting to catch two through bred race mares the property of W B Withers <hi rend="underline">Mr</hi> Withers called upon Petitioner with others to assist him in protecting his property and in capturing the theives, and he together with others run under great excitement to the pasture when Petitioner was directed to gard one string of fence, whilst others entered the pasture and searched for the theives and others still, guarded the other sides of the pasture with the disign of capturing the theves if possible, Petitioner had only for a moment been stationed, at his post and was greatly Excited when in the darkness he thought he discovered some person advancing toward him up the fence, he was guarding; instantly he called out "hault" which was twice repeated and to no Effect as the person still advanced whereupon in the excitement of the Moment he fired, and unfortunately Killed Dick a Slave the property of Joseph McAlister, against whom Petitioner believes no suspicion could attend of Guilty intention to steal the horses aforesaid Petitioner states<hi rend="str">d</hi> that at the <date when="--09">September</date> Term of<pb/>
<lb/>the Lincoln Circuit Court last he was indicted by the Grand Jury of Lincoln for (<hi rend="str">Manslaughter</hi>) the Malicious Shooting <hi rend="str">and Killing</hi> of said boy -- Now Petitioner states he was ^not^ guilty of Murderous intent in Killing said boy, That it was done in excitement of the moment, without any malice whatever, under the honest belief that said boy was the thief who was attempting to steal the two Mares aforesaid of W B Withers, all of which was by Petitioner acknowledged at the time of the Killling</p>
<p>It was a great and Lamentable mistake over which God Knows your Petitioner has been already sufficiently punished The regrets of which will follow him to the grave; but he feels that he is not a fit subject for the state prison, has no proof of his innocence save the facts alone stated, and is unwilling to be convicted upon the records of his native county of Such an Offence, and fears that under the peculiar circumstances of his case such might be the result, and therefore humbly begs your Excellency -- will pardon him, for the Offence charged in said indictment, which he feels would be but Just to him, <hi rend="underline">and</hi> believes will be approved by the Enlightened public sentiment of the County</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>Thos Purdon</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Thos Purdon this <date when="1865-07-21">21<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> dy of July 1865</date></p>
<p>S S M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Roberts Clk L. C. C.<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned Citizens of Stanford and vicinity <hi rend="str">County</hi> Concur in the pryer of the above Petition of Thos Purdon and by his Excellency will pardon said Purdon for said Offence charged in the indictment now pending against him in the Office of the Lincoln Circuit Court this <date when="1865-07-21">21<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> July 1865</date></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J H. Bridgewater
<lb/>T, W, Varnon
<lb/>A G Huffman M D
<lb/>W B Berrey J. P. L. C.
<lb/>M. V. Smith
<lb/>R. G. Craig
<lb/>E. S. Fisher
<lb/>Wm.A. Pollock
<lb/>P H Shanks
<lb/>John C. Cooper
<lb/>D. W. Vanderveer
<lb/>P. M. Talbot
<lb/>E. B. Caldwell S. L. C.
<lb/>H. T. Harris -- 
<lb/>James M Shackelford
<lb/>G W Heath
<lb/>John Bridgewater
<lb/>H B Middletin
<lb/>H. P. Middleton
<lb/>Dayton Tucker
<lb/>James Tucker
<lb/>Willis G. Thurman
<lb/>Henry. R. Thurman
<lb/><cb n="2"/>S S M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Roberts clk, L, C, C,
<lb/>R. Carson Clk. L. C. C.
<lb/>W G Bailey, <unclear>P</unclear> L C C
<lb/>George M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Roberts M. D.
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> B Montgomery M D
<lb/>J. M. Higgins C. L. C.
<lb/>J. N. Hughes
<lb/>Simon Hicks
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Tho</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi><hi rend="underline">. C. Davis</hi>
<lb/>Peyton Embree
<lb/>Mack Huffman
<lb/>W R Casson J P L C
<lb/>D. R. Camden
<lb/>T. P. Douglass
<lb/>W. A. Henson
<lb/>James Vanhook
<lb/>P <unclear>Spragens</unclear>
<lb/>A. S. Myers
<lb/>W R Warren
<lb/>S M. Carver Town Marsh
<lb/>R. M. White Jailor
<lb/>J. C. Carter Merchant
<lb/>Robert R. Gentry, Farmer
<lb/><hi rend="str">D W V</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Lincoln Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Purdom
<lb/>Pardoned &amp; Penalties Remitted <date when="1865-08-29">29 Aug /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
