<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2421"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Ben Slavin, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7058</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-362 to BR15-363</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Garrard County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-13">13 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>At the August Term of the Garrard Circuit Court, the Grand Jury of Said County, Indicted James W Ross for the Murder of M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clure with Malace aforethought. The Circumstances Connected with the affair So far as I Know them, are as follows,</p>
<p>In the fall of <date when="1862">1862</date>, a few days after Braggs Army Pressed through our County on the retreat, Myself &amp; Bro. John L. Slavin were Arrested by a ditachment of Col. Wolfords Redgment at my Fathers House, Some three Miles from our Homes -- being Anxious to see our Fameles we ast. of Lt W D Carpenter the Commander of the squad. Permission to go by home, we also requested Ja W Ross to go with us (we feared being arrested by some other Soldier<hi rend="sup">s</hi> <hi rend="str">&amp; perhaps would</hi>. That might not treat us well we therefore wished to be in his Custody) He (Ross) agreed to go by permesson of Lt,, Carpenter, which was granted; on the way, I was detained by Dennis Ryon a few Moments, which gave them (Ross &amp; my Brother) Some distance the start within about fifty yards of them (Brother &amp; Ross)<pb/></p>
<p>I met M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clure ^or a man I learned afterwards was McClure^. I at the Same time Saw that They (my Brother &amp; Ross) had stop<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> &amp; Ross tourned back, when I met Ross I ast him where he was a going. He answer: To See who that fellow was. That he beleived him to be a rebel Soldier &amp; perhaps a spy and ast me if I new him I told him I did not, and told him to be careful, that he had a pistole &amp; might shoot him</p>
<p>I did not notice them any moore (not expecting any violence) until I hear<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Ross hollow Halt, I tourne<hi rend="sup">d</hi> my head &amp; saw M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clure tourn to the left &amp; a cross the road &amp; Ross rode up to him. From their actions I Judged they had Some words, I was not near enoughf to hear what was Said by this time I had overtaken my Brother My attention was next attracted by the firing. at the 2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> fire M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clure fell from his Horse. he then rose on his hand and fell over near the fence. Ross then got off of his Horse about the place where M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clure fell &amp; picke<hi rend="sup">d</hi> up something. that I Supposed was M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clures pistole<pb/>
<lb/>which I afterward understood to be so, he (Ross) then got on his Horse and rode back to his command. I believing the man was dead. and also that he at least might ^be^ the advance of a rebel squads. we did not go back to him but went on home, as we passed we told a neghbour. M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> F J Corne what had, occured.</p>
<p>They had picked up a number of rebel soldiers, &amp; had them under guard before we Left them to go home</p>
<p>Ben F Slavin</p>
<p>Sworn to and subcred before me <hi rend="str">this</hi> by Benjamin Slavin this <date when="1865-09-13">13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of September 1865</date></p>
<p>James H Henry J P G C</p>
<p>I concur with the Statement of B, F, Slavin. &amp; also state that B F Slavin was not up with us when Ross <unclear>tourned</unclear> back to See M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clure. &amp; also state that <hi rend="str">we</hi> he beleived him. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>C was a rebel &amp; perhaps a spy &amp; so stated. I was the witness and only one before the Grand Jury</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Jno L Slavin</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Sworn to &amp; Subscribed before me by John L Slavin <date when="1865-09-15">Sept 15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>.</p>
<p>James H Henry J P G C</p>
<p>Garrard Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Ross
<lb/>Pardoned <date when="1865-10-02">2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> Octr/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
