<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-003-0126"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">A. H. Bowen to James S. Brisbin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1643</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR5-223 to BR5-227</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lexington, Fayette County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-25">25 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Hd. Quarters 1 Div Dept Ky
<lb/>Lexington Ky <date when="1865-09-25">September 25/65</date>
<lb/>General</p>
<p>In compliance with instructions of <date when="1865-09-22">September 22'</date> I have the honor to state that I have made a thorough investigation of the interference on the part of the Military with the civil laws at Harrodburg Ky and would respectfully summit the following report</p>
<p>On the <date when="1865-09-05">5' day of September</date> Lieut Col. John D. Hale of the Mercer County Militia was seized by a party of fourteen "14" citizens living in the vicinity of Harrodsburg: Ky, armed with double barrel ^shot^ guns, pistols and knives and forcibly taken by them to some distance in the country and kept for twenty four 24, hours when he was released upon his promising not to prosecute any of them for making an illegal arrest, At the<pb/>
<lb/>time of arresting him the party were nearly all intoxicated and threatened to kill him by hanging and shooting and said openly in the streets of Harrodsburg that they came there for the purpose of killing Hale.. and they intended to do it. When Hale was first arrested and the party made the above remarks a man by the name of Jefferson Robards came up to the party with a rope and urged them to hang Hale saying that if they would he (Robards) would tie the ropes around his (Hale) neck.</p>
<p>On the release of <hi rend="underline">Hale</hi> he returned to Harrodsburg Ky and seeing Robards followed him into the office of Mr. Chas H. Hardin Atty. where he spoke to him and asked him why he had done as he did the day before Robards denied every thing. When Hale told him to come with him, and he would have him confront a man who would prove that he had done what he was charged with<pb/>
<lb/>Whereupon Robards jumped up and thrust his hands into his pocket as though in the act of drawing a pistol when <hi rend="underline">Hale</hi> drew his revolver (a large sized navy) and presented at Robards breast and told him if he drew a pistol on him he would shoot him</p>
<p>At this time several others interferred and took Hale out one side and talking with him a few moments when the trouble was settled. A man by the name of Mr Bowen acting in the capacity of civil policeman on learning of the above quarrel between Hale &amp; Robards applied for and obtained a warrant for arrest of Hale for a breach of the peace in drawing a pistol on Robards which he attempted to serve on the evening of the <date when="1865-09-09">9' day of September</date> When Lt W. F. Bishop Comdg a Co of 5' Vol U. S. C. C stationed at that place interferred and prevented the officer from making the arrest</p>
<p>I will here state that at the time<pb/>
<lb/>Hale was arrested (as will be seen by the accompanying affadavits) several of the civil officers including the police judge and several of his policeman stood by and saw it and did not attempt to stop the proceedings but actually urged others who were giong to the assistance of Hale from doing so under the pretext they they were afraid that if any one interferred they would all be killed I enclose here the affadavist of Thomas A. Hardin Judge of Police court Chas H. Hardin atty. Mr. Bowen policeman and Col Hale also the official report of Lt Bishop in which this report is based As will be seen by referring to affadavits of Col. I D. Hale Judge Hardin told him <hi rend="underline">Hale</hi> "during the absence of Lt Bishop that Lieut Bishop had gone to Lousiville in arrest and that if he returned to Harrodsburg Ky he (the judge) intended to order out the citizens and kill Bishop and all his niggers. It would show by their re=<pb/>
<lb/>marks that Judge Hardin might if he had chosen to do so have ordered out citizens enough to have prevented 14 men from perpetrating there disgraceful outrages that was pertrated in arresting Hale</p>
<p>Taking into consideration the fact of Hales being taken and treated as he was by this party of citizens and the non interference of the legal authorities in endeavoring to prevent it and the prompt manner in which a warrant was issued for Hales arrest when he quarrelled with this man Robards. It certainly looks like a desire on the part of the civil authorities to pester Hale all they could do legally and take no step to prevent others from doing it illegally if they chose therefore I consider the interferrence of Lt Bishop was proper and well timed</p>
<p>I have the honor to be
<lb/>Very respectfully,
<lb/>Your obt Svt<pb/>
<lb/>A, H, Bowen
<lb/>Major and A. A. I. G
<lb/>I. D. D. Ky</p>
<p>Brig General
<lb/>Jas S. Brisbin
<lb/>Comdg 1 Div Dpt Ky<pb/></p>
<p>Hd Qrs D o D Ky
<lb/>Lexington Ky <date when="1865-09-26">Sep 26/65</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Bowen
<lb/>Major &amp; A A. I. G
<lb/>1 D D Ky<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Forward report of investigations of affairs at Harrodsburg. Ky.<figure type="hr"/><pb/></p>
<p>Hd. Qrs 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Div D, K,
<lb/>Lexington Ky. <date when="1865-09-26">Sept 26" 65</date>
<lb/>B 451. 1st Div D Ky <date when="1865">1865</date><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Respectfully returned with attention invited to enclosed reports of Maj <hi rend="underline">A. H. Bowen</hi> A. I. G. and <hi rend="underline">Lieut Bishop</hi> 5" U. S. C. C. and affidavits of <hi rend="underline">Judge Hardin</hi>, <hi rend="underline">Cha</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> A. Hardin</hi>, <hi rend="underline">M.V. Bowen</hi> and Col <hi rend="underline">J. D. Hale</hi>.</p>
<p>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> S. Brisbin
<lb/>Brig Genl.
<lb/>Comdg. Div<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Recd D K -- <date when="1865-09-27">9-27-1865</date></p>
<p>E &amp; M. C G Vol. 3. D K. <date when="1865">1865</date>.
<lb/>Hd. Qrs Dept Ky.
<lb/>Louisville. <date when="1865-09-28">Sept <hi rend="underline">28/65</hi></date><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Respectfully returned to Thos. <hi rend="underline">E. Bramlette</hi> Gov. of Ky -- inviting atttention to report of Maj Brown and to accompanying affadavits -- </p>
<p>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> W <unclear/>
<lb/>Capt. &amp; A. A. A. Genl.
<lb/>In absence of Genl. Comdg.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
