<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-022-0011"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George C. Hallet to Daniel W. Lindsey</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11937</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>37th - 76th Regiments Enrolled Militia Primary Source Documents (1861-1866)</collection>
      <idno>Box 80, Folder 863-64 FULTON COUNTY Recruiting and Raising Company 40th Rgt. Ky. Militia</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hickman, Fulton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-11-24">24 November 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Head Quarters 40<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Regt Ky Militia
<lb/>Hickman Ky <date when="1863-11-24">Nov. 24. 1863</date>.
<lb/>General D. W. Lindsey
<lb/>Inspector General of Ky.
<lb/>General.</p>
<p>The history of this stupendous rebellion is yet to be written and to be written in all truthfulness, the future historian must look to the public archives among which he will find the evidences of outrages committed on both sides, as they are communicated to superiors under a deep sense of the responsibility of honor and position on the part of those communicating.</p>
<p>Without further apology or excuse, permit me to say, that without waiting for an answer to my last communication, I had just finished the draft of the enclosed bill, embodying my view, as to the proper legislation, necessary for the ordering out of the militia in this most rebellious portion of the state, when at about 11 o'clock, A. M. a band of men claiming to belong to Capt Brown's Battery of Artillery from Union City, and being some eight or ten in number, suddenly made their appearance in this city and forthwith began seizing some of our most peaceable and loyal citizens. These men, they declared were conscripted and were forced to go with them to the Military post at that place, as they said, to be pressed into the service. Some of these men, <hi rend="underline">i e</hi> the Soldiers, remained behind, after the depart-<pb/>
<lb/>ure of the main body, and being intoxicated, commenced an indiscriminate attack upon the shops of our most loyal citizens, breaking in the windows, doors and so forth, and also in firing upon defenseless people. One man, a M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Cato Davis, from Tennessee, was shot at and wounded in the arm, while standing in Messer<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. Leonard &amp; Co's store door, and at the same time, M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Buckner, the Board of Trade was fired at four times. This state of things is hardly endurable, and it does seem to me, that now, more than at any other time, is it important for this part of Kentucky to be placed under the protection of the Governor, and the laws of the commonwealth enforced by its military <hi rend="str">force.</hi> power.</p>
<p>As we are at present circumstanced, we have no peace and can have none. To day a <hi rend="underline">raid</hi> is made upon us by rebels, outlaws, robbers and cut-throats; and to morrow we will be sujected to attacks by irresponsible soldiers from our own military posts stimulated to acts of attrocity by "<hi rend="underline">mean whisky</hi>." It is but right to say, that these acts are disapproved by the officers in command, but you will readily perceive General, how difficult it is, to identify the men, who commit the outrages.</p>
<p>The Civil power is inadequate to the protection of the people, and the principal reason of this is, the entire want of arms in the first place and the want of amunition, in the second.</p>
<p>The draft of the bill you will find inclosed, is entirely for this section of the state. The powers conferred upon the Governor are large, it is true, but they are necessary. Without them, and without the confiding of the command to an energetic determined man as Brigadier Genl. the militia even if called out, will be but a <hi rend="underline">sham</hi>. You will readily comprehend the<pb/>
<lb/>object intended to be effected.</p>
<p>Whether the views embodied in the bill will meet your approval or not, or whether the hints embodied in it may be made available in a general bill, I cannot of course know; but as a citizen, a Civil and a military officer, I have felt it my duty to communicate them in form.</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>Your Obt Servt
<lb/>Geo C. Hallet
<lb/>Col 40<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Regt Ky. M.<pb/></p>
<p>40
<lb/>Fulton Co <date when="1863-11-28">Nov. 28. 1863</date>
<lb/>Geo C Hallet
<lb/>Col 40<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Regt<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Presents a Bill to organize the Militia for consideration of the Legislature<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>ans<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-12-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Decr 63</date>
<lb/>J. M. B.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Rec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> I. G. O. <date when="1863-12-01">Dec. 1. 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
