<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0418"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John M. Farrar et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4537</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-159 to BR9-160</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-01-21">21 January 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thos. E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your petitioner William Brockman would respectfully represent, that at the <date when="--12">December term</date> of the "City Court of Louisville" a fine of $50 was assessed against him, and one of $25 dollars was assessed against his wife on a charge of assault and battery.</p>
<p>He says, that <hi rend="str">at</hi> the alledged asssault was not committed by either him or his wife <hi rend="str">first</hi> that a man by the name of Starkie had been working for him, and they had had some misunderstanding, and he had forbid Starkie to come on his premises; but he came notwithstanding, and he went toward him to prevent him going up Stairs in his house, and when he got in reach of Starkie, he was Struck by him. These facts were witnessed by two Soldiers, only one of which he could possibly get at the trial the other having gone, or ^having^ been ordered out of the State on duty.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth proved however <hi rend="str">the</hi> by a bitter enemy of his and a worthless trifling witness ^not Starkie, for he failed to appear^ that he committed the first assault. This was false, and the Soldier contradicted the witness in every material point; but notwithstanding this the Jury found a verdict <hi rend="str">of</hi> as above. He moved the court to Set aside the verdict, but it refused; he moved in arrest of<pb/></p>
<p>Judgmt against his wife but then was refused. He there would have taken an appeal to the court of Appeals, but his only witness, had been ordered out of the State to Join his regmt and he had no witness atal by whom he could prove the facts as they occurred if a New Trial had been granted him.</p>
<p>He Says the Judgmt against his wife is manifestly erroneous, because he was present &amp; participating in the fight, and the law presumes that whatever She done was by his coercion; and that hence She was guilty of no offence, but no appeal ^will be to the court of Appeals for a sum of the $50.^</p>
<p>The injury was but trifling, and there was a large amount of cost in the case which he will be compelled to pay; and the part of the city atty; and this is punishment sufficient even if he were guilty. But he Says he is not guilty, but that witness Swore falsely against, and that he is the victim of her mallice.</p>
<p>He respectfully prays for Executive clemency.</p>
<p><date when="1864-01-21">Jany 21. 1864</date>
<lb/>John M. Farrar
<lb/>Jo<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Clement
<lb/>C Daubert
<lb/>Isaac Cronin
<lb/>W. P. Hydes
<lb/>Phil Tomppert
<lb/>George Seaton
<lb/>Henry C Russell Dan C C L
<lb/>L. W. Salp
<lb/>Garrett Burr<pb/>
<lb/>R. A. Collins
<lb/>J. M. Stephens
<lb/>Robt. A. Hamiltons<pb/></p>
<p>Louisville City Court
<lb/>Wm. Brockman
<lb/>Petition to the Gov.</p>
<p>Rebecca S Brockman was improperly fined and the fine of $25.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> <hi rend="str">Remitted</hi> one half the fine of fifty dollars against Brockman is Remitted to cover the amount of costs and fees improperly assessed against the wife</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
