<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2523"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. F. Burgess to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7160</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-36 to BR16-37</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Sherburn, Fleming County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-30">30 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Sherburn Fleming County Ky <date when="1865-10-30">oct 30 1865</date>
<lb/>Govener Bramlett
<lb/>Most Esteemed Friend</p>
<p>I Communicate to you this morning a Subject which I hope Shall not pas your notice and due imparshall considerations, as follows during the Summer of <date when="1865">1865</date> my Father George W Burgess and <hi rend="str">one</hi> one W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Bateman met in the road had a few cross words when Said batemen beat my Father Severley they was boath tried by John Roby, J P and fined and ofterwards Said Roby remitted the fine of Said Bateman which I think very unjust unless the fine of G W Burgess be Remitted and I ask your Honor to Remit the fine of Said G W Burgess if you pleas this is the first case of this kind that has occured with him for 20 odd years he Burgess an old man nearly helpless not able to get far from home, only been to his County Seat twist in 3 years and one was to hear you speak you got acquainted with him coming from Flemingsburg to this place Last <date when="--07">July</date> in the buggy and furnished you with a horse to ride to Owingsville Ky when you was canvasing the State I am the man you Spent the night with in this town I only mention this to give you some <unclear/> of his appearance think you would Recolect him<pb/>
<lb/>our County atterney wrote to you asking you to Remit the fine Some time Since &amp; he told me that he thought it Likely you had not received his letter, and I take the responsibility on myself to write to you asking this favor and should you wish to no the whole Proceedings of the case you can Soon get them by writing to me or W H Cord Esqr our County atterny who is well acquainted with the whole matter you can Drope me a Line and I will get the prominent citizens of the community to Sign a petion for the Remitting of the fine if required</p>
<p>you have the Best Wishes of my Father and many frend of this Community and Ever Beleave me your true Friend</p>
<p>J F Burgess<pb/></p>
<p>John Roby
<lb/>J. Peace
<lb/>Fleming Co
<lb/>vs
<lb/>G W. Burgess
<lb/>$7.50
<lb/>Breach Peace
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-11-07">7 Nov /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
