<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3183"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. R. Smith et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5302</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-233 to BR41-234</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Calloway County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>We the undersigned Citizens of Callaway County in the immediate neighborhood of the residence of Henry Cooper Free man of Color would respectfully represent unto the Excellency of Thomas. E. Bramlett Govenor of Kentucky that at the <date when="--06">June term</date> of the Marshall Circuit Court that this- Grand Jury found an indictment against Henry Cooper charging him with commiting an assault on J. H. Cope which took place at a steam mill in Marshall county near the Callaway line at which Mill the said Cooper was employed as fireman and was dilligently attending to his work when J. H. Cope <hi rend="str">came</hi> come to the Mill highly intoxicated and went to where the defendant was and commence a difficulty with the defendant by very abusive language and choking him while out of the presence of any one but when they got to where they could be seen one witness saw the defendent strike Cope one lick with a stick. we would further represent that we have known- Cooper all of his life and that he is now and has been all of his life a good quiet peaceable Freeman and that this is the first difficulty we and only difficulty that we have ever heard of his being in and he is poor and has a large family<pb/>
<lb/>to support by his daily labor, <hi rend="str">upon</hi> at the Present term of the Marshall Circuit Court Henry Cooper was tried and his find assessed by the Jury at forty dollar now we think that this is case in which the clemency of the of Executive might Properly he extended and we hope that you Excellency will remit all of said find except the cost and states attorneys fee</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>signing names
<lb/>J. R. Smith
<lb/>E H Brown
<lb/>Amos Copeland
<lb/>G W Jackson
<lb/>W Brown
<lb/>John Curd
<lb/>W T Milugan
<lb/>J. I. Miller
<lb/>N. A. Cleaver
<lb/>H C Gardner
<lb/>L J Booker
<lb/>J Gardner
<lb/>F F Ward
<lb/>T. H. Pettit
<lb/>R A Heath
<lb/>P P Russell
<lb/>J P Jarny
<lb/>D C Penny
<lb/>J H Russel
<lb/>J W <unclear/>
<lb/>T M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Elrath Jr
<lb/>J. H. Peterson
<lb/><cb n="2"/>signers names
<lb/>George Owings
<lb/>J.. S. Gourdner
<lb/>W. S. Head<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>The fee of $2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> for the Asst Secty of State will be forwarded if necessary Z M</p>
<p>B &amp; M</p>
<p>Marshall Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Henry Cooper
<lb/>M.C.
<lb/>assault
<lb/>$40</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
