<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3194"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Wilkerson Warren, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5313</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-366 to BR41-367</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bath County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>S Crane
<lb/>Philip Milams
<lb/>George Spencer</p>
<p>Bath Circuit Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against } Indictment
<lb/>Wilkinson Warren</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Bath County in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky accuse Wilkinson Warren of the offence of Murder committed as follows to wit</p>
<p>The said Wilkerson Warren on the <date when="1865-04-20">20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of April 1865</date> in the County and Circuit aforesaid did wilfully &amp; feloniously &amp; with malice aforethought Shoot and kill &amp; murder one - Adams whose first name is not known to the jurars with a gun and Pistol loaded with powder and lead which he then and there held in his hand Against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>J S Cury
<lb/>Commonwealth Attorney
<lb/>upon the back of which is endorsed "A true Bill signed" J A Trumbo Forem"an,,<pb/>
<lb/>The following notes are enclosed in the Indictment to wit-</p>
<p>"Commonwealth 
<lb/>vs } Indictment the <date when="---28">28<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi></date><hi rend="sup">
<lb/></hi>Wilkison Warren</p>
<p><date when="1865-04-20">20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of April 1865</date> the body was found in the Cty Bath near Polksville for the murder of <gap/> Adams by shooting in the head &amp; body and also he was wounded &amp;c Thomas Ragland, John Mayse James H Mayse William Moore William Rodgers Caraner Julius Christy Doct J Wills Andrew Mays,,</p>
<p>We the undersigned certify that the forgoing is a true and correct copy of the Indictment for Murder in the Bath Circuit Court against Wilkinson Warren for Murder ^Adams^ and also a copy of the notes filed by the Grand Jury with Said Indictment as the evidence before them produced<pb/>
<lb/>upon which the Indictment was found</p>
<p>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlett
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner would respectfully represent that near the close of the war the body of a man named Adams was found near Polksville and Your petitioner Wilkerson Warren was Indicted in the Bath Circuit Court for the murder of said Adams. He states that said Adams was found dead and there was no proof who killed and when he was found he was so mutilated that he could not be recognized</p>
<p>Your petitioner states that he is innocent of the charge and to avoid the expense and trouble of a trial he respectfully asks your Excellency grant him a Pardon for said supposed offense</p>
<p>He states that he was a soldier of the U S army during the rebellion and in Consequence believes that he could not get Justice in the County of Bath where a large majority of the people sympathise with the rebels and from this fact he is of opinion<pb/>
<lb/>Your excellency ought to interfere in his behalf</p>
<p>Respectfully Your petitioner
<lb/>Wilkerson Warren</p>
<p>We the undersigned have read the foregoing petition and from the infor mation we can gether we believe its statements are about correct wherefore we heartily join in the prayer of the foregoing petition</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J M Elliott
<lb/>J. E. Clarke Co Atty R. C.
<lb/>A Bailey
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Welch
<lb/>Thomas.J. Wright
<lb/>Hiram Green
<lb/>Thomas F Razor
<lb/>Solmon Cox
<lb/>John Razor
<lb/>James L Wright
<lb/>Nuten traylor
<lb/>N R Abott J P
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Pagett
<lb/>Samson Green
<lb/>Thomas Green
<lb/>John Green
<lb/>W. J. Razor
<lb/>John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Carty
<lb/>Al Razor
<lb/>H H Lewis
<lb/>J G Barnes
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Moore
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John Shrout Jr.
<lb/>A K Manley
<lb/>Wilis Tralor
<lb/>Henry Wills
<lb/>John Power
<lb/>John P Harrick
<lb/>Sanders Power
<lb/>W L Flood
<lb/>Thomas Spencer</p>
<p>Bath Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Wilkins Warren</p>
<p>This is a case for trial not for pardon before trial. Nothing is presented except a claim of innocence which is a question for trial-</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
