<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2893"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thornton Mobley, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7530</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-208 to BR17-209</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Union County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-25">25 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Union County Ky near Morganfield
<lb/><date when="1865-12-25">December 25<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date></p>
<p>this is to certify that I was acquainted with John P Hall and his wife -- and Dr R.W N Taylor Decd -- that I have been intimately acquainted with Hall from his infancy to the present date that I knew his wife Josephine Hall intimately from the time of their marriage until they <hi rend="underline">finally</hi> Separated -- a period of Something over three years -- Dr Taylor had been in the County but a few years hence my acquaintance with him was limited</p>
<p>Hall was a Carpenter by profession -- though poor was a good mechanic and by his industry and attention to business was prosperous and contented in the enjoyment of his humble home and the Society of his young wife they often visited my house a difficulty and estrangement arose between Hall and his wife and at his request I visited his house and learned from them both that the difficulty was caused by She having while attending a Sick friend permitted Dr Taylor<pb/>
<lb/>to take improper liberties with her -- She however while frankly admitting the fact Justified herself upon the ground that while temporarily ill -- the Dr" gave her opiates and while under its influence in a condition of Stupor he "had taken advantage of her -- the affair caused the Separation of Hall and his wife which occured Soon after -- I was not present when this affaird finally culminated in the Killing of Taylor by Hall -- but from all facts in my possession Knowing So well and So fully realizing the cruel wrong inflicted gratuitously by Taylor upon him -- I was clearly of the opinion that Hall had the right to Slay him -- </p>
<p>I in fact had So much confidence in the Justness of his cause that during the terrible excitement that was aroused against him in the community at the time I went Halls Security to the amount of nine hundred dollars for attorneys fees (all of which he has Since paid) -- and when he was finally admitted to bail in the Sum of five thousand dollars I Cheerfully Joined with him</p>
<p>I am now released from his bail bond<pb/></p>
<p>Hall was a poor man comparatively little known -- The friends and relatives of the Deceased had wealth and influence both of which were exerted to procure the most able and influential prosecution ever had in this part of the State</p>
<p>It was a Source of Gratification to me upon hearing the testimony that in addition to the cause above related -- I could Justify Hall in Slaying Taylor upon the Grounds of Self defense</p>
<p>to all of which I certify on honor </p>
<p>Thorton Mobley</p>
<p>Kentucky -- 
<lb/>Union County } Sct</p>
<p>I Samuel C Hughes Presiding Judge of Union County, do hereby certify that I have ^known^ Thornton Mobley, from my earliest recollection, and that he is a reliable man, and implicit reliance can be place upon his veracity -- I further certify that the above is his genuine signature</p>
<p>Witness my hand this <date when="1865-12-27">27" day of December 1865</date></p>
<p>Sam C Hughes P J U C<pb/></p>
<p>Mobley</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
