<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-024-0005"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James P. Hendrick to John W. Finnell</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG12059</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Mitchell A Krock</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>1st - 20th Regiments Kentucky Infantry Primary Source Documents</collection>
      <idno>Box 7, Folder 1st Ky Infantry - Misc</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-01-28">28 January 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Danville <date when="1863-01-28">Jan. 28th 1863</date>
<lb/>Adt. Gen John W. Finnell
<lb/>Frankfort Ky. Dr sir</p>
<p>In compliance with a communication from you to Hon Mr. Marshall and by him sent to me I respectfully submit the following statement</p>
<p>On Saturday <date when="1861-10-05">Oct. 5th. 1861</date> After marking a short speech to the Citizens of Fleming (a large number of whom had assembled in our county court House) I offered my services to my Country and invited as many present as I could influence, to do the same. Almost nothing had been done up to that time in most of our county in the way of recruiting soldiers for the U. S. service. <hi rend="underline">One</hi> <hi rend="underline">week</hi> afterwards we organized a company, having about <hi rend="underline">(70)</hi> seventy men, of which I declined the command and went with it into Camp Kenton as a <hi rend="underline">private</hi> <hi rend="underline">soldier</hi> on Wednesday <date when="1861-10-16"><hi rend="underline">16th</hi> Oct 1861</date>. On <hi rend="underline">the same</hi> day at the request of Col. Marshall, into whose Regiment my Company went, I was appointed Chaplain to Col Metcalfe's Fractional Regiment which was also recruiting at Camp Kenton. Both Marshall &amp; Metcalfe were ordered into the field, under Gen Nelson, since Ky afterward, and made with him the Campaign into Eastern Ky. I served under Metcalfe during that expedition<pb/>
<lb/>in the capacity of Chaplain, doing at the same time whatever was in my power to render the men comfortable and effective and using my horse and buggy as an ambulance, as we had with us no ^other^ conveyance for the sick. After we returned from Piketon and while in camp at <hi rend="underline">Lower</hi> <hi rend="underline">Blue</hi> <hi rend="underline">Licks</hi> I recruited and brought into Camp the greater portion of the company now commanded by Capt Rodgers of <hi rend="underline">18th</hi>. Ky. Infantry -- To which ^Regiment^ <hi rend="underline">two</hi> <hi rend="underline">companies</hi> of Metcalfe's men were attached by the process of Consolidation. By that process of Consolidation Metcalfe and his nominal staff are thrown out of the service I of course with the rest. The Consolidation took place about <date when="1861-12-10"><hi rend="underline">10th</hi></date> or <date when="1861-12-15"><hi rend="underline">15th</hi> Dec./61.</date> I will send you the <hi rend="underline">exact</hi> <hi rend="underline">date</hi> as soon as I hear from Col Metcalfe who I suppose has it. For the above service I have received no pay save the consciousness of having attempted to do my duty. I have never made any efforts to get any pay save the writing of a letter to Senator Marshall, last week, giving him a statement of the facts. If I am legally, as I feel I am justly, entitled to pay for the above time and labor I would be very glad to receive it, as I sacrificed over <hi rend="underline">six</hi> <hi rend="underline">hundred</hi> dollars for the priviledge of rendering the above service -- gave up for a session my school for <hi rend="underline">the</hi> <hi rend="underline">time</hi> my church For the truth of the above in <hi rend="underline">all its</hi> <hi rend="underline">particulars</hi> I refer to Cols Marshall &amp; Metcalfe to Capts Barns &amp; Palmer of <hi rend="underline">16th</hi> Ky Infantry and to Hon's W. H. Wadsworth &amp; L. W. Andrews,<pb/>
<lb/>&amp; R. H. Apperson Jr. all of whom (save Mr. Andrews) were with us in the expedition to Piketon and are perfectly conversant with the facts.</p>
<p>Yours Truly
<lb/>Jas. P. Hendrick</p>
<p>P. S.
<lb/>The date of the Commission I now hold as Chaplain of 10th Ky. Cav. is <date when="1862-09-05"><hi rend="underline">5th</hi> <hi rend="underline">Sept</hi> 1862</date> I suppose the muster you propose to make for my benefit ought <hi rend="underline">antedate</hi> that period -- that howeve you can best determine</p>
<p>J. P. H.<pb/></p>
<p>1 Inf -- 
<lb/>Headquarters Ky Vols.
<lb/>Adjt. Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">ls</hi></hi> Office
<lb/>Frankfort <date when="1863-01-29">Jany 29, 63</date></p>
<p>Issue commisssion to James P. Hendricks as Chaplain 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Ky. Reg<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Vol. Infantry date <date when="--10-16">16<hi rend="sup">th</hi> October</date> and endorse to be mustered for pay from <date when="1861-10-16">16<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Octo.</date> to <date when="1861-12-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> December 1861</date> -- he having served as chaplain to Metcalfes regt. during that period. under orders from Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Nelson then in command of forces of United States in Eastern Kentucky -- <hi rend="str">and has</hi></p>
<p>By order of the Governor
<lb/>Jno W Finnell
<lb/>Adj<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Gen<hi rend="sup">l </hi>Ky</p>
<p>1. 2. 3. 4. 5. 6. 7. 8. 9. 10.
<lb/>forw<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> to H. at Danville Ky -- </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
