<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0094"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Philip D. Yeiser to Rufus K. Williams </title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8546</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-146 to R3-147</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Paducah, McCracken County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-10-04">4 October 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Paducah Ky <date when="1862-10-04">Octr 4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>Judge R K Williams
<lb/>D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Sir</p>
<p>Will you so much oblige me as to go to Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Robinson &amp; present my Case as herein after stated for executive clemency, it is a really meretorious one as the facts will show and I pledge you my honor what I say is true</p>
<p>At the term of the Lyon Circuit Court before the last I was security on a recognizance bond for the appearance of W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Reeder indicted for a misdemeanor, his trial came on he was present and fined 50$ -- (there was a protem Judge at that Court the regular Judge being absent) in the morning or about noon of the next day after trial the commonwealths atty caused Reeder to answer to the judgment he answered and I delivered him up to the court and so announced, but some confusion in same way occuring about that time the clerk omitted to make an entry of my surrendering him up &amp; it being about the close of court the entry was not made and Reeder went off and I have'nt seen or heard of him since -- <hi rend="str">with it</hi> however after it was ascertained that Reeder had gone home &amp; the entry of his surrender was not made, Just before the Court was about to enter the adjoining order finally the Coml<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> atty on Motion took the Recognizance bond for $200 for foreited -- at the last <date when="1862-06">June term 1862</date> of the said Lyon circuit court all these facts were proven<pb/>
<lb/>but the court (Judge Dabney) not feeling authorized to correct the record &amp; adjudging that no proof short of the record evidence of my having surrendered him up would do rendered Judgment against me but both he &amp; the Commonwealth atty wrote out a statement of the facts for the Governor with recommendations for pardon, which statement I sent to Frankfort to Jonas Martin a representative and he never presented it &amp; besides lost it &amp; now the Guerillas are so thick in Lyon, Caldwell and Trigg that I cannot see the Judge &amp; atty to get another statement, nor go to Lyon to get a copy of the Judgment, but I herewith inclose a copy of the execution issued to the sheriff of M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracken County on the said Judgment &amp; the sheriff is pressing payment and really I have'nt the money to pay -- besides you know I have spent several months hard labor without fee or reward for the State, however as a patriot I should have done that, but on the other hand she ought to kindly consider the meretorious appeals of her sons for clemency -- The costs of this execution which the governor court remit will pester me to pay, for I tell you those infernal villains in Lyon have nearly ruined me -- I lost at least 5000 or 6000$ in this rebellion to say nothing of the loss of time and business.</p>
<p>Yours &amp;c
<lb/>P. D. Yeiser<pb/></p>
<p>Lyon Cir Ct</p>
<p>The collection of the Judgt &amp; Exetn in this Petttn hand respited for 4 months</p>
<p>J F Robinson
<lb/>$200. } Recog.
<lb/>P. D. Yeiser
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Boyd
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-10-09">Oct 9. 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
