<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3118"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">G. H. Lewis et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5237</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-287</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Morgan County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><hi rend="underline">Petition</hi></p>
<p>To his Excellency the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Morgan County state that we are informed that there is Indictments now pending in the Morgan Circuit Court clerks office against J. T Lewis in three cases with others &amp; also against Maron Lewis in two cases W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> A Lewis Ben A T Lewis. Each in one case &amp; Green Oakly &amp; Harrison Lewis ^John Farmer^ in one case with others charged with horse stealing &amp;c ^and also James Brown^ we state that we are well acquainted with Each one of these party and that the offences with which they stand charged was done during the Rebellion &amp; when they was acting as home guards. that up to the Breaking out of the Rebellion &amp; for some time afterwards they conducted themselves as good citizens &amp; in fact untill they were <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> ^droue^ into the home Guard Service for self protection from the Guerilas &amp; those who gave them aid &amp; comfort. your Petitioner would state that they do not believe that they ought to be persecuted under said Indictment &amp; for the charges therein made as They think that what was done was done with any intention of stealing but as a punishment for ading &amp; harboring Guerrilas They are satisfied that the charge of Robry against J S Lewis is a false charge against him It seems that those who commited offences agt the Law &amp; who was endeavooring to Break up the Governt go unpunished It is but just that your Excellency should overlook charges against those who was trying to sustain the Govenet against its enemies<pb/>
<lb/>That which seemed to be right in time of war is not right in Time of peace hence your petitioners would ask your Excellency to pardon the said John J Lewis Green Oakly Harrison Lewis Marion Lewis John Farmer William A Lewis &amp; Ben A J Lewis we state we are Union men &amp; have Been so <unclear/> the out Break of the Rebellion &amp; will we pray</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>G H Lewis J P
<lb/>John Martin
<lb/>Jesse Barber
<lb/>Henry Craig
<lb/>James. Barber Jr.
<lb/>Henry Blankenship
<lb/>Anderson. B. Gose
<lb/>Cyrus Perry
<lb/>James Blair
<lb/>Adam Crose
<lb/>Jesse Perry
<lb/>Anderson Perry
<lb/>Henry T. Gose
<lb/>Simon Link
<lb/>John Link
<lb/>Thomas Link
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Lewis Hunt
<lb/>T J Broon
<lb/>John K Broown
<lb/>William B Elliott
<lb/>Benjamin S Elliott
<lb/>Samuel S Elliott
<lb/>T. A. Lewis
<lb/>Isaac Sergent
<lb/>D. A. Sergent
<lb/>E Sergent</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
