<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3438"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">M. Goldsmith to A. G. Phelps</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5557</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-336 to BR42-343</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865">1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">1</note>
<lb/>Louisville Ky <date when="1865">1865</date>
<lb/>Sir,-</p>
<p>In compliance with your request I visited the Soldier's Home, at Harrodsburgh Ky and gave to it and its belongings - a patient and careful study</p>
<p>I find that the main or central building has been burned, and that the two rows of dormitories, standing at right angles to the front line of the main building, and forming with it three sides of a hollow square, are mere wrecks of walls, incapable of repair, except at an expense almost equal to the erection of new buildings. I find that the sills of the floors of the brick dormitories, has rotted off with the dampness of the ground, that the ceilings are low, and that they could never be made fit for winter<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">2</note>
<lb/>habitations</p>
<p>This cluster of houses is situated at the lower end of a ravine, some sixty or seventy feet as nearly as I could estimate by the eye, lower than the ridge bordering it</p>
<p>The location is the worst on the whole grounds The ground is damp, the soil retentive- there is no chance for drainage. The ground there being lowest, Nor is there any opportunity for the free movement of air, the higher ground on either side baffling the wind-currents, and draughts along the line of the ravine, being cut off by the thick wood copses, which constitute the sole scenic beauty of the place</p>
<p>I am concerned that the situation is wholly unfit for any habitation, in which it is desired to attain the highest salubrity</p>
<p>The buildings now remaining on the<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">3</note>
<lb/>ground, may be rendered habitable, but even if in good and habitable condition I am utterly at a loss to see how any system of administration could be devised for the convenient and comfortable or economical care of the inmates. There are none amongst them suited for kitchen, laundry and the like- If there were such the houses are to detached that long lines of coridors would have to be built to connect them, with the administrative facts- The cost of such corriders would be very great.</p>
<p>The soil is thin,, and a descent of a few feet, uncovers the rock- &amp; that the cess-pools would be shallow and offensive, for they could not be drained, or if drained, the sewage would flow into the town and breed a sickness</p>
<p>I am clearly of the opinion, that the<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">4</note>
<lb/>present building should not be repaired and that whatever future arrangements are entered into, provision should be made for the inmates, upon the higher grounds, open to free currents of an and capable of drainage.</p>
<p>I have also inspected the building situated near the Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> property, and known as the Bowman and Williams property. One of these is simply a large, handsome and substantial private gentleman's residence - and would be ample for officers quarters and offices - elegant at that</p>
<p>The other, that which has been, and is now used as seminary - is just about such a building as the Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> would probably build, with reference to convenient and economical administration It has an abundant water supply - It has it Steam Laundry and kitchen, already fixed and fitted and in working order.<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">5</note></p>
<p>It has all the outhouses and detached buildings necessary for the attachès of the institution, as well as for storage &amp;c It is situated on a high ridge overlooking the surrounding grounds - capable of drainage on two sides The sewer matter can be carried off into running streams, or can be utilized in farming operations at proper distances from the buildings.</p>
<p>The house could be occupied at once, and to fit it for the use of the inmates, not a dollar of expense is required, nor would any be required before the number of inmates exceeds one hundred. When the number exceeds this the walls which are double - would have to be perforated, and grates put in to each room, a cost of perhaps three (3) dollars per room and a lower turret over the stairway costing perhaps one hundred (100) dollars<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">6</note></p>
<p>The capacity of the building, estimating it on the scale of an space of hospitals is about 150 - a number which must be lessened or may be increased in accordance with the ventilation practised</p>
<p>I understand that these buildings are offered for sale. What their price or commercial value is, I am unable to state- Of this however I am confident- that they are substantially such as should be built &amp;c <unclear/> if the Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> intend to keep this locality as a home for invalid soldiers -- except perhaps -- that she would not build so expensive quarters for the officers.</p>
<p>They are such, not only in construction, but in situation in regard to the all important matter of free currents of air; isolation from surrounding buildings &amp; forests, and drainage conditions, which are simply impossible where the old buildings are placed.<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">7</note></p>
<p>The site of these buildings is as high if not higher, than any part of the Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> grounds, and has the advantage of bordering the Harrodsburgh and Danville turnpike.</p>
<p>The singular exemption from malarial diseases which Harrodsburgh enjoys the ancient unown which its mineral waters have earned in the restoration of those suffering from the Chronic- malarial cachexia, would seem to indicate the use of the locality as a Sanitarium, as well as a home for Invalid soldiers -- an indication all the more pointed in the consideration that a very large number of those invalided during the past war, were stricken by marsh miasms, and that in the sewer to come, the chief danger to life will be found in sea-wash and near-bottom palludials poisons.
<lb/><note place="footer">over</note><pb/></p>
<p><note place="header">8</note>
<lb/>I have the honor to be
<lb/>Your obt Sert
<lb/>M Goldsmith
<lb/>Surg u. s. r.</p>
<p>To Bv<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Lt Col A G Phelps
<lb/>Med D<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Dept of Ky.</p>
<p>a true copy
<lb/>M Goldsmith
<lb/>Seug u s r</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
