<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0785"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Timberlake to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4904</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-209 to BR10-210</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency James F Robinson, The Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner William Timberlake would respectfully represent that on the <date when="1863"><gap/> day of 1863</date>. in the Circuit Court of jefferson County in the state of Kentucky; He was indicted, tried, and convicted, on a charge for Horse Stealing. The Testimony given against him is on file herewith, and from the reading of the evidence, it must be apparent to every right minded-man, that it does not show guilt either directly or circumstantially; and your Petitioner most solemnly disavows any participation in the horse stealing:</p>
<p>and He state most honestly, that he did not know that the horses were stolen until he was examined and tried. then he found out, that the horses did not belong to Allen Snooks of Shelby County, and that the man now called Patrick Noland was not the son of Allen Snooks: </p>
<p>Your Petitioner states that He is young, and that having been raised in Covington where his father now resides, that he undertook to manage the books for some time for his father, at his fathers Mills, and that he becamse tired of home, and left going to the City of Louisville, when He got there he was wandering about, and fell in by chance, with the young man who now turns out to be Patrick Noland. This same man told your Petitioner that his name was Snooks, and that his Father lived in the County of Shelby, and was name Allen Snooks and that he traded in horses and Cattle, and that he young Snooks assisted him to drive his stock to market, and that his said Father lived near Eminence on the railroad to Frankfort and that He had a fine horse and man up there<pb/>
<lb/>and if your Petitioner would go up with him he would bring the horses to Louisville and sell them Your Petitioner consented to go with him, and when we reached Eminince He at first said they would stay all night then, but finally concluded to go on to the Stable that night and get the horses so as to start back early next morning, which we did. The horses were rode to Louisville and put up at the Shelby House. Snooks began next morning to try to sell the horses, by riding down in the time, and your Petitioner finding him on the street surrounded by men interfered and told the crowd of men that he was the son of Allen Snooks and that he could show him he came by the horses and who he had gotten them from, when they were beating young Snooks your Petitioner interfered, and they beat your petitioner and finally arrested your petitioner as they said for attempting to resuce a prisoner, and this was the charge they at first made against me; </p>
<p>It now turns out that it was not Allen Snooks son but the young man Patrick Noland as I have learned did at one time live with Snooks and assisted him to drive his stock to Louisville.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner thinks that He ought not have been convicted because, 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> He did not felonisouly take the property. 
<lb/><note place="left margin">2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi></note> Because, <hi rend="str">2</hi><hi rend="str"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> He now had a felonious posession of the property; 
<lb/><note place="left margin">3</note> Because the property never was, but constrictively in his possession 
<lb/><note place="left margin">4</note> Because no witness from that he took the property. 
<lb/><note place="left margin">5</note> Because no witness from that be set up any ownership to the property at any time or place: on the contrary the<pb/>
<lb/>proof shows conclusively that Noland was in the possession of the property at Louisville that He claimed and was endeavoring to sell it.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Humbly prays your Excellency to interpose execution clemency and in consideration of the promises to grant him a Pardon and will ever pray.</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>William Timberlake</p>
<p>The foregoing <hi rend="str">is</hi> ^corresponds^ substantially ^with^ a statement as to the facts of the case, which statement was made by the accused to his attorneys <hi rend="underline">before</hi> the proof was presented on the trial of the indictment</p>
<p>Craig &amp; Elliott
<lb/>Attos for Timberlake.<pb/></p>
<p>William Timberlake
<lb/>To } Petition
<lb/>The Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> of Ky
<lb/>Horse Stealing</p>
<p>I can discover no good cause for Excte interference in this case</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J. F Robinson</hi></p>
<p>Pardon granted
<lb/><date when="1864-04-02">April 2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Thos E Bramlette</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
