<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0642"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Allison Price to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4761</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-514 to BR9-515</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-03-08">8 March 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thomas E. Bramlette, Governor.</p>
<p>Your petitioner Allison price, would most respectfully state, that in the year <date when="1860">1860</date>, in Livingston County Ky, where your Petitioner then resided, one John Story Stold from the possession of your petitioner, a lot of money, and your petitioner had him arrested, and confined in Livingston County Jail, and on his trial your petitioner and the father of your petitioner, were witnesses for the Commonwealth against Story, and they testified in the case, and during the argument, one C. Bennett a lawyer, defending Story, charged upon your petitioner and his father, that they had sworn a lie, and had perjured themselves, which so exasperated your petitioner that he whipped Bennett or attempted to do so and partially succeeded, whereupon Bennet went before the Grand Jury and gave information, and your petitioner was indicted for a Breach of the Peace, &amp; upon the trial, Bennet was <hi rend="underline">the</hi> witness for the Commonwealth, and Your petitioner<pb/>
<lb/>was fined Fifty dollars, by the Verdict of a Jury, under the instructions of the court, that "words did not justify an assault"- Story was convicted and sent to the Penitentiary. Now Your petitioner admits the whipping of Bennet, he used no deadly weapons however, and frankly confesses that under Similar circumstances, being changed with Perjury and false swearing, he would do so again. He holds that, being innocent of the charge, a lawyer has no right to assail the character of ^a^ witness in that way. and he felt in duty bound to defend himself from Oppression &amp; Slander. He is in humble circumstances, and poor, and unless he defends his Character for truth &amp; honesty, he will be, and ought to be despised. Your petitioner further states, that his reputation through life and that of his old father, has always been good and he prays that your Excellency interpose and remit that portion of the fine due the state, and your petitioner will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p>Allison Price<pb/></p>
<p>Allison Price says that the statements in the forgoing petition are true.</p>
<p>Allison Price</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Allison Price, this <date when="1864-03-08">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of March 1864</date>.</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi>. W. Herndon J. P. M. C. C.</p>
<p>We say that the statements in the foregoing petition are true, of our own knowledge</p>
<p>J. H. Flournoy
<lb/>S H Flournoy</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens, have been acquainted with Mr A. Price &amp; his father for several years, and endorse the statements in the foregoing petition and request the Governor to grant the prayer of the Same.</p>
<p>T. B. Husbands
<lb/>Charles H. Webb
<lb/>M. Livingston
<lb/>J G Roberts
<lb/>C S Blanton
<lb/>Young Rucker
<lb/>John S. Leffler
<lb/>J R Hayward
<lb/>James W. Ausenbaugh
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> J Jennings
<lb/><unclear/> Matthews<pb/></p>
<p>Petition
<lb/>of
<lb/>Allison Price<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracken<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>Breach Peach
<lb/><date when="1864-04-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Apl 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
