<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-028-0064"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William M. Pratt to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7719</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Appointments by the Governor, Military Appointments, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R2-204 to R2-205</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-10-13">13 October 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Covington <date when="1862-10-13">Oct 13, 1862</date>
<lb/>Hon J. L. Robinson
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Dillerd &amp; myself start for the interior to day. I would be glad to secure your influence in behalf of Rev W. Pope Yeaman, who has recently settled here as pastor of this church. He is brother of Geo. H. Yeaman. is a genuine union man. He has a precious support here where there is so much division of sentiment. There are three hospitals in Covington and a great many sick in them, &amp; no post chaplain for the patients. If you would suggest to the appointing power his appointment as Post chaplain at this place, he would faithfully attend to his duties &amp; devise thereby a support for a large family, &amp; the government would have no man in her employ more worthy of patronage -- I dislike to trouble<pb/>
<lb/>you upon a matter of this kind but I am confident if you were acquainted with M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Yeaman, &amp; knew the circumstances of his family you would not hesitate. He left a lucrative practice of the law from conviction of duty to preach the gospel, &amp; his strong Union sentiment has deprived him of the sympathy &amp; support of many secessionists.</p>
<p>Yours most respectfully
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> M. Pratt<pb/></p>
<p>Revr<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Wm. M. Pratt</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
