<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2582"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. H. Hoyt to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7219</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-129 to BR16-130</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-11-09">9 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Frankfort Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-11-09">Novr 9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Gov Bramlette</p>
<p>Mr Gillespie of Washington County Comes to you with a petition for the pardon of his son who has been ^Convicted &amp;^ Sentenced to the penitentiary for the killing of Lawrence, he brings with him ^a transcript of^ the Record in the case, you will see by an examination of the transcript that Johnson Edwards one of the Jury who tried the Deft, was one of the Grand Jury that brought in the Indictment against him -- which was not known to him or his Counsel until after the verdict was rendered.</p>
<p>The Counsel for the Dept M. R. Hardin writes to me that for this error the Circuit Court ought to have granted a new trial, but that it is not an error that can be corrected in the Court of appeals.</p>
<p>The Deft Henry Gallespie has faithfully served his Country as a Soldier in the 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Ky Cavalry -- the evidence Shows that the killing was done in a sudden encounter<pb/>
<lb/>without malice, the witnesses for the Deft prove that the Killing was justifiable -- if you will read the transcript of the evidence I beleive you will be satisfied that this is a case in which your clemency ought to be exercised by so doing you will rejoice the heart of the Defts aged father a very respectable old Gentlemen who has given three of his sons as soldiers to the Federal Army</p>
<p>W. H. Hoyt</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
