<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2057"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Adam Tuttle to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6694</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-243 to BR14-244</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Laurel County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-07-12">12 July 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency Thomas E, Bramlett 
<lb/>Gov. of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Adam Tuttle respectfully shoeth unto your excellency that he is a quite a poor man with a large family and feeble health, and at the last term of the Laurel Circuit Court he was fined in the sum of Sixty Dollars upon an indictment charging him with keeping a Tipling-house Your petitioner states that he was a stiller and had the right to sell w^h^iskey by the quart and your petitioner frequently gave his neighbours &amp; customers a dram but never charged it unless they took as much as a quart. He states that William Cook the witness upon whose testimony petitioner was a lone convicted is a man of General bad moral character for truth so notoriously bad that he is not entitle to credit upon oath.</p>
<p>William Cook stated to William Morris that he Cook had never bought any liquor from petitioner by the smalls &amp; paid the money for it, and on the trial he swore he had done so. Witness Cook swore there was no prejudice upon his part against your petitioner when in truth &amp; in fact he had great prejudice at petitioner -- </p>
<p>Your petitioner states that he has had to pay a heavy tax to the United States on the whiskey he stilled and is now greatly insolvent and if he can not get relief his<pb/>
<lb/>family will have to suffer for the absolute necessaries of life, he therefore prays your excellency to interpose your pardoning power and remit said fine, and he will ever pray</p>
<p>Adam Tuttle Petitioner</p>
<p>Milton Jones states that William Cook had him summoned to <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> sustain him in his testimoney that he had bought Whiskey twice of the petitioner &amp; paid the money for it &amp; stated that affiant was presant. And affiant has no recollection upon earth of ever seeing William Cook at anytime buy Whisky brandy or any liquor from the petitioner &amp; pay the Money for it -- by the smalls or in any other way -- </p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Milton Jones this <date when="1865-07-12">12 day of July 1865</date></p>
<p>Wm. R. Jones J. P ^for laurel county^</p>
<p>Marlan Jones states that William Cook is a man of bad moral Character that from the sumer of the Country in Cook's Neighbourhood he would not believe him upon oath affiant heard Cook sworn upon the above trial &amp; he stated he had no prejudice at petitioner and affiant states that at that same time Cook did have prejudice at petitioner and afiant heard the trial of Tuttle &amp; he was convicted a lone upon the testimony of Cook<pb/></p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Marlan Jones this <hi rend="str">30</hi><hi rend="str"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> <date when="1865-07-12">12 day of July 1865</date> -- </p>
<p>Wm. R. Jones J P for laurel county</p>
<p><hi rend="str">We</hi> I Nancy Burnett state that I heard the said William Crook say he would go &amp; hire us a substitute &amp; then Change his name &amp; get off. affiants Housband A. Burnnett then &amp; still in the U S, service as a soldier, remarked to Cook that the officers would swear her Cook stated he would swear a lie for the bounty</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Nancy ^&amp; A^ Burnett this <date when="1865-07-12">12 day of July 1865</date> -- </p>
<p>Wm. R. Jones J P for laurel county</p>
<p>We Marion Phelps, Will Mcgee W, J, Cook <hi rend="str">and William</hi> William Weaver and F, G, Crawford state that we are acquainted with the general moral Character of William Cook, that it is bad &amp; so bad that we would not believe him upon his oath.</p>
<p>Sworn to before me this the <date when="1865-07-12">12th day of July 1865</date> Wm. R. Jones J P</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Marion Phelps, Will Mcgee W, J, Crook, William Weaver and F. G. Crawford this day of <date when="1865-07">July 1865</date> -- </p>
<p>Wm R. Jones J. P for laurel c.<pb/></p>
<p>Remit</p>
<p>Laurel Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Adam Tuttle "
<lb/>Petiton "
<lb/>$60.
<lb/>Tipling
<lb/><date when="1865-09-18">18 Sept/65</date></p>
<p>Sent for fee
<lb/><date when="--07-20">20 July</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
