<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0045"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James V. McKasson to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14074</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1864</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Gentryville, Spencer County, Indiana</placeName>
    <date when="1864-07-18">18 July 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Gentryville Ind <date when="1864-07-18">July 18/64</date>
<lb/>Gov Bramlet</p>
<p>Dear Sir discover since I came home from the Army of the Potomac that there is a large number of Guerillas on the border here and it is reposted that they are doing considerable amount of damage and I have heard that you want to have the State cleared of them and also I am informed that one Capt Willson is in Davis or Ohio County and is troubling them that is the Guerillas Now the object of my writing to you is to know how you want men to operate on what terms time pay and so forth <hi rend="str">Some</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Now Sir as I have Served three years in the Cavalry I think I know something about the management of mounted men and scouting and so on.</p>
<p>I have thought since I came back that if I could get a command or a commission to command a company I would go in for awhil and I think I can raise fifty or one hundred men in a few days there is several men here that has been compelled to leave your State that say that they would like to help put the Guerillas out of the way and would like to go in you will please answer this you will send to me in Gentryville Spencer County<pb/>
<lb/>State of Indiana</p>
<p>I am verry respectfully yours
<lb/>James V M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kasson</p>
<p>P, S, Referances of character and Qualifications can be given if required</p>
<p>A V M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>K<pb/></p>
<p>State of Indiana
<lb/>Spencer co Genrtyville
<lb/><date when="1864-07-18">July 18<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kasson, Jas. V.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>writes to the Govr to Know on what terms, time, pay &amp; c he wants men to serve agst guerillas. wants a com,s,n. Can get 50 men, some of them refugees from Ky wants an answer immediately com'n'c'n refrd by Govr to Inspr Genl<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Answered <date when="1864-07-22">July 22 -- 1864</date>
<lb/>On Letter. Book Page 522.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Recd I. G. O. <date when="1864-07-21">July 21<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
