<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1624"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Mary Carter, et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6261</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-78 to BR13-79</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Marion County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-04-20">20 April 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency.
<lb/>Govr Thos. E. Bramlette=</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Mary Carter widow and Adm<hi rend="sup">x</hi>. of Thomas Carter Dec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> would most respectfully state and show that at the <date when="1863-11">Nov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Term 1863,</date> of the Marion Circuit Court her said husband &amp; Intestate became the surety of one John Hardin in <hi rend="str">ag</hi> a recognizance entered into in said Court in the Case of the Commonwealth of Ky Plff against said Hardin on an Indictment of alleged Robbery of one John. R. Redmond. Said recognizance was for the sum of one thousand dollars. Said Indictment it appears was pending and undetermined up to and including the last <date when="1865-02">February</date> Term of said Court. In the mean time said Thos. Carter (my husband) departed this life on the <date when="1864-01-10">10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Jany 1864.</date> and your Petitioner became his admx. and was wholy ignorent that her husband had ever become bound in any way as Mr. Hardins securety until served with the Copy of Summons hereto attached as part hereof. It will be seen that at the last <date when="1865-02">February</date> Term of said Court a forfeiture of said Recognizance Bond was taken on motion of<pb/>
<lb/>the Atty for the Comth. Now your Petitioner states that she was wholy ignorant of her liabelity on said recognizance. and in fact is advised that no forfeiture should have ever been taken against her on said recognizance. for the fact that said Hardin had been theretofore during said term of said Court surrendered into and was at the time of the act complained of as a forfeiture occurred in the custody of said Court and beyond the Controll of his Bail. The ground was that pending the trial of said Indictment said Hardin had left the Court House and escaped It was true she supposes that he did escape but it was from the Custody of the Court under circumstances that did not make her as adm<hi rend="sup">x</hi> as afs<hi rend="sup">d</hi> as she is informed amenable under said Bond= She would further state that your Excellincy after maturely considering the Petition of said Hardin for a <hi rend="str">rem</hi> pardon of the alleged Robbery did grant to him a Pardon for the Same. and he now stands clear of same but this Petitioner is attempted to be made responsible for the $1000. Bail. She has lost a great deal during this war and from the loss of her hands is barely able to make enough for the support of herself and family</p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">T C. W
<lb/><date when="1865-04-20">Apl 20 1865</date></note><pb/></p>
<p>She feels that if she is to be made to pay any of these forfeitures she will loose the same as Mr Hardin is not able to reimburse her</p>
<p><hi rend="str">the support of herself and family</hi> She therefore most respectfully prays your Excellency for a remission of the said forfeiture=</p>
<p>She further says that at the <date when="1863-11">Nov. Term 1863</date> her said husband entered into one other recognizance Bond in said Court for Said Hardin in the sum of $500. in the Case of Comth Pllff against Said Hardin on an Indictment for alleged "shooting wth intent to kill" of one Morris Doody. Said Case was undetermined at the last <date when="1865-02">Feby</date> Term of said Court and there was a forfeiture entered against Petitioner as Adm<hi rend="sup">x</hi> of said Carter on said Recognizance= She knew nothing of this Case either and the escape of Mr. Hardin was made as above stated and for that the forfeiture was entered and judgment is now sought against her for the $500. for this forfeiture She also most respectfully prays a remission. And as in duty will ever pray &amp;c.</p>
<p>Mary Carter</p>
<p>Sworn to by Mrs. Mary Carter before me this <date when="1865-04-20">20" April 1865=</date></p>
<p>Thos. C. Woods. N. P. M. C.<pb/></p>
<p>We Citizens of Marion County most respectfully recomend the Petitioner Mrs. Thos. Carter to His Excellency Thos. E. Bramlette Govr of Ky for the clemency prayed for by her in her foregoing Petition= <date when="1865-04-20">April 20" 1865</date></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>S A Spalding
<lb/>E. P. Mahon
<lb/>E. S. Mayes
<lb/>J. H. Sanders
<lb/>Tho Johnston
<lb/>G H Browning
<lb/>J G Philips
<lb/>R. B. Edmonds
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Brannon
<lb/>J. H. Edelin
<lb/><cb n="2"/><hi rend="str">Cap</hi> John W M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Whorter Cap
<lb/>of State troop and Pro Mar
<lb/>of allen Co and taylor Co
<lb/>A Edmonds
<lb/>James M Fioler Cap &amp; Pro. Mare H. D. Ky.
<lb/><hi rend="underline">F B. Merimee</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">T. C. Jackson</hi>
<lb/>O Ames<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>Marion Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Mrs. Mary Carter
<lb/>Petition to Govr</p>
<p>2 judgts
<lb/>$500 -- 
<lb/>$1,000 -- 
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1865-04-27">27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> <hi rend="str">M</hi>April/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
