<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0456"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Andrew J. Snowden, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4575</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-217</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Clark County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-01-29">29 January 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky, Clark County Sct
<lb/>Andrew J. Snowden of said County &amp; state being sworn according to law, says</p>
<p>First, That at the <date when="1860-11">November Term 1860</date> of the Clerk Circuit Court, he was indicted upon charge of Carrying concealed deadly weapon_ which is still pending That Richard Allen of said County became at his instance his surety in bail bond for his appearance in Court</p>
<p>Second That at the <date when="1863-07">July Term 1863</date> of the said Court, his recognizance was forfeited under the following State of case, to wit That he left his residence in the morning early of the first day of said term of Court for Winchester the County seat of Clark County to appear at the call of the Docket, and when he had reached in 2 1/2 miles of the Court house, he was informed by several persons that the Rebels were in Winchester close thereto, and engaged in pressing or Stealing horses indiscriminately, and upon the information thus received he returned home as there seemed in his judgment from what he deemed reliable information good foundation to do as he did as he did not want as a Union man either to be injured in his person or have his Horse stolen from him. That he has appeared since to wit at the <date when="1863-11">November Term 1863</date> of said Court, and<pb/>
<lb/>the Cause was continued at the instance of the Commonwealth. That he does not and never has feared the result of his case upon trial, and his failure to appear at the <date when="1863-07">July Term 1863</date> of the Clark Circuit Court, was not in anywise to evade trial a judgment, as he has been ready at all times to amenable to the Court and Laws of the Country. That I am a poor man without any means of any Kind.</p>
<p>Andrew J. Snowden</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Andrew J Snowden this <date when="1864-01-29">29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> January 1864</date></p>
<p>E. T. Taylor P. J. C. C.</p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">E T T
<lb/><date when="1864-01-29">Jany 29 
<lb/>1864</date></note></p>
<p>For the reasons stated in <unclear/> petition and who stated in the note appended by me to that petition ^in the case of Jno. D. Snowden^ I write in the prayer for remission. <hi rend="str">Snowden has been arrested since Judgt. &amp; attended &amp; was Recognized at last term</hi></p>
<p>A H Buckner</p>
<p>I concur in the above statement of M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Buckner</p>
<p>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> B Huston</p>
<p>Clark County
<lb/>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Richard Allen
<lb/>Pet<hi rend="sup">n</hi> for Remission of two Judgments on Forfeited Recognizance</p>
<p><figure type="hr"/>Refused
<lb/><date when="1864">64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
