<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0445"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George Houchens to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8897</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-215</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1863-06-18">18 June 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Governor James F. Robinson</p>
<p>Your petitioner Martha Williams would respectfully ^state^ that on the <gap/> day of <date when="1863-05">May 1863</date> one Mary A. Gravel a woman of doubtful character came to the house of your petitioner and used very insulting language to petitioner whereupon she ordered Mrs Gravel out of her (petitioners house) and Mrs Gravel refused to go and abused and greatly provoved your petitioner so she put her out of the house which Mrs Gravel resolutely resisted and a few days after wards Mrs Gravel had your petitioner &amp; her dauter (to prevent the daughter being a witness) arrested for a breach of the peach and upon her testimony alone your petitioner was fined $20.00 her daughter was acquited but the court refused her evidence for your petitioner the daughter &amp; husband of petitioner alone being present at the time Mrs Gravel was put out of the house of your petitioner your petitioner files a copy of the Virdict &amp; Judgment herewith she says she &amp; her husband are ill able to pay the <hi rend="str">file</hi> ^fine^ which fine if the true facts could have been before the Court she is satisfied would never have been assessed Wherefore She prays that the fine be remitted &amp; for all Just relief</p>
<p><date when="1863-06-18">June 18th 1863</date><pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned Join in the pray of the petitioner believing his a case Justly deserving executive clemency</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>George Houchens
<lb/>Martin Roof
<lb/>Daniel Roof
<lb/>P. M. Heath
<lb/>George J. Hack
<lb/>Andrew J. Hack
<lb/>Silas Simons
<lb/>C. H Durbin
<lb/>T. J. Vinsant
<lb/>Josua Woosley
<lb/>Redmond Thoms
<lb/>James Gatton
<lb/>B. P. Henderson
<lb/>Thomas Goodwin
<lb/>M, M, Logan
<lb/>James. C. Durbin
<lb/>J. D Medcalf
<lb/>Joseph Woosley
<lb/>Thomas Duvall
<lb/>John. M. Durbin
<lb/>Gabriel French
<lb/>Fountain Woosley
<lb/>Alexander Higgs
<lb/>Robert Lastley
<lb/>Harvy Wood
<lb/>George W. Cissel
<lb/><hi rend="str">Chippen Melian</hi>
<lb/>James Jones
<lb/>Christian Whalin
<lb/><cb n="2"/>James Jonson
<lb/>B A Basham <hi rend="str">Jury</hi> Juror
<lb/>John Faris <hi rend="str">Jury</hi> Juror
<lb/>Wm E Davis
<lb/>Asa Davis
<lb/>Alexander White
<lb/>Francis Raymer
<lb/>James M Williams
<lb/>Luke S Williams
<lb/>John H. Williams
<lb/>Warner <unclear/> howard
<lb/>L L Skaggs
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H Scaggs</p>
<p>Those are petitioners serounding heighbours living near petitioners heighbourhood in Edmonson County Ky Please address to Martha Williams or J H Williams Edmonson County Brownsville R H</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
