<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1436"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. Saige Dury to Smoloff P. Love</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6073</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-235</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mount Sterling, Montgomery County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="--03-12">12 </date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Mt. Sterling Ky. <date when="--03-12">March 12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi></date>
<lb/>Col. Love</p>
<p>Our Circuit Court closed closed the past week in February -- Two seperate returns on the bail bond of "not found" -- that is as against the Securities of the same, in the Bosquit Bond -- having been made, I was, of course, entitled to a judgement against them, &amp; not having heard from you any more, (contrary to promise made last fall) I took Judgement. So the case stands, &amp; of course you can expect nothing els but that I will order execution to the respective counties of the securities. However, as I said once before to you in my letter, I will get you rid of the whole if you will send me my per cent -- I appreciate under what peculiar circumstances you all got into it. -- Aye, I will even do better -- if you save me all further trouble -- &amp; take $100 -- knocking off $50 -- So send me a check for the same, &amp; I will send you a receipt in full, when you can make your co-sureties <note place="left margin">contribute. Let me hear from you at once
<lb/>Yours Truly
<lb/>J. S. Dury Com<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Atty.</note><pb/></p>
<p>"A"</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
