<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0999"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Shelby Harwell to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5118</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-45</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Franklin, Simpson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-06-14">14 June 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Franklin Simpson County Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-06-14">June 14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor &amp;C.</p>
<p>The Undersigned Petitioner Shelby Harwell States that he is a resident of Franklin Ky. That some time back he was induced At the Solicitation of his friends, and against his Inclination, and Judgement to accept the office of Jailer of Simpson County. That while he was acting as Jailer he could not on account <hi rend="str">on</hi> <hi rend="str">Account</hi> of the unfortunate Condition of his wife who was at times A lunatic with propriety or conscenience reside at the Jail buildings. During last fall four prisoners esCaped from the Jail. Some of them were desperate characters. All had been arrested by the military Authorities and handed over to the Civil for trial, One had previously broken Jail, And the Jail was a weak structure of the kind. The Military Authorities at the time had partially the contract and use of the Jail</p>
<p>Your petitioner was Indicted for suffering the four prisoners to escape and at the present<pb/>
<lb/><date when="--06">June term</date> of the Simpson Circuit Court Judgment has been rendered against him in each of Said prosecutions for One hundred dollars, in favor of the Commonwealth. His duty to his family was Such that he could not give the Jail the Attention which in the then condition of the Country it Should have had. His wife is now At the Asylum in Lexington a lunatic, not however a pauper patient. He supporting her. He asks, that Said fine be remitted</p>
<p>Shelby Harwell</p>
<p>The Undersigned citizens of Franklin &amp; vicinity State that the facts above subscribed by Mr Harwell are true. They regard the petition meritorious. And Unite in Asking that the relief asked be granted him, believing it a matter of right &amp; Justice to him</p>
<p>F. D. Wade
<lb/>C W Millikin
<lb/>Geo H Millikin
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi> F. Potter
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> W. Bush
<lb/>D. Hail
<lb/>G. W.. Datton<pb/></p>
<p>Simpson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Petition of S Harwell &amp; others
<lb/>4 judgts
<lb/>$100. each
<lb/>Remit
<lb/><date when="1864-08-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Aug/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
