<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-009-0043"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Wiley P. Fowler to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1198</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR1-86 to BR1-87</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Morganfield, Union County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-12">12 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Morganfield Ky. <date when="1865-10-12">Oct. 12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Gov. T. E. Bramlett
<lb/>Dear Governor</p>
<p>I enclose herewith Judge Cooks letter to me, also the statement of J. W. Blue who arrived here to day from Marion Crittenden County. &amp; the list of names refered to by Judge Cook. From these you will see we have troubles with us, and the prospect of more in the future.</p>
<p>I have conversed with many of the most reliable citizens of this, Webster, and Crittenden counties, and from all I could learn and from an affidavit filed before Judge Hughes of this place on day before yesterday, I believe suspicions rest upon the men <hi rend="str">by</hi>mentioned by Judge Cook.</p>
<p>Great allarm, and a sense of danger <hi rend="str">is</hi>are felt by the good citizens in the neighbourhood; so much so, that many of them have quit their homes, and others sleep in the woods of nights.<pb/></p>
<p>Judges Hughes and Cook have issued their warrants of arrests against all that are on the list. The sheriff of this count<hi rend="str">ies</hi>y &amp; Webster were out yesterday with their posses; some four or five are now in Custody, and will be tried before them as soon as the witnesses can be obtained.</p>
<p>From Mr Blues statement I fear that this man Guess, may either deceive you or the U. S. military authorities now in the state, and get some authority in his hands From all I can learn he heads the band of depredators that have done so much mischief; Murders roberies, hanging, and horse stealing in this section within the last few months are of constant occurance</p>
<p>Cant you give authority to some person to raise a company sufficiently strong to cooperate with the civil authorities in order to assist the courts, to overcome any resistance to the law, this band may offer. I do not want black troops and had rather risk the effort of the civil authority alone than that they should be sent<pb/></p>
<p>You may place entire and full confidence in the statement of Judge Cook and Mr Blue as they are both known to me and I vouch for the truth of all they have said</p>
<p>Please let me hear from you as early as may suit your convenience My court will continue here for fifteen days yet. giving time for a reply to reach me before I leave; and suggest what is best or anything that can be done beyond the efforts now being made</p>
<p>I am dear sir most truly
<lb/>Your friend &amp; obdt Servt
<lb/>W. P. Fowler</p>
<p>P. S.</p>
<p>I learn from Mr Blue all whoes names are on the list are being enrolled in Guess<hi rend="sup">s</hi> company now being made up</p>
<p>W P Fowler</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
