<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3202"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Robert Luttrell et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5321</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-379 to BR41-380</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Barren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thos. E. Bramblette
<lb/>Gov State of Ky.</p>
<p>We neighbors and acquaintances of Albert Burgan ^alias Stemburgin^ would respectfully State that we have been for several years well acquainted Said Burgan<hi rend="str"> for several years.</hi> his character as a gentleman for truth veracity &amp;c. has been good he is a very poor man but honest in all his dealings. he has been an unwavering Union Man during the late war. Said Burgan was Indicted by the Grand Jury of the Barren Co. Circuit Court at its <date when="1865-03">March term for 1865</date> for stealing a horse from One Joseph Peck whom we know to be a vile rebel man and was during the late rebelliion we are credibly informed and believe the following to be the facts in the case. Said horse was lost on our Friday night at meeting, and was found by its owner. (So he reports) in the woods near where Said Burgan fed his hogs. Said Burgan was accustomed to feeding his hogs twice a day. <hi rend="str">viz</hi> morning and evening and on the evening he was arrested he was going to feed his hogs with corn in his arms. When coming near the usual place of feeding his hogs he was suddenly arrested by Burgan Whitney, Thomas Kelly, John Kelly, Wootan Bratcher James Payne, Radford Lee, Jacob Peck, &amp; Joseph Peck, three of whom were or had been rebel guerrillas and the other four were rebel citizens. These men had been laying in the woods waiting for Said Burgan to feed his hogs so they might arrest him and accuse<pb/>
<lb/>him of stealing Said horse, which was as they said found tied in the woods near where Said Burgan was accustomed to feeding his hogs, we believe this action to be brought ^against^ him Burgan through rebel influence and by them for vengance upon Mr. Burgan because he was a strong Union Man hoping you see the spirit in which this affiar has been managed and through your highly appreciated clemency you will grant Mr Burgan Pardon in the alleged offence. feeling assured that you will do nothing more than Justice toward our friend and neighbor we are respectfully yours Loyal citizens of the United States,</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Robert Luttrell
<lb/>Elisha Jones soldire 37 mt infantry ^Co A^
<lb/>Joseph T. West
<lb/>H. W. West
<lb/>John R. Littrell
<lb/>H E Steenbergen
<lb/>J F Steenbergen
<lb/>W Steenbergen
<lb/>J. L. Steenbergen
<lb/>H. Payne
<lb/>A. S. Maginis
<lb/>F. M. Rigdon
<lb/>Jesse Busley
<lb/>William Burley Soldier
<lb/>T Ridge <unclear/>
<lb/>thomas C Burley Solder
<lb/>Thomas Bureley 37 mt intr Co A
<lb/>Hugh.M. Steenben
<lb/>Ephriam Berry
<lb/><cb n="2"/>William N Todd Late soldier of the 9<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky Vol parden :Gov: if you can for i think it is <unclear/> Animosity yours truly
<lb/>W P Gilson
<lb/>A J Taylor Belonging to the 9th Ky (Co. A)
<lb/>James Lane
<lb/>James Johnson late soldier of the 9th vol 
<lb/>Thomas.W. Steenbergen
<lb/>John i Tinsley
<lb/>Airon K Jonson
<lb/>Seth Betteley late vol Soldier of the 9 Ky
<lb/>G <hi rend="str">W Rigdon Co K</hi>
<lb/>G W Rigdon Late a solger of 9th Ky Vol<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Thomas Lane
<lb/>John W Jones Co A 9 Ky
<lb/>William Wiliams
<lb/>Joseph Jonson
<lb/>W T Jones
<lb/>D Payne
<lb/>J B Payne co a 37 Ky
<lb/>John H Jones
<lb/>John Bradshaw
<lb/>John.L. Steenberger
<lb/>Bartholamew France.
<lb/>Joseph M<hi rend="sup">c</hi> Genis
<lb/>James Mesker
<lb/>J. P Kinshaw enrolling Officer.
<lb/>O A Burgess
<lb/>James Littrell
<lb/><unclear/> volenteer of the 37 Ky reg co C I No that Said Burgin was a union man During the late war W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Barton
<lb/>E Carver
<lb/>Elish Parvier
<lb/>John Rigdon
<lb/>Jesse Payne
<lb/>Edman G Steern Bergan
<lb/>Elias Littrell
<lb/>Jacob Wright
<lb/>Barnett Payne
<lb/>Begmon Littrell
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Caleb Lowe
<lb/>Robert Boatman
<lb/>George S. Gibson
<lb/>Uriah ,,T,, Gibson
<lb/>Martin Wright
<lb/>William Rigdon
<lb/>B H Veach
<lb/>Edward Elmore
<lb/>William Rigdon<pb/>
<lb/>Barren Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>A Steenbergen
<lb/>&amp;
<lb/>Jas Jones</p>
<p>Refused</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
