<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1315"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. T. Colvin et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5952</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-45 to BR12-46</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Falmouth, Pendleton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-11-26">26 November 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To Governor Thomas E Bramlette</p>
<p>The undersigned would respectfully State to your Excellency that at the late October term of the Pendleton Circuit Court a judgment was rendered against Jacob Fogle upon the forfeited recognizance of Daniel Fogle and Mahala Fogle, which recognizance was executed before R. F. Colvin Esq -- a Justice of the peace for Said County during the pendency of proceedings before him render a peace warrant against Said Daniel and Mahala Fogle issued at the instance of one P. F. Allen. Before the trial on Said Bond in the Circuit Court. Said Allen and Daniel &amp; Mahala Fogle had compromised and Settled all difference between them. with the understanding that none of them Should appear in Said Court neither to prosecute or defend. Under these circumstances relying upon the good faith of the parties, and believing that the aforesaid parties had the legal right to Settle said difficulty Jacob Fogle made no effort to Secure the attendance of those for whom he was responsible. Besides at the time Daniel Fogle was a soldier in the United States army which he believed would exonerate him as Surety from liability if Said compromise did not, Consequently he failed to take Such Steps as the law required him to take. Said judgment was rendered agst Jacob Fogle for the Sum of fifty dollars. Mr Fogle is a quiet peaceable and industrious citizen but a man with a large family to Support with very limited means to do So. From our knowledge of Mr Fogle we believe that he acted in good faith in the premises as above Stated. And we believe that if your Excellency would remit Said judgment to the extent that you are authorized to do. it would be a generous commendable act of kindness we therefore respectfully ask your Excellency to remit said<pb/>
<lb/>judgment agst Said Jacob Fogle if consistent with your Sense of duty and right. Falmouth Ky <date when="1864-11-26">Nov 26th 1864.</date></p>
<p>R. F. Colvin J P P C
<lb/>W. S. Newell
<lb/>Leroy. C. Boyd
<lb/>John Whalin
<lb/>J. B. waters
<lb/>J S Rankin
<lb/>L F Strune
<lb/>J R Hare
<lb/>William Beckett
<lb/>William Creswell
<lb/>P C King
<lb/>John Louson
<lb/>John Woolery
<lb/>James E Beads
<lb/>Will rankins
<lb/>Willis rankins
<lb/>B G. Whitaker
<lb/>C. W. King
<lb/>H H Haviland J P H C
<lb/>A. P. West
<lb/>W. W. King
<lb/>J A Haviland</p>
<p>Havilandsville Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-11-28">28 Nov 1864</date></p>
<p>Hon T Bramlet. Gov<hi rend="sup">r </hi>of Commonwealth of Ky Dear Sir your Kind consideration of the above, I most respectfully ask &amp; Pray. at your earliest convenience and much. oblige your petitioners &amp;c</p>
<p>Jacob Fogle<pb/></p>
<p>Pendleton Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Jacob Fogle
<lb/>$50
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1864-12-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Dec/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
