<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2565"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Lowry to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7202</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-101 to BR16-102</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlette, Governor of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>Your petitioner William Lowry would respectfully show unto your Excellency that he was convicted by a Jury of Laurel County Ky. at its <date when="1864-08">August term 1864</date> upon a charge of felony for horse stealing, and sentenced to the Penitentiary for the term of four years</p>
<p>He states that he is about twenty one years of age, and a member of Captain Burroughs company when he resigned, and Roland was appointed his captain, and belonged to Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Frank Wolfords old regiment, and has been in the service from the formation of said regiment until the present difficulty He states he was on his road home in company with others, and his horse was tired and unable to go farther, that he did take a horse in the day time and time left his; He did not take the horse with any felonious intent He was going through the mountains, where there was danger of being overtaken by rebels, and thought if he was left alone, he would, in all probability be captured or bushwhacked -- </p>
<p>Your petitioner states that he was and is a perfect stranger in Laurel County, and was out of money, and of course had no chance for defence on the trial, or at least a very bad chance to show his innocence</p>
<p>Your petitioner will say to your Excellency that he<pb/>
<lb/>has been a faithful soldier all the time</p>
<p>He is an obscure boy, and has always demeaned himself as an honest man, and was never before accused of dishonesty, or before a Court of Justice on any charge whatever -- Your petitioner therefore asks your Excellency to pardon him, and let him go into the service of his country And if your Excellency will not pardon him upon any other grounds he here proposes to volunteer in the army and help up wind up the war</p>
<p>Your petitioner hopes that under all the facts and circumstances in the case, Your Excellency will pardon him</p>
<p>William Lowry</p>
<p>We whose names are hereto annexed, from our knowledge of the petitioner would most respectfully ask that he be pardoned</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>P P Ballard
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Nelson D Burriss
<lb/>William lowry sen
<lb/>Samuel Gill
<lb/>Richard Turner
<lb/>William Deny
<lb/>J. P. G.
<lb/>J. F. G.
<lb/>Shelby C.
<lb/>Thomas Sanders
<lb/>J P Newe
<lb/>J W Kent<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>J H Jarvis
<lb/>Daniel Tuder J P
<lb/>P. P. Stapp j P M C
<lb/>grifen gulley
<lb/>Stephen <unclear/>
<lb/>William <unclear/>
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>John Gill
<lb/>John W may
<lb/>Robert May
<lb/>J. P. Stapp
<lb/>Doven Hendren
<lb/>Moses M Davis
<lb/>A F Teater
<lb/>Thomas H Reynolds
<lb/>franklin goen
<lb/>Joel vancent
<lb/>w d Teater
<lb/>Richard Burton
<lb/>Thomas Hendren
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>Wills Reynolds
<lb/>William A. Hughes
<lb/>Moses C Masters
<lb/>Tolmon umphry
<lb/>Russel umphry
<lb/>peter umphry
<lb/>James Foster
<lb/>William Ward
<lb/>Johnithan Harry
<lb/>J<hi rend="underline">as</hi> H. Saunders<pb/>
<lb/>W E Warner
<lb/>James J Davis
<lb/>A. Burton
<lb/>Geo M Hendren
<lb/>Levi,, H,, Hendren</p>
<p>Laurel Cir Ct
<lb/>vs.
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Lowry
<lb/>Pardoned <date when="1865-10-11">11 Oct /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
