<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2821"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William H. Holt et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7458</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-92</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>His excellency Thomas E Bramlett Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioners (whose names are <hi rend="str">as</hi>signed hereto) would respectfully Represent that at the <date when="1865-11">Nov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Term of the Magoffin Circuit Court 1865</date> One Matthew Gullet (of Magoffin County) was found Guilty of Keeping a Tipling house &amp; fined therefor by said Court the sum of <hi rend="str">Fi</hi> Sixty Dollars</p>
<p>The proof on the trial agaisnt Gullet in regard to his being guilty of keeping the Tipling house was as follows It was proven that Gullet was at the time a soldier in the Union Army &amp; stationed at the County seat of Magoffin County that he sold a Small quantity of Liquor to two or three Citizens and Soldiers whilst Stationed there &amp; upon this proof he was fined Guilty of Tipling. Gullet served <gap/> years in the union Army &amp; got wounded by the enemy and somewhat disabled &amp; <hi rend="str">remains</hi> will remain so through life he is also a very poor man -- these are the facts of his case &amp; we your Petitioners think it a case that demands executive clemency -- <hi rend="str">Wher</hi> We therefore <hi rend="str">urge</hi> ask that your excellency remit said fine of sixty Dollars</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Petitioners names
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> H Holt
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> L Hurst
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Petitioners names
<lb/>Jno Harkins
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>over<pb/></p>
<p>This man was proven guilty he has lost a part of thumb in the army -- He is said to be a poor man</p>
<p>R. Apperson</p>
<p>The facts within I believe to be true &amp; the petition worthy of your consideration</p>
<p>J. S. Dury
<lb/>Com<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Atty.</p>
<p>Mr Page
<lb/>Assistant Sec of State
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>When in Magoffin Co last week Mr W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> L Hurst Atto at Law handed me this petition to send to his Excellency Gov Bramlette. I told him if the petiton was granted your fee for making out the remission was $2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> He said he was not aware of that, but requested me to send the petition and ask you to send the remission to me and at the next Term of the Magoffin Court he would send you your fee. There is no mail to Magoffin. If the Governor should grant the remission and if you see fit to make it out &amp; send it to me I have no doubt but Mr Hurst will send you your fee.</p>
<p>I am
<lb/>Your Obt Svt
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> H Holt</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
