<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0060"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Richard J. Brown to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14089</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1864</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Springfield, Washington County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-11-29">29 November 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header"><milestone unit="column" n="3"/><cb n="1"/>Lt Col. Thomas Hall
<lb/><cb n="2"/><p>Sam Green
<lb/>John Foster</p> } Mercer Co.
<lb/>Isaac Butner
<lb/><cb n="3"/>(Sam Berry &amp; Isaih Coulter</note>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Springfield Ky.
<lb/><date when="1864-11-29">29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov 1864</date>.
<lb/>Gov Thos. E. Bramlette.
<lb/>"<hi rend="underline">Private</hi>"
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>On last Saturday some twenty five guerrilla's under the notorious Sam Berry and Isaiah Coulter. Entered this County. and passing from West to East robed every body they came across. at Moxville the plundered the town, after which they left in the direction of Cornishville Mercer County. They shot down in cold blood. Sam Green a private in Woolfords Cavalry who had not been home an hour on a leave of absence, They also Killed John Foster a discharged soldier from the same Regiment, who was quietly at home. Passing on further they came to the house of a citizen and there found Isaac Butner a private in Fry's old Regiment, who was at home on a furlough. They shot him down and robed him, of his money. and watch neither of these men made this least demonstration ^of a resistance^ so far from it that Green tried to hide under the bed, but<pb/>
<lb/>they discovered him and put their pistol against his head and shot him dead. After killing these soldiers they went to the houses of Lt Col Thos Hall of the Malitia <hi rend="str">and</hi> and before he discovered them surrounded the house. He gave them fight, firing seventeen times at them wounding several of them after his ammunition gave out. He surrendered. and with his <hi rend="str">f</hi> wife and child, clinging to him. They shot him seven times killing him. <hi rend="str">They have <unclear/> so</hi> They <unclear>cumenced</unclear> as they passed through the county ^then determinated^ to kill all persons who have been in the federal army -- At Moxville they robed Mr Bosley new Sheriff but only got a little over $100<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> from him -- </p>
<p>These are apart of the same band that stay about Bloomfield ^and Chaplin^ <hi rend="underline">Those</hi> <hi rend="underline">great</hi> <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> They came from that <unclear>direction</unclear> to this County The worth of this County and the adjoining parts of Nelson and Anderson are said to be filed with them.</p>
<p>It looks very much as if a law had gone out. To have four persons shot at different places on the same day. In a county in the centre, of the state and so far removed from the seat of <hi rend="underline">public</hi> war.<pb/></p>
<p>The citizens of this county are anxious to have organized a company after the order of that of "Bridgewater" of Lincoln. They can furnish the best of material, both for officers and privates. It would be of the greatest service in this part of the State to operate in Nelson Anderson and This county. Can they organize such a company and what steps will be necessary to be taken.</p>
<p>Yours Most
<lb/>Respectfully
<lb/>Rich<hi rend="sup">d</hi> J Brown<pb/></p>
<p>Springfield Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-11-29">Nov 29<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date>.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Brown Rich<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> J.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>To The Gov<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>On account of recruit depredations of guerillas the citizens of this county are desirous of organizing a Co. after order of Bridgewaters to serve in this county &amp; in Nelson and Anderson counties -- Can they organize such a Co. &amp; what steps are necessary to be taken -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>L B. N<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi> 8 P<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup"> -- </hi></hi>248
<lb/>Made Arrgts with <unclear/><unclear/><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Rec<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> A. G. O. <date when="1864-12-01">Decr 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
