<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2731"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George Williams and A. McMahann to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7368</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-413 to BR16-414B</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-11-15">15 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>vs } Jefferson Circuit Court Petition to His Excellency Gov Bramlette
<lb/>Thomas B. Williams A. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Mann Geo Williams
<lb/>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlette
<lb/>Govenor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioners would respectfully state that on the 10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of<gap/> <hi rend="str">T B</hi>Geo W Williams was arrested charged with stealing the sum of Fifty dollars from Kate Shaffer and was presented upon said charge before his honor the Judge of the City Court of Louisville and upon said charge was held to bail in the sum of three hundred dollars. and L A Wood an attorney at the Louisvill bar was surety for his apperance at the next term of the Jefferson Circuit Court during said time said Wood surrendered said T B Williams and he gave afterwards as his surety to appear your pettitioners A M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Mann and George Williams said Wood only entered upon the bond of said T B Williams until he could<pb/>
<lb/>give your petitioners Geo Williams &amp; M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Mann as surety as heretofore mentioned the next term of the Jefferson Circuit Court <hi rend="str">yo</hi> <hi rend="str">Geo</hi>Thomas B Williams did not appear whereupon a forfeiture was had against him and your petitioners. At the <date when="1864-10">October term Cout 1864</date> the term that said Geo B Williams was to appear, his (Williams) wife was confined to her bed at Emminence Henry Co. Ky <hi rend="str">at</hi> upon the point of death and that she had no one to stay with her at this time but her husband, her precarious condition was of such character that no other but a husband could give her the attention her verry embarrising situation demanded. Being near unto death as afforesaid the dictates of humanity demanded he should remain with his wife who did not recover for sometime after the Jefferson Circuit Court had commenced its work and it was at the worse stage<pb/>
<lb/>of his wife's illness that Williams was to appear, said <hi rend="str">Geo</hi> Thos B Williams is a hard working man a (painter by trade) but verry poor and was not <hi rend="str">pecun</hi> able to pay any one to remain with his Wife had be been disposed to leave her to go to Louisville to answer the charge against him. Your petitioners would further state that <hi rend="str">Geo</hi> Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> B Williams is inocent of said charge. that he was painting his house of M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Smith and while there he in sport took the money of the woman Shaffer whom he knew well that at the time he took said money a witness a M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Brown was present and Williams told <hi rend="str">the</hi>him he was taking it to joke her (Kate Shaffer) he afterwards gave her the money and the matter was thought of no more until one Swe<hi rend="str">a</hi>ney an enemy of Tom Williams had him arrested. He is now willing to stand his trial and always has been, Your petitioners A M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Mann &amp; <hi rend="str">Geo Williams</hi> and Geo Williams further state that they only were induced to go upon the bond of T B Williams from the fealings of<pb/>
<lb/>kindness to him beleiving him inocent of any crime of such a character they did it without reward or the hope of the same All the foregoing statements ^are^ established by the statements of D<hi rend="str"><hi rend="sup">rsr</hi></hi> Ireland and W K Thorn made upon oath before N W Gould a notary Public for Henry County also the statements of said Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Williams and W P Thorn and the Hon J A Neff Represenetive from Henry Co states that Mr Thorn is Known to him to be an honest and truthful Man (all of which exibits are filed herewith as part hereof Your petitioners A M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Mann and Geo Williams as suretys of <hi rend="str">G</hi>T B Williams w<hi rend="str">ill</hi>ould further state <hi rend="str">state</hi> that they are poor men carring on <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>the wagon making busness at Emmenence and not able to pay so large a sum as Three hundred dollar's. from the foregoing statements they pray your Excellency will remit the penalty against them</p>
<p>Signed
<lb/>Geo Williams 
<lb/>A M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Mahann<pb/>
<lb/>The undersigned unite in the prayer of the foregoing petition -- </p>
<p>T B. Cochran
<lb/>J B Kinkead
<lb/>Geo. T. Barret</p>
<p>I am, and have for some time been, acquainted with Geo Williams and his son, and can say that they are both worthy of relief in this matter. They are, and have always borne a good character -- are hard working, and of limited means, and as the accused is under bonds for his appearance, and his first absence was produced by the extreme illness of his wife, and the illness &amp; death of his child (omitted to be stated in the petition) prevented any response to ^sums on the^ forfeited recognizance, I respectfully urge a favorable consideration of the petition -- Mr Williams is an old acquaint<hi rend="str">ed</hi>ance and a worthy citizen -- </p>
<p>Respy
<lb/>James Harlan Jr
<lb/>Frankfort <date when="1865-11-15">Nov 15/65</date><pb/></p>
<p>The Petition states only a <hi rend="underline">forfeiture</hi> of the bond It does not appear that there has been any judgment rendered thereon. The court would set aside a <hi rend="underline">forfeiture</hi> upon the production of the accused in court &amp; the proof of the causes of absence set forth in the Petition. But M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Williams states that Judgement has been rendered If he will produce to me a copy of <hi rend="str">of</hi>the judgment or a certificate from the Clerk of the court that Judgement has been given on the forfeited bond &amp; Shall also bring me evidence that T. B. Williams has been surrendered to Custody or given a new bond for this appearance at the next court &amp; return the same with these papers -- I will grant a remission</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov
<lb/><date when="1865-11-15">Nov 15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
