<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0871"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Martha B. Powell, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10339</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-373 to MG19-374</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-03-01">1 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Affiant Martha B. Powell, states, that she is the wife of J. H. Powell, who was convicted at the <date when="1861-01">January Term 1861</date> of the M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracken Equity and Criminal Court, for Grand Larceny -- She states, that a few days before he husband reached Paducah Ky from Memphis Tennessee, he was quite Sick, emaciated and low spirited, and she perceived alarming Symptoms of aberation of mind, and his melancholy continued to increase for Some days after reaching Paducah -- That they have a Small child now at the breast -- <hi rend="str">they had an ordinary Carpet Sack, with the clothes of the child in it</hi> Stoped at the St Francis Hotel in Paducah -- after resting for a while, her husband, being a mechanic and having his tools with him, started out in Town to find a cheap private boarding house, and afterwards returned to the Hotel much fatigued, having engaged a boarding house in Paducah -- A few minutes thereafter, Affiant, husband and child, paid their Hotel bill, and left the Hotel for the private boarding house, Carrying with them, their baggage, among which was a Carpet Sack, much like affiants, which was not however, and they were pursued and the carpet Sack, was identified as belonging to a Mr Gardner, and had in it about $175. It was given up and every cent of money also, and Mr Gardner was perfectly satisfied<pb/>
<lb/>The carpet Sack was handed to affiants husband, by the clerk at the Hotel, among Other things -- Gardner lives in Tennessee -- The Carpet Sack was taken and Carried off through mistake, and no damage done or loss sustained, by any person, except to the reputation of Affiants husband and family -- Some persons were tried at the same term before Mr Powell was, for larceny and found guilty, and the impression prevailed, that <hi rend="underline">all</hi> were guilty -- That the petit Jury, have all signed the request to the Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. to pardon him, except those who are not in the County, but who declared their willingness to sign the petition at Court -- </p>
<p><hi rend="str">I</hi> Affiant Solemnly, befor her God, States, that she has unabated Confidence in the rectitude and honesty of her husband -- and whilst, under outside pressure and force of Circumstances, her husband has been unjustly Convicted, nevertheless, the affection she bears to him, and the offspring of their love and devotion, will cause her to cling to him in his afflictions and chains, and if possible, share his dungeon, his disgrace and his grave, committing her soul and her lisping, prattling babes, to the care and protection of our all Wise &amp; merciful Providence -- </p>
<p>Mrs. Martha B. Powell<pb/></p>
<p>The foregoin affidavit has this day been Sworn to before me by Martha B Powell <date when="1861-03-01">March 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>Josiah Harris Jr
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Notary Public</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Commonwealth
<lb/>v } Afft of <hi rend="underline">M H Powell</hi>
<lb/>J H Powell</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
