<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1820"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Charles Peter Springer to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11288</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Bradley Strait</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG23-197 to MG23-198</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Harrodsburg, Mercer County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-04-18">18 April 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Governor of Kentucky </p>
<p>The prayer of ^Charles^ Peter Springer to your excellency respectfully sheweth that at a court held by the Police Judge of Harrodsburg in the month of <gap/> <date when="1861">1861</date> a fine was adjudged against him an a charge of Drunkenness &amp; disorderly conduct for five dollars and costs in said court. He sates that this is the first offense of the kind with which he has been charged. That he deeply regrets having ever done anything to make himself liable to such charge. The disorder of which <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>your petitioner was guilty if any was nothing more than loud hurras and outcries in said town without uttering anything insulting indecent or hurtful to the feelings of any one. He states that he is a poor man and works industriously for the support of himself and family. That he works at his trade, being a painter, when he can get work which at the present time in the present depressed condition of business and the tightness of money matters but seldom and when he can not find work at this trade he seeks any other employment that is honest. He states that it will be very difficult ^<hi rend="str">for him</hi>^ <hi rend="str">to</hi> if not impossible for him to raise the money to pay said fine as it takes about all he can make with hard labor to support himself and family. He states that he is not habitually a drinking man and his drunkenness on the occasion refered to was accidental </p>
<p>He prays your Excellency to remit and release him from the payment of s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> fine of $5.</p>
<p>C. P. Springer<pb/></p>
<p>Sworn to before me by C P Springer this <date when="1862-04-18">18th day of April 1862</date></p>
<p>Chr Chinn PJ M C C</p>
<p>The undersigned being acquanted with the petitioner C. Peter Springer know him to be a hard working industrious and honest but a poor man and believing that h<hi rend="str">e</hi>is case is one deserving the executive clemency. respectfully unite with him in the prayer of his petition for a remission of the fine of five dollars imposed on him by the Police Court of Harrodsburg</p>
<p>Chr Chinn
<lb/>John, C, Chinn
<lb/>Nimrod Harris
<lb/>S. S. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Fatridge
<lb/>Ben C. Allin 
<lb/>J. B. Renfro
<lb/>S M Brayer 
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Tho</hi> <hi rend="underline">Allin</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Remitted 
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Harrodsburg Po. Ct
<lb/>$5. } Mis
<lb/>C. P. Springer
<lb/>Iss <date when="1862-05-04">May 4. 1862</date><pb/></p>
<p>Peter Springer
<lb/>To } Petition
<lb/>The Governor </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
