<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2437"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Burton, Sr. et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7074</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-386</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-09-26">26 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E Bramlett Go<hi rend="underline">v</hi> of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, Your Petitioners John Burton Sr, John Burton Jr, Jesse Burton and Jesse Stephens would Respectfully Represent that at the <date when="1859-11">November Term 1859</date>. of the Morgan Circuit Court that there was a fine imposed by said Court at the aforesaid Term against each of Your Petitioners for $50<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> each, upon which Judgments there issued Executions and the same was Replevied about the breaking out of the Southern Rebellion and now there has issued Executions on said Replevin Bonds which is now in the hands of the sheriff of Morgan County who is about to sell the Property of your Petitioners, Your Petitioners would further State that in consequence of the war that, they have been almost reduced to Poverty, and owing to their Present conditions that they are actually unable to pay said fine. Wherefore they humbly ask your Excellency to remit said fines and that all officers be enjoined from the collection of the same and they will forever Pray</p>
<p>John Burton sr
<lb/>John Burton jr
<lb/>Jesse Burton
<lb/>Jesse Stephens</p>
<p>We the undersigned Join in Prayer with the above named Petitioners and ask that the fines against<pb/>
<lb/>Petitioners be remitted and held for naught, That said Petitioners are Very Poor and actually unable to Pay said fines &amp; they have Very large families who are dependent on your Petitioners for a support and said Petitioners has everly been loyal to the Constitution &amp; Government of the United States</p>
<p>Respectfully yours
<lb/><date when="1865-09-26">Sept 26<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Stev Stephens C S
<lb/>moses scaggs
<lb/>B Williams
<lb/>A. F. Fraley
<lb/>Alvin Sturgeon
<lb/>Isaac S. Sturgeon
<lb/>John L. Hanna
<lb/>A C Fraley
<lb/>James Fraley
<lb/>J, K, Howard
<lb/>Isom Waggener
<lb/>Ira Isaac Jr
<lb/>C. W. Carter
<lb/>S. G. Hunter
<lb/>Charles Adkins
<lb/>S D Stanton
<lb/>Miles Whitt
<lb/>John Coling C S
<lb/>John Stephens
<lb/>James my horn
<lb/>Wiiliam binion</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
