<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1196"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. F. Evans to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10664</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-31</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Glasgow, Barren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-06">6 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Glasgow <date when="1861-06-06">June 6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Dear Governor.</p>
<p>Doct Wheat of this county and against whom a judgment has been rendered at the present term of our Equity &amp; Criminal Court for $200 upon a forfeited recognizance as the bail of James White, Sends herewith to you a petition asking a remission of all of said Judgment, so far as you can act. I defended young White before the Court of Inquiry, he was sent on to further trial, the proof being positive, I never knew the young man before, I became fully satisfied that he was one of that unfortunate class who are constititionaly pilferers, he seemed to be perfectly careless about the arrest &amp; trial, indeed after he stole the shawl in this place, and before he was arrested, he stole several small and indeed to him perfectly valueless articles from another person, which when demanded he gave up quite cheerfully, more like a child than a grown person, said "he took them for fun he reconed"</p>
<p>Doct Wheat through kindess and unsolicited by any one hearing of the case came to town and bailed him out of jail, from the fact as he told me, that the Father of the Young man had been his friend, and he knew James when he was but a child, Doct Wheat is a kind hearted gentleman and a very clever man.<pb/>
<lb/>Doct White I once knew, he was then and I hear now is a perfect gentleman, I understand he is poor and greatly afflicted at the conduct of his unfortunate son.</p>
<p>As I am satisfied that the young man ought not to be punished, you will I think do a good act to grant the prayer of Doct Wheat in his petition.</p>
<p>From letters which I have received from Danville and else where stating the character of James White, I am satisfied, could the witness have been got here, who knew all about his <hi rend="str">chara</hi> condition of mind on this particular subject, he could have been acquited, but this would have cost his Father much more than the bail. I hope you will find it consistent with your feelings of right to remit all of said Judgment except cost and the part going to the Comth., atty. which can be easily settled should you remit the ballance as Mr. James knows all about the condition of the young man.</p>
<p>your friend
<lb/>W. F. Evans</p>
<p>P. S. please ^see^ statements of Mr. James the Comths, Atty in this district, made on petition of Doct. Wheat.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
