<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1565"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Sarah A. Tomlinson, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11033</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-191 to MG22-192</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Scott County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-12-17">17 December 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Sarah Ann Tomlinson thinks it right and proper that she should state all the facts and circumstances connected with the affair which resulted in the conviction of C H Tomlinson her husband to the penetentiary for the killing of Thomas H Estes her Brother affiants Brothers wife was a witness against her husband, and she thinks her statement entitled to as much weight in his favor as the other against him</p>
<p>a fact well Known to all our family that my Brother and husband was Kind friends to each other, but that Tom contrary to charles Knowledge had conceived an enmity to him uncle W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Hockersmith told him several times in the presance of affiant, but Charles would not believe Tom could an enemy Uncle Will told him Tom was sure to hurt him, that he would not believe him, but he would find it out and when he did it would be to his sorrow the time the unfortunate affair took place Uncle Will came and promised to stand up to him But our numerous relations caused such an excitement, by their false reports, that he got frightened off and turned against him </p>
<p>About a year before that time Brother George fell a tree without intending it on a<pb/>
<lb/>Dog belonging to Brother Tom, He swore vengeance against who ever done it if he ever found them out although they Knew Tom judged Charles with it they kept it a secret from him to the Day of his death and he never knew who did do it But from the fact that my younger sister told us how it was done it would not have been known outside of my mothers family after my Brothers death we discovered that some lieing mischief maker had told Tom that it was Charles who hurt the dog And it is evident that my Brothers and Toms wife Know wh that infamous and atrocious character is who told that mischeiveous lie, one thing is Known, is that he had been told it was Charles who hurt the dog and believe the at the moment know who it was that told It was that circumstance evidently that caused my Brothers death Brother Tom was a hasty and violent man and his Brothers all feared him, as their course in relations to that dog prove and we have reason to believe they did not grieve on account of his death A regard for truth demands that I should State a fact Known to all our family, that Tom was a man that would do a private injury through revenge He held a grudge against his Brother in law<pb/>
<lb/>when he had his things packed up ready to remove to missouri Tom cut his beds bed cloths, and his own sisters dresses in holes and this fact is well Known to all the family I have had several conversations with my mother since Toms death who believes that Charles was justifiable in what he done but was afraid to express her feelings, and from her weakness suffered her self to be carried away by the croud</p>
<p>Sanford Tomlinson was a particular friend to Tom He was a witness in his behalf and testified to his good character in a slander case in the Franklin circuit court for which Sanford Tomlinson allways showed himself a particular friend to Tom Sanford Tomlinson being the only witness Charles had my Brothers summoned numerous witnesses to attack his character Knowing that Tom has testified on oath to his good character, and that he invariably spoke of him in the highest terms and the only person in the neighborhood that Tom spoke well of, and also the attempt to assail his character was promted by his enemies who were defeated in the slander case It is plain they were attacking the character of their deceased Brother<pb/></p>
<p>It is well known to my Brothers and my mothers family that Tom intended thrashing Samuel Wright They cannot fail to believe that he got drunk for the purpose of attacking Wright, and Sanford and Charles urging to Start home was from the purest friendship and which must have saved Toms life for the time being my mother and sister told me that they heard them pass their house in friendly chat but a few moments before the pistol was heard M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Wright told me that Sanford and Charles prevented Tom from attacking him, and that if he had he would have shot him. There was great sympathy for my Brothers wife It is known to my mother and family that Tom and his wife life live very disagreeable together that Tom intended separating from her They had not spoke for six weeks before his death</p>
<p>Sarah A. Tomlinson</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed before my by Sarah A. Tomlinson this <date when="1861-12-17">17<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Dec 1861</date></p>
<p>J. E. Alsop. J. P. S. C.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
