<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0106"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. L. Tinsley, H.C. Ellis, and Newton Bright to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4225</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-157 to BR8-158</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Eminence, Henry County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864--">1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Eminence Henry County Ky. 9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> <date when="1864">1864</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency, Thomas E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Ky</p>
<p>Your Excellency will find by refering to the proper record that the Legislature of Ky. at its Last session passes an act entitled, "An Act for the benefit of R L Tinsley &amp; others," The reasons for the passage of that act were substantially the following. In the spring of <date when="1863">1863</date>, the undersigned had stolen from them five head of valuable horses. The thieves were pursued with all possible dispatch &amp; vigilence across the Ohio river through the state of Indiana &amp; Illinois &amp; across the Mississippi river into the state of Missouri, without capturing any of the stolen property, &amp; expending in the fruitless search over two hundred dollars ($200).</p>
<p>George Myres, a citizen of Indiana &amp; a horse thief by profession, was arrested and brought to trial upon the charge of being accessory to the theft. By due process of law he was placed under bonds of ($750) to apear and answer at the ensuing term of the Henry County Circuit Court. C M Mathews becoming<pb/>
<lb/>his security on the bond. The undersigned believing that Myres would never ap^p^ear for trial &amp; that the penitentiary would be defrauded of its just dues &amp; knowing that Mathews was or thought he was secure <hi rend="str">in</hi> against loss in case Myres should forfeit his bond, asked &amp; obtained the passage of the above mentioned act, by which your Excellency will see is appropriated ^to them^ $500) of the forfeited bond when collected and paid into the state Treasury.</p>
<p>The undersigned would beg leave to further bring to your notice the fact that Mathews <hi rend="str">made known</hi> ^admitted^ to more than one of them that Myres had made to him a deed to his farm in Indiana, &amp; that he had secured from him two horses, and it is believed money besides, leaving no doubt on our minds that he was made <hi rend="str">good</hi> ^secure^ in signing the bond. The fact is well known and can be substanciated that his friends in Indiana raised a considerable sum of money for the purpose ^as is supposed^ of obtaining his release. The undersigned would also represent that they believe Mathews abundantly able to pay the amount of the bond, and in as much as we, who have ^lost^ our property our time and our money &amp; have at<pb/>
<lb/>all times held our selves in readings &amp; have <hi rend="str">furnished to</hi> aided the Commonwealth in every way in our power to bring to justice a common enemy. Would respectfully ask that you ^do^ not remit the bond, &amp; that you remove all hindrance to the execution of the Judgement of Court.</p>
<p>R. L. Tinsley
<lb/>H. C. Ellis
<lb/>Newton Bright</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
