<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2593"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Robert L. Douthat and Angelin Douthat to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7230</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-144 to BR16-145</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Franklin, Simpson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-24">24 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Franklin Simpson County Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-10-24">24<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> October 1865</date>.
<lb/>To Governor Thom<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E Bramlette</p>
<p>The petition of the Subscribers, Robert L Douthet and his wife Angeline Douthet late Finn, respectfully represent that they are under Indictment in the Simpson Circuit Court. The Said Angeline in the name of Angeline Finn for Polygamy and the Said Robt L Douthet as accessary thereto the indictment being joint. They State that Said Angeline was formerly the wife of Meshack Finn That She &amp; her Said husband Seperated, and during the Seperation, Something more than five years thereafter, but before She was divorced She and Said Douthet intermarried. Said intermarriage Causing Said indictment. That their intermarriage was in good faith, That they were ignorent of Law and did not know that they were violating the law -- That Since their marriage aforesaid, the Said Angeline has obtained a divorce from her former husband, and Since the obtaining of Said divorce, they have re-married and are living to-gether as husband &amp; wife, they trust honorably &amp; reputably</p>
<p>They prey a pardon, in advance of a trial -- They are Satisfied this Community desires neither their trial or Conviction -- The Community have no interest in the prosecution, and the prosecution would be attended with a publicity mortefying to the parties, and regretted by the Community.</p>
<p>R L Douthat
<lb/>Angelin Douthat<pb/></p>
<p>Franklin Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-10-24">Octo 24<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>.
<lb/>To his Excellency, Gov. Bramlette,</p>
<p>The undersigned respectfully call your attention to the within petition of Rob<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> L Douthet and his wife Angeline, and hope you will at an Early day release them from further trouble in this matter -- we are confident that by Complying with their request you will Serve the wishes of this Community.</p>
<p>Respectfully.
<lb/>Geo H Millikin Clerk of Simpson County Court
<lb/>Saml N Forline Clerk Simpson Circuit Court
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Kidd Judge of the Simpson County Court<pb/></p>
<p>Simpson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Robt L Douthat &amp; Angeline Finn
<lb/>Polygamy
<lb/>Pardoned <date when="1865-12-02">2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> Dec/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
