<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0824"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. McKee Fox to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10292</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-295 to MG19-296</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-03-28">28 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency. B. Magoffin, Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, Your petitioner, would represent, that at the present <date when="1861-03">March Term 1861.</date> of the Pulaski Circuit Court, there was a Judgment obtained against James Clark, for an alleged breach of his bond as Tavern Keeper in said county and W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Love, James Vanhook and W. R. Smith his surities in the bond, for the sum of $300, in favor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky --.They represent to your Excellency that there are persons in ordinary circumstances in life, and to remit said Judgment would be nothing but an act of Justice, as well as one of great kindness -- <hi rend="str">And</hi> That the bond on which said Judgment was rendered is not such a bond as is required by the statute; that W<hi rend="sup">m</hi>. Love and James Vanhook, the most responsible persons on said bond were by reason of sickness prevented from attending to the trial of said case; That James Clark and W. R. Smith ^are^ now insolvent -- They (Love <hi rend="str">&amp; Smith</hi> &amp; Vanhook) could have successfully defended said suit if they had been able to have reached the court -- (over)<pb/>
<lb/>They ask, that your Excellency would remit all that portion of the fine which is going to the Commonwealth_<date when="1861-03-28">March 28.<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">W. M</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi><hi rend="underline">Kee Fox</hi></p>
<p>I am satisfied that the securities ought to be released from the judgment, it was agreed that your excellency should be appealed to rather than take up the time of the court in an application for a <hi rend="str">continuance</hi> new trial -- as the court was about to adjourn -- It is certainly a hard case upon the securities &amp; they were to some extent imposed upon by the material witnesses from what I learn</p>
<p>E L VanWinkle
<lb/>atto comth</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>David Lee
<lb/>Robert Cherry
<lb/>J P Nunnelly</p>
<p>I Join in the prayer of the above petition</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Sherrod Williams</hi>
<lb/>J E Casson
<lb/>Frank,, J,, White,
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J. W. Sallee
<lb/><hi rend="underline">John G. Lair</hi>
<lb/>W B Moore
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Bourne,, Goggin</hi>
<lb/>Dunn Boyle
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="underline">. F.</hi> <hi rend="underline">Goggin</hi>
<lb/>John. Crawford
<lb/>F. F. Stigall
<lb/>C B. Bacheller
<lb/>L Colyer<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>I believe that the remission of the fine by the Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> would be right -- The case is meritorious</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>Judge Pulaski Circuit</p>
<p>I Know the securities, Vanhook and <hi rend="str">Smith</hi> Love, they are good citizens in moderate circumstances, both have families -- and owing to the hard times the fine if collected will be oppressive -- I join in the prayer for remission</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">A. J.</hi> <hi rend="underline">James</hi></p>
<p>We William Love &amp; James Vanhook make oath before the undersigned that the statements in this petition are true <date when="1861-03-28">March 28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>J. E.. Casson J. P.<pb/></p>
<p>
<lb/>Pulaski Cir. Ct
<lb/>$300. } Fortd Bond
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Love &amp; Others
<lb/>Iss <date when="1861-04-01">Aprl 1<hi rend="str">1</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>Respite 6 mo
<lb/>B. M</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
