<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-023-0080"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, An act to amend an act entitled "An act to amend article three, chapter Eight-six Revised Statutes"</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG2993</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG1-288 to MG1-289</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-09-30">30 September 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Proclamation/Legislation</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>An act to amend an act entitled "An act to amend article three, Chapter Eighty-six Revised Statutes" approved <date when="1861-09-30">September 30 1861</date> -- </p>
<p><hi rend="str">Sec</hi> Be it enacted by the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Sec 1 -- That in all cases wherein a judgment or decree has been rendered for the sale of the real estate of an infant or infants upon the petition of the guardian of such infant on infants, and a sale has been made under such judgment ar decree, and it shall appear that there are errors or defects in the proceedings in which the judgment or decree was obtained, it shall be lawful for any purchaser of the estate under such judgment or decree, to file his petition in the Court which rendered such judgment or decree, making all persons interested parties, &amp; upon all such persons having been brought before the Court by actual or constructive service, and the Courts being satisfied that the sale was fairly made, that all the infants have come to full age, that the sale has been confirmed, &amp; the purchase money paid<pb/>
<lb/>by the purchaser &amp; been withdrawn by the infant or infants, their guardian or agent, it shall render a decree confirming the original judgment or decree and sale which shall render the same as valid and binding in all respects, as if the original proceedings had been in every respect according to the requirements of the law</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Sect II</note> This act shall take effect &amp; be in force from its passage &amp; shall apply to proceedings ^had^ before or after its passage<pb/></p>
<p>An Act to Amend an Act entitled "an Act to amend article 3 Chap. 86, Revised Statutes" Approved <date when="1861-09-30">Sept. 30. 1861</date><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><unclear/> at <unclear/> &amp; <unclear/>
<lb/>(<unclear/> bills)</p>
<p>Beriah Magoffin</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
