<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2538"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">T. J. Edwards et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7175</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-58 to BR16-59</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Metcalfe County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Metcalfe County State of Kentucky
<lb/>To his Excellency the Gov of Kentucky.</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Metcalfe County would most respectfully represent unto your Excellency that some time in the year <date when="1863">1863</date> Joseph T Whitlow then a citizen of said county assaulted one Willis Wood of said County &amp; a commonwealths warrant was sued out against said Whitlow &amp; he was arrested and tried by a Jury before C C Harvey a Justice of the peace for said county &amp; fined the sum of fifteen dollars ^&amp; 75 cts^ -- that afterwards the said Whitlow was indicted for the same offense &amp; afterwards was arrested on a <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>Bench Warrant and gave Bond in the sum of one hundred dollars for his ^appearance^ at the regular <date when="1864-06">June term 1864</date> of the Metcalfe circuit Court, the Judge of said court, in the mean time, however, ordered &amp; called a court to commence in <date when="1864-05">May 1864</date> &amp; only one week prior to the said <date when="--06">June</date> term of said court for the trial of Equity &amp; criminal causes &amp; said called term of said Court was held -- that the said case of the Commonwealth v Whitlow for assault upon said Wood in his absence &amp; without his Knowledge was called for trial ^at said called term of said Court^ &amp; his said Bond was forfeited &amp; the case was tried &amp; the Jury returned a verdict of fifty dollars v said Whitlow; that afterwards, the records of the Metcalfe Circuit Court were destroyed by fire &amp; a Judgment having been previously rendered, upon summons executed, against said<pb/> 
<lb/>Whitlow for the sum of one hundred dollars, the amount of said Bond, a notice was given him to reenter said Judgment for $100 -- &amp; at the <date when="1865-06">June term 1865</date> of said Court said Judgment was reeentered as appears by a copy of the record herewith filed &amp; refered to -- They state that said Whitlow has a wife &amp; children &amp; is in moderate circumstances. They do not believe that the ends of Justice require that said Whitlow should be subjected to such illegal &amp; unnecessary punishment They further represent that they are advised that your Excellency upon proper application has remitted so much of said fifty dollars fine as your Excellency had power to remit &amp; as the Justice of this application to the Clemency of your Excellency has equal merit to recommend it they pray your Excellency to remit so much of said one hundred dollars ^Judgment^ <hi rend="str">fine</hi> as to your Excelllency may seem right under the extraordinary circumstances of the case &amp; as in duty bound will ever pray -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>T J Edwards
<lb/>C A Edwards
<lb/>L, R Harbison
<lb/>J M. Birch
<lb/>W. R. Robson
<lb/>J W Reynolds
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/>J. B. Page -- 
<lb/>M. L. Williams
<lb/>D. C. Williams
<lb/>J, W, Strode
<lb/>Nathaniel Smith
<lb/>Thomas Wilson
<lb/>R. T. Norman
<lb/>W. W. Wright<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Barnett. H. Harvey
<lb/>James Rush
<lb/>P. S. Rush
<lb/>John Runyon
<lb/>Granville Whitlow
<lb/>Matthew, Wade
<lb/>James Word
<lb/>James Page
<lb/>Marion Franklin
<lb/><hi rend="underline">T. H. Hord</hi>
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Smith Page
<lb/>Fendell hagen
<lb/>J J Pitcock
<lb/>Fendell r <unclear/>
<lb/>F,, L,, Varman
<lb/>James. Sympson
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> alvis
<lb/>A C, Hale
<lb/>Ruben Wilson
<lb/>Jesse Gee
<lb/>Grant Halloway
<lb/>John S Gee
<lb/>William Bartley
<lb/>James Bartley
<lb/>James Tudor
<lb/>G W Harlan
<lb/>John R Duncan
<lb/>Wood Tudor
<lb/>John, U, Young
<lb/>John Evans
<lb/>William Babbitt
<lb/>L. W, Gee
<lb/>John. W. Wile
<lb/>E K Hurt
<lb/>A. T. Harbison
<lb/>James Ballard
<lb/>John W Pedigo
<lb/>Isham Hurt
<lb/>Joshua Harbison
<lb/>N. W Tudor</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
