<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0346"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. B. Tharp to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8798</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-58 to R4-59</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-05-30">30 May 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Frankfort Ky <date when="1863-05-30">May 30<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1863</date>.
<lb/>To His Excellency J. F. Robinson
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>I have today been informed by Maj. Luckett that you wished in writing the Substance of the statements made by Rev. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Stevenson and myself at our interview with you about the <date when="--03-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> of March</date> last in regard to Philips, a convict in the Ky Penitentiary. I therefore with much pleasure communicate ^to^ you in writing, Substantially what I said on that occasion, viz. That I have been acquainted with said Philips four or five years, This acquaintance was formed by my being thrown among the convicts in a business and ministerial <hi rend="str">character</hi> capacity, During this acquaintance I have found him a man of good deportment in every respect. A feeling of sympathy having been thus awak^en^ed in my mind in his behalf, I was led to inquire into his history. I learned from the officers of the Prison, that his conduct Since he had been there, had been unexceptionable. I learned too that his character prior to this offence had been good. In my personal interviews with the Prisoner he frankly confessed the crime, and the justice of his sentence. His only ground of hope was that in your clemency as the Executive of the laws of the Commonwealth, your Honor would adjudge that he had paid the penalty of violated law. And could<pb/>
<lb/>therefore be restored to the freedom and to honorable standing. From what I know of the matter I draw<hi rend="str">n</hi> the following conclusions. viz</p>
<p>First. That beyond a doubt Philips was guilty of the offence charged against him. But</p>
<p>Second. That it was his first offence, he in a State of intoxication, being made the root of experienced villains, while they escaped the punishment due to their crimes.</p>
<p>Third. That his previous character being good, <hi rend="str">and</hi> his conduct Since his imprisonment, <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>having been commendable, and his having already for Several years Suffered the penalty of his offence, the majesty of the law has been vindicated, the ends of public justice fully met, and the life of the prisoner reformed, And that where these ends have been attained mercy should come to his relief.</p>
<p>Fourth. That the Prisoner having a refined and pious wife, who seems devoted to him even in his degradation, it would be an act of humanity, and a source of inexpressible joy to her if he could be restored to his family.</p>
<p>With great respect
<lb/>Your obd<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Servant
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J. B. Tharp</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
