<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0193"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Mix, Jr. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9661</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-139 to MG17-140</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-11-27">27 November 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville <date when="1860-11-27">Nov. 27<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1860</date>,
<lb/>Hon. B. Magoffin.
<lb/>Dear Sir.</p>
<p>The prosecuting witness &amp; her husband resided near my fathers farm Since five years ago, and I have knew their character since that time.</p>
<p>They are mischevious, quarrelsome, and thieving persons. The husband will steal, and I have known of several persons being shot ^&amp; shot at^ by him I was his Atty for some months but refusing to lend myself to his purposes of malice and vengence I lost his patronage I have not see Brookman in the act of stealing, but I knew as well as one can knew<pb/>
<lb/>without seeing him in an overt act that he will steal, as a gentlmen of wealth &amp; truth living adjoining my fathers farm &amp;c across the public road from Brookman has informed ^me^ that he repeatedly caught him stealing his fruit &amp; his neighbors have ^since name other occasions^</p>
<p>I could not proove that either Brookman or his wife were unworthy of credit on oath, as the desperate nature of their revenge, sparing neither age, sex, or condition have made them a terror to all who are brought near them. or in contact with them. made such persons as knew them afraid to testify.</p>
<p>Individually, I would not believe either Brookman or his wife on oath, if they could injure a human being by<pb/>
<lb/>swaering to a lie, they are unscrupulous</p>
<p>I acted as Attorney for Reel &amp; Beck in the case in which they are asking your clemency I unite with them in their prayer, as worthy &amp; industrious citizens.</p>
<p>I finally believe that there prosecution was unfounded &amp; malicious</p>
<p>Yours truly
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Mix Jr.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
