<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1891"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">David L. Scott to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6528</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-467</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-05-24">24 May 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>I am the father of Morton Scott, who stands now indicted in the Jessamine circuit Court for stealing mules. I do not believe he is guilty of the offense charged. He was intemperate at one time and if any suspicion of wrong attach to him ^<unclear/>^ it grows out of conduct when not sober. He is now reformed &amp; recently married. and has on a small farm gone to work in Indiana. I sincerely trust your Excellency will pardon him, as I believe a demand for him and his return to Ky. for trial would prove extremely unfortunate for him, so far as his habits of temperance are concerned.</p>
<p>David L Scott</p>
<p><date when="1865-05-24">24 May 1865</date></p>
<p>We heartily concur in the petition of David L. Scott, who is a highly respectable gentleman of Garrard County and believe good will be done by the pardon asked for his son. I have <date when="1865-05-24">24 May 1865</date> heard a full statement of the case at a time before this, and believe his is not guilty of the offense charged</p>
<p>W N Fishback<pb/></p>
<p>I took a deep interest in the case of Morton Scott &amp; examined the same carefully &amp; from that examination I believe he was not guilty</p>
<p><date when="1865-05-24">24 May 1865</date></p>
<p>W N Fishback</p>
<p>Petition of persons in matter of Morton Scott -- </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
