<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0300"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. G. Owen to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8752</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-442 to R3-443</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hartford, McLean County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-03-30">30 March 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Hartford <date when="1863-03-30">March 30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>Govenor Thomas E Bramlett
<lb/>Frankfort Ky
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>At the March Term just past, of the M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Lean Circuit Court Thomas B. Lawton was convicted and sentenced to the penitentiary, for the Crime of robbery.</p>
<p>I was employed to assist in his prosecution and did so. And although I am convinced that in point of Law his conviction was just, there are circumstances connected with the commission of the crime for which he was convicted which appeal to sympathy -- and which prompt me to write you briefly in his behalf.</p>
<p>Lawton is but a youth of respectable parentage and connections, and like thousands of others of the young men of Ky. was in the Summer of <date when="1862">1862</date> deluded into the service of the Confederate States He remained in the Service however, only, a month or two when he voluntarily surrendered himself a prisoner, and took the oath of allegiance to the U. S. and gave bond for his good behavior, And has ever since, in good faith kept his pledge or oath</p>
<p>While in the Confederate Service he took, the horse -- for the taking of which he has been convicted of robbery -- under an order from his Captain -- </p>
<p>Whilst these circumstances show, Lawton a rebel and traitor --, they yet relieve his conduct of that<pb/>
<lb/>sort of criminal and <hi rend="str">fellonious</hi> felonious intent which is the gist of all crimes. I allude to the particular fact for which he was convicted.</p>
<p>I have no tolerance of rebellion and treason in any shape. Nor can I perceive that in the commission of those grave offenses there is any legal justification, of the lesser offences which may be committed <hi rend="underline">by</hi> <hi rend="underline">the way</hi>, or in the purpose certain of the leading design</p>
<p>Yet in view of the youth of Lawton the excited state of the country -- The many artifices used by the older and more designing to delude the more youthful and unsuspecting, the former good character of Lawton your Excellency, I doubt not will be moved to consider the application which will be made to you for his pardon with favor</p>
<p>I trust Sir you will excuse me for attending this letter upon you</p>
<p>And believe me Ever
<lb/>Your Most Obedient Servant
<lb/>W. G. Owen<pb/></p>
<p>McLean Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Thos B. Lawton</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
