<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-009-0003"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Unknown to Thomas E. Bramlette
</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1158</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR1-7 to BR1-8</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Decatur, Macon County, Illinois</placeName>
    <date when="1863-09-28">28 September 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Decatur Ills. <date when="1863-09-28">Sept. 28<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1863</date>.
<lb/>Dear Cousin.</p>
<p>Your more then kind letter reached me, remailed at Mattoon to the above mentioned city where I am spending a few weeks at a brother<hi rend="str">e</hi>s<hi rend="str">s</hi>-in-law, and attending the State Fair, of which I send you the Directory.</p>
<p>Your picture is very natural and lifelike, the ladies wanted to know what fine looking officer that is on the table? I tell ^them^ unfortunatley you are married, and they need not make the inquiry. Titles and honors do not change your old propensity for teasing I perceive from the mirthful tone of your letter.</p>
<p>"<hi rend="underline">You</hi> <hi rend="underline">must</hi> <hi rend="underline">marry</hi> and <hi rend="underline">want</hi> to <hi rend="underline">marry</hi> <unclear/>." The simple fact of my being a widow precludes the necesity of my denying what <hi rend="underline">you</hi> have so<pb/>
<lb/>unjustly affirmed as well as a cruel and heedless world, but enough on this score, suffice it that if I had hold of your ear I should treat you as you would treat the French and English, that "<hi rend="underline">how</hi> <hi rend="underline">to</hi> <hi rend="underline">repect</hi> <hi rend="underline">my</hi> <hi rend="underline">rights</hi>. Is your eye as penetrable that you can see through the mist of years and discern the exact extent to which a person is liable to change? and surely you must think I have changed my notions vastly since we met.</p>
<p>I could not return thanks sufficient for your kind and cordial invitation to spend the winter <hi rend="str">at</hi> <hi rend="str">your</hi> <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> at your house, there being such "ample room in the Gov. Mansion", and I have taken it into concideration. Nothing would give me more pleasure, and I might possibly give up my school-teaching this winter, replenish my wardrobe and set out for the pleasures and amusements of a season in your city with <hi rend="underline">this</hi> <hi rend="underline">promise</hi>, that you will come out here <hi rend="underline">first</hi> and then I could return with you. I am very timid these war-times, and should be af<hi rend="str">frai</hi>eared on your side of the Ohio that some great Lion with Epulttes would get hold of me and send me on to Dixie<pb/>
<lb/>You say, come, <hi rend="underline">do</hi> come -- what say you, and suppose you try it, so you can first concider the same reversed if you please. I would like to see you all and if cousin Sallie and all of them desire it, and I had some body to keep the Lions and Tigers off of me I would be <hi rend="underline">more</hi> <hi rend="underline">than</hi> <hi rend="underline">delighted</hi> to suit you all, this coming season. I remember M P. Buster if he is the one that took me to Burkville and also cousin John Van Wincle, your present secretary of state. Will you please write again. My love to all.</p>
<p>As ever affectionally,
<lb/>Your cousin
<lb/>Villie</p>
<p>P.S. I infer that you were at the Inaugural hop. Take care sir, ^or^ you will in the absence of your wife and your more sober connections like myself <hi rend="str">and</hi> loose your equilibrium and find your arm reaching round some pretty womans waist, joining in the giddy mazes of the dance.</p>
<p>Your Inaugural has not reached me yet. When it does I will find out what the <hi rend="underline">Copperhead</hi> think of it</p>
<p>L V M. </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
