<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0082"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">T. A. Butler et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9550</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17A-161</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hopkins County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Hopkins County who have heretofore Known Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> B. Wadlington who has been convicted by a jury of the country in the county of Caldwell of the crime of murder would represent to your excellency that we have Known the unfortunate man long and that his character as a gentleman a true hearted and loyal citizen of the commonwealth of Kentucky had never been questioned</p>
<p>It is true that we Know nothing of the circumstances of his case but we feel that we do not depart from the duty that we owe to humanity and to the previous character of the accused as a man of peace, industry and Sobriety to ask your honor to review his case and to exercise the powers that are confered upon you to Suspend or modify the rules of Strict law and to either extend to the accused a full pardon or a commutation of his punishment as justice tempered with mercy in your opinion may require</p>
<p>Yours Respectfully
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>T, A, Butler
<lb/>Pendleton Sisk
<lb/>John W Goodloe
<lb/>W W Cardwell
<lb/>S,, H, Harvey
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> R Cardwell
<lb/><cb n="2"/>R W Sisk
<lb/>J J Outlaw
<lb/>G W Slater
<lb/>B R Wright
<lb/>T. Q. Almon
<lb/>Joseph Robertson
<lb/>John J Hardwick<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>George Klein
<lb/>J. L. Robertson
<lb/>J M Todd
<lb/>A M Hentell
<lb/>Absalom Robertson
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Slaton</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
