<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0003-092-0112"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George W. Johnson to Anne E. V. Johnson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14404</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>George W. Johnson Papers</collection>
      <idno>Folder 4</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Richmond, Henrico County, Virginia</placeName>
    <date when="1861-07-15">15 July 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Richmond V<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">a</hi></hi>
<lb/><date when="1861-07-15">July 15. 1861</date>.
<lb/>My Dear Ann</p>
<p>Since I arrived here I have been engaged in some business, connected with our interests in Kentucky. There is a complete "circumlocution office" in this place and you may wait a whole day for an interview. Indeed it was not like today, that I had hopes of accomplishing what I came here for: I now believe I will succeed and <hi rend="str">if</hi> ^so^ it will be of very great value to our Party and I will wait a few days longer, although I regret very much not being able to return with Matty. Your anxiety<pb/>
<lb/>will be released when you see him, and on that account I will feel more satisfied. I hope I ^have^ done something also, to set on foot a project for peace.</p>
<p>It may be that I may visit, the camps at Manassas and York River and Bethel with some friends. Hon I. W. Stevenson is here &amp; is very anxious for me to go with him tomorrow but I have declined, hoping that I may get through my business by remaining &amp; watching it. If I go on both camps, there will be no more danger than in riding to Georgetown &amp; I hope you will not be uneasy.</p>
<p>The enthusiasm manifesting every where in Virginia is very cheering &amp; I have not the slightest doubt of our ultimate success.</p>
<p>No news here is accessible to the public which, is not found in all your papers. What is said today, being generally contradicted tomorrow. Every thing Exaggerated, distorted misrepresented &amp;c. &amp;c. according to the feelings and caprice of the writers.</p>
<p>There has been no night, since I left home in which you &amp; the the Children, have not been the last thing I thought of before sleep. May a Good God bless you.</p>
<p>Yours, Affectionally
<lb/>George W. Johnson<pb/></p>
<p>P. S.
<lb/>I will probably start home, in 4 or 5 days after tomorrow. -- G. W. J.<pb/></p>
<p>M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> Ann E Johnson</p>
<p>By Matty</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
