<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2589"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">P. H. Leslie to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7226</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-147 to BR16-148</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Glasgow, Barren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-09">9 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Glasgow Ky <date when="1865-10-09">Oct 9 1865</date>
<lb/>Gov. Th<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi> E. Bramlette</p>
<p>My Nephew J B McMillin a youth from 22 to 24 years old (now) went into the Rebel Armies, was Regularly in from early in 1862 to the close of the War. The last 15 months of the time he was a Prisoner at Johnsons Island (being a Lieut) He was regularly discharged after the Surrender of Johnson &amp; took the amnesty oath, came home and did fully &amp; in good faith has been demeaning himself correctly.</p>
<p>But he is now ordered to be arrested under charge of having robd the U S Mail. has not been arrested. but that charge hangs against him.</p>
<p>The facts about the Mail robery are these A year or two before he was captured He was in the of edge of Kentucky in Comm-<pb/>
<lb/>and of a Squad of Soldiers by directions of his Col. with orders to Capture the U S Mail, if he could &amp; to do other service. And he did come up with the Mail Carier near Center Point in Monroe County &amp; took it Opened it &amp; examined it.</p>
<p>All this he did regarding it as a legitimate capture. More particularly as it was a part of the duty assigned &amp; directed by his Commanding Officer Col Hughes.</p>
<p>Now I have never figured much any way in these unfortunate difficulties. but I know this Boy to be a true man And a gentleman. never was a gurilla and I desire very much to have him relieved</p>
<p>Will you do me the favor if you can consistent with your feelings? to write a note for my use with the President upon application for a Pardon.</p>
<p>You know me and have my assurances of the truth of what I have written &amp; I think I hazzard nothing in<pb/>
<lb/>promising that he will be a good citizen &amp; faithful</p>
<p>I feel deeply &amp; anxiously for this relative youth and I feel that you can enable me to procure his Pardon Hope you may deem it not improper to interpose.</p>
<p>Yours Truly
<lb/>P H Leslie</p>
<p>Please advise me at your earliest Convenience</p>
<p>L<pb/></p>
<p>Letter of Leslie</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
