<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0139"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Henry Connally to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9607</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-57 to MG17-58</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency 
<lb/>The Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Henry Conley will respectfully represent that one Willim Frooks was arrested &amp; held to Bail in the city court of Louisville to Answer an Indictment on a charge of Assault &amp; Battery.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner became bail for the appearance of said Frooks who is an Ignorant young man &amp; when the case was called for Trial said Frooks altho about the courthouse at the time &amp; waiting to answer the Indictment, when called did not Answer &amp; failed to have his appearance entered -- and the Atto for the city had a Default entered &amp; sued out a Scifa against said Frooks &amp; your Petitioner and at the <date when="1860-09">September Term 1860</date>. a Judgement was rendered against your Petitioner he alone being served with process for the sum of One Hundred Dollars and the costs amounting to Twelve Dolls 95 cents Exclusive of the city attor Thirty per cent of the fine. The whole costs amounting to $42:95.<hi rend="sup">ct</hi> which Petitioner will be bound to pay.<pb/></p>
<p>Your Petitioner states that he Knows Frooks went to the courthouse on the day the case was set for trial for the purpose of Answering to the Indictment &amp; He did not go up, feeling no uneasiness about his liability but by reason of the Ignorance of said Frooks in not answering &amp; Surrendering himself when the case was called, the Default was entered -- Frooks is a verry poor young man &amp; the costs will fall upon Petitioner &amp; he humbly Insists that he ought not be made to pay more &amp; asks your Excellency to remit said Judgement for the collection of which a capias is now in the hands of the Marshall of said Court who is Insisting on payment of the whole amount of said Judgements. -- </p>
<p>Henry Connally</p>
<p>City of Louisville Ss.</p>
<p>This day Henry Connally made oath before me that the statements contained in the foregoing Petition are True</p>
<p>Geo. W. Johnston J. c c L<pb/></p>
<p>I am Marshall of the city court of Louisville &amp; distinctly recollect that the case refered too in foregoing Petition was called &amp; laid over the next day, that on next day I saw Frooks about the courthouse but when the case was called he did not answer; I presume he did not Intend to avoid an appearance, but that his failure <hi rend="str">an</hi>to answer when he was called was the result of Ignorance on his part of the Necessity of his personal presence I hope the Governor will remit the Judgement against Connally the Security. -- </p>
<p>W. C. Benson. M. C, C, L</p>
<p>I corroborate the above statement of M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Benson the Marshall of the City Court with this addition, I distinctly recollect that when the first Case was Called that the Deft ^Frooks^ was present to answer the Case &amp; that as there was a case set for trial the next day -- the Case Called on the first day was passed over and on the next day I saw the Deft about the Court, and suppose that he did not hear his name Called when the Case was reach</p>
<p>W C Price<pb/></p>
<p>I am well acquainted with the Petitioner Connally. He is a worthy good citizen &amp; from his statement &amp; those of Benson &amp; Price, I am satisfied the Executive should remit the Judgment. The Petitioner has had great Domestic Difficulties recently &amp; neglected to make defense to the suit on scifa consequently a Judgement was rendered against ^him^ If the facts as stated by Benson &amp; Price, had been proved on the Trial I am satisfied no Judgement would have been rendered</p>
<p>Geo. W. Johnston.</p>
<p>Louisville Cty Ct
<lb/>Remitted 
<lb/>B M
<lb/>$100 } Forfeited Recognizance
<lb/>Henry Conley
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1860-11-13">Nov 13. 1860</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
