<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2138"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Elisha Clark to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6775</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-363 to BR14-364</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-07-11">11 July 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency the Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky Your petitioner Elisha Clark would state that he ^is^ now upwards of fifty five years of age he has <hi rend="str">sum</hi> seven children from the age of six years to twenty two Your petitioner is himself of feeble constitution and his wife is now prostrated by an attack of inflamatory rheumatism Your petitioner is to day worth about five hundred dollars He states that some time since his oldest son unfortunately fell into bad company and was found traveling together with men who had stolen or some way got possession of two mules not their own The entire company was arrested and tried for Larceny <hi rend="str">the</hi> by the county judge of Marion county and sent on to further trial <hi rend="str">the</hi> and required to give bail in the sum of $500 each. in default of Bail his son was committed to a loathsome Jail after he had remained there some time your petitioner yealding to the suggestions of paternal feeling became bound in the sum of $500.00 for his appearance at the June term of the Marion circuit court This said son failed to appear and the bond was forfeited and a summons on said forfeiture was this day served upon your petitioner and is made part hereof To pay the bail will take all the earthly goods your petitioner has or nearly all and leave him ^thus destitute^ in the decline of life to take care of his afflicted wife the helpless children If your petitioner and his wife were not denied the ordinary measure of health they could meet with composure the just requirements of the law but such <hi rend="str">are</hi> is their condition as above plainly and truthfully<pb/>
<lb/>stated that Your petitioner feels constrained to ask your excellency to exercise on his behalf whatever of clemency your <hi rend="str">sense</hi> excellency may feel justified in offering him under all circumstances</p>
<p>Elisha Clark</p>
<p>The above petition was this day sworn to before me by the petitioner Elisha Clark <date when="1865-07-11">July 11 1865</date>.</p>
<p><stamp/><note place="stamp"><unclear/></note>
<lb/>R Hite J. P. M. C.</p>
<p>We most cheerfully unite in asking his excellency the Governor of KY t<hi rend="str">he</hi>o remitt<hi rend="str">ing</hi> the penalty of the bail bond referred to in the foregoing petition of Elisha Clark</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J, J, Beard
<lb/>W. F. Dunn
<lb/>George Dunn
<lb/>J. F. Averitt
<lb/>John L, Fleece
<lb/>W. W, Newcomb
<lb/>Phil Purdy
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Burke
<lb/>P F Hunter
<lb/>Marten Ross
<lb/>Thomas J Avritt
<lb/>Samuel Gaston
<lb/>James H Tucker Jr
<lb/>Joseph Sarrbe
<lb/>William Thornton
<lb/>Uriah Garten Jr
<lb/>Lewis wright
<lb/>Isaac Jones
<lb/>H P Thornton
<lb/>James Averit
<lb/>Thos H Hugh
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Richard Calhoon
<lb/>G W Glascock
<lb/>George Coppage
<lb/>H Purdy
<lb/>A Dunn
<lb/>S, F, Boswell
<lb/>Wayne Ferguson
<lb/>F Abell
<lb/>S, L, Hughs
<lb/>Sam<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Hocker
<lb/>Leroy Yowell
<lb/>G W Scott
<lb/>F. G. Philips
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Lankford sr.
<lb/>J, W Chelf
<lb/>B. D. Wilson
<lb/>James W. Austin
<lb/>Tomas thornton
<lb/>Micjah Wilson
<lb/>Green R. Hays<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Elroy
<lb/>M M Beard
<lb/>J, W, Beard
<lb/>K A Goode
<lb/>Elijah Beard
<lb/>G, A. Beard
<lb/>Josiah Beard
<lb/>L, L, Edwards
<lb/>Melvin Simpson
<lb/>Meletus Simpson
<lb/>Beauford Simpson
<lb/>John C Simpson
<lb/>Horm Tunget
<lb/>george Saly
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Harvey Avrett
<lb/>John Young
<lb/>Timothy hughes
<lb/>Richard Baggley
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Durham
<lb/>William Jaraboe
<lb/><cb n="2"/>B. <unclear>Spalding</unclear>
<lb/>John D Brown
<lb/>John R. Thomas
<lb/>L A Spalding
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J, G, Philips</hi>
<lb/>James M. Fidler</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
