<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3199"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. Green et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5318</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-373 to BR41-374A</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To your Excelency Thomas E Bramlet
<lb/>Govner of Kentucky</p>
<p>We the under sined ^citizens^ of Washington and other Joining county moste Respectfuly Represent to your Excelency that a bout the <date when="--12-07">7th day of December <hi rend="str">1864</hi></date> William Hatchett and Matt Taerel Who Belonged to the Stat gards who Was comended by James Lasen and the Companey not haven enof of armes furnished to them that was orderd to go and arme them selves By taken gones and pistols from the Rebel Citizen and as the gurilers being a grate terer William Hatchtt an Terrel Did take <hi rend="str">ab</hi> one pisol of James Red and he Was a Rebl and your Petitioneshener Nathaniel Millbern Being farst to go to the campes of sed state gards for pection as<pb/>
<lb/>the gurilers war at that time through hear very Bad and that had <unclear/> Thomes Howl and Samul Green and a Mister Buttener and all so John Foster was murdered hear and in the distance of a bout 8 miles a round and they had thretend all other union soldiers and as a bove mentioned Nathaniel Mellborn Was pasing By the said James Reed in compnay with Hatchet and Terel and Hatchett and Terel did get a pistol of the sed James Red But he gaves no a count of Your petitoner Nathaniel Millbern <unclear/> there in his no body and the sed Hatchett was indited in the circuit cort cort of Washington County in the ^<hi rend="str">april</hi>^ <hi rend="str">year</hi> <date when="1864">1864</date> and at the <date when="1867-04">April terme of 67</date> the circuit cort the said hatchet was put upon his trile and after the investigation of his<pb/>
<lb/>and Him Being the some of a old soldier who is now 66 years of age he in listed in the 11<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> ky,, Cavalelry and did good Survis <hi rend="str">un</hi> un till he lost his helth and is all most helples and your petitioner as his onley singel son nad onley manly help he has and so forth So wee the under sind citizens do not Bleav that Nathaniel Millburn your Petitoner is gilty of the charge that he now asques pardon for he is thought to Be a nis and credertebal young man so in re vewe of his case Wee the under sind citizens most Respectfuly do pray his Pardon &amp; so forth to yoru Excelency prey Remember your best citizens and ther request far well<pb/>
<lb/>suit Suit the commonweths at torney Dismist his Suit and your Petitioner <hi rend="str">and</hi> Bring a Witness in the Hatchet case against and for Hatchett wen the indictment Was a gam resued by the grand Jurey he Was charged withe the same ofense and all so the Sed hatchett and <unclear/><unclear/> and your Petitoner Nathaniel Milburn Was indited form his own testimoney and now wee the under sind citzens do certify that in the Brekin out of the Rebllion in <date when="1861">1861</date> that the Said Nathaniel Milburn did in <unclear/> in the 19<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> kentucky Redgment Which was comanded By W.. J.. Landrum and all so did good survis un till <date when="1864-05-16">May the 16th 18"64</date> and then was discharged on reasons of disability and so farth<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W Green
<lb/>William M. Sharp
<lb/>William Ross
<lb/>William M. Levy
<lb/>Willsom Millbern
<lb/>William Hutcheson
<lb/>William H. Montgomery
<lb/>William S yansery
<lb/>Jaison W Long
<lb/>Jacop McManons
<lb/>James Pinkestone
<lb/>Joseph Hayse
<lb/>John Sharp
<lb/>John athen Pruit
<lb/>Jakeson A. Simes
<lb/>John V. taw
<lb/>John Jarrett
<lb/>James gardner
<lb/>John hardin Millbern
<lb/>James hayse
<lb/>Merril Pinkeston
<lb/>Peter H. Head
<lb/>Berry Hatchett
<lb/>Benjamin foster
<lb/>Billey Hickeson
<lb/>Dick Littrel
<lb/>A. D geenwood
<lb/>David Hendren
<lb/>Alon Littrel
<lb/>Andrew D. Devine
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Ritchard Perkins
<lb/>R L. Williams
<lb/><hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> <hi rend="str">Pinkeston</hi>
<lb/>R L Pinkston
<lb/>Robert R Mackmilen
<lb/>Simps. Hendren
<lb/>S. B Noel
<lb/>Ritchard M. gardner
<lb/>Thomas A. Tatum
<lb/>Logan Hickeson
<lb/>William Brown
<lb/>James Kinder
<lb/>edomnd Helard
<lb/>Benjamon F. Crow
<lb/>John Hille
<lb/>James Ross
<lb/>David Hilbert
<lb/>Samuel Long
<lb/>gary foster
<lb/>James H Brown
<lb/>C. H. Buttner
<lb/>F. S. Hill
<lb/>J. J Becker
<lb/>W. G. Spern
<lb/><unclear/> O Cawling
<lb/>John Moore
<lb/>S. S. Moenen
<lb/>A. W cuttSinger
<lb/>John Smith
<lb/>H.M. Philips<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>John W. Burton
<lb/>Samuel Alatum
<lb/>John Riley</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
