<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-021-0033"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Edward P. Campbell et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG3103</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Apprehension of Fugitives from Justice Papers, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG8-120 to MG8-121</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Princeton, Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-16">16 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>E. P. CAMPBELL,
<lb/>ATTORNEY AT LAW,
<lb/>PRINCETON, KY.
<lb/>Princeton, KY., <date when="1861-06-16">June 16" 1861</date>
<lb/>Hon B Magoffin
<lb/>Frankfort Kenty
<lb/>Dr Sir</p>
<p>At the <date when="1861-06">June Term</date> of the Caldwell Circuit Court Wesley a Slave the property of the Estate of Jesse Williams Decd -- was tried on an Indictment charged with the murder of Edmund Stevens and was found guilty by the Jury -- the evidence on the trial disclosed that Jesse Williams Decd was a violent reckless and desperate man and he entertained a grudge and hatred towards Edmund Stevens the Decd -- and Stevens was on the morning of the <date when="1859-05-25">25" day of May 1859</date> shot down while engaged at work on his farm -- and suspicion rested on Williams and his family as the persons guilty of the murder of Stevens and after circumstances led to the detection and arrest of the Negro man Wesley<pb/>
<lb/>and after Wesley was arrested and committed to <hi rend="underline">Jail</hi> he confessed to the Jailor and other persons that he did shoot and kill Stevens but he did it by the command and coercion of his master Jesse Williams Decd -- and stated that Williams was standing by him when he shot Stevens and -- one of the comth witnesses to whom Wesley confessed the <hi rend="underline">murder</hi> on the same day of the killing of Stevens -- stated that about a week before Stevens -- was killed he heard Jesse Williams tell Wesley that if he Wesley did not kill Stevens he Williams would cut his back all to pieces -- and stated that he was present several times when Williams started Wesley out with a gun to kill Stevens and heard Williams tell Wesley to kill said Stevens -- We are satisfied from the evidence that Wesley killed Stevens through <hi rend="underline">fear</hi> compulsion and constraint of his master Jesse Williams and from no wish or will of his own and so<pb/>
<lb/>stated in his confession to the Jailor and other -- we are of the opinion -- that Wesley case demands the interposition of executive clemency on his behalf -- and we are equally opposed to his being granted a free pardon so as to let him go back into the possession of the family of Jesse Williams Decd We request and hereby urge of Your excellency to commute his punishment from death to confinement in the Penitentiary for life</p>
<p>Yours very truly
<lb/>E, P,, Campbell atty
<lb/>For Commonwealth
<lb/>Tho C Dalmer Judge
<lb/>E. P. Watkins Clk Caldwell ct ct.
<lb/>Jesse Stevens Sheriff
<lb/>Jas A. Johnson D S
<lb/>James S. Lowry Jailor
<lb/>L. Pepper<pb/></p>
<p>Caldwell Cir. Ct
<lb/>Wesley -- Slave
<lb/>Murder
<lb/>Commuted to imprisonment for life.
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-08-26">Aug 26. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
