<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0845"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Wilson et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10313</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-327 to MG19-328</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioners William Wilson, William Murphy, J. C. Wickliffe William H. Newman &amp; J. W. Muir Respectfully represent that at the <date when="1860-09">September</date> term of the Nelson Circuit Court one Henry Smith was held to Bail in the sum of one thousand dollars to appear at the <date when="1861-03">March term of said Court for the present year (1861)</date> to answer an Indictment for murder and being a poor man -- without any estate and a stranger in the said County without relatives or friends, and he having appeared at one term and surrendered himself into custody and was tried &amp; there was a hung Jury, and the trial having developed the fact that the killing of which he was accused was done only after he was provoked to the attack by being first without his offending <hi rend="str">being</hi> fired upon with a pistol in the hands of the slain, the undersigned believing he was guilty only of justifiable ^or excusable^ homicide entered as his bail for his appearance to the <date when="1861-03">March term aforesaid.</date> The said Smith has since contracted an alliance with a young lady of respectability of Said County and with her has gone to parts unknown as is supposed with the intent to marry her which was in opposition to the wishes of her Family. This alliance no doubt has been the prime cause of his forfeiting his recognizance whereby your petitioners will be compelled to pay the sum of one thousand dollars unless relieved by the Executive Clemency of your Excellency &amp; owing to the peculiar financial condition<pb/>
<lb/>of the country, and the moderate circumstances of your petitioners (who are all young men with families to support) the payment of said Bail would be greivous burden to them and each of them</p>
<p>Wherefore your petitioners do most anxiously solicit Your Excellency to relieve them of the payment thereof</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Wilson
<lb/>J. W. Muir
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Murphy
<lb/>W. H. Newman
<lb/>W. R. Grigsby
<lb/>P. B. Muir
<lb/>Tho W Riley
<lb/>John E Newman
<lb/>John L. Helm<pb/></p>
<p>I was present at one trial of Henry Smith on the charge mentioned in this petition. There was a Hung Jury. I heard the trial and am of opinion Smith ought to have been acquitted</p>
<p>Tho W Riley<pb/></p>
<p>Nelson Cir Ct
<lb/>Respite 12 mo
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>$1000 } Recogn
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Wilson &amp; Others.
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-03-30">Mar <hi rend="underline">30. 1861</hi></date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
