<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0300"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Jesse Young et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9768</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-297 to MG17-298</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Green County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>We the undersigned Citizens of Green county and neighbors of J. J. Russell and his father and Mother &amp; Brothers, residents of said county ^state that^ said J J Russlel has been tried for the alledged affence of <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> misdemeanor in Disfiguring or maiming stock and has been convicted and is now in the County Jail under Sentence for 4 months. We believe in all Sincerity and Candor that said Russell is innocent of the charge and We are satisfied that his Conviction has been brought about by unjust and unfair means. the chief Witnesses against him were his bitter Enemies who not only persecuted him in every way but prosecuted him by Employing some four Lawyers the ablest at the Bar in addition to the Attorney for the Commonwealth and then becoming the chief witnesses in the case. We do not beleeve in all Candor that said Russell has had Justice done him -- he is a poor man with a wife and two little children who rely solely upon him for a support. he is an honest hard working clever man &amp; has the good will of his neighbors and with the Exception of a few Enemies he stands fair and above suspicion of the crime. indeed we are satisfied he could not have been<pb/>
<lb/>guilty of the Crime as he could have proven by respectable testimony and a number of them that he was Elsewhere We State to your Excellency that his old father <hi rend="str">&amp;</hi> was a veteran of the War of 1812 and done good Service for his Country. &amp; we believe he has raised an honest and Clever family the Defendant being one of them</p>
<p>We pray your Excellency to take this poor mans Case into your favorable Consideration and release him from this unjust imprisonment and restore him to his family. Which we are satisfied will be most heartily and Cordially approved. by our Citizens and Especially those who know the Deft best all of which we respectfully submit to your Excellency We will add that the gloom prevading our land at present and the destress to this community. by the dry weather. calls aloud for the Sympathy of your Excellency. to lend your authority to. restore the unfortunate man to his familys aid</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Jesse Young 
<lb/>Joseph Davenport
<lb/>Alaxander N. Skaggs
<lb/>T. Skaggs
<lb/><cb n="2"/>P, D. Williams
<lb/>F Williams
<lb/>M. J Willilliams
<lb/>S Williams
<lb/>Washington Heron<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>M. C. Skaggs
<lb/>R. J, Skaggs
<lb/>S. F. Skags
<lb/>James Mathews
<lb/>John Mathews
<lb/>F Shuffit
<lb/>George B Boston
<lb/>Thomas Abner
<lb/>William Boston
<lb/>M. Boston
<lb/>Samuel F Wells,
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> P Forbes
<lb/>Thomas Meurry
<lb/>David Forbis
<lb/>Paterson Jeffries
<lb/>J. T. Houk
<lb/>Green Forbis
<lb/>William Wallacie Ser
<lb/>Richman Robinson
<lb/>Warren Erwin
<lb/>Mansfield Houk
<lb/>N, G, Forbis
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> P M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Candless
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Wallace
<lb/>F. Wallace
<lb/>W. Batey
<lb/>Samuel Pittman
<lb/>Gilbert. Isaacs
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Joseph Pittman
<lb/>Solomon Pittman
<lb/>James Pittman
<lb/>John Pittman
<lb/>Sterlin Pittman
<lb/>James Forbis
<lb/>Calvin Crail
<lb/>James Crail
<lb/>S Q Lively
<lb/>Joseph Abner
<lb/>James. Robinson
<lb/>Reuben Lobb
<lb/>W C Davenport
<lb/>William Lobb
<lb/>Z, R, Cannon
<lb/>N. R Shuffit
<lb/>David Towles<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>J J Russell Petition
<lb/>Names of Petitioners on his behalf</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
