<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2305"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. W. Clark to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6942</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-185 to BR15-186</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lyon County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-23">23 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>H W Hendon
<lb/>J C Lee
<lb/><cb/>T J Frohack
<lb/>John Long</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>To his Excellency Thos E. Bramlette Govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned petitioners would respectfully state that in the year <date when="1860">1860</date> one P. F. Bail was indicted in the Lyon Circuit Court four an Assault and Battery and was held to bail to answer said offence in the aforesaid Court M. M. Lyon, J. R. Dudley, C. R. Marshall, W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> R Gracey, Robert Boyd, John W. Bush &amp; H. Setberry were the sureties on said Bail's bond for his appearance in Court. Said P. F. Bails having failed to make his appearance agreeably with his bond it was taken as forfeited at the <date when="1860-12-12">December term of the Lyon Circuit Court on 12 day of December 1860</date>. A copy of said judgement is here copied and properly attested by the clerk of the Afsd Court, to wit,</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Lyon Circuit Court
<lb/><date when="1860-12">December term 1860</date>
<lb/>Commth v M. M. Lyon &amp;c</p>
<p>This day came the attorney for the Commonwealth and the defendants being Summoned and failing to appear, it is adjudged by the court<pb/>
<lb/>that the Commonwealth of Kentucky recover of the defendants M. M. Lyon J. R. Dudley, C. R. Marshall Wm R. Gracey Robert Boyd, John W Bush &amp; H Setberry the Sum of one hundred dollars being the amount Specified in the recognizance entered into herein for the appearance of P. F. Bail in the Court and for a forfeiture thereof with interest thereon from the <date when="1860-12-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of December 1860</date> at the rate of 6 per cent per annum until paid and also her costs herein Execution is awarded &amp;c</p>
<p>A Copy -- Attest
<lb/>J. W. Clark clk
<lb/>Lyon Cir court</p>
<p>They further state that P. F. Bail is dead &amp; left no property out of which said forfeited recognizance could be made or any part thereof they also state that the sureties J. R. Dudley &amp; C. R. Marshall have since died leaving no property whatever, and the other sureties have gone beyond the jurisdiction of the sheriff of this County (Lyon) excepting<pb/>
<lb/>M. M. Lyon, who was in fact the only responsible party at the time they entered into said recog'nce but who is now in a destitute condition (from a loss of his property during the rebellion which consisted principally in slaves) with a large family to support by his daily la<hi rend="str">i</hi>bor. We know it would work a great hardship for him to pay said amount set-out in the judgement herein, and in fact it is impossible for him to satisfy it except in the County jail, nothwithstanding it is a small amount. And therefore we ask your Excellency as a matter of justice and mercy to remit so much of said forfeiture against M. M. Lyon and the other sureties for P, F, Bail as lies in your power. <date when="1865-09-23">Sept 23<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> 1865</date></p>
<p>Respectfully &amp;c</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>F Machen
<lb/>J N Holloway
<lb/>S N Gracey
<lb/>John Boyd S, L, C,
<lb/>M. G, Catlett
<lb/>H C Marshall
<lb/>Wm Gish Clk
<lb/>C Warfield
<lb/>D W Gore
<lb/><hi rend="underline">G S Cobb
<lb/></hi><cb/>F. A. Wilson
<lb/>D. L. Gardner
<lb/>J. W. Clark Clk
<lb/>Cyrus Boyd
<lb/>T.. P.. Panir
<lb/>Geo,, C,, Lester
<lb/>W M Bowman
<lb/>Isaac Gray
<lb/>J, H, Brock<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Rob<hi rend="sup">t</hi> L Cobb
<lb/>R Holland
<lb/>Isaac Lazarus
<lb/>R. Hayden
<lb/>A. Brock
<lb/><hi rend="underline">O M. Jenkins</hi>
<lb/>Edward Reily
<lb/>R, H, Cash
<lb/>D. C. Dun
<lb/>R, W, Ethridge
<lb/>W. H. Williams -- 
<lb/>James Boyd
<lb/>James M Bigham
<lb/>Arch Hunter
<lb/>G, M, Huggans
<lb/>R W Wake
<lb/>John Brindly
<lb/>L. L. Cummins
<lb/>W, T, Smith
<lb/>F. H. Skinner
<lb/>W, M, Robertson
<lb/>C H Boyd
<lb/>S Stafford
<lb/>James ,H, Hollaway
<lb/>B. C Bullard
<lb/>Saml Garrett
<lb/>E P George
<lb/>George Purdle
<lb/>F,, B,, Evins
<lb/><cb n="2"/><hi rend="underline">John Stacker Jr</hi>
<lb/>Abner Cooper
<lb/><hi rend="underline">G</hi>. <hi rend="underline">W</hi>. <hi rend="underline">Holcomb</hi>
<lb/>W. W. Hollman
<lb/>V. Sauvage
<lb/>J. Lehr
<lb/>R. F. Fraziell
<lb/>Linah M Cobb
<lb/>L F. Cash
<lb/>R Cobb
<lb/>J. C. Cobb
<lb/>Jno B Bradshaw
<lb/>C F Jenkins
<lb/>M T Braswell
<lb/>M V Hawley
<lb/>James Lester
<lb/>O B Herring
<lb/>L, W, Hill
<lb/>J L Washington
<lb/>T. J. Watkins
<lb/>Chesley Kelly
<lb/>J M Haywood
<lb/>R, A, Dickson
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Gregory
<lb/>B Dorr
<lb/>James Scott
<lb/>T G Dyars
<lb/>W T Thompson</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Lyon Cir Ct
<lb/>Remit vs<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>M. M. Lyon &amp;c
<lb/>$100 forfeiture
<lb/><date when="1865-09-28">28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sept./65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
