<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1964"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Fountain Riddell to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11432</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Bradley Strait</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG23-416</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Burlington, Boone County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-06-13">13 June 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Burlington Ky <date when="1862-06-13">June 13/62</date>
<lb/>B Magoffin 
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>An indictment was found against one Benjamin Sandford of this ^county^ (Boone Co) at the <date when="1860-09">September Circuit Court ^of said couty^ for the year 1860</date> the indictment charged Sandford of the offens of selling whisky to minors in violation of the Statute You were petitioned Something like a year ago to remit the fines assessed against Sandford on that indictment (The fine<hi rend="str">d</hi> was assessed at the <date when="1861-04">April term 1861</date> of the Boone Circuit) Your action upon that petion was only to respite the colection for twelve months The circumstances of the offense are set fourth in the petition above refered to Sandford is no longer a tavern Keeper &amp; is now unable to pay the fine except by a great ^sacrifice^ of his property ^(&amp; he has very little property,)^ The minor to whome he soled the whisky had the appearance of a man of 24 or 25 year of age he had for several years been trading at large in the country &amp; was thought by anyone to be of full age untill he <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> he swore to the contrary before the jury in Sandfords case<pb/>
<lb/>We <hi rend="str">think</hi> know that an interference on your part to Stop further proceedings in this case against Sandford will meet with the hearty approval ^of^ all his neighbors &amp; acquantances I will therefore in behalf of Mr Sandford ask a further consideration of the subject by you &amp; <hi rend="str">if not</hi> a final remit of the <hi rend="str">of the</hi> Said fine ^save costs &amp; atty fee^ if not against your opinion of the justness of the case <hi rend="str">which <unclear/></hi> </p>
<p>Yours respectfully 
<lb/>Fountain Riddell</p>
<p>Remitted 
<lb/>B. M.
<lb/><date when="1862-07-08">July 8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">"</hi></hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>Boone County</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
