<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1531"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. L. Mitchell et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10999</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-132 to MG22-133</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jessamine County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-09-16">16 September 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin Governor of the Commonwealth. -- </p>
<p>The undersigned Citizens of the County of Jessamine respectfully represent &amp; petition as herein set forth.</p>
<p>That John J. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Afee was arrested in the Town of Nicholasville Ky -- on the <date when="1861-08-05">5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of August 1861</date> under a warrant for an alledged shooting with intent to Kill -- and on the <date when="1861-08-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of the same month and year</date> he was tried for said offence before James G. Bruce and James H Lowry Esqrs. Justices of the peace for said County as an examining Court -- &amp; by them adjudged that there were "reasonable grounds for believing that said Deft -- M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Afee was guilty of the offence charged" &amp; held him for trial before the Jessamine Circuit Court in bail in the sum of $4.000 &amp; said M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Afee not then giving said bail was Confined in the Jail of said County from that date till the <date when="1861-08-10">10<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of August</date> ensuing when W<hi rend="sup">m</hi>. H. Daniel, Nathaniel Welch, Edward Cosby, &amp; John S. Welch became his bail in the sum named by the execution of the requisite Bail Bond before H. J. Campbell Presiding Judge of the Jessamine County Court -- for his personal appearance before the Jessamine Circuit Court on the <date when="1861-09-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> day of its September Term 1861</date> -- The said M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Afee failed to make his personal appearance before Said Court as required by Said Bond &amp; the Same was so noted on the record of said ^court^ &amp; said Bond declared to be forfeited &amp; Summons duly awarded thereunder against Said Surities for the ensuing <date when="1861-03">March Term 1861</date> -- of Said Court. -- </p>
<p>Your Petitioners are Satisfied from all<pb/>
<lb/>the evidences and circumstances attending Said case and the Shooting charged that there are just Mitigating facts and circumstances as to the alledged acting of Said M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Afee which entitle him &amp; his said Securities as Bail to the clement consideration of Your Excellency. -- </p>
<p>The Shooting charged is alledged to have been done near the Court house in the Town of Nicholasville Ky -- On the <date when="1861-08-05">5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of August 1861</date> ^on election day^ -- at one W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Dowell -- in a personal rencounter at the time and place between said M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Dowell &amp; one W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H. Daniel for alledged political differences. -- between whom several pistol shots were fired by each &amp; at each other. -- </p>
<p>At the time of said M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Afee's examining trial it was believed and apprehended that said M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Dowell would die from the wound recieved -- but is yet alive -- &amp; as we understand is recovering &amp; now supposed out of danger of death resulting therefrom -- &amp; we think &amp; believe that Such apprehension of his probable death resulting had great weight &amp; influence with the examining Justices in affixing the Bail of said M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Afee so high as it was affixed -- &amp; which we then &amp; now regard as excessive -- &amp; we believe furthermore that in Consequence of the excessive &amp; extraordinary excitement on the part of said M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Afee's enemies &amp; political adversaries ^against him^ in the present &amp; then political excitement it is now &amp; has been ever since said M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Afee was bailed out &amp; left -- as we think ^&amp; believe^ positively unsafe to his life for him to have ^made^ his appearance at the Circuit Court or in the County -- Since.</p>
<p>The evidence as developed in the case is<pb/>
<lb/>that at the Commencement of the rencounter between M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Dowell &amp; Daniel, that before the shooting between ^them commenced,^ a third party one D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Young ^a partisan friend^ delivered to M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Dowell a Pistol &amp; urged on him to fire on Daniel which ^he done^ in advance of any <hi rend="str">of</hi> fireing by Daniel -- &amp; so soon as they exausted their shots they each closed &amp; M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Dowell was on Daniel &amp; had him down on the ground &amp; in the act of strikeing Daniel on the head with his pistol when it is alledged that M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Afee (as the personal &amp; political friend of Daniel under the exciement of the moment &amp; under a seeming simultaneous pressure of the friends of each party) ran in &amp; fired a single pistol shot at M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Dowell -- &amp; here the whole affair ended -- </p>
<p>We therefore petition your Excellency for your clement interposition in behalf the securities in said Bail Bond -- <date when="1861-09-16">Sept 16 1861.</date></p>
<p><date when="1861-09-16">Sept 16. 1861 -- </date></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/> Grant Knight
<lb/>Franklin Wiley
<lb/>D Portwood
<lb/>R. D. Long
<lb/>Jno J. <unclear/>
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Davis 
<lb/>Tho B Scott
<lb/>G. T. Cooley
<lb/>P. H. Smith
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. B. Cook
<lb/>G. W. Mitchell
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi>. W. Robinson
<lb/>J B Cook
<lb/>S. H. Campbell
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> L Cook
<lb/>Elijah Bourn
<lb/>A. G. Hauser
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J. L. Mitchell
<lb/>M F Miller
<lb/>Woodson Dickerson
<lb/>P N Penston
<lb/>James D. Carlise
<lb/>Herry Metcalf
<lb/>M T Campbell
<lb/>Irvine Mastus
<lb/>Geo. T. Keith
<lb/>George M Barkley
<lb/>John J Ben
<lb/>John Portwood
<lb/>J Knight Lowy
<lb/>Joseph Rutherford
<lb/>George T. Nowe
<lb/>Jas H Robard
<lb/><unclear/> Jorry.
<lb/>C Rutherford S. J. C.<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Jessamine Cir. Ct
<lb/>Commonwealth
<lb/>$4000 vs } Petition
<lb/>Jno. J. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Afee -- </p>
<p>No Judgment but McDowell recovering -- </p>
<p>Remitted as to Three Thousand dollars
<lb/>B. Magoffin</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-11-21">Nov 21. 1861</date></p>
<p>Jessamine County Sct:</p>
<p>I am personally &amp; well acquainted with the person whose names appear to the foregoing Petition being thirty five in number &amp; they are all resident citizens of my said County, are persons of honesty and probity &amp; are each entitled to full faith and credits. -- </p>
<p>Given under my hand this <date when="1861-09-16">16<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sept 1861. -- </date></p>
<p>M. T. Lowry Clk.
<lb/>Jessamine County &amp; Circuit Court.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
