<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0425"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Clay to James P. Metcalf</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8877</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-182</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Carlisle, Nicholas County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-06-03">3 June 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Carlisle <date when="1863-06-03">June 3rd 1863</date>
<lb/>James P Metcalf Esq
<lb/>Frankfort Ky
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>There is an old free negro women in this county by the name of Sarah Mullins. She lives on the other side of Licking river not far from the residence of Thompson Parks. Thompson Parks owns a boy Harry who I think is her son. I have known this old woman for a long time and know her to be a good honest industrious old woman. She has a good reputation in her own neighborhood. She has a son Isaiah who lives with her (and upon whom she is almost entirly dependent for Support) who was on Saturday last convicted of a breach of the peace before judge West (County judge) and fined $20 and imprisoned 15 July. This boy has always born a good character for honesty industry and sobriety. The people of his neighborhood speak well of him, and I have also known him for a long time and can testify to his good character. The punishment imposed by the jury I think was unduly severe even if he had deserved punishment at all considering his pecunary circumstances, But I have taken considerable pains to inform myself concerning all circumstances of the case and am firmly convinced that Isaiah Mullins was unjustly fined &amp; imprisoned. There was an attempt made<pb/>
<lb/>by his mother in law (a worthless wretch) and a good for nothing white man to take from his house a a trunk containing his wife's clothing, and all Isaiah did was done in defense of his person and property. The only witness in the case was a boy about 12 years old (a son of the white man) who was evidently prejudiced against Isaiah, and in favor of his father. The counsel for the Commonwealth was permitted (notwithstanding the objections of Isaiah's counsel) to elicit from the witness by means of leading questions just such answers as he wished; and it was evident that the jury were actuated to some extent by prejudice and a disposition very prevalent first at this time to deal severly with free negroes. Sarah Mullins has sent a petition to the Governor praying a remission of her sons fine and a release from imprisonment, Her Son has commenced raising a crop for her support. She has no one else to work this crop but her son. I have not had time to go and see his neighbors but have learned from reliable authority that they are all willing and anxious to have the boy released from imprisonment and his fine remitted. Will you have the kindness to go and see the governor about this matter and if it is not asking to to much of do what you can to have this boy released</p>
<p>Yours very respectfully
<lb/>John Clay</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
