<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0610"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James R. Hallam to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4729</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-468 to BR9-469</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Newport, Campbell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-03-10">10 March 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Newport Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-03-10">March 10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E. Bramlette
<lb/>Gov. of Kentucky
<lb/>Dr Sir</p>
<p>In the winter or Spring of <date when="1852">1852</date>, I went on a bail bond for Samuel Ganow, in the Grant Circuit Court to the amount of $125. The recognizance was forfeited &amp; Judgment renered against me. Ganow resided in Ohio, &amp; I learn, died about the time he should have appeared. Whether before or after I am not able to say.</p>
<p>My recollection is that the judgment was remitted by Gov. Powell <hi rend="str">about</hi> shortly after it was rendered but I have no written evidence of it. The Commonwealth's Attorney I know recommended the remission However the matter has slept until the present time, &amp; recently an Execution has been issued against me for the $125. credited by $25 paid by me, <hi rend="str">at</hi> the interest of the Attorney for the Commonwealth which is now in the hands of<pb/>
<lb/>the Sheriff of Campbell County</p>
<p>It would oppress me seriously to pay it now &amp; I never received any indemnity against it from any one.</p>
<p>I ask therefore that it may be remitted by the Executive</p>
<p>The Judgment was rendered at the <date when="1854-04">April Term 1854</date> of the Grant Circuit Court</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>James R Hallam</p>
<p>Under the circumstances of the above case I would recommend the remission prayed on by Mr. Hallam.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">M. M. Benton</hi></p>
<p>I concur in Bentons Statements</p>
<p>R. T. Baker</p>
<p>So do I Guy Atsman Clk Cir Ct</p>
<p>and so do I Sidney B. Jones D.S.CC</p>
<p>I recommend the remission asked for in the petition</p>
<p>Oliver W. Root County Atty for Campbell -- 
<lb/>J. Hawthorn<pb/></p>
<p>Grant Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>Jas R Hallam
<lb/>$125 -- 
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/><date when="1864-03-14">14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Mch 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
