<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0396"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Ellin Walls, Judgment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9864</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-115 to MG18-116</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lincoln County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Lincoln Circuit Court
<lb/><date when="1860-03">March term 1860</date>.
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Ky Plaintiff
<lb/>against } Upon an Ind<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi>
<lb/>Ellin Walls Defendant </p>
<p>The def<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> pled not guilty and the following Jurors towit. Logan Murphy, N. G. Tevis, T. C. Humber, H. C. Helen, T. J. Thurman, W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> C. Bailey, John S. Murphy, Owen Hacker, W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Young, C. Engleman, H. S. Withers, and Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Reynolds were Sworn to try the issue, after hearing the evidence rendered the following verdict, we of the Jury find the def<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> guilty and assess her fine at one hundred dollars N. G. Tevis foreman.Therefore it is ordered and adjudged by the court that the def<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> is guilty of the offense as charged in the Indictment, that she do in consequence thereof make good her fine with the Commonwealth by payment of one hundred dollars</p>
<p>A Copy
<lb/>Att G. H. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kinney clerk
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Lincoln Circuit Court</hi></p>
<p>To His Excellency Beriah Magoffin. Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky,</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Ellen Walls respectfully representing would show unto your Excellency that at the <date when="1860-03">March term 1860</date> of the Lincoln<pb/>
<lb/>Circuit Court she was found guilty by a judgment of said Court, of an offense against the laws ot the Commonwealth and judgment rendered against her for the sum of $100 -- </p>
<p>She states that she is a widow, penniless and friendless, with nothing whatever whereby to extinguish said fine: with a family of defenceless children, all of whom are infants, dependent upon her daily exertions for bread.</p>
<p>Under the process of the Court afsd the Sheriff of Lincoln County is now about to take her from her said children and incarcerate her in the jail of Lincoln County, leaving her infant children without bread or any human being to watch over and care for them; at a time when the inclemency of midwinter, and the great scarcity of provison would bring upon them certain distress. In addition to all of which your Petitioner is now <hi rend="underline">pregnant</hi> and will be confined in the course of a few weeks.</p>
<p>In the midst of distress therefore she humbly petitions your Excellency to remit said fine. and promises no more to violate the laws of the Commonwealth</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>Your obedient Servant
<lb/>Ellen Walls<pb/></p>
<p>His Excellency Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> of Kentucky</p>
<p>We whose names are herto annexed humbly ask Your Excellency to Grant the prayer of the petitioner Mr<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Ellin Walls herewith Annexed</p>
<p><date when="1861-01-22">January 22<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> 1861</date>.
<lb/><table rend="rules">
<row>
	<cell>Huffman &amp; Pendleton</cell>
	<cell>Merchants ^Stanford Ky^</cell>
	<cell/>
	<cell/>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Huffman &amp; Cook</cell>
	<cell>do</cell>
	<cell/>
	<cell/>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>T. S. Parsons</cell>
	<cell>Merchant</cell>
	<cell>Stanford <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi></cell>
	<cell>Ky <hi rend="str">Rangers</hi></cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>D. W. Vandiveer</cell>
	<cell>"</cell>
	<cell>"</cell>
	<cell/>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Embry &amp; Shanks</cell>
	<cell/>
	<cell>"</cell>
	<cell>"</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Hughes &amp; Engleman</cell>
	<cell/>
	<cell>"</cell>
	<cell>"</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>J N &amp; W Craig,</cell>
	<cell>"</cell>
	<cell>"</cell>
	<cell>"</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>L, A, Lytle</cell>
	<cell/>
	<cell>"</cell>
	<cell>"</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>A R Penny</cell>
	<cell>"</cell>
	<cell>"</cell>
	<cell/>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Whitley &amp; Dunne</cell>
	<cell/>
	<cell/>
	<cell/>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>H. S Withers (one of the Jury)</cell>
	<cell/>
	<cell/>
	<cell/>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>R Carson Co Court Clerk</cell>
	<cell/>
	<cell/>
	<cell/>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>H. T. Harris, County Atty.</cell>
	<cell/>
	<cell/>
	<cell/>
</row>
</table></p>
<p>Stanford Ky
<lb/><date when="1860-01-22">January 22<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> 1860</date>
<lb/>His Excy
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> of Ky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>We ask permission to make a short statement in behalf of the petitioner Ellin Walls -- In addition to her other misfortunes she has some 3 or 4 small children one of what is an Idiot all of whom are dependant upon her exertions for a support and having had her house burnt down she has lost the small handful of goods with which she was possed and she together with her little ones are dependant upon the charity of a few neighbors for a<pb/>
<lb/>support. but for them they would be upon the point of starvation a small allowance is made to her out of the Treasurey for her Idiot child -- But it is far inadequate to her present wants -- The rate of living being excessively high as to the poor of our country we therefore Know of no case in which Your Excellency could interpose which would confer an equal amount of good in cases of this kind -- If you think proper to interpose remit the fine afs<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> we pledge our selves to releive You ^of^ any odium that might or could attach to you by taking the Same upon our Selves</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>Your obedient Servants
<lb/>G. H. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kinney clerk
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Lincoln Circuit Court</hi>
<lb/>Thomas W Napier
<lb/>Presiding Judge lincoln <hi rend="underline">County court</hi></p>
<p>If an answer is given Please address us</p>
<p>Lincoln Cir Ct
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>$100
<lb/>M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> Ellen Walls
<lb/>Issd <date when="1861-01-31">Jany 31 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
