<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0316"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John W. Marques to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4435</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-8 to BR9-9</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Grant County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-11-25">25 November 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thos. E Bramlett Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. The undersigned your petitioner John W. Marques of Grant County most respectfully states and represents that he became the bail of one John Neal upon his recognizance to answer to a charge of Felony in the Grant Circuit Court- that soon after your petitioner became the bail of the said John Neal as aforesaid the said John Neal was notified and required by a large ^number of^ determined and dangerous men to leave and forever abandon Grant County and not return to it under the penalty of death. That had the said Neal remainded in or returned to Grant County to answer to said charge it would have been at the peril of his life as almost the entire community in which he lived embracing portions of the Counties of Grant, Harrison, Scott &amp; Owen were greatly enraged and inflamed at and openly threatened his life upon his failing to leave or his return to Grant County. Neal abandoned the County, has never returned, did not appear<pb/>
<lb/>to answer said charge and at the <date when="1862-10">October Term 1862</date> of the Grant Circuit Court an order was made on motion of the Commonwealth attorney forfeiting said recognizance and at the <date when="1863-05">May Term 1863</date>. Judgment rendered thereon against your petitioner and said John Neal for Eight Hundred Dollars the amount of said bail bond and Execution is now in the hands of the Sheriff of Grant for collection returnable on the Fourth Monday of December next. Neal is worthless and has abandonded the state but would return but for the threats aforesaid. Your petitioner further states that although the judgment recites that a summons had been served upon the "<hi rend="underline">Defendants</hi>" that it was not served upon Neal but was returned by the sheriff of Grant not served as to Neal he files as part hereof copies of said order of forefeiture, Judgment, summons and return. Your petitioner is a poor man of Sixty Seven years of age whose estate consists of a poor hill farm in Grant County of Two Hundred acres. To compell him to pay said<pb/>
<lb/>Judgment would break him up and leave him in poverty to support himself and a large family of <hi rend="str">dang</hi> children and grand children one of them deaf and dumb and including the wife ^&amp; seven children^ of a son <hi rend="str">and seven children</hi> who is a soldier in the Federal service in the Eighteenth Kentucky Regiment. Wherefore he most respectfully requesets your Excelency to remit so much of the judgment as is <hi rend="str">in</hi> ^within^ your consitutional power to do.</p>
<p>Grant County <date when="1863-11-25">Nov 25"1863</date>
<lb/>John ^his X mark^ W Marques
<lb/>attest 
<lb/>W S Rankin</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens and acquaintances of the above petitioner John W. Marques fully corroborate the statements set forth in this petition from their own personal knowledge and the most reliable information. and most respectfully and earnestly ask for him the relief sought</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>John Metcalfe
<lb/>J Q Gouge
<lb/>W. Geo. Levin
<lb/>H H Sully
<lb/><cb n="2"/>W. G. Frank
<lb/>J. W. Collins
<lb/>Floyd Wilson
<lb/>M Burnett
<lb/>M P Savage<pb/></p>
<p><cb n="1"/>W H Hume
<lb/>J W <unclear/>
<lb/>William Smith
<lb/>W. T. Simmons
<lb/>A Kendall
<lb/>B. Stewart
<lb/>James Lemmon
<lb/>Willis Marksberry Sr
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> A Franklin
<lb/>D. L. Cunningham S
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. W. Hutchinson
<lb/>Frank Hodge
<lb/>R. A. Collins
<lb/>F Burch
<lb/>John Rains
<lb/>W. T. Tully
<lb/>John Lotts
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Darie Bass
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi>. S. Annis
<lb/>T. S. Porter
<lb/>B. N. Carter
<lb/>Saml Marnsbury<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>Grant Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>J. W. Marques
<lb/>Bail Bond
<lb/>$800 -- 
<lb/><date when="1864-01-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Jany/<hi rend="underline">64</hi></date></p>
<p>Remit except fees &amp; costs as to Marques
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
