<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1641"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Rice, et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6278</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-99 to BR13-100</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Richmond, Madison County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865">1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Richmond Ky <date when="1865">1865</date>
<lb/>Hon. Thomas E. Bramlette
<lb/>Govenor of Kentucky
<lb/>Frankfort Ky.
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Madison County Ky would respectfully represent to your Excellency that on the day of <gap/> <date when="1864">1864</date> the Grand Jury of the aforesaid County Indicted Edward Paris for Assaulting Thomas Palmer of the same county and on the <gap/> day of the <date when="1865-03">March Term of the Madison Circuit Court for 1865</date> he was tried and sentenced to pay a fine of "$25.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi>" and be imprisoned "four months". Palmer &amp; Paris are neighbors; Palmer is in good Circumstances Paris is a poor young man and supports himself and his widowed Mother by daily labor; Paris being a union man and Palmer being considered ^a^ rebel some person informed Paris that Palmer did not like him &amp; that Palmer had spoken Slanderous words about Mrs. Paris his mother; he was thus informed by a young lady friend of honorable character and in whom he had purfect confidence, laboring under the excitement produced by this information<pb/>
<lb/>and seeing Palmer soon afterward he instantly attacked him, striking him twice perhaps &amp; then desisted of his own accord without doing him any material injury. Paris went to trial without a witness in his behalf not having time to obtain the testimony of the young Lady before named who had gone to Jessamine County. Palmer was the only witness in the case, whose testimony would inevitably be biased by his feelings natural under the circumstances. Mr. Paris is willing to pay the fine imposed and admits that he did wrong through excitement produced by his information. He &amp; a brother as poor as himself are the only support of their mother and a sister and it will be a great loss of time &amp; health to be compelled to under go the imprisonment four months. He regrets what he has done. Under all the circumstances we respectfully ask your Excellency to release Edward from the sentence of imprisonment, believing that it is a proper case for the exercise of <hi rend="underline">Executive Clemency</hi>; hoping you will extend to him the Pardon we are
<lb/>most respectfully yours.<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>.. Rice
<lb/>W E Strother
<lb/>L H Ball
<lb/>G. E. Billingsly (dont know
<lb/>anything about Palmers politics)
<lb/>John. G. Taylor
<lb/>C C Ball
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi>. C. Allison
<lb/>J W Harcourt
<lb/>Leonard Storsch
<lb/>John Driscall
<lb/>J M. Shackelford Clk. Mad: Cr ct.
<lb/>Sydney Shanks
<lb/>Will Rodes
<lb/>John M Harris
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Ed W</hi> <hi rend="underline">Turner</hi>
<lb/>David Russell
<lb/>R. H. Johnson
<lb/>U S Assessor
<lb/>J R Williams
<lb/>H. F. Falls. Capt. 53<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> Ky
<lb/>P. P. Ballard
<lb/>Dept. Pro Mar 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Dis Ky
<lb/>J. C. Millis Capt. Co. C. 185<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> O. V. I
<lb/>R. H. Osgood 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Lieut. Co. C. 185th Regt O. V. I.
<lb/>M. G. Mize
<lb/>T J Gorden
<lb/>S. Smith
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J. N. Mize
<lb/>T. P. Ballard
<lb/>J. T. Estill
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H Smith
<lb/>R. B. Cornelison
<lb/>C. R. Estill
<lb/>John Gillen
<lb/>H, C, Staysur
<lb/>James Bates
<lb/>Sam<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Fechhimmer.
<lb/>K Armstrong. Dep<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi>. Col.
<lb/>Frank Bland.
<lb/>W. G. Haley.
<lb/>Joel. W. Rogers
<lb/>G. W. Ballew J P
<lb/>Anderson, Yates
<lb/>A Bernatt
<lb/>A G Bush
<lb/>J N Burton
<lb/>A A Hunter
<lb/>J C Carver
<lb/>A.. Tribble
<lb/>John Taylor
<lb/>J. Francis
<lb/>R. R. Harris
<lb/>Amos. Worrell
<lb/>William Simmons<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>W C Harris
<lb/>Patrick Tuohy
<lb/>Franklin Todd
<lb/>John. A. Warrell
<lb/><cb n="2"/>G W Broch
<lb/>G. H. Kardor.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
