<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2490"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. R. Edwards to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7127</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-460 to BR15-461</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Laurel County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-08-26">26 August 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thomas E Bramlette Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>your Petitioner W. R. Edwards would respectfully represent unto your Excellency that at the Present <date when="1865-08">August Term 1865</date> of the Laurel circuit court The Grand jury returned into said court an Indictment against him for Illegal voting at the late <date when="1865-08">August Election 1865</date> to which Indictment He entered his appearance &amp; pleaded guilty and judgment went against him for fifty dollars your Petitioner would further represent that he was entirely ignorant of the law in relation to voting that he had lived in the district in which he voted for several years but was not quite Old Enough to vote but was advised and believed that if the Judges permitted him to vote and did not Challenge his vote and no one else did challenge it That he could vote without violating law That the officers of the Election nor no one else questioned his right to vote and He thought he was not doing wrong nor violating laws by voting and did vote but when he found out that he had voted in violation of<pb/>
<lb/>law He came into Court entered his appearance &amp; pleaded guilty &amp; Judgment went as aforesaid your Petitioner is a poor man and not a violater of law</p>
<p>The premises considered the prayer of your Petitioner is that you remit said fine for which he will ever feel greatful and promises to trouble your Excellency no more for the remission of fines</p>
<p>W. R. Edwards</p>
<p>W. R. Edwards <unclear><hi rend="str">Says that the foregoing</hi></unclear> the Statements in the foregoing Petitioner are true</p>
<p>W. R. Edwards</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by W. R. Edwards this <date when="1865-08-26">26th day of August 1865</date></p>
<p>C B Farris clk</p>
<p>We believe the Statements in the foregoing Petition are true and join in the prayer thereof</p>
<p>C B Farris
<lb/>R. Boyd
<lb/>W. A. Miller
<lb/><unclear>Jos M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Lean</unclear>
<lb/>S. F. Hibbard
<lb/>James Dees
<lb/>David Y. Lyttle
<lb/>Robrt Hays
<lb/>Wm I Moren
<lb/>John Brock
<lb/>Jarvis Jackson<pb/>
<lb/>John Pitman
<lb/>C Pitman
<lb/>John. C. Blakely</p>
<p>Gov Bramblet</p>
<p>I hope that you will remit the fine against W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> R Edwards for illegal voting</p>
<p>Granville Pearl
<lb/><figure type="hr"/>W. H Randall M. C
<lb/>8<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Dis<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Ky<figure type="hr"/><pb/></p>
<p>Laurel Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> R Edwards
<lb/>$50,
<lb/>Illegal voting
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-10-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Oct /65</date></p>
<p>Fee paid by R Boyd</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
