<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3159"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">E. Lillard et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5278</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-198</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Anderson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thos E Bramlette Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned petition your excellency to pardon Washington Preston who is charged with Killing Washington Gilpin late of Anderson County Ky and who stands now indicted therefore in Anderson Circuit Court He was tried before an examining Court &amp; held to bail in $800, and the Circuit Court fixed the same bail_ We state that Gilpin was a desperate and dangerous man and had threatened the life of Preston and Gilpin began the difficulty when the killing occured_ Gilpin had killed a man before and was known to care but little for human life_ Preston was always a quiet peaceable citizen &amp; wholly inoffensive in his ways</p>
<p>We believe the causes of justice would in no way be injured by the pardon of Preston &amp; we petn your excellency to pardon him</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>E. Lillard
<lb/>E S Dawson
<lb/>L. Mountjoy
<lb/>R P Searcy
<lb/>W.. H.. Boswell
<lb/>J H M Sutton
<lb/>James R. Droffin
<lb/>J. M. Hawks
<lb/>J F Johnson
<lb/>W. N. Witherspoon
<lb/>John F Wills
<lb/>M R Taylor
<lb/>E. G. Harris PH Jordan
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J. F. Smith
<lb/>G W. Catlett <hi rend="str">PCJ</hi> P. J. A. C. C.
<lb/>W J Frazier
<lb/>Person Bond J. P. A. C
<lb/>A A Gordene
<lb/>H H Walker
<lb/>Jeff Searcy
<lb/>Jas M Searcy
<lb/>Samuel Price
<lb/>David Bond
<lb/>Thomas Dawson
<lb/>John Croffer<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>I know nothing of the statements in the petition I have from statements been impressed with the belief that Preston is worthy of executive clemency
<lb/>G H Fenwish c. a c c</p>
<p>I entertain the above opinion
<lb/>Tho. H Hanks
<lb/>J Witherspoon
<lb/>Lemuel Hammond
<lb/>George L Hammond</p>
<p>I acted as the atto of Your Petitoner in the Examining Trial of his case, &amp; I endorse the statements of the petition. The facts as set out were proven before the examining trial.</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>Your obt Servt
<lb/>W. H. Sneed</p>
<p>To Governor
<lb/>Thos E Bramlette.</p>
<p>Anderson Cir Ct
<lb/>Vs
<lb/>N. Gilpin</p>
<p>Refused</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
