<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1032"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. C. Wilkins to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5669</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR[11]-91</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-07-23">23 July 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Bowling Green Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-07-23">July 23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>Thomas E Bramlette Esq.
<lb/>Frankfort Ky
<lb/>Dear Sir.</p>
<p>At the <date when="1860-02">Feby term 1860</date> of the Warren Eq. &amp; Criminal Court two judgts. upon Confession were rendered in favor of the Comth vs E. J smith for keeping a Tipling House, which were respited for one year by yr predecessor for one year except fees &amp; costs which were paid. Since you became Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> a petition was sent up by M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Smith and a recommendation by myself, our Clark Mr. L L Cooke and sff <unclear>Hunt</unclear> &amp; others asking that the two judgts be released -- but have heard nothing from you.</p>
<p>The facts and reasons are there stated for the application and will not here be repeated. I am fully satisfied that it presents a case for Executive Clemency.</p>
<p>I dislike to trouble you again about the matter, but believe if you have not fully settled the case fully, you will look into the case and grant the relief asked, and if required I am persuaded the atto for the Comth M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> W B Jones will unite in asking relief for mr Smith.</p>
<p>Well Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. how are you getting along?</p>
<p>Much sympathy exists for you in the hearts of the <hi rend="underline">truly loyal</hi> <hi rend="underline">men</hi> in this<pb/>
<lb/>part of our State. And from my knowledge of the original Union men in six Counties I practice law in, I <hi rend="underline">know</hi> they stand almost as a unit when they did in <date when="1861">1861,</date> and I dont hesitate to declare that no Executive since my recollection has enjoyed the Confidence of all true men more than yourself.</p>
<p>What I write I know.</p>
<p>As ever yours truly
<lb/>J. C. Wilkins</p>
<p>Warren Equity &amp; Crim Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>E J Smith</p>
<p>Remit.</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette</p>
<p><date when="1864-08-08">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Aug'/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
