<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1493"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George W. Thompson et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10961</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-83 to MG22-84</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To the Honorable Beriah Magoffin Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitoner Geo. W. Thompson would Respectfully represent to your honor that at the <date when="--09">Sept.</date> Term of the Kenton County Circuit Court held in Covington he was fined the sum of fifty dollars for selling to a slave the property of one D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> <hi rend="str">J,</hi>C <hi rend="str">C</hi>J Blackburn of the said county,</p>
<p>and your petitioner would respectfully state that said Blackburn had allowed said Slave to work about the city and had authorised him to employ and pay said boy for his services and that while said boy was thus employed his bar keeper gave him a dram of old Bourbon whisky, for which he was fined as aforesaid the said boy being as he thought entitled to the same, but owing to the strict sense of the law in such cases made and provided your petitioner violated said law not having a knowledge of the same, he further states that he has paid the Attorney for the Commonwealth his fee and replevied the fine <hi rend="str">for</hi> which fine he is able, but unwilling to pay, as he was totally ignorant of the law; Wherefore he <hi rend="underline"><hi rend="str">e</hi></hi><hi rend="underline">Earnestly</hi> <hi rend="underline">prays</hi>, your honour to remit the Bal of said fine and your petitioner will ever pray &amp;C</p>
<p>Geo W Thompson<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Covington Kentucky state that we are well acquanited with the petitioner Geo W Thompson and know him to be a good citizen and a law abiding man and that we believe the statements made in the foregoing petition are true</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Petitioner Names
<lb/>S. C Perrin
<lb/>R. Richardson
<lb/>R K Sumerwell
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi>. Maxwell D. S.
<lb/>J A Goodson
<lb/>A C Ellis
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Petitoner names
<lb/>John R. Ricke, City Clerk
<lb/>H F Bowen<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>I think that the fine pd to the attorney for the Comth of $15. &amp; the costs -- is sufficiently severe for the offense and that the residue <hi rend="str">should</hi> presents strong claim to the executive for remission -- </p>
<p>M. M. Benton
<lb/>Jas. Pryor
<lb/>John F. Fisk<pb/></p>
<p>Kenton Cir. Ct
<lb/>Geo W Thompson
<lb/>Petitions
<lb/>Gov. Ky<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>$50 } Liquor to a slave</p>
<p>Re<hi rend="str">spited</hi>mitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Issd <date when="1861-10-26">Octo 26 1861<figure type="hr"/></date><hi rend="underline">
<lb/></hi>Perrin</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
