<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2416"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">David Schroeder to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7053</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-354 to BR15-355</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-07">7 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Tho E Bramlette Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>I David Shroeder would respectfully state that in the month of <date when="1861-11">November 1861</date> I purchased a cow of Joseph Nicholas on Market streret near 6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> ^street^ in Louisville Ky in open market &amp; in presence of Joseph Kramer &amp; my son John then about 13 years old. On the following day I killed the cow and sent the hide to a tanner. One Geo F. Huber on the same day having lost his cow as he said, went to the tanner and there among about 20 green skins found one which he claimed as the hide of his cow. I was arrested &amp; gave bail for my appearance at the next term of the Jefferson Circuit Court. At the next term in <date when="1861-01">Jan 1861</date> I was indicted for stealing said cow. The case was continued from time to time, till <date when="1864-05-14">May 14<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date> when it was stricken from the docket with leave &amp;c. On the <date when="1865-09-05">5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Sept 1865</date> the case was reinstated</p>
<p>I state that Joseph Kramer shortly after witnessing the purchase of the cow by me as above stated enlisted in the 28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Reg<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Kentucky Volunteer Infanty and was <hi rend="str">killed</hi> wounded and taken to the Hospital in Nashville where he died in the spring of <date when="1864">1864</date>.</p>
<p>My son John left home on Sunday last that is on the <hi rend="str">4</hi>3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> inst to go to Mexico with the intent to remain there several months -- perhaps a year. If I had known that this case would be reinstated I would not have permitted him to leave. I had no notice that the case would be reinstated, and I supposed that it was ended forever.</p>
<p>I state that several other<pb/>
<lb/>persons were present when I bought said cow as aforestated but no person except said Kramer &amp; my son John knew that ^the^ cow which I killed and from which I took the hide claimed by said Huber was the very cow that I bought of Nicholas as aforesaid</p>
<p>I state that Nicholas was killed at the battle of Shiloh, but if he were living he could ^not^ know <hi rend="str">that</hi> the hide to be the same taken from the cow I bought of him.</p>
<p>I should regard my position as dangerous even if my son John was here from the fact that the oath of a young son in faver of his father is regarded with distrust. If Nicholas &amp; Kramer were living and I could procure their testimony I would court an examination, <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> but situated as I am I fear to trust my case to a jury.</p>
<p>I now pray your Excellency to pardon me of the offence charged as will be seen in the Copy of the indictment which I send herewith a part hereof and as in duty bound &amp;c</p>
<p><unclear>David Schroeder</unclear></p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me by David Schroeder on this <date when="1865-09-07">7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of <hi rend="str">October</hi> September 1865</date>.</p>
<p>John N Mattingly
<lb/>Notary Public Jeff Co Ky
<lb/><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">John N. M
<lb/><date when="1865-09-07">Sept 7 /65</date></note><pb/></p>
<p>I Isaac R Greene state that David Schroeder employed me as his atto' to defend him on the charge contained in the Copy of indictment sent with his ^foregoing^ petition I talked with <hi rend="str">said</hi> Joseph Nicholas Joseph Kramer &amp; John Schroeder.</p>
<p>Nicholas said that he sold a cow <hi rend="str">the</hi> to Schroeder on the morning before, that is one day before the hide was claimed by Huber and that the skin resembled that skin which Huber claimed at the tanner's as his -- Nicholas saw the skin in possession of Huber some three days after he got it from the tanner. Nicholas appeared like a good man.</p>
<p>Joseph Kramer &amp; John Schroeder both told me that they were present saw David Schroeder buy the Cow of Mr Nicholas -- they saw him kill her and John took the hide to the tanner soon after it ^was^ taken from the cow as was his custom when his father killed a beef. Schroeder at the time was engaged in the butchering business. Kramer was a simple man -- appeared honest and looked as though he told the truth I considered Schroeder perfectly safe while Kramer was living. On trial before the examining ^court^ there were no facts or circumstances proved against Schroeder. Huber swore positively to the skin and on the proof he was required to <hi rend="str">answer</hi> give bail to answer. I live near to Schroeder and am sure that John Left before the prosecution was reinstated</p>
<p>Isaac R Greene</p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">John N M
<lb/><date when="1865-09-07">Sept 7 /65</date></note></p>
<p>Subscribed &amp; sworn to before me by Isaac R Green on this <date when="1865-09-07">7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of September 1865</date></p>
<p>John N. Mattingly
<lb/>Notary Public Jeff Co Ky<pb/></p>
<p>To the Governor of Ky</p>
<p>We the undersigned pray your Excellency to grant the foregoing petition of David Schroeder.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>The Position in which the accused is placed by the death of an Important Witness and the absence from the County of Another. It seems to me presents some claim for Executive clemency. &amp; particularly so after a lapse of so much time</p>
<p>Geo W. Johnston.
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John N. Mattingly
<lb/>John Sullivan
<lb/>Michal Sullivan
<lb/>Timothy Sullivan
<lb/>Jos,, Clement.
<lb/>Hamilton Pope
<lb/>F G Dannecker
<lb/>H. W. Hinman
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Sam</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi><hi rend="underline">. Matlock</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">E W,</hi> Rutledge
<lb/>L. A. Wood
<lb/>Philip Tomppert Mayor
<lb/>J, H, Price
<lb/>W R Hydes
<lb/>Z. P. Gailbreath
<lb/><unclear>Tervel Wurtele</unclear>
<lb/>Christ Kronmueller
<lb/>N. Oerther</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
