<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0036"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">S. W. Towry et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9504</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17A-98 to MG17A-99</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-01-22">22 January 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency, Beriah Magoffin Governor of The Commonwealth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>We, the undersigned, citizens of Caldwell County Kentucky, have long known Thomas. B. Wadlington &amp; he has ever been considered, a good and true hearted Citizen, Known &amp; noted for his industry and his orderly conduct. The difficulty in which he was engaged with Milton A. Cartwright, did not appear to us, to be of his seeking, nor are we satisfied that the case was presented to the Jury as it really occurred. We hope your Excellency will review the case &amp; give the poor man the benefit of every doubt <hi rend="str">or</hi> ^and we^ desire, that his case may be judged of in mercy, &amp; regarded with favor, &amp; that your Excellency will take into consideration every circumstance that ought to operate in his behalf. And we desire that your Excellency may &amp; will be persuaded that it is consistent with your duty to extend to him executive clemency, &amp; that his life may be spared. either by a full pardon or by a commutation of his punishment -- Yours respectfully, 
<lb/><date when="1861-01-21">Jan'y 21 1861</date>.<pb/></p>
<p>S,, W,, Towry
<lb/>E,, S,, Cannan
<lb/>John W. Davis
<lb/>R H Towery
<lb/>W. S. Fryer
<lb/>I. E. Osborn
<lb/>W, M, Steven
<lb/>V. B. Simpson
<lb/>R, B Judge
<lb/>Amos Sigler
<lb/>P L Hall
<lb/>M H Truman
<lb/>Wm Hicks
<lb/>W. R. Wood
<lb/>H, J, Davis
<lb/>G W Casner
<lb/>J. G. Campbell
<lb/>George Towery
<lb/>H. C. Davis</p>
<p>State of Kentucky Caldwell County</p>
<p>The affiant H. C. Davis states that the foregoing petitioners signed their names to this petition in his presence, he having charge of the same</p>
<p>H, C, Davis</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by H. C. Davis <date when="1861-01-29">Jany 29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>.</p>
<p>J. C. Barnes D. C.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
