<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2027"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. John A. Brooks, et al., Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6664</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-190 to BR14-191</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Webster County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-06-24">24 June 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Webster Circuit Court
<lb/>Th Commonwealth of Kentucky.
<lb/>against
<lb/>John A Brooks Thomas Chandler James P Smith &amp; Joel Johnson</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Webster County in the name and by the authority of the Commonwelath of Kentucky accuse John A Brooks Thomas Chandler James P Smith and Joel Johnson of the crime of Robbery committed as follows Viz. the said John A Books Thomas Chandler James P Smith and Joel Johnson on the <date when="1862-09-30">30th day of September 1862</date> in the County aforesaid feloniously took a Blaze face sorrel mare the property of William Rabourn in his presence and against his will by putting him in fear of some immediate injury to his person against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Jno Barret
<lb/>Commonwealth atty
<lb/>14 Judicial District.</p>
<p>Information by
<lb/>William Rabourn
<lb/>Newton Hunter</p>
<p><hi rend="str">Common</hi> Webster Circuit Court
<lb/><date when="1863-09-17">September 17<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>,
<lb/>Commonwealth Plff
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John A Brooks &amp; c Defts</p>
<p>On motion of the <hi rend="str">de</hi> Plaintiff it is ordered that this cause be continued, thereupon the defendant John A Brooks together with his sureties J. A. Spaulding and D H Hugs &amp; S B Vance in open Court<pb/>
<lb/>acknowledged themselves indebted to the Commonwealth of Kentucky in the sum of Five Hundred dollars to be void however upon the said John A Brooks appearing in this Court on the first day of its next <date when="--03">March term</date> and answer an Indictment for felony against him herein, and not depart without leave of the Court.</p>
<p><date when="1865-03">March Term 1865</date>
<lb/>Comlth Plff
<lb/>against } No. 1.
<lb/>John A Brooks &amp; c Defts</p>
<p>This day came the attorney for the Comlth and by leave of the Court filed the Opinion of the Court of appeals herein, the death of the deft Joel Johnson is suggested of Record, and it is ordered that the cause abate as to him, And the defendant John A Brooks failing to appear It is adjuged that his <hi rend="str">bond</hi> recognizance herein be taken as forfeited and summons is awarded thereon=</p>
<p>I M C David Clerk of the Webster Circuit Court do certify that the foregoing is a true copy of the Indictment. Recognizance and order of forfeiture in the case of Comlth vs John A Brooks &amp; c Indictment No 1. in this Court,</p>
<p>Given under my hand this <date when="1865-06-24">24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> June 1865</date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">M C Davis </hi><hi rend="underline">clerk</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
