<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-022-0004"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Isham G. Harris, Requisition</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG2902</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Requisitions for the Return of Fugitives from Justice, 1859-1861</collection>
      <idno>MG7-157 to MG7-158A</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Nashville, Davidson County, Tennessee</placeName>
    <date when="1861-03-13">13 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Tennessee,
<lb/>EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENT.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>TO HIS EXCELLENCY, THE GOVERNOR OF Kentucky -- </p>
<p>Sir: It has been made known to me that a certain H. H. McManners &amp; Alice Long alias M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Donald alias M<hi rend="sup">c</hi> Manner of our County of Shelby -- stands charged with having in the month of <date when="1861-01">January 18<hi rend="str">5</hi>61</date> unlawfully and feloniously break into the the houses of Mssr Stebbens &amp; Pullen and of M Simon and steal and carry away Goods silver ware &amp;c to the amount of Four Thousand, Three hundred dollars as will more fully appear from an authenticated <hi rend="str">refuge</hi> of Affidavit -- herewith transmitted: And whereas, it has been made known to me that the said M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Manners &amp; Alice Long alias M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Donald alias M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Manner fled from justice and are now running at large in the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>Now Therefore, I, Isham, G. Harris -- Governor of the State of Tennessee, in pursuance of the Act of Congress, entitled "An Act respecting, Fugitives from Justice," do hereby demand that your Excellency will please cause the said M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Manners &amp; Alice Long alias M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Donald alias M<hi rend="sup">c</hi> Manner to be arrested if to be found within the limits of the State over which you preside, and have them safely delivered to I. S. Dyer -- who is appointed Agent on the part of this State to receive the said fugitive from the civil authorities of the State of Kentucky to the end that they may be brought to the State of Te<unclear>nnessee</unclear> and dealt with according to law.</p>
<p><figure type="seal"/></p>
<p>In Testimony Whereof, I have hereunto set my hand and caused the Great Seal of the State to be affixed at NASHVILLE, on the <date when="1861-03-13">Thirteenth day of March 18<hi rend="str">5</hi>61</date></p>
<p>BY THE GOVERNOR:
<lb/>Isham G Harris
<lb/> 
<lb/>E <unclear/> Ray Secretary of State.<pb/></p>
<p>STATE OF TENNESSEE,
<lb/>SHELBY COUNTY. } SS.
<lb/>TO ANY LAWFUL OFFICER OF SAID COUNTY -- GREETING:</p>
<p>WHEREAS, B. <hi rend="str">R</hi>K. Pullen having this day complained on oath to me, that H. H. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Manners &amp; Alice Lo<unclear/> alias M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Donald alias M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Manner late of said County, did, on the <gap/> day of <date when="1861-01">January 1861;</date> in said County, and with the jurisdiction of the Criminal Court of Memphis, unlawfully &amp; feloniously break into the Store House of W A Meier, Cha<hi rend="sup">s </hi>Stebbins &amp; B. K. Pullen under style of Meier, Stebbins &amp; Pullen &amp; steal take &amp; carry away a lot of Silver Plate &amp; other goods of the value about three Hundred Dollars,^the property of said Meier Stebbins &amp; Pullen^ &amp; did break into the Store House of M Simon &amp; Steal take &amp; carry away a lot of Goods of the value of Four thousand Dollars the property of Said Simon contrary to the Statutes in such cases made &amp; provided &amp; against the peace &amp; dignity of the State</p>
<p>THERE ARE, THEREFORE, to command you to apprehend the said H. H. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Manners &amp; Alice Long, Alias, M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Donald alias M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Manners^ if to be found in your County, and bring him before me or some other Justice of the Peace for said County, to answer the premises, and further to be dealt with according to law.</p>
<p>Given under my hand and seal this <date when="1861-03-11">11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of March 1861.</date></p>
<p>J. Horne J. P. L. S.<pb/></p>
<p>Isham G. Harris
<lb/>Governor of the State of Tennessee:<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>To all who shall see these Presents, -- Greeting:</p>
<p>It is hereby Certified, That J. Horne -- whose genuine signature appears to the above Certificate, is and was at the time of signing the same, an acting Justice in and for the said county and State duly elected and qualified</p>
<p>And that full faith and credit should be given to his official attestation as such.</p>
<p><figure type="seal"/></p>
<p>In Testimony Whereof I have hereunto set my hand and caused the Great Seal of the State to be affixed at NASHVILLE, in this <date when="1861-03-13">13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of March 1861.</date></p>
<p>BY THE GOVERNOR:
<lb/>Isham G Harris</p>
<p>I E R Ray
<lb/>SECRETARY OF STATE.<pb/></p>
<p>Tennessee<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Warrant
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-03-14">Mar 14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>H. H. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Manners &amp; Alice Long
<lb/>Felony</p>
<p>STATE OF TENNESSEE
<lb/>VS. } WARRANT.
<lb/>H. H. McManners &amp; Alice Long alias M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Donald alias M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Manners</p>
<p>Executed this Warrant on <gap/> by arresting and bringing <gap/> before J. HORNE, Esq., for trial.</p>
<p>This <gap/> day of <gap/> 186<gap/>
<lb/><gap/>
<lb/>C. S. C.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
