<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1912"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Milton B. Hays to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6549</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-24 to BR14-25</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-05-18">18 May 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E. Bramlette Gov. of Ky.</p>
<p>Your petitioner states that sometime in the year <date when="1861">1861.</date> he was indicted in the Monroe curcuit Court for <hi rend="str">foregoing</hi> forgery, very unjustly,</p>
<p>The circumstances were as follows. Another man named Speer and himself were partners in buying some horses to drive to the south, each one however haveing some horses of their own, But there was a particular horse in the neighborhood, which your petitioner bought and executed his note and Speer's jointly, as he thought he had a right to do by the understanding between himself and Speers, but which right Speer afterwards denied, and caused your petitioner to be indicted as aforesaid, whilst said indictment was depending one Hamilton a gurilla burnt the Court house Clerks offis in Monroe County and all the records amongst which was said indictment and which has never been recovered and perhaps never will be, but he is desireous to have the matter fully settled so that no enemy can distract him upon that score, He states that since that time he has served three years and seven months in defending his county and aiding to put down the rebellion<pb/>
<lb/>as a member of the 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky cavalry, the most of the time under that glorious and galliant Sherman, he traveled with him through his daring campaign <hi rend="str">from</hi> through Georgia and until he reached goldsboro N. Carolina on the <date when="1865-04-10">10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of last month,</date></p>
<p>He has now come home, and wishes to remain a private and peacible citizen and take care of his family and enjoy that peace and quietude for which he has risked his life for the last three years and seven months,</p>
<p>The note to which he put the name of Bennet Speer was for $125. and was payable to James Payne</p>
<p>He now most respectfully asks your Excellency to pardon said offence, though he is perfeclty innocent of any wrong in the matter</p>
<p>Milton. B. Hays</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Milton B. Hays <date when="1865-05-18">May 18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date></p>
<p>W. F Evans J. B. C. C.</p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">W F E
<lb/><date when="1865-05-18">May 18 1865</date></note><pb/></p>
<p>Gov. Bramlett</p>
<p>I hope you will pardon Mr. Hays, I know him well and I never believed from what I heard of the case whilst the indictment was depending, that he was guilty, he has made an active and good soldier, I saw him several times whilst he was in the service, he was cheerfull and full of hope, and beloved by his comrades in arms I hope you will grant his petition I suppose he could get at least two thirds of the people in Monroe County to sign his petition, perhaps all except a few rebels, but I have advised him as he is here now just to send his petition to you at once</p>
<p>Your friend
<lb/>W. F. Evans</p>
<p>Glasgow
<lb/><date when="1865-05-18">May 18. 1865</date><pb/></p>
<p>Monroe Co
<lb/>Milton B Has
<lb/>Pardoned
<lb/><date when="1865-05-31">3<hi rend="str">0</hi>1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> May/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
