<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1640"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Hiram Brogan to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6277</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-98</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Laurel County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-03-19">19 March 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlette Governor of The Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Hiram Brogan would respectfully Represent unto your Excellency that at The <date when="1865-03">Present March</date> Term of the Laurel circuit court he was fined fifty dollars for an assault, he says that when his case was called for trial he entered a plea of guilty and the testimony did not go to the Jury he says it is true that he assaulted the man with his fist but that it was after he had been cursed and abused by the man who was a Stranger without provocation that notwithstanding the mans having abused him as above Stated He knew that he was guilty of the assault &amp; thus plead &amp; did not think of the importance of the jury hearing the circumstances in mitigation Your Petitioner would further State that he is a Peacible Law abiding man never having before been Indicted for any offence and never having troubled your Excellency before for Pardon or remission &amp; is a Poor man The circumstances considered the prayer of your Petitioner is that your Excellency remit said fine for which he will ever feel greatful</p>
<p>Hiram Brogan<pb/></p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>County of Laurel } SS</p>
<p>Subscribed &amp; Sworn to before me by The Petitioner Hiram Brogan this <date when="1865-03-19">19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of March 1865</date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Tho</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi><hi rend="underline">.</hi> J <hi rend="underline">Canifax</hi> P, J</p>
<p>We are Satisfied that the Statements in the foregoing Petition are true and heartly join in the prayer thereof</p>
<p>David Y Lyttle
<lb/>W. C. Gilliss
<lb/>R. Boyd
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W. H Randall</hi>
<lb/>C B Faris Clerk L C C
<lb/>Isaac J Finley
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> L W <unclear>Lavers</unclear>
<lb/>M. L. Rice
<lb/>L. A. Byron
<lb/>W K,, Wilson
<lb/>W H. Bratford</p>
<p>Gov. Bramlett I think the fine in the above case was excessive &amp; ought to be remitted</p>
<p>H F Finley
<lb/>John F Kirby
<lb/>Isaac Jones
<lb/>Wm J. Moren
<lb/>J. W. Ridgett
<lb/>Robrt Hays</p>
<p>Gov Bramblett Dear Sir I hope that you will remit this fine</p>
<p>yours Truly 
<lb/>G Pearl</p>
<p>Laurel Co
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Hiram Brogan
<lb/>$50
<lb/><date when="1865-05-04">4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> May/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
