<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-006-0086"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Samuel Matlack, Warrant</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1132</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Requisitions for the Return of Fugitives from Justice, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR6-109 to BR6-110</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-12">12 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The Commonwealth of Kentucky,
<lb/>To Any Sheriff, Constable, Marshall or Police officer of said Commonwealth,</p>
<p>From information ^on^ oath, given to me by Thos Forman of Jefferson County, There are reasonable grounds for believing, That one Mathew Skifington, <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>now Residing at Peoria in the county of <gap/> Illinois, did on the <date when="--07-01">1st day of July</date> last, Steal, take, and carry off from the person of Said Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Forman, of Jefferson County, a Gold watch and chain, the propety of said Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Forman, Said watch is a ^magic^ <hi rend="str">double</hi> cased watch, with the name of W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Reader engraved upon the inside case, and with a square &amp; compas, also three links engraved on the back of the inside case, and a very heavy gold chain usually known a a vest chain, and worth <hi rend="str">in</hi> the sum of Five Hundred dollars, -- These are therefore to command you in the name of the Commonwealth to forthwith arrest the said Mathew Skifington if he befound within said state, and to take him before some Police Judge<pb/>
<lb/>or Justice of the Peace having jurisdiction in cases of Felony, that he may be tried according to law, and have there then this writ.</p>
<p>Given under my hand as Justice of the Peace for Jefferson County this <date when="1865-10-12">12th day of October 1865</date></p>
<p>Sam<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Matlack J. P J. C<pb/></p>
<p>Requisition on Gov Illoinois &amp; 
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>vs } order for arrest
<lb/>Mathew Skifington 
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Hipwell appt<hi rend="sup">d </hi>Agent
<lb/><date when="1865-10-13">13 Oct/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
