<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2165"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. H. Short to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9241</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-260 to MG24-261</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Hon Beriah Magoffin</p>
<p>Dear Sir Before you proceed farther I ask you to pardon my impudence in thus making free to address you but feeling that from the Nature of the case that I may be allowed to proceed to inform you of the case in question you will if I am Rightly informed, before this reaches you be petitioned for to remit a fine imposed on W B Walters &amp; John Disman at the <date when="--09">September term</date> of the Marsahll Equity and Criminal Court for two hundred Dollars Each Now Sir in there petition they say Nothing of the facts in the case and it is for that purpose that I write the facts are simply these that W B Walters John Dishman Blufort Dishman and Flavius Walters all of them four if you will Notice entered the House of my mother for the purpose of beating me which they did and during the melee B Dishman struck me with an axe severely wounding me on the head with<pb/>
<lb/>the same I will state that on theere trial that the comonwealth proved by T A Crenshaw John B Troutt Hugh English J C Wolpool that on the day previous that these men all had attempted to assault me but was proven and that they then said that they would whip me if they had to go in the house to do it which threat they carried and and that one of the party ran of from here since then leaving three to face the musick and that the same Jury that assessed the fine against W B Walters &amp; John Dishman also assessed a fine against, B Dishman of seventy Dollars &amp; Six -- months imprisonment in the county Jail B Dishman is Not in the petition I will also state that my mother a woman sixty years of age was cruelly abused by the same set of men at the same time and as my health has been such that I was unable to attend to this as it might have been done by having the Citizen of this County to remonstrate against it that is their petition but as is is Now recovering I humbly ask that you will Delay for twenty Days in granting their petiton as in that time<pb/>
<lb/>I shall be able to send you <hi rend="str">your</hi> the whole facts in the case backed by the Resp^ect^full portion of the citizens of Marshall County and as in there case as I have been informed they have had sighers from out of the County men who knew Nothing of the case only that it was a very large fine for to have to pay yours With Respect</p>
<p>W H Short<pb/></p>
<p>Shorts remonstrance
<lb/>Marshall Co in Case Walter &amp; Dishman -- </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
