<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0801"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Sam Sympson to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4920</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-237</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Franklin, Simpson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-05-04">4 May 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Franklin Simpson County
<lb/>Ky <date when="1864-05-04">May 4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>To his Exencely
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Bramlett
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Sir <hi rend="str">I</hi> address you in behalf of John W Roby and his Son Ezra Roby Citizens of Simpson County who were fined in our Criminal Court one $100, the other $50- the onely witness to prove the charge was the Depty Sheriff himself I was a Lookeron in court when the trial took place and I am clearly of the opinion that it is Such a case as calls for Executive clemency I am by no meanes an advocate for violators of our law<hi rend="sup">s</hi> but witnessing the manner of the witness deposing and Suing the great feeling exhibited by him in connection <hi rend="str">of</hi> ^with^ the facts of the case I am clearly of the opinion the Jury Ered the old man has been unfortunate and is much involved his wife is old and helpless and the young man without meanes and in verry poor health If your Exencely careful Justified in remitting the portion of the fines going to the State it <hi rend="str">and</hi> ^will be^ out of charity</p>
<p>Respectfully &amp; co Sam Sympson</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
