<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2672"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas W. Riley to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7309</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-297 to BR16-298</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-11-27">27 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville <date when="1865-11-27">27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Governor Bramlette</p>
<p>I send herewith duplicate of papers enclosed on tuesday of last week which I suppose were lost in the conflagration of the offices, or mislaid in the confusion consequent thereon -- </p>
<p>I defended the prisoner without fee or reward, or the hope or promise thereof I do not on my conscience as a christian man believe he ought to have been convicted on the testimony -- But your Excellency was lawyer long enough to know our partiality <hi rend="str">four</hi> for our clients' causes, and that ^we^ abate nothing or our zeal for our charity clients, but rather increase it, though "the poor we have always with us."</p>
<p>I would have taken down the testimoney and sent with this petition, but suppose it unnecessary as the Jury who found the Verdict, voluntariliy recommend the accused to your Excellency's Clemency<pb/>
<lb/>I beseech your Excellency to interpose in behalf of Patrick Welch, for I do assert on my faith, that in my long experience I never saw a conviction that presented stronger claims on the exercise of the prerogative of mercy -- </p>
<p>I trouble your Excellency with great reluctence -- and because I have not done so often before, I am encouraged to hope for a favorable reponse to this appeal -- But come what will of this,</p>
<p>I remain your Excellency's deeply
<lb/>obliged &amp; verry humble
<lb/>serv<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi>
<lb/>Tho. W. Riley<pb/></p>
<p>I presided at the trial of the Cause referred to in the foregoing letter of the counsel, and think it a proper case for the <hi rend="str">E</hi> exercise of Clemency And unite with the Jury in recommending Patrick Welch to your Excellency's Clemency</p>
<p>Geo. W. Johnston
<lb/>ct Judge</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
