<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0147"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Halsell et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4266</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-231</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-10-02">2 October 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency
<lb/>Govr. Bramlette</p>
<p>Your petitioners, the undersigned, would respectfully represent &amp; state that One, Jesse T. McCormack, was recognized to appear at the <date when="1862-07">July <hi rend="underline">term</hi> <hi rend="underline">1862</hi></date> of the <hi rend="underline">Warren</hi> <hi rend="underline">Equity</hi> &amp; <hi rend="underline">criminal court</hi>, in a bond of <hi rend="underline">four</hi> <hi rend="underline">hundred</hi> <hi rend="underline">dollars</hi>, with the Subscribers his security. The said Jesse T. is &amp; was a young &amp; inexperienced man &amp; by the adice of evil disposed persons &amp; contrary to the advice &amp; wishes of your petitioners, he left this state &amp; of consequince, his bond was, at the <date when="1863-02">Feby. term 1863</date>, forfeited ^and judgement rendered thereon at s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> last mentioned term^ &amp; your peititioners, and now liable to pay the judgement of 400$ so as aforesaid rendered against them. By the courtesy of the Comths" atty. the execution is suspended until so can hear from your excellency. Now we beg leave to state that all of by, with One exception, and in very limited cirumstances &amp; have as much as we can conveniently do to support our families &amp; to pay the afd. judgement, altho" apparently small, will oppress us. Wherefore we respectfully ^pray^ a remission of the afd. Judgt. or so much thereof as you are authorized to remit.</p>
<p>As execution has been suspended<pb/>
<lb/>until we can hear from you. Permit us to hope to receive a favorable response at your earliest convenience.</p>
<p>With high consideration, we are
<lb/>Very respectfully
<lb/>Your Obt Scts</p>
<p>Bowling Green, Ky -- 
<lb/><date when="1863-10-02">Octr. 2nd. 1863</date>.</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Halsell
<lb/>James M. Halsell
<lb/>John S. Jones
<lb/>John W. Grubbs
<lb/>James Jones
<lb/>James J. McCormick</p>
<p>Respite for 12 mos
<lb/>Thos E Bramlette
<lb/><date when="1863-10-24">Oct 24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date></p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Warren County state that we know the gentlemen whose signatures appear above, &amp; have implicit confidence in the truth of their above statements, and concur with them in their ^prayer &amp;^ foregoing petition</p>
<p>Very respectfully &amp;c</p>
<p>W H Payne
<lb/>Wm Loving
<lb/>R Rodes
<lb/>P. Hines</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
