<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2042"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">D. K. Weis and John Alexander to Richard T. Jacob</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6679</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-217 to BR14-218</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Flemingsburg, Fleming County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-05">5 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Flemingsburg <date when="1865-09-05">Sept 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Lieut Gov Jacobs,
<lb/>Dear Sir,</p>
<p>At the request of Lieut Col Patton who is now confined in the Fleming County jail upon a charge of horse Stealing, we address this note to you</p>
<p>He has been indicted in the Fleming Circuit Court, in five Several charges, all for the same offence, From all we have been able to learn in regard to his case, we are satisfied that he had no Criminal intention in taking the horses. He evidently believed that, as a confederate Soldier Acting under the orders of his superior officers in Coming to Kentucky. to recruit his Battalion, gather up Straglers, and stop the Geurilla System, which had proved so ruinous to Many of our Citizens he had a right, by the rules of war, to seize horses, &amp; Mount his Men, as well as himself if necessary, We do not, believe that Patton appropriated one horse to his individual benefit, but those which were seized by him or his orders were for the use of the Confederate Army, -- We think<pb/>
<lb/>he should be turned over to the Military Authorities, and placed upon the same footing as other prisoners of War -- From the tenor of a letter written to him by M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Keenans of Hillsboro, whose Unionism is undisputed you will percieve, in that one instance at least, he was of service to the people of this locality in preventing depredations being made upon them by Evan<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> men who were notorious Guerillas,</p>
<p>We see every day, men passing through our streets and country -- who have been guilty of similar offences, to those charged against Patton, Yet, they are unmolested</p>
<p>We see Northern Men in our Midst -- enticing our negoes to leave their Masters, issuing free passes to them, and in Many other ways demoralizing our negro population -- all of which is in direct violation of our laws. Yet we scarcely hear a whisper in Condemnation of these offendors from our people, but on the contrary many of them who are thirsting for Patton<hi rend="sup">s</hi> conviction -- by their acts approve the deed, From all that he has stated to us -- we believe you can be of service to him -- There is a great deal of undue prejudice against him in this County<pb/>
<lb/>resulting, as we are satisfied from the bad Conduct of others -- Our County during the war was very much annoyed by Guerillas -- A great many robberies were committed by them, and other outrages were Committed. From the best information these outrages were mostly Committed by men disconnected with both armies, and who were plundering for their own personal benefit -- The prejudice against them, has very naturally extended to Patton -- who unfortunately, ^for himself^ was a little late in going out of Kentucky after the surrender of Lee<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> forces -- While we are not the apologists of Col Patton, we think his care should not be made an exceptional one -- Especially as the war has now Closed, and ^sentiments of^ peace and good will are being rekindled in the hearts of our people -- We are Counsel for Col Patton &amp; we therefore address this note to you at his request we are</p>
<p>With much respect
<lb/>Your obt Servts
<lb/>D K Weis
<lb/><hi rend="underline">John Alexander</hi></p>
<p>The indictments against him are the Comwlth vs Oliver A Patton, and stand N<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi> 1, 2, 3, 4 &amp; 5</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
