<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3205"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Z. Corben et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5324</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-384 to BR41-385</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Owen County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov of Kentucky</p>
<p>Whereas at the present term of the Owen Circuit Court John J Auth was fined Three Hundred and fifty dollars for an alledged misdemeaner charged to have been committed on one Jeptha Estes in the <date when="1864">Spring of 1864</date> while the late war was still going on</p>
<p>now we would respectfully represent the circumstances of the case to be about these and John L. Wilhoite who had been a Soldier in the Union Army in the Company of Capt Thos Ward in Col Jacobs, Regiment and that s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Wilhoite came a long and still represented himself to be a soldier and in the service and representing also that he had seventy soldiers under his command ^men at hand^ and that he had orders to arrest sd Estes and for the purpose of doing so forced a number of citizens to assist him in ^making^ this arrest and among the number was your petitioners we would further represent that there was no arrest made no person hurt no property injured whatever sd Wilhoite had always been the name of being a good soldier and ^was^ Orderly sergeant of his company, we would further represent that your petitioner is a very poor man has a large ^family^ <hi rend="str">numbering</hi> a wife and nine children who are entirely dependant on him for a support now therefore<pb/>
<lb/>the undersigned citizens of Owen County would respectfully request you to interpose as far as you may deem proper</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Z Corben
<lb/>H H Head
<lb/>Ben Perry
<lb/>David Water
<lb/>W M Verve
<lb/>Jasper H Wert
<lb/>T E Colman
<lb/>Fedde Cups
<lb/>P. B. Musselman
<lb/>P. Watson
<lb/>W S Watson
<lb/>M Watson
<lb/>W. B. Sharp
<lb/>F A Watson
<lb/>D B Power
<lb/>W C Glass
<lb/>W A Goddard
<lb/>W.W. Glass
<lb/>Jab W Niles
<lb/>James W Sharp
<lb/>P M Nall.
<lb/>B F Wiley
<lb/>J H Wiley
<lb/>J L Gaines
<lb/>B.L. Glass
<lb/>W M Goines
<lb/>George A. Goddard
<lb/>James K Turner
<lb/>Paul Cook
<lb/><cb n="2"/>M Recter
<lb/>Belfield marshall
<lb/>John Marshall
<lb/>William H Romeris
<lb/>J W Head
<lb/>J. M. Moreland
<lb/>Nathaniel Morgan
<lb/>M B Dowell
<lb/>Georg Marshel
<lb/>Thomas Colman
<lb/>M C Wiley
<lb/>J P. Hutcheson
<lb/>J. D. Hutcheson
<lb/>Clat Wiley J P O. C
<lb/>Franklin z Matthews J. P. O C
<lb/>John Perry
<lb/>C. M. Hall
<lb/>S. Hancock
<lb/>G. W. Long
<lb/>T hall
<lb/>William W. Juett
<lb/>Martin Vice
<lb/>charles dority<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="str">Pardon</hi></hi><hi rend="underline">
<lb/>Remit</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
