<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3169"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George V. Hawk et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5288</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-211 to BR41-212</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>New Albany, Floyd County, Indiana</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency, Hon<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Thomas E Bramlette, 
<lb/>Governor of the State of Kentucky;</p>
<p>We, the undersigned, citizens of the city of New Albany, in the County of Floyd, and State of Indiana, respectfully represent;</p>
<p>That there is now confined in your State Prison a man named Josiah Eaton, sentenced for the Term of four (4) years,- more than two of which have now expired. For some six years prior to the commencement of the late Rebellion, the said Eaton resided in this City, during all which time he was a peaceable, honest, and industrious man, and fully enjoyed the confidence and respect of those who knew him. Soon after the commencement of the Rebellion, he was employed by the Government in the capacity of a Teamster, and served as such for sometime After this we have no knowledge of his actions or conduct.</p>
<p>But we do know, and we respectfully invite your attention to the fact, that he has a most amiable and affectionate Wife, with a family of five children betwen the ages of four and fourteen years, who are utterly destitute of property. His wife has hitherto, by her own industry on the most menial labor, managed to provide for herself and children a very meager support, and to keep her family together. For the proper support of his family, and for the proper education and protection of his children, his own labor is almost indespensable</p>
<p>Therefore we, his former friends and acquantances, but not related to him blood or marriage, most earnestly desire your Excellency to pardon and release the said Josiah Eaton, and permit him to return to his wife and family, and<pb/>
<lb/>in so doing we firmly believe that your clemency will not be misplaced.</p>
<p>And as in duty bound, we will ever pray, &amp;c.
<lb/>George V. Hawk Att
<lb/>W. L. Sanderson
<lb/>Mayor City
<lb/>Geo Gresham city Treas
<lb/>R M. Weir, City clerk
<lb/>W. F. L. Morgan City Attorney
<lb/>Herman Akers, ^City^ Marshal
<lb/>W N Foley Clerk F. C. C.
<lb/>Walter L Smith T F C
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Sackett Auditor
<lb/>Josiah Gwin Recorder
<lb/>W. Penn Swift, County Commassares
<lb/>W. Q. Grisham Brig<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Genl</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
