<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0665"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Michael Wyrick to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4784</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-21 to BR10-22</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-03-31">31 March 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency The Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky The undersigned Petitioner would respectfully represent that at the <date when="1864-03">March Term of the Laurel Circuit Court 1864</date> a Grand Jury of Laurel County found an Indictment against him for failing to keep up in his Tavern house the Tavern Rates of said county To which Indictment he entered his appearance and plead guilty and Judgmnt was rendered against him for $75.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi></p>
<p>He states that he had no desire or intention to violate, or evade the law by such fortune the truth is he did not know that it was a violation of law, that it has been but a very short time since he commenced the business of Tavern keeping, and is free to admit that he was not posted as to his duty in every particular.</p>
<p>He also states that as a Tavern keeper he kept Liquors in his house that his two sons Bord Wyrick &amp; Lee Qyrick and Dr Brounly sold Liquors at his Bar without having taken the oath required to be taken by Tavern keepers, that the Grand Jury for the Term aforesaid found an Indictment against each of them for retailing to which they severaly appeared plead guilty and Judgmnt was<pb/>
<lb/>rendered in each case for $20.<hi rend="sup">00</hi></p>
<p>In these cases your petitioner can only plead ignorance of the Law. That he had no knowledge of any act requiring bar keepers to take the same oath as taken by the proprietor of a Tavern That his two sons the said Boyd Wyrick &amp; Lee Wyrick are young men that they were acting under his license. The said Dr Brounly was at the time boarding at his Tavern and under the circumstances the undersigned feels morally bound to meet the responsibility and if said Judgments are collected he expects to pay them out of his own means</p>
<p>He states that no grievance or violation of the penal laws has been committed in consequence of his failure to keep up Tavern rates that in no instance did his charges exceed the rates as fixed (a copy of which he now has), neither has there been any complaint of a violation of the penal laws and he feels confident There has been none by the said Dr Brounly Boyd Wyrick and Lee Wyrick selling Liquor as above stated (except their failure to take the oath as required)</p>
<p>Wherefore your petitioner prays your Excellency to remit said Judgments</p>
<p>Michael Wyrick<pb/></p>
<p>Michael Wyrick says he believes the statemts in the foregoing petition are true</p>
<p>Michael Wyrick</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Michael Wyrick on the <date when="1864-03-31">31st day of March 1864</date></p>
<p>O B Davis clerk</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Laurel County are personally well acquainted with Michael Wyrick and have every reason to believe the statements made by him in the foregoing petition one time that they have heard of no violation of tavern rates committed by him or any other violation of law under his Tavern license save that for which the above named indictments were found. The said Wyrick is a good citizen has lately commenced the business of Tavern keeping in London his means are limited and the payment of the above named Judgment would bear heavly upon him</p>
<p>We therefore respectfully petition your Excellency to remit said Judgments</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>John Farmer
<lb/>John. H. Wilson
<lb/>J. T. Brown
<lb/>John H Carrier
<lb/><cb n="2"/>C B Faris clk L. Cir. Ct.
<lb/>John Carrier
<lb/>Gr. H. H. Thompson
<lb/>Geo. M. Adams Jr.<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. M. Mason
<lb/>Murry Boreing
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H graves
<lb/>Jno. H. Faris
<lb/>H. Q. Blakely
<lb/>C. W. Catching
<lb/>C Pitman
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee
<lb/>Jesse Lovelace
<lb/>W. H. Jackson
<lb/>H. H. Wilson Com<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> 8th Dis<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Ky
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. J. Canifax Presiding Judge the Laurel County Court</p>
<p>Laurel Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Michael Wyrick
<lb/>Dr. Brounly
<lb/>Lee Wyrick
<lb/>Boyd Wyrick
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1864-04-04">4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> April/64</date>
<lb/>Tipling</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
