<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?> 
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1470"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James N. Armstrong to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10938</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-50 to MG22-51</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-09-09">9 September 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Exlencey B Magoffin
<lb/>Gov of the Commenwealth of kentucky your Petitioner Jas N Armstrong would Represent that he was fined before, O, M, Rannal Justice of the peace in &amp; for Shelby Cty the sum of six Dollars &amp; Sixty two Cents for Brech of the peace commited on Election Day the facts of the Case is this that he was attending Election &amp; a Man by the name of Lang attackted him &amp; abused him by using insulting Language &amp; drawing a knife on him &amp; attempti<hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>ng to Stab him Cutting his Cote &amp; Making a flesh wound on the hand when he knocked the said Lang Down &amp; administered such chastisement to him as was nessary to cause him to desist from firther attempts on his Life that they were both taken up before the said Justice &amp; after herring the <hi rend="str">Law</hi> Evidence the said Justice onstructed the Jury that it made no difrenece who be gun the fight or what Lang Dun that they must fine your Petitioner in order to Stop fighting now he state that he is advised that he had a perfict Right to do what he did that he violated no Law &amp; Should not be Required to pay Any fine it is true that the fine is small but the principle is the same<pb/>
<lb/>&amp; that the way times is it harder to pay the amount assesed then &#36;20 a short time back he states that he is a young man having a widowed mother &amp; childrin to suport &amp; that if he was Justifi<unclear>a</unclear>ble in what he did as he clarly thinks he was it would be wrong for him to have to pay Any thing wherefore he prays your Exlenccey will Remit said fine.</p>
<p>Jas N Armstrong</p>
<p>sworn to before me by Jas N Armstrong this <date when="1861-09-09">9th day of sept 1861</date></p>
<p>A G Roberts N P P C</p>
<p>this affiant states that he saw the fight between the pet &amp; Lang on Election day that Lang Cut at Armstrong <hi rend="str">two</hi>, <hi rend="str">or</hi>, <hi rend="str">three</hi>one times with a Knife before he Struck Lang &amp; that what Armstrong did was in defence of his Life</p>
<p>Sworin to before me by Richard Kirk This <date when="1861-10-14">Oct<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 14<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>J, H, Reddish J, P, F, C<pb/></p>
<p>Shelby J. P.</p>
<p>Jas N Armstrong
<lb/>Vs &#125; Pet.
<lb/>Commonwealth</p>
<p>&#36;6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">62</hi></hi> &#125; Breach</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M
<lb/> 
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1861-11-01">Nov. 1. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
