<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-034-0005"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">David Tod, Requisition</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7733</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Requisitions for the Return of Fugitives from Justice, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-6 to R3-9</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Columbus, Franklin County, Ohio</placeName>
    <date when="1800-10-06">6 October 1800</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>DAVID TOD,
<lb/>GOVERNOR OF THE STATE OF OHIO:
<lb/>To his Excellency, the Governor of the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>It appears by the annexed papers, duly authenticated according to the Laws of our State, that William Orr and George Orr, late of Hamilton County, State of Ohio, have been charged by O. W. Dimmick within committing the crime of breaking open the stable of said O. W. Dimick, on the <date when="1862-09-27">27<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of September A. D. 1862,</date> in the night season, within intent to steal, in the County of Hamilton, in the State of Ohio and it has been represented that said William Orr &amp; George Orr, have fled from the Justice of this State, and have taken refuge within the State of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Now, Therefore, Pursuant to the provisions of the Constitution and Laws of the United States, in such case made and provided, I do hereby require that the said William Orr and George Orr be apprehended and delivered to James L. Ruffin Esq who is hereby duly authorized to receive said William Orr &amp; George Orr and convey them to the State of Ohio, there to be dealt with according to law. </p>
<p><figure type="seal"/></p>
<p>In Witness Whereof, I have hereunto affixed my name, and the Great Seal of the State of Ohio, at Columbus, this <date when="1862-10-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of October in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and sixty-two</date></p>
<p>David Tod
<lb/>BY THE GOVERNOR:
<lb/>W S Kermon Secretary of State.<pb/></p>
<p>State of Ohio
<lb/>Hamilton County } ss</p>
<p>Before me the undersigned a Justice of the Peace in and for said County personally came O. W. Dimick and after being duly sworn says that on the <date when="1862-09-27">27<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of September A D. 1862</date> one William Orr and George Orr did in ^the^ night season break open the stable of said affavient with intent to steal in said Hamilton County</p>
<p>O. W. Dimick</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this <date when="1862-09-27">27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of September A D 1862</date></p>
<p>R. Marchant
<lb/>Justice of the Peace<pb/></p>
<p>State of Ohio
<lb/>Hamilton County } ss</p>
<p>This is to certify that I know the within named, O. W. Dimick to be a credable person and intitled to balief
<lb/><date when="1862-09-27">Sept. 27<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1862</date></p>
<p>M. Marchant
<lb/>Justice of the Peace<pb/></p>
<p>The State of Ohio
<lb/>vs } Application for a Requisition
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Orr and George Orr</p>
<p>I W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> H. Kerr Asst Pros Atty in and for Hamilton County Ohio, do hereby certify that I approve of the application herewith made for a Requisition for W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Orr and George Orr, charged with Burglary, that the said parties are now in the state of Kentucky whither they fled from the State of Ohio in order to avoid arrest, that the ends of Justice require that they should be brought back to this State for trial and that if the facts as stated are true <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>a trial would in my opinion result in a conviction I therefore ask that a Requisition upon the Governor of Kentucky and name James. L. Ruffin as a proper person to be appointed agent of the State of Ohio.</p>
<p><figure type="seal"/></p>
<p>State of Ohio
<lb/>Cincinnati, O, <date when="1862-09-27">Sept 27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> /62.</date>
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H. Kerr
<lb/>Asst Pros Atty
<lb/>Ham. Co. O.<pb/></p>
<p>Cincinnati <date when="1862-10-05">Oct 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>Hon David Todd
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>I take the liberty of addressing you to asertain if you have received a letter and affidavit for a Requisition for two men by the names of <hi rend="underline">Orr</hi> they broke into the Stable of one of our best citizens and attempted to steal four horses valued at fifteen thousand dollars they are both Rebels one of their <unclear>brothers</unclear> is a Col in the rebel Army -- the people here are very anxious to have them caught if consistent I wish you would please issue a requsition.</p>
<p>Yours respectfully
<lb/>Jas L Ruffin<pb/></p>
<p>The State of Ohio
<lb/>Hamilton County
<lb/>vs
<lb/>William Orr &amp;
<lb/>George Orr<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Fugitives from Justice
<lb/>Requisition
<lb/>Warrant Iss<hi rend="sup">d </hi><date when="1862-10-09">Octo 9. 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
