<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3300"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Martin Jones to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5419</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-127 to BR42-128</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Laurel County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency Thomas E. Bramlett Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky your petitioner Martin Jones states that at the presant term of the Laurel Circuit Court he was fined in the sum of twenty Dollars on an indictment for gameing Your petitioner states that he is no gambler, but happened to engage in a little game for amusement (where there was merely a treat but) at Mr Gibson,s store in Laurel County-</p>
<p>and he was indicted &amp; fined as above stated, he is a poor man who makes this support of himself and family by honest labour &amp; he therefore prays that your excellency may remit said fine all except the cost</p>
<p>Martin Jones petitioner</p>
<p>We the undersigned are acquainted with petitioner Martin Jones &amp; state that he is a sober industrious harmless man &amp; we pray to be heard in his behalf that your excellency may remit said fine</p>
<p>David M. Lyttle<pb/>
<lb/>We concur in the <hi rend="underline">prayer</hi> of the foregoing petition</p>
<p>R. Herndon
<lb/>R. P. Young
<lb/>L. A. Byron<pb/>
<lb/>Laurel Cir Ct
<lb/>Martin Jones
<lb/>Petition</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
