<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-009-0002"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">E. P. Fyffe to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1157</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR1-1 to BR1-2</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Urbana, Champaign County, Ohio</placeName>
    <date when="1863-09-21">21 September 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">(Private)</note>
<lb/>Urbana Ohio <date when="1863-09-21">Sept 21<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>Thos E. Bramlette
<lb/>Gov of Kentucky
<lb/>My dear friend</p>
<p>Permit an old friend and companion in Arms, to congratulate you on your promotion to Commander in chief of Kentucky. There are no Kentuckians living who are, or can be more rejoiced at your triumphant election, than are the Officers and men of the 26<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Reg Ohio Vol. Infantry, from the first moment of our acquaintance. yourself and myself, your officers and my officers, your men and my men, were more like brothers than strangers, and there was no man in the Army who we were so sorry to part with as yourself, but when we <pb/>
<lb/>did part with you, we were in hopes it would be but a short time, that when you did come back to us, you would come back as a General, that we believed was your just due, but it has turned out otherwise and we are satisfied, Kentucky has done you justice and we cannot ask more, but the time is coming when we hope your own Kentucky will ask for you yet a higher office, We of the 26<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> want you for our Candidate for the Vice Presidency of the U S, and we see no reason why you should not be, Old Kentucky has been loyal to the Union. no living man can say you have not proved yourself loyal and have supported the Union both in the field, and Civil life, and as Gov of your State, and most certainly the northern States will not put forth hereafter, both a candidate for President, and Vice President. not<pb/>
<lb/>while loyal Kentucky can furnish us with as good material as can be found in any of the States.</p>
<p>Think of this matter my dear Colonel and let me know, I have been talking to some of my friends, and all agree with me, if it meets with your approbation, I will begin to "<hi rend="underline">howl</hi>," and and have your name published all over the country as a suitable person. I will do it, "on my own hook", not as coming from you, no one shall know where it came from, all that is necessary, in my opinion, is in some way to have your name mentioned in connection with that office &amp; it will be taken up in Kentucky, and travel all over the country like wild fire, We can but try it, it will do you no harm if not successful, and if successful the very thing we want, Say the word, and "we will let him off"<pb/></p>
<p>I am here on duty, "to take charge of and bring forward all drafted men assigned to Regiments in the Dept of the Cumberland", The authorities are slow in commencing the draft and i may be here some time to come. In addition I have been very lame from an injury received at Shepherdsville last winter when in command of the troops at that point when Morgan &amp; Forrest threatened Lousiville<hi rend="str"> last winter</hi>, I went on to Murfreesboro joined my command, was in command of the Brigade until in <date when="1863-06">June</date> my lameness then continued, but I never missed a Brigade or Division drill, had to be pushed up on my horse, at last Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Garfield insisted that I should go home to get well, after I came home he assigned me to this duty -- I am yet lame but hope I will be well enough to join by the time the draft is made in Ohio.</p>
<p>In the mean time I have, or my friends have for me, tryed to get the people at Washington to do me justice, whether they will or not is to be seen -- You are aware that I am the oldest Colonel from Ohio, yet I have been overslaughed by men that have not seen half the service I have,</p>
<p>If you can find the time write me, I know you are very busy as a matter course, but yet you may find a few minuts</p>
<p>Your friend &amp; obedient servant
<lb/>E. P. Fyffe</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
