<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0448"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Hamilton Pope to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4567</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-205 to BR9-206</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-01-21">21 January 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville, <date when="1864-01-21">Jany 21", 1864</date>.
<lb/>Dear Sir,</p>
<p>Allow me to introduce to you Mr<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Philip Byerback of this city, whose son was yesterday in the circuit court convicted of malicious stabbing. &amp; Whose husband I have known for twenty years, &amp; who is as brave, gallant &amp; loyal a man as can be found anywhere. I appeared as his council in <date when="1863-09">Sept 1863</date> before the Judge of the Police Court -- Judge Johnston -- <hi rend="str">b</hi> the Judge was about to discharge, &amp; would have discharged him, if it had been shown, as it could have been, that the man who was stabbed could have gone to the Police Court. The character of the young man was abund=<pb/>
<lb/>dantly proved before the Police Judge &amp; was very admirable, both for sobriety &amp; amiability. I was taken sick last Saturday night &amp; have not been off of my back since, &amp; am utterly unable to sit up &amp; had to ask my nephew A Q Pope, to attend to the case for me, who reported the pro<hi rend="str">f</hi>f that had been adduced both against &amp; for him, &amp; I was surprised to hear how much the witnesses for the former had colored their testimony they delivered before the Police Court, &amp; how the latter had forgoted In brief - Joseph F. Sanniger, a young stone cutter, &amp; Byerback were attracted by the music of a serenade near the home of the latter, went to the house &amp; were ordered away<pb/></p>
<p>They went away peacably &amp; quietly making no nosiy demonstrations whatever, &amp; on the way down Byerback was knocked into the street &amp; rose from the gutter, into which he had fallen, &amp; said "if thats what you want, come on" &amp; the man hallowed "I am cut". The man stabbed is largely superior to Byerback in strengh, muscle &amp; size. I understand he swore in the Circuit Court that he neither struck, nor pushed Byerback, until after Byerback cut him, &amp; then only he pushed him. In Police Court the opposite was shown &amp; I saw myself on the throat of Byerback the marks of a blow <hi rend="str">w blow on the</hi> between the chin &amp; the ear, sufficient to have knocked down any man or beast In my Judgment the conviction<pb/>
<lb/>is wrong. I say it to you Governor as a gentleman, lawyer &amp; a Christian. May I ask your interference I am yet unable ^to sit up^ &amp; my nephew Mr. Pope writes this for me.</p>
<p>I have the honor to be your obt. sevt
<lb/>Hamilton Pope</p>
<p>Thos. E. Bramlette
<lb/>Gov. of Ky.
<lb/>Frankfort, Ky.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
