<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0758"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George Donaldson to White</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10226</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-179 to MG19-180</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Three Forks, Barren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-03">March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Three Forks
<lb/>Barren County
<lb/>Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1861-03">March 1861</date>
<lb/>D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> White</p>
<p>Sir I have ^been^ put to much inconvenience and expense to recover a large and valuable Knife which was stolen from me by your Son on the <date when="1860-11-05">5 day of Novem<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 1860</date> while I was on a Visit to my friend M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Samuel Murrell who lives in Warren County about 10 miles from Bowlinggreen, he arrived at M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Murrells on the evening of the 5. he ate supper slept all night and had his breakfast in the morning he left without paying his bill, and took my Knife along with him which he found upon the Mantel piece in the parlour. He got to Bells Tavern here that same afternoon being the to where he registered his Name as J. W. White Bowlingreen" he was recognized upon his arrival by M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> John Bell, who had Known him in Danville, we ate supper and went to bed but left secretly about 3 oclock on the following morning without paying his bill he then went on to Glasgow but I feel it unecessary here to state to you the particulars of the robbery he committed on the house of Mr Robb there for which he was afterwards apprehended in<pb/>
<lb/>Greensburgh and carried to the Jail in Glasgow. I went a distance of 9 miles to see M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Robb from whom I obtained some information regarding my knife and I had also a communication from M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> David Denton the Jailor in Glasgow from the particulars I obtained from M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Robb I concluded to go to Greensburgh, and I started off from here on the <date when="--12-30">30 of Decemr last</date> by the Rail road to the Lebanon Junction, and from that I went to Lebanon where I moved that evening, I stayed at the Harvey House in the register will show the following <unclear/> I hired a Buggy and a Black Boy at M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Hoods stables and drove to Greensburgh and stayed all night at Mr Hilliards Hotel, whose son gave me all the information I wanted and told me that he not only saw my Knife in possession of your Son but he saw him sell it to a M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. John Brewer for 50 cents!!!! I went that night and consulted with Mr Golder a Lawyer who was of my own opinion that I should go and see M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Brewer who lives at Brush Creek about 9 miles from Greensburgh. I did so, and saw M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Brewer he immediately acknowledged that he bought the Knife for 1/2$, and had sold it afterwards to a M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Cox for $3- he believed my statements, and said he would endeavor to<pb/>
<lb/>recover my Knife, (I paid him the 1/2$ he gave for it) I would have gone in search of M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Cox, but it not only was some distance off but M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Brewer told me that I might not find him at home, upon learning this I concluded that it would be better to return to Lebanon which I did by crossing Pitmans creek and staying all night at the private house of a M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Bound near Mulders Hill on my arrival in Lebanon I wrote to M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Golder intimating all the particulars, and requesting him to see both Brewer &amp; Cox with whom he had several intrusions and after much trouble and delay he only suceeded a few days ago in getting possession of the Knife, which he forwarded by the Mail rider from Greensburgh to Glasgow who left it charge of M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Denton the Jailor there. I employed a M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Smith to get it for me and on the morning of the <hi rend="str">4</hi>7<hi rend="sup">t</hi>h he handed it to me here.</p>
<p>As we are strangers to each other, I feel it my duty to confirm this statement by referring you (if you consider it necessary) to M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> A. K. Young, who lives about 4 miles from Lebanon on the Danville road with whom I spent two nights who will give you every information regarding me I may here mention, that his Lady is a Daughter of M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Samuel Murrells from whose house my Knife was stolen</p>
<p>I have put myself to just trial<pb/>
<lb/>of truths to establish the theft; but from a feeling of sympathy I have little intention to do so provided that the expence of the mere outlay is remitted to me by an early opportunity_ the particulars of which are as follows.</p>
<p>Driving 9 miles to see Mr Robb - Rail road fares going to and returning from Lebanon- hired Buggy servant and tolls from Lebanon to Greensburgh and back - John Brewer - mail rider c and M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Smith.
<lb/>$18.65</p>
<p>I have not yet paid Mr Golder for his assitance but I could not offer him less than <hi rend="underline">3.</hi>
<lb/>$21.65</p>
<p>I have within included board nor lodging in the above sum }</p>
<p>Having futher reference as required you may satisfy yourself by application to Mr. Frank <unclear>Yorhn</unclear> Lawyer Louisville, or Judge Underwood Bowlingreen</p>
<p>I am Sir Your Ob<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> ser<hi rend="sup">t</hi>
<lb/>George Donaldson</p>
<p>My Knife has been much injured</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
