<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1307"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">A. G. Roberts, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10775</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-196</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-08-06">6 August 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>this affiant A G Roberts states that he sold to Wm Ray a Large Colts Revolver some time before A. J. Hand Jun was Indited for carring conseald weapons that after Ray had bought said pastal he stated that he had got it for young Hand he knew there had been a difficulty between Hand &amp; Ray some time before Ray bought the pistol &amp; this affiant states that it is his Recalection that he told Hand to be on his Gard. before the carring of the wepons by hand &amp; also told him what Ray had said. about Hand when he got the pistol he states that he advised Hand to stay at home at the time of court as he believes his famaly was not in a condision to leave.</p>
<p>A G Roberts</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by A G Roberts this <date when="1861-08-06">6th day of Aug 1861</date></p>
<p>Harvey Smith J. P. P. C.<pb/></p>
<p>A J Hand Sen states that he knows that the wepon for which A J. Hand Jun was Indited for carring was obtained &amp; carred by said Hand for the purpos of defending himself from an apprehended attact from Wm Ray who<hi rend="str">s</hi> he was informed had made threats against him &amp; was carring a pistol for the purpos of making said threats good ^ &amp; he nows that R. J. Hand Jr was told of it^ he knows that the said Hands wife was so sick at the time of Court that it would not have been safe for him to Leave her to come to court in consequence of his falure to attend Court there was no defence made &amp; Judgment <hi rend="str">wher</hi> went on the evdence that he had been seen carring the<hi rend="str">m</hi> Pistol</p>
<p>A. J Hand Sen</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by A J Hand Sen this <date when="1861-08-06">6th day of Aug 1861</date></p>
<p>Harvey Smith J. P. P. C.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
