<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1214"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Joel Baker to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5851</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-366 to BR11-367</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-08-25">25 August 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thomas <unclear>E</unclear> Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>your petitioner Joel Baker would respectfully represent unto your Excellency that at the <date when="1864-03">March Term of the Whitley circuit court 1864</date> the grand Jury of Whitley County found an Indictment against him for Retailing ardent Spirits and ^same was^ returned into court by them &amp; at the <date when="1864-08">August Term</date> of said court thereafter Judgement towit against your Petitioner for twenty dollars your Petitioner would further represent that he sold the Ardent Spirits for which he was fined as aforesaid for one A. J. Curd a vender of Ardent Spirits by Licens without being sworn that he was selling goods in the same Room with said Curd &amp; when he was out Curd attended to business for him &amp; when Curd was out your Petitioner sold groceries &amp; whisky for Curd &amp; not for his own benefit that he received no pay for his trouble in selling same &amp; had no interest in the Whisky sold or the profits arising from the sale thereof but did the selling merely as matter of accomodation &amp; not for gain<pb/>
<lb/>your Petitioner did not even dream of violating the law at the time of selling the whisky or he would not have done so until he conformed to the requirements of the law that your Petitioner was never before Indicted for any offense that he is a law abiding resident &amp; does not knowingly violate the law That he is a poor man just trying to make a start in the world &amp; a living by Honest dealing &amp; Industry. The premises considered the prayer of your Petitioner is that your Excellency Remit said fine for which he will ever feel thankful &amp; will guard against any further violation of law</p>
<p>Joel Baker</p>
<p><note place="left margin">At the time he sold the whisky for which he was Indicted &amp; fined &amp; for a long time previous thereto this county was overrun by the Rebels &amp; there was no U S Mail here &amp; the acts of the Legislature was not then distributed in this county &amp; your Petitioner had no chance to know that the law making the sellers of whisky without being sworn an offense had ever passed or was a law</note></p>
<p>Joel Baker says the Statements in the foregoing Petition are true</p>
<p>Joel Baker</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Joel Baker this <date when="1864-08-25">25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of August 1864</date></p>
<p>C L Creekmore p j w c c</p>
<p>We have Examined the foregoing Petition &amp; believe the Statements therein contained are true &amp; hope your Excellency will <unclear>re</unclear>mit the fine</p>
<p>R. Boyd
<lb/>J.C. Watkins
<lb/>Clerk Whitly cir ct
<lb/><hi rend="str">Tyrel Foley Clerk</hi><pb/></p>
<p>We hope the fine against Mr Baker will be remitted he is a law abiding citizen &amp; dont believe he would knowingly violate the law</p>
<p>H F Finley
<lb/>Granville Pearl
<lb/>John Smith</p>
<p>Whitley Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Joel Baker
<lb/>$20 -- 
<lb/>Remit <date when="1864-09-08">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sept/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
