<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1350"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Fallen to Thomas E. Bramlett</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5987</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-101 to BR12-102</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N001000">Thos. E. Bramlette</persName><lb/>Govenor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Fallen would respectfully state, that at the <hi rend="str">October</hi> Sept Term of the  he was convicted of a misdemeanor &amp; sentenced to six months imprisonment in the <placeName ref="cwgk:P00001161">Jail of Jefferson County</placeName>.<orgName ref="cwgk:O001838">Louisville City Court</orgName> 1864.</p>
<p>The misdemeanor charged was trying to facilitate the escape of a prisoner. Your petitioner will admit that the evidence had on the trial was sufficient to convict, but your Excellency knows that many times circumstances may indicate the guilt of an accused person &amp; he be innocent.</p>
<p>Your petitioner will say this much in his own defence, that he never intended to violate the law, that wittingly he did not violate the law</p>
<p>Your petitioner lives in the <placeName ref="cwgk:P00001160">state of Maryland</placeName>, far away from home &amp; friends: an aged Mother dependent upon him for surport<pb/>
<lb/>a mother whoes heart would be utterly crushed if the terrible tidings reached her that her son, her only son was confined in prison: Sad indeed would be her fate, her hopes all dead, struck with a subtle doom, such as in one short night fell on all the first born of the land of <placeName ref="cwgk:P00001159">Egypt</placeName>. It would be hard if I were alone in the world'; but O, how much more terrible it is when I reflect that my mother must beare the pain of my confinement; she the inhabitant of the lowly cabin, strugling with poverty, &amp; may be with disease; her son far away shut up in prison, no one to furnish sustanance to her feble body, none to smooth her sick bed.</p>
<p>Govenor it is a light thing to pardon me, no wrong has been done any one, no wrong was <unclear>in</unclear>tended: pardon me &amp; I will ever feel greatful, I will never forget my sad dificulty, &amp; as long as I live I will adhear to the right, &amp; my dear mother will be spared the pain I have so feebly endeavored to depict,</p>
<p>Your expectant servant<pb/>
<lb/>William. Fallen</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of the city Louisville unite in the prayre of the petitioner &amp; respectfully ask that your Excellency grant him a Pardon</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00001156">H J Billings</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00001157">Thos J. Frazier</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N002035">Geo. Jonas</persName> Interpreter C. C. of Louisville.<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N002038">Phil Tomppert</persName> Jr C, C, C, L,</p>
<p>I presided at the Trial of the case against the Petitioner, the act charged against him in the Indictment was fully proved to have been committed, but I am Inclined to think he did it when drunk &amp; under the persuasions of some bad men confined in the Prison. I think the punishment he has received is sufficient and I am well satisfied he will not offend in like manner again</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00001155">Geo. W. Johnston</persName>.</p>
<p>being the assistant Jailor I was the principal prosecuting Witness and Think under the circumstances that the petitioner has suffered enough for his offence and I Join in the prayer of the petitioner</p>
<p>Yours Truly <persName ref="cwgk:N002026">H C Thomas</persName></p>
<p>I concur with. Mr Thomas
<lb/>W. G, Reasor city atto.<pb/></p>
<p>Fred'K Wobbe Dpy Clk City Court</p>
<p>Direct to the Jailer of Jefferson County Ky. Louisville Ky</p>
<p>Louisville City Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Fallen
<lb/>6 mos conft in Jail</p>
<p>Remit</p>
<p><date when="1864-11-08">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
