<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0142"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Frances Hodges to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8594</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-218 to R3-219</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hammonsville, Hart County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-12-12">12 December 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Hammonsville Hart County Ky.
<lb/><date when="1862-12-12">December 12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency, James F Robinson, Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>The undersigned would beg most respectfully to transmit to your Excellency the ^copy^ of records in a case against my husband, (Thomas Hodges) &amp; others &amp; beg leave to state that the said Thos Hodges was one of the securities for R D Murry as the records will show and that nothing could or can be made off of <hi rend="str">the</hi> either of the three Murrys, they being notoriously insolvent. So it fell upon my husband who was not able ^at that time^ <hi rend="str">at the</hi> to raise the money &amp; therefore he got Mr. J. Chase to go his security in replevin Bond. My husband (the said Thomas Hodges) was killed in the Battle of Chaplin Hills, near Perryville on the <date when="--10-02">8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> of Oct.</date> last, having been in the service nearly twelve months. He belonged to the 15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Kentucky. (Col. Pope: I am left with a family of children (some very young) with 75 acres of land as a home &amp; but little property besides. Probably not enough to pay the amount of said debt were it put up and sold for cash in hand to the highest bidder. I do not intend &amp; will not suffer the said chase as security for my husband to pay the debt and can not ask for the estate of my husband (the said Thomas Hodges) to be released without releasing the said Chase also. Having here stated briefly the facts in the case I most earnestly beg your Excellency to remit the debt so far as to relieve the little estate of the said Hodges, &amp; Chase and you will confer a kindness upon me &amp; family which will be gratefully remembered</p>
<p>Frances Hodges<pb/></p>
<p>We hereby certify that we are acquainted with all the parties mentioned in the foregoing petition &amp; records of the case and their circumstances and believe all the statements made in the foregoing petition to be entirely correct and hope it will be the pleasure of the Governor to release the estate of the Deceased Hodges &amp; his Security, the said J. Chase.</p>
<p>E Hankins,
<lb/>W. W. Cates
<lb/>John T. Thornbury
<lb/>R S Thomas</p>
<p>Subscribed and Sworan to before me by E. Hankins, W. W. Cates ^John^ <hi rend="str">Thomas</hi>T Thornbury R S Thomas this <date when="1862-12-13">13. Dec. 1862</date></p>
<p>R S. Dawson J P H C<pb/></p>
<p>The forfeiture judgement &amp; bond in replevin in the within Pettn &amp; record remitted in full</p>
<p>J F Robinson</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
