<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0002"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Josiah A. Jackson to Phil Swigert</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14031</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1861</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Red River Iron Works, Powell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-07-23">23 July 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>R R Ironworks <date when="1861-07-23">23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> July 1861</date>
<lb/>Phil Swigert Esqr
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>We have ^had^ a home Guard organized at this place for about 6 weeks. We have made an attempt to procure arms from the Genl Goverment. but have as yet failed most of our men are poor but first rate &amp; these hard times many of them cannot raise Means to pay for their uniform &amp; Gun both. as the freights of on the Guns from the Government will cost $1.50 each. We have money to pay for uniform &amp; music. I wish to know if we cannot get Guns from the State. If we organize according to the late law in regard to Home Guards -- There was 100 Guns I think Given to Genl Johnson<hi rend="sup">s</hi> secession Co of Montgomery Co. He never paraded more than 25 or 30 men I understand that Company is about to disband It was raised under a secession flag. What chance would there be to get 50 of those Guns -- or some from Frankfort. There is a company at Stanton 4 <hi rend="sup">1</hi>/<hi rend="sub">2</hi> miles from me that want guns. Home Guards good men If we could get Johnson<hi rend="sup">s</hi> guns would do for both companies. The company at Stanton I wrote you about several days since marched last Saturday under a secession flag -- <pb/></p>
<p>There has been in the last 3 or 4 days considerable stir amongst the secessionst in this neighborhood. on last Saturday two of them 1 from Paris. R Haw<hi rend="sup">s</hi> son &amp; a man by the name of Cole from Winchester arrived in the neighborhood at 12 oclock at night &amp; next morning early had conference with Some Secessiont &amp; returned Sunday morning. I have had some hints that they expected to make an attack upon the arms in case any should be attempted to be carried through Ky for East Tennessee</p>
<p>I have a Son Geo M Jackson of Winchester. late Editor of the National Union. a paper published in that town who is now engaged in raising a company to Join Genl Rousus Regiment near Louisville or to go to Cumberland Gap if necessary. he has only been at it a week &amp; has about 50 No 1 men &amp; think he will make it from 80 to 100 this week. If not too busy will you please write me. I feel some interest to know where we are to get Guns. We have ^some^ desperate secessionist in our neighborhood &amp; may have to use the guns at home</p>
<p>Your Friend
<lb/>Josiah A Jackson</p>
<p>You might show this to Harry I Todd &amp; other friends you might think proper</p>
<p>J A J</p>
<p>J. A. Jackson
<lb/>Estill
<lb/>Recd Kyans <date when="1861-07-25">25 July 1861</date>.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
