<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2041"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">L. M. Cox to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9117</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-51 to MG24-52</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Flemingsburg, Fleming County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-07-10">10 July 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Flemingsburg <date when="1862-07-10">July 10<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Gov. of Kentucky -- 
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>When in Frankfort in <date when="1862-06">June last</date> I filed with your secretary a petition signed by a number of Gent of Mason and Fleming Counties, praying your Excellency to pardon Henry Heffhenstein and remit the remaining portion of the time he had to serve in the state prison -- and I in conjunction with Mr Cord an attorney who resides here stated that the gentlemen who signed said petition were respectable citizens Since my return -- home I have been requested by several gentlemen to write to you and unite in the prayer of the petition I am satisfied that Helphestein was the dupe and tool of sharper men, who have escaped punishment. And believing that he would not again engage in violations of the criminal laws, and as he has a family, wife, and children I believe, who depend alone upon him for support I most earnestly ask your Excellency to pardon him and release him prison. Henry Helphenstein was a private in the company which I raised and<pb/>
<lb/>commanded in the war with Mexico, and in that service during the campaign he behaved him well and did his duty as a soldier -- Independent of the reasons which would prompt me to interpose in his behalf every true representation of the history of his case and claims to your clemency, his service in my company in Mexico created a strong claim upon my humanity and justice. And I feel that I discharging a pleasant duty in -- presenting his just claims to your favour He has under the sentence of the law remained sometime in prison -- and all that could be expected from his conviction has been accomplished -- and now when a helpness woman and little children require his labour for their support, I feel that I may -- justly appeal to you in his behalf and ask that he ^be^ pardoned and permitted to return to -- their support -- I make this earnest request under a due sense of duty to the community in which Helphenstein resides as well as in accordance with the dictates of humanity to the convict and prisoner. My friend Dr E. Logan will add his request -- and I hope not unavailing petition in the prisoner's behalf.</p>
<p>I am dear Sir
<lb/>your friend &amp; Ob<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Serv<hi rend="sup">t</hi>
<lb/>L, M, Cox<pb/></p>
<p>I fully concur in the statement of Capt Cox and in addition would add that his little farm has been sold under Execution and that he has a wife and five helpless children dependent on the charity of the neighborhood for support, and his pardon would be act of humanity and all the ends of Justice satisfied</p>
<p>Your friend and
<lb/>obed sevt
<lb/>E. Logan<pb/></p>
<p>Helphenstein's Case Par-</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
