<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2037"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Oliver A. Patton to Richard T. Jacob</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6674</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-207 to BR14-207</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Flemingsburg, Fleming County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-08-12">12 August 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Flemingsburg Ky.
<lb/><date when="1865-08-12">Aug 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Governor. Jacobs,
<lb/>Sir -- </p>
<p>Your Excellency will pardon me -- I write at the request of my mother &amp; sister -- your traveling companions en route to the "Rebel" lines whither you were being "<hi rend="underline">Sent</hi> <hi rend="underline">to</hi> <hi rend="underline">your</hi> <hi rend="underline">friends</hi>." by order of Genl Burbridge -- -- And where I hope you were received in the spirit of magnanimity -- &amp; hospitality. -- so characteristic of your Southern Countrymen.</p>
<p>I speak sir of Mrs. Patton &amp; daughters, who were making there way thither to our Father, resident in N. Ca.</p>
<p>I have received several letters recently from <hi rend="underline">home</hi>. (N. C), from my Mother &amp; sisters containing messages of great kindness to you for the distinguished manner in which you entertained them, and honored -- <pb/>
<lb/>them by many kind offices -- </p>
<p>They are very anxious to hear from you -- Should you write me I will communicate your letter to them.</p>
<p>They appear to be much pleased with <hi rend="underline">Lenoir</hi>.The Academy offering fine educational facilities for my sisters, and the healthfull character <hi rend="str">will</hi> of the climate with other causes will combine to keep them from Ky. for perhaps a <hi rend="underline">long</hi> time</p>
<p>They are all well -- Your excellency will excuse me for venturing a remark of myself. I am resting under criminal bans -- and in the hands of the civic courts. "Horse Stealing" is the charge -- I took the horses with which I am charged besides many others not charged to me. -- I did it in my official capacity as Lt Col. of the P. C. S. A -- to mount confederate soldiers -- Can the remedy be reached by executive action? * There <hi rend="str">is</hi> was no "feloneous intent" -- Would be honored by a letter.</p>
<p><note place="left margin">*As to my character &amp; reputation I refer to any respectable Gentleman of Covington Gov. Fisk Col Stevenson.</note><note place="right margin">John G Carlisle -- Hon. G. Clay Smith. -- Menzies &amp; Pryor.</note></p>
<p>Your Most Humble &amp; Obt. Svt -- 
<lb/>Oliver.. A. Patton
<lb/>Lt Col. (late) P. C. S. A.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
