<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1496"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">T. B. Chandler et al. to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10964</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-90</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Germantown, Mason County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-10-01">1 October 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Wheras about the <date when="1861-09-15">15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Sept 1861</date> one John Gallegher Hapened to get Drunk and made some noise in the Town of Germantown and was Taken up and fined by a justice to the Extent of the Law for Drunkeness also fined by a jury of the Country $15" for Disturbing the peace it being the first time anything of the Kind ever Hapened here and the family is Quite poore and have a Large family dependent upon the old man for a suport.</p>
<p>Now we the undersigned petitioners would respectfully Solicit the Interposition of your Honors magisty and respectfully ask you to remitt the fine of $15. as we think it is one of the cases that comes justly in the catilogue thers has bin more agrivated cases committed in our midst and no notice Taken of them we <unclear/> make the above request of your Honor because we Know it to be one of the cases that ought to be <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> excused by you if there ever was one from the fact of there being Nine or Ten children in the Famly all Dependent upon the old man for a suport. your petitioners again respectfully ask <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>your Honor to remitt the above fine believing that the small fine which he will pay and the cost is s great a burden as he can bare. We submitt the matter to your Honor believing you will do what is right in the matter, this <date when="1861-10-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Oct 1861</date></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>T. B. Chandler
<lb/>Arthur Campell
<lb/>William Mingy
<lb/>W. N. Gallaghe
<lb/>E. T. Thompson
<lb/>Anderson White
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/>John Curtis
<lb/>John Curry
<lb/>Samuel Curry
<lb/>Michael Osburn
<lb/>Charles Bradbery
<lb/>Thomas Murphy<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>John Case
<lb/>Eedwardd Ginn
<lb/>J A Mingee
<lb/>M Medows
<lb/>Leadwell Hinson
<lb/>J H Reede
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Morakon
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John Burton
<lb/>Fin Guy
<lb/>Robert Sellers
<lb/>Greenbury Gallagher
<lb/>T H Miller
<lb/>Benjain Hinson
<lb/>Alfred Knight<cb n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Mason J. P.</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>$15 } Drunkeness</p>
<p>Jno. Gallagher
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1861-10-30">Octo 30. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
