<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0833"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Joshua Dunn to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4952</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-285</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-05-06">6 May 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><date when="1864-05-06">May 6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date></p>
<p>To his excellency Thomas E Bramlitt Govr of Kentucky I brought ^several^ suits against G. W. Alford for selling whisky to Negroes he hired or kept my witnesses away I got but one tried I attemped to present him to the Grand Jury he got the witnesses out of the way we tried one case the Jury fined him fifty dollars and cost I am told his is a getting a petition to get his fine remitted I do not know what his plea is but he is selling to every Negro that applies as I will convince you when I get my cases all up I will attempt to get him before the Grand Jury again his object is to keep the Witnesses away but I will summons this Summer to be in time</p>
<p>Yours truly
<lb/>Joshua Dunn<pb/></p>
<p>J. Dunn's Letter
<lb/><date when="1864">64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
