<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1981"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John P. Davis et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6618</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-121 to BR14-121A</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E. Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>The Petition of the Subscribers of the County of Marion State of Kentucky respectfully showeth that one John T. Merrimee a citien of Lebanon Ky -- was indicted before the Circuit Court in and for the County of Marion at its Spring Term of <date when="1865">1865</date> for selling <hi rend="underline">liquor</hi> to a Negro man named "sam" The property of one Henry Gilmere -- was Tried and fined the sum of fifty dollars -- That said John Merrimee is a good Citizen -- and a young man of steady habits and good promise. That he is poor and unable to bear such penalties -- That said Merrimee had returned from service of the United States in the fourth Kentucky Inft when served with distinction and from which he was honorably discharged on account of disability onyly ^a^ short time before the offense charged, That we believe The offence was committed more from carelessness and ignorance Than from any intention to violate the law, -- In full consideration of the character, guilt and inexperience of said John T. Merrimee as also The slightness of The injury done by him The subscribers very earnestly That said fine of fifty dollars be remitted and your Petitioners will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>John P Davis
<lb/>J P Maxwell
<lb/>J M Fiddler
<lb/>L A Spalding
<lb/><cb n="2"/>H D Gilmore
<lb/>B Spalding
<lb/>j. D. Thomas
<lb/>R, H, Rountree
<lb/>Geo W. Riley
<lb/>F M Chandler
<lb/>Ben Spalding Jr<cb n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Marion Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John T. Merrimee
<lb/>$50,
<lb/>Selling liquor to slave
<lb/><date when="1865-06-27">27 June/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
