<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0508"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. S. Ratcliffe to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9976</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-287 to MG18-288</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Smithland, Livingston County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-01-19">19 January 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Smithland <date when="1861-01-19">Jany 19<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>His Excellency B Magoffin
<lb/>Governor of Ky</p>
<p>Der Sir at the last Term of the Livingston Circuit Court Mr H C Murry a citizen and steam Boat Builder at Paducah M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Crackin County was fined One Hundred Dollars for Permiting a fence to Remain a Cross the Public Road</p>
<p>The circumstances are these Mr Murry Living at Paducah Bough a saw Mill on the Ohio River in Livingston County that in fencing up a lot or a small field they had Run it a cross where and old Road had been established for propabily fifty years but the old Ferry had been Discontinued for a number years and the Road was Onely used for those going to the River or mill and the hands at the Mill seemed to knot know there was any County Road there the proof showed there was plenty of Room and Just as near to go along by the side of the fence and that no invonveinance was intended<pb/>
<lb/>or done any One </p>
<p>yet they Jury seeme to feel they had no Discretion and found him guilty of obstructing the Road One Hundred Days Now we would say that Mr Murry is a very Industrious mecanick and would not knowingly violate the Law- and further that the County Court amediately made an Order changing the Road where it had been turned by the building of the fence. Under these circumstancees We beleive this to be a case calling for executive interference and Do hope you will at Once Remit the fine as the sheriff is pressing him for the Money which is verry dificul Rare under the present state of affairs</p>
<p>Your OBT servt
<lb/>R S Ratcliffe<pb/></p>
<p>I have reviewed the statements made in the foregoing letter and find them to be corrct I defended the case for Mr Murry There is one additional fact <unclear/> <unclear/> to consideration. The fence had been built across the road before Murry purchased the land and there was no proof he had knowledge of the road being there until long after he had purchased the land</p>
<p>W. P. Fowler<pb/></p>
<p>Livingston Cir. Ct
<lb/>$100. } <unclear/>
<lb/>H. C. Murry</p>
<p>Remission Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi>
<lb/><date when="1861-01-30">Jany 30. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
