<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0051"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Sebastian C. Vick, Proclamation</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14080</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1864</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>South Carrolton, Muhlenberg County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-07-14">14 July 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Proclamation/Legislation</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>South carrolton Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1864-07-14">July the 14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/><hi rend="str">To all</hi> For the Information of all persons that may Be concerned</p>
<p>On the <date when="1863-11-17">17 day of novr. 1863</date> Thos. E. Bramlett governor of this commonwealth authorized me to Raise a Regt. of State guards and acordingly commissioned and as, col, of Said organization I comenced, Recruiting and on the <date when="1863-12-19">19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of december</date> I was orderd to disband my Recruits which order I obeyed</p>
<p>again on the <date when="1864-05-15">15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of may</date> I was orderd By his Excellency to Raise a Battallion of Soldiers for the purpose of Supressing Guerillars In Southern Kentucky <unclear/> official Instructions to Impress horses to Mount my Battallion on untill the quarter master of this State could furnish horses and horse Equipments for me I am all so ordered to give vouchers to all persons that I Impress property from<pb/>
<lb/>By appointing twoo disinterested men to value Said property which I will Take a pleasure In dooing at any Time when called on By the owners of property</p>
<p>I am further orderd that when any disafected Rebels are guilty of using any language that Is calculated to hinder or discourage my organization that I Sall Imedially arrest all persons So violating those orders and Send them 6th State guard. General Head quarters to Be tried, for treason Before a general court martial</p>
<p>all of which I will obey Respectfully
<lb/>Sebastian C. Vick
<lb/>Col Comd,g, 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Regt Southern Kentucky
<lb/>State guards<pb/></p>
<p>South Ca</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
