<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0267"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas W. Gibson to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4386</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-422 to BR8-423</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-11-07">7 November 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville <date when="1863-11-07">Nov 7. 1863</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency the Governor of Kentucky
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>Your favor of yesterday is reserved informing me that the application in behalf of James Russell for pardon have not come to hand. It was certainly mailed some two weeks since. I enclose duplicates ^of the verdict &amp; Judge's recommendation^. Russell is a mere boy. Was discharged from the army in consequence of wound received in Western Virginia, and if guilty of which I have much doubt, was seduced into the crime by his associate who is an old convict. Russell was drunk at the time, though not in the habit of drinking. His statement is that his associate committed the crime without his knowledge, and afterwards gave him the pistol, ^&amp; money^ which was found on him, and there was nothing in the evidence inconsistent with the statement. He was probably guilty of reseiving the goods knowing then to be stolen, but I feel very confident he has nothing to do with the theft not any previous knowledge that it would be committed. He <unclear>proves</unclear> a most excellent character for honesty. He is the sole dependence of a widowed mother for her support. I respectfully request that a pardon may be granted. He is still retained here until the determination of your excellency can be learned</p>
<p>Very respectfully yours
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> W. Gibson<pb/></p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Jas Russell
<lb/><date when="--11">Nov term</date>
<lb/>Pardoned
<lb/><date when="1863-11-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov/ 63</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
