<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0340"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Neal and Henry B. Wallen to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9808</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-28 to MG18-29</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Clinton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency B. Magoffin governer of Ky. Your petitioners state that at the term of the Clinton Circuit Evin Wallen was indicted by the grand jury for stabing one James Rogers &amp; your petitioners wint his bail for his appearance to answer said indictment. The said bond has been forfeited &amp; Judgment then on against your petitioners for the amt. They state that they in good faith believed that said Evin Wallen would appear and stand his trial, &amp; they also believed &amp; still believe him innocent of the charge, and that the stabing he done was in self defence but being young &amp; easily alarmed he departed the Country without the connivance &amp; against the will &amp; expectations of your petitioners. The person stabed was not serioulsy injured &amp; himself was the agressor having assaulted said Evin with a club They are poor ^&amp; Petitioner Neal has a^ <hi rend="str">with</hi> families and are unable to pay the fine. They hope that all good men who know the facts will Join them in prayer that your excellency will pardon the said Judgment as far as you have the power, It being for one hundred &amp; fifty dollars with Interest &amp; Cost. A copy of the Judgment will accompany this petition. Said Rogers was a large young man, weight about 175 or 80. &amp; Evin Wallen weighed only 135 or 40 &amp; was by<pb/>
<lb/>no means able to defend himself against said Rogers in fair combat. Said Evin Wallen Would have staid &amp; stood his trial, but they complained that the bail your petitioners were not good for the bond &amp; got after him with out authority to imprison him in default of better surety &amp; his friends all being poor &amp; he knowing that he could not give better surety left as they suppose not on account of any fear of Conviction but on account of his dread of temporary imprisonment in Jail for want of better sureties. Your petitioner Thomas Neal is an old man with 11 children and about two years ago got his house &amp; property all burned up &amp; is in great nead of all &amp; more than he has. Said ^Evan^ Wallen is is son in law of Petitioner Neal &amp; he could not see him imprisoned when he thought him not guilty of the offence</p>
<p>Thomas Neal
<lb/>Henry B. Wallen</p>
<p>We Join in the prayer of the petitioners believing that the case ought to meet with Executive Clemency</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Joseph E Hays
<lb/>E L Van Winkle atto Comth
<lb/>B Branham
<lb/>John. J. Denten
<lb/>John Shipley
<lb/>James Craig
<lb/>Wm Henry
<lb/>Wm Lee
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Abner Beaty
<lb/>Jesse Beat
<lb/>Anderson Mainard
<lb/>W Jo <unclear>Tobas</unclear>
<lb/>James perdue
<lb/>Nathaniel 
<lb/>Jones
<lb/>O, H, P, Snow<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>G G Baty
<lb/>C H Myers
<lb/>Enod Talent
<lb/>Wesly Jones
<lb/>David Stockton
<lb/>Levi Barber
<lb/>Joseph Brown
<lb/>Seres Wright
<lb/>Milton Bunch
<lb/>Jasper C Avery
<lb/>J S stockton
<lb/>W Wilborn
<lb/>J A Morrison
<lb/>O P Dickerson
<lb/>E' G Griffey
<lb/>W T. Long
<lb/>John W Marian
<lb/>B F T Hancock
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Holsapple
<lb/>W. L. Hancock
<lb/>J M Gwinn
<lb/>James Sloane
<lb/>Wm Vann
<lb/>C, P, Gray<pb/></p>
<p>Respite 12 M<hi rend="sup">os</hi>
<lb/>B. M</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
