<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-019-0069"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John M. Johnson to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1375</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG5-130 to MG5-131</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Union City, Obion County, Tennessee</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-02">2 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>1st dispatch of this date
<lb/>Union City Tenn
<lb/><date when="1861-06-02">June 2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>To Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Magoffin</p>
<p>Sir, Since My dispatch of <date when="1861-05-31">31<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi></date> &amp; my private note of the <date when="1861-06-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi></date> I determined to Visit Camp Union, at Union City, which is on the line of rail road from Columbus to Mobile, distant from the former place about 25 Miles</p>
<p>I have just had an interivew with Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Cheatham Commanding who has given Me the most satisfactory assurances, that no inrode upon the sovereignty of Kentucky shall be Made as you will see from his note of ths date ^a copy of which is^ enclosed herewith</p>
<p>I am now happy to inform you that all danger of interfearance from the Confederate States with<pb/>
<lb/>our affairs (if there ever was any, which I do not beleive) is set finally at rest</p>
<p>I am happy also to inform you, that there are no men at Columbus, and there has been none; -- The effort of which I apprised you, to throw a disorganized force of 3 or 4.00 men has been a failure, and I am assured that all the force at the Command of the Commander in chief &amp; his officers will be exerted to prevent it, as it has been heretofore</p>
<p>I shall await instructions from you by <hi rend="str">Capt</hi>Lf Cobb</p>
<p>I have the honor to be your
<lb/>Excellencies obt Servt.
<lb/>Jno M Johnson</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
