<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-027-0015"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Gabriel Netter to George D. Prentice</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1248</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R2-22 to R2-23</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hartford, Ohio County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-08-21">21 August 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Head Quarters Netter's Battalion
<lb/>Hartford Ky <date when="1862-08-21">Aug. 21/62</date>
<lb/>George D. Prentice Esq.</p>
<p>You have a right to expect me to do something -- All my friends have -- They have all been kind to me -- I would not have it for the world -- that they ever came to believe unworthy of their kindness -- </p>
<p>I, came to this place -- without a man or a gun -- At my arrival here the homeguards were all out -- on a wild goose chase after guerrillas -- </p>
<p>All that display was made to carry out Gen. Boyle's order to the Major -- Having not over twenty men of his own -- when he contrived to get his order to take the field -- Maj. Shanks intended his campaign as a recruiting expedition.</p>
<p>For that purpose -- he swore &amp; before all who would listen that he was independent of anyone &amp; that whoever joined him -- might rely upon remaining all the time near ^to^ his home -- as his business &amp; men's was merely, to settle difficulties protect the locks &amp; dams on green river &amp;. &amp;.</p>
<p>Such things ruin the "élans" of the Vol. Service -- Once deceived -- the volunteers' enthusiasm is gone forever -- All that imposes upon simple minds &amp; young men -- </p>
<p>The home guards are tired even yet of their useless trip -- Were no account to take a trip with. when coming back from their excursion -- Found myself paralised -- Could not do anything -- </p>
<p>If Gen. Boyle -- had not been imposed upon so thickly -- he would have understood long ago the deception Practiced upon him in the matter.</p>
<p>Maj. Shanks raised most of the 17<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky -- one<pb/>
<lb/>year ago -- After serving with it as a Suttler, Q. M. commissary &amp; Major -- for three months -- the regimental election came on -- His men threw him out of his position of Major -- He went home then &amp; has been home ever since -- </p>
<p>He has now about "one hundred men in all belonging truly to his reg<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi>" -- I state facts -- so help me God -- </p>
<p>His regiment was accepted on the <date when="1862-08-16">16<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> inst</date> -- accepted as Cavalry -- accepted as nearly full -- </p>
<p>Me, I cannot get any satisfaction -- </p>
<p>Generals Finnell &amp; Boyle -- ordered me both to raise cavalry -- the last named Gen. giving me positive orders stating that fact -- &amp; signing requisition to that effect -- </p>
<p>Gen. Finnell tells me, in his writen instructions -- that my men shall be mounted as soon as permission can be obtained from the war department -- That was on <date when="1862-07-25">July the 25<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi></date> -- promising me also -- that if permission was obtained for ^the raising of^ twelve months troops -- the privilege -- should be extended to me as well as to Shakelford &amp; others -- </p>
<p>Gen. Boyle told my Q. M. a few days ago -- that I could not be received as such -- that the order from the war dept. was imperative &amp; universal -- for the non acceptance of twelve months volunteers</p>
<p>As soon as I received the letter stating, such to be the case -- I told my men that they were free again -- from any obligation to me or U.S. -- I had then three hundred men in camp -- </p>
<p>After liberating them -- I called upon them to remain -- for the sake of their State -- cause -- &amp; people -- for their honor's sake -- Two hundred of them remained by my side -- </p>
<p>It was on the <date when="1862-08-14">14<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> inst.</date></p>
<p>H. D. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Henry (who will never forgive me -- to have done with 20 men, that which his brother the Col. refused to do with 150 -- )<pb/>
<lb/>has been at work in Frankfort -- ever since his arrival &amp; there -- doing all the mischief to my interest that he possibly can -- I have been changed from the 1, to the 3, years service -- Mr. McHy. wrote home, to his wife a letter which promenaded the streets here -- with much show -- that I would be ordered away from here &amp; that such an order was made out before he M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Hy. reached Frankfort &amp; -- </p>
<p>I have not received any such order yet -- </p>
<p>Shanks is prominating and the letter of McHenry's to-day -- stating that I will be changed from cavalry to infantry -- or cannot be accepted -- </p>
<p>My men have been changed once -- They must not be changed again -- Wishing one to do such a thing -- would be wanting to drive me out of the service -- The men I recruited are for cavalry -- 100 of them armed (partly only <unclear/> happily) &amp; clothed as cavalrymen -- Wishing to impose upon me &amp; men in any such way would be horrible -- Cannot be -- Would be very unfair and unjust -- </p>
<p>Shanks, who does not know how to drill a squad -- with half of field officers, in the same fix -- waiting to enter the army untill -- (I wont say it -- but may God forgive me -- think it nevertheless) had his regt accepted -- on the <date when="1862-08-16">16<hi rend="sup">th</hi> inst</date> as cavalry -- his strength then was 73 men -- </p>
<p>I will not speak of myself -- but <hi rend="underline">all that</hi> would be much more aggravating yet -- if it was not so very contemptible.</p>
<p>All I ask now to go to work is -- Arms. Horses -- Clothing.</p>
<p>My desires &amp; wishes are to remain in the service -- My prayer to the great Unknown "to let me die -- if die I must on the battle field" -- with my face turned towards my country's foes my last breath expending itself, in a devout kiss -- to <hi rend="str">my</hi> the <hi rend="str">fine</hi> blade<pb/>
<lb/>drawn in defence of our noble &amp; holy cause!</p>
<p>My men must remain "Cavalry" -- George D. Prentice -- for goodness sake -- for the sake of the service -- do no not foresake me -- My heart wishes me to stay -- "quand même" but mistreatment is a terrible blow, to anyone -- Mr Prentice do not allow them to mistreat me -- </p>
<p>The Governor I understand is a just man -- Will you not tell him -- that I am worthy of his protection -- Tell him what may be expected from me -- All I ask is justice -- </p>
<p>Mr. Prentice -- believe me please -- as I am</p>
<p>Truly, Your friend &amp; serv<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi>
<lb/>Gabriel Netter.
<lb/>Lt. Col.</p>
<p>Gov. Robinson, My Dear Sir, I have thought it best to send Col Netter's letter to you. He is unquestionably a most devoted and enthusiastic <hi rend="str">and devoted</hi> patriot, and one of the most chivalric officers in the service.</p>
<p>Very Truly Yours,
<lb/>Geo. D. Prentice</p>
<p><unclear>Col</unclear> Netter &amp;c
<lb/>letter</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
