<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0133"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William S. Beauchamp to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8585</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-204 to R3-205</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>FLeming County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-12-11">11 December 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>James F. Robinson Gov. of Ky.</p>
<p>Your petitioner William Beaucamp States that at the <date when="1861-09">September term of the Fleming Circuit Court in the year 1861</date> he was Indicted by the Grand Jury of said county for cutting and wounding another in ^a^ sudden affray, without previous malice <hi rend="str">another</hi> and also in another Indictment for carry concealed a deadly weapon -- which indictments are still pending and undetermined in said court -- The cutting and stabbing charged in the indictment took place under the following circumstances -- The person cut and stabbed was John Keithly a man of very bad character both as to honesty and peaceable habits -- a man who had been frequently engaged in brawls and fights, and notoriously a dangerous violent man -- your petitioner was summoned as a witness to give evidence on the part of the Commonwealth against a man for stealing a pocket book and some money, who was an associate and neighbour of Keithleys -- Keithley had declared that petitioner should not give testimony in the case and threatened to drive petitioner from town if he appeared -- Petitioner went to town in obedience to the summons and having heard of Keithley's threat he had a small sheath knife on for his personal defence if he should be assaulted -- <pb/>
<lb/>There was another witness in the same case in town by the <hi rend="str">same</hi> name of Ham, and Keithly early in the day they went to town, assaulted and beat Ham -- and upon your petitioners meeting him and asking him why he struck -- Ham he struck petitioner two blows one with his fist and with some hard substance which he held in his hand which your petitioner believes was a sling shot. Petitioner was stunned by the blows and grappled with Keithley who is a very large and stout man -- and bearing great injury from him he drew his knife and cut him in buttock a flesh wound and not at all serious -- These are the facts and nearly all or quite all of them will be fully proved if the witnesses can ever be got to trial -- Keithly soon after entered into the service of the U. S. as a private soldier and is still in the Service But he voluntarily made a written statement desiring the Indictment to be dismissed which statement is filed in the case a copy of which is herewith filed as part of this petition -- The other Indictment is for housing ^the knife^ which your petitioner and on occasion and which he was induced to carry because of Keithley's character and threats -- One of the witnesses who saw the fight and by whom nearly all the facts can be proved is George Taylor<pb/>
<lb/>who is a soldier in the 10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Reg<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> of Ky. Cav. in the Service of the United States -- Your petitioner is also a true and loyal man to the Government and has always been -- He is a mechanic and poor and has a wife and five children to support and raise by his labour -- He wishes to remove to the state of Illinois where he believes he can better his condition -- But he can not leave with the indictment hanging against him without subjecting himself to more expense than he is able to depay in attempting to meet his recognizance without any certainty of the time when he can obtain a trial -- and he is unwilling to forfeit his bail -- The attorney for the Com<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> resides some 30 miles from Flemingsburg, and is a <unclear/> to your petitioner and to his case -- your petitioner therefore prays your excellency to interpose in his behalf and repreive him from said Indictments -- and in duty bound will ever pray &amp; c -- </p>
<p>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> S Beaucamp</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by William S. Beauchamp this <date when="1862-12-11">11<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of December 1862</date></p>
<p>John M. Harbeson Clerk
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Fleming Circuit Court</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
