<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1015"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Wesley Berry to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5652</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR[11]-67 to BR[11]-68</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Fleming County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-07-26">26 July 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramblette Govr. of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, your Petitioner Wesley Berry would most respectfully State. to your Excellency, That at the last <date when="1864-03">March Term of the Fleming circuit Court, 1864,</date> a Judgment was rendered against him, in favor of the Commonwealth of Ky. for $20. the penalty demanded by Statute, for a Simple act of retailing Ardent Spirits without a Liscence. The fact and circumstances of the case were, about these: Some ^time^ in year <date when="1863">1863,</date> prior to the finding of the presentment against him, Esqr Hugh S Young and two or three others good law abiding reputable citizens of Fleming County, were out, on a certain Occasion on a fishing expedition, and called at his house and got a small Bottle of whisky, to use whilst in the water with their <unclear>scin</unclear> The object being an innocent and honest one, he filled their Bottle without intending to violate the law He kept no Spirits to Sell by the retail, and only complied on this Occasion as a matter of accomodation He however regrets, the act and will try and do so no more, The amount though small is hard for him to raise, as he is poor having but little means -- He therefore believes the facts of the case present strong and reasonable grounds for the interposition of Executive clemency. He therefore prays your Excellency to remit Said fine, except cost &amp; Officers fees, and in duty bound will ever prey</p>
<p>Wesley Berry</p>
<p>The petitioner Wesley Berry States that he believes the facts Stated in the foregoing are true<pb/></p>
<p>Sworn to before me by the petitioner Wesley Berry this the <date when="1864-07-26">26 day of July 1864</date></p>
<p>T. T. Moore J. P. f. c.</p>
<p>W. T. Dudley clk cty court<pb/></p>
<p>Flemingsburg <date when="1864-07-13">July 13<hi rend="sup">th </hi>1864</date>
<lb/>To Govr. Bramllette
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>I was present in court when this case was tried, and believe the facts as proved <hi rend="str">were</hi> are substantially setforth, and as no criminal intent was intended in furnishing the whisky, but simply an act of accomodation I think you might safely remight the fine against the petitioner, and it would afford him considerable relief as he is poor. and is ignorant upon the subject of the law. I should be gratified if you could feel ^it^ your duty under the circumstances to remit the fine He will have to pay a considerable portion of it any how, and the object of the law ^will^ be perhaps as fully subserved with Sentiments of high respect I remain yours obt servt</p>
<p>L, B, Cox Judge of
<lb/>The Fleming County Court</p>
<p>I have read the above and concur in the sentiments</p>
<p>L M Cox by
<lb/><hi rend="underline">L, B, Cox</hi> </p>
<p>I did not hear the case in court but if the facts as Stated are beleieved by you as Sustained I think that the case is Such as calls for your clemency</p>
<p>Wm S Botts<pb/></p>
<p>Fleming Cir Ct vs Wesley Berry
<lb/>$20
<lb/>Tipling
<lb/>Remit
<lb/><date when="1864-07-30">30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> July/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
