<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-003-0125"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Unknown to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1642</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR5-217 to BR5-220</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Paducah, McCracken County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-18">18 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>&amp;#9758;Private and Confidential
<lb/>Paducah, Ky. <date when="1865-09-18">Septr. 18th. 1865</date>.
<lb/>To His Excellency,
<lb/>Hon. Thos. E. Bramlette,
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky,
<lb/>Frankfort, Ky.
<lb/>Honored and Respected Sir:</p>
<p>My object in addressing you is to apprise you of some gross and flagrant outrages against the Constitution and laws of This State, which have recently transpired here; and which, I think, call loudly for your interference as Chief Executive of this Commonwealth, to whom is entrusted The execution of its laws, and the guardianship of the people and protection of their rights. -- I will state some facts.</p>
<p>You may be aware That There is here a branch of what is called The "Freedman's Bureau," under the control of Superintendence of one Col. York, of, I believe, The 49th Ills. Infty. (neither officer nor regiment being of This State, while There are plenty of <hi rend="underline">loyal</hi> men here belonging to the State, as able or abler to fill the place.) A citizen of our town corrected (in a mild and humane manner) a negro under him, as he had a right to do, and as customary in case of refractory Servants. The negro, <hi rend="str">as</hi> it seems, made complaint to ^Col.^ York, who had the man ^arrested and^ taken before the city Judge; Smedley; but because ^Col.^ York wanted to introduce <hi rend="underline">negro testimony</hi>, which you know is contrary to the constitution and laws of our State ^and not permitted by them,^ Judge Smedley would have<pb/>
<lb/>nothing to do with The case; whereupon York took it before the Military, had The man fined <hi rend="underline">twenty</hi>-<hi rend="underline">five</hi> <hi rend="underline">dollars</hi> ($25.00,) and gave <hi rend="str">it</hi> ^(the sum)^ to the negro!</p>
<p>In another case, a man corrected his negro servant, was hauled up before York, who fined him <hi rend="underline">one</hi> <hi rend="underline">hundred</hi> <hi rend="underline">dollars</hi>, ($100.00,) and gave it to the negro! (Though it has been whispered by some, That York <hi rend="underline">divided</hi> These fines with the negroes, <hi rend="underline">retaining</hi> <hi rend="underline">one half</hi> <hi rend="underline">himself</hi>!) truly a "money making" business for him!)</p>
<p>But one of the worst and most aggravated cases, was That of the Clerk of a steam-boat, which occurred only a week or two since. He corrected a negro ^boy or waiter^ on the boat, for insolent conduct towards a lady ^on the boat.^ While the boat was at our wharf, the negro went and made complaint to York, who Sent down a <hi rend="underline">negro</hi> <hi rend="underline">guard</hi> to the boat for the Clerk. The boat was backing out, but gave The signal to land, regardless of which it was fired upon by This sable guard; who, it is said, fired several rounds at it, broke The leg of the pilot, and greatly endangered the lives of several <hi rend="str">laws</hi> lady and male passengers aboard. The Clerk was carried before York, who fined him <hi rend="underline">fifty</hi> <hi rend="underline">dollars</hi> ($50.00,) and gave it to ^or <hi rend="underline">shared it with</hi>,^ the negro!</p>
<p>These occurences are taking place every few days; and the negroes, being Thus protected, and paid, are becoming more and more emboldened every day, to commit acts of insolence, lawlessness and violence!<pb/>
<lb/>Such, sir, is The ^lamentble^ state of Things under which we are living and groaning; and which seems to be getting worse every day; and, as I conceive, calls loudly for your interference. What right, I would ask, has Col. York to do These Things, in violation and contravention of the Constitution and laws of our State? There are said to be "Freedman's Courts" -- why does not Col. York have These cases tried before Them; and not make himself the umpire and the court to decide -- the judge, jury and all? If such a state of Things is permitted to be continued, (and if so it will become worse and worse every day, in the nature of such Things,) we will soon be living under one of the worst systems of tyranny, with which a people has ever been cursed!</p>
<p>But This is not all. These lawless and arbitrary acts are producing a state of feeling among our citizens, of the worst, and most ^malignant,^ vindicitive character -- one bordering on desperation, and which, if these things are not stopped, must result in open acts of mutiny and violence, ^and blood shed,^ which is greatly to be regretted. The people declare That They cannot and will not submit to These ^Things;^ and That, if a stop is not put to Them, They will take the remedy into their own hands.</p>
<p>I see, from the papers, That The same State of Things is prevailing elsewhere,<pb/>
<lb/>and engendering The same state of ^ill^ feeling; and, I give it as my opinion, That, if There is not a stop put to it, an insurrection or revolution -- and That Too of the most relentless and bloody character -- will be the result. When a free people -- or <hi rend="underline">once</hi> free people -- become exasperated and goaded on to revenge, ^fearful and^ awful will be the retribution! If The state of Things I have been describing, is permitted to go on ^unrebuked and unchecked^ and become more and more aggravating, as must be the case, it must result ultimately in the extirpation or driving out of the negro!</p>
<p>Hoping that you will do all in your power to rectify The unhappy and disastrous state of Things under which we are placed, and from which we are suffering, and to avert such an awful calamity as That with which we are Threatened, I am, Sir,</p>
<p>Very Respectfully,
<lb/>Your Obd<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Serv<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi>
<lb/>An Unconditional Union Man
<lb/>&amp; one who has always been for the Union</p>
<p>Please excuse my writing on a sheet of foolscap paper, as I can say more upon one Than a sheet of letter paper. I have headed This "Private &amp; Confidential," as, were my real name to become known here as the writer of the foregoing, it might expose me to the vengeance of others.<pb/></p>
<p>P. S.</p>
<p>Permit me to add That, as you are aware, African slavery still exists in This State, in accordance with its constitution and laws; and has never yet been constitutionally and legally abrogated. It also exists in accordance with The Constitution of the United States, by which it is and always has been recognized. The rebellion being over and our state never having Seceded, I cannot regard it as still under martial law; and until the constitutions of the United States <hi rend="str">is amended</hi> and the State are amended so as to abolish Slavery, and the laws on the Subject repealed by the Legislature, I can see no authority whatever, constitutional or legal, for branches of the "Freeman's Bureau," or for "Freedman's Courts," but must regard both as unconstitutional, illegal, unauthorized, arbitrary, oppressive, and at war with the rights and privileges of our citizens.<pb/></p>
<p>I have Stated to you facts which can be Sustained by the most respectable men in this community.<pb/></p>
<p>&amp;#9758;You will please not let Col. York or any one else here see or read this letter; as my hand-right might be recognized, and their vengeance called down on me. I have given you the facts, and inferences, and That is enough, without even giving my real name, as all my assertions and affirmations can be well Substantiated.</p>
<p>Writer</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
