<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2560"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Z. Morrow to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7197</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-95 </idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Somerset, Pulaski County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-03">3 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Somerset Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1865-10-03">Oct 3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Gov Thos. E. Bramblette -- 
<lb/>Dear Sir -- </p>
<p>I herewtih enclose for your favorable Consideration a Petition of Judge G K Marcum of Monticello Ky -- He stands indicted with some thirty others, in the Clinton Circuit Court, for robbing the store house of one Mr Harrisson in Albany in <date when="1862">1862</date> -- He is the only Deft upon whom the process can be executed the remainder having left the state -- He says (and I believe him) that he did not enter the store nor did he reap any of the profits -- His only crime is that he was a member of the independent company and was in Town when the act was committed -- The act itself was done because a short time before, Harrisson had guided a band of guerrillas into Albany to rob D P, White, The act was one of retaliation and not in the mere spirit of plunder. You will remember that for several years the union men of Wayne and Clinton were forced to protect themselves in independent companies -- They sometime committed grave errors but I do not think any crime can be imputed to Marcum -- He has served since that time two years faithfully in the union Army and has made a good Soldier -- He is at present County Judge of Wayne and has always been true to the country -- For this he has incurred the wrath of the Sneaking traitors at home and I have some reasen<pb/>
<lb/>to believe, that the prosecution has been commenced at the instigation of men who are embittered against him on account of his devotion to the country -- Since the courts have opened, the entire terms of the court seem to be occupied with rebel complaints and are about to be prostituted to mere engines of rebel malice and oppression -- This prosecution is of a piece with what is going on all over the state. It has no other end scope or design than the crushing of ^a^ man who had the patriotism and courage to do battle for his imperilled government -- The war is over and the soldiers mustered out and the sneaks now think their time has come -- I make no charge against the officers of the law. I Speak of the out door influence -- Judge Marcum has a young and interesting family and the good name of the family should not be at the Mercy of traitors -- Your interposition before trial is most earnestly asked -- Marcum is alone, The guilty parties have escaped and he is left to bear the entire brunt of the affair -- A traitors blow is descending upon his heard, Your Excellency can arrest it ere it fall, If you do so, You will save a true man and his future conduct will vindicate your Course -- I must cordially and earnestly concur with the petitioners in their prayer for his pardon -- </p>
<p>Yours truly
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Thos Z Morrow</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
