<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1963"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. William A. Lindsay, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6600</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-98 to BR14-99</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lexington, Fayette County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Lexington City Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky.
<lb/>against
<lb/>William A. Lindsay</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of the City of Lexington in the Name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky accuse William A. Lindsay of the offence of suffering gaming &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. Committed as follows viz; The Said William A. Lindsay on the <date when="1865-06-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of June 1865</date> in the county aforesaid did suffer and permit divers games of <hi rend="underline">hazard</hi>, chance and cards upon which money property bank notes Treasury notes and other things of value were bet won and lost, to be played in a house room and or premises in his occupation and under his control against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Z. Gibbons City attorney</p>
<p>Witnesses
<lb/>Geo. Pettit, Jas. M White, W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> White H. Metcalf Sam. Downing Henry Norton H. Clamis, Geo. Cadwalader, Jas P. Gears, Jno Sayre Chas Craig J. B. Ingles, Capt Bell, Maj. A. J. Konkle, Buck. Owens. K Shelton, Stivers (at Craigs store)</p>
<p>Endorsed
<lb/>a. true bill. J. W. Scott. Foreman.</p>
<p>Returned into Court <date when="1865-06-13">June 13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>att Geo K. Letcher C L. C C.</p>
<p>Upon the foregoing Indictment the following Bench warrant issued viz</p>
<p>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>To any Sheriff, Constable, Coroner, Jailor, Marshal or any Policeman in this state</p>
<p>You are hereby commanded forthwith to arrest<pb/>
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> A. Lindsay and bring him before the Lexington City Court to answer an Indictment in that Court against him for permitting gaming in his house; or if the court be adjourned for the term that you deliver him to the Jailor, of Fayette County Given under my hand as Clerk of said Court this <date when="1965-06-13">13 day of June 1865</date></p>
<p>att. Geo K. Letcher C. L. C C</p>
<p>Endorsed
<lb/>The Defendant May give bail in the sum of Two Hundred Dollars; and if he desires to give such bail it may be taken by the Sheriff of the county in which he is arrested or by the Sheriff of Fayette County</p>
<p>att Geo K. Letcher C. L C C</p>
<p>Marshalls Return
<lb/>Executed <date when="1865-06-14">June 14. 1865</date>
<lb/>C. H. Wickliffe D. M C L</p>
<p>True Copies
<lb/>att. Geo K. Letcher
<lb/>C. L. C C<pb/></p>
<p>Dear Govenor</p>
<p>W. A. Lindsay you know keeps the Broadway Hotel here &amp; a first rate house. I know he does not permit gambling in his house or other improprieties -- He is strict in his police of his house -- Of course I know nothing of the facts. Mr Lindsay says he is not guilty &amp; I have confidence in his statements -- There is something of an effort, as I learn, in the city court here to get up cases that will pay the officers I feel sure Mr. Lindsay is entitled to releif &amp; I earnestly recommend it</p>
<p>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi>. B. Huston</p>
<p>Fayette Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> A. Lindsay</p>
<p>Pet<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Premature cannot remit until after Judg<hi rend="sup">t</hi> unless recommended by the Judge or Comths atty -- </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
