<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0033"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">O. J. Skinner to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14062</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1863</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bark Camp Mills, Whitley County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-11-18">18 November 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Bark Camp Mills Ky.
<lb/><date when="1863-11-18">18<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Nov. 1863</date>.
<lb/>Gov. Bramlette -- </p>
<p>Dr Sir -- I have confered with Many Citizens of our County since my return form Frankfort and think I cannot do better than to present the name of Henry L. Gilliss as a suitable person for the office of Lieut. Col. He was formerly Lieut. in the 16<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky. Inf. -- discharged on account of ill health -- and a gentleman. I know the proper channel for such communications is through the Adjt_ Genl -- but having had a conversation with you upon the subject and no acquaintance with the Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> I have taken the liberty to trespass thus far upon your attention,</p>
<p>With regard to the active Militia or S. Guard -- I think two or more companies could be raised in this Co-provided they can feel any certainly of permisison to protect their own borders. They wish to feel that their organization will add to the security of this section of the state. It seems but justice to a county so unanimously &amp; unconditionally loyal -- after furnishing so many men (about 1.00) to the Federal armies, from a sparse population -- that it should -- in furnishing additional volunteers -- receive the benefit of such latitude as may be within the province of the Executive, to exercise -- <pb/>
<lb/>Point Isabel -- is becoming a place of importance. The Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> is making it a Post -- building a commissary Store house 400 feet in length &amp;c. &amp;c. The first rise in the river is expected to bring a fleet of Steam Boats laden with stores for our troops in E. Tenn.</p>
<p>I find no letter paper at hand, and we have little use for record paper at home. Our Clerks have not dared attempt the keeping of their offices open regularly, until Burnside passed beyond us. we have had one session of our Circuit Court in two years.</p>
<p>I am Sir
<lb/>Yours Truly
<lb/>O. J. Skinner</p>
<p>Bark Camp Mills Ky
<lb/><date when="1863-11-18">Nov 18 -- 1863</date></p>
<p>O. J. Skinner recommends Henry L. Gilliss for Lt Col of Whitley County<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>issue Com as above recommended<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Rec<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> I. G. O. <date when="1863-11-23">Nov 23<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
