<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0042"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. J. Maxey to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14071</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1864</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Tompkinsville, Monroe County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-06-22">22 June 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Tompkinsville Monroe County Ky
<lb/>Gov Tho E Bramlet
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>Under ordinary circumstances I would not trouble you with Reading a letter from me; but I feel that you would be glad to know in your present position <hi rend="str">if you</hi> the condition of Each and Every county This conclusion I come to from your position and from my acquaintance with you. You<hi rend="str">r</hi> are apprized of the fact that this county is and ever has been Loyal Every test has proved that. but your attention may not have been called to this county in particular<hi rend="str">ly</hi>. I will state my Recollection in regard to some of the tests In the first race for congress after the rebellion) Grider (Union) against Lewis (Rebel) May for Grider if I am not mistaken was between 700 &amp; 900 Lewis got about 75 votes and in every vote since ^(you perhaps noticed <unclear/>^ in your Race for Governor) the result in proportion was about the same When Volunteers were called for in <date when="1861">1861</date> Monroe furnished a large number the 9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Infantry and 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky cavaly were the main Regiments they joined but other Regments have soldiers from Monroe I think if a neat calculation ^was made^ between 800 &amp; 1000 have volunteered from this county. I could Enumerate many things we have suffered but it would occupy your time and trouble your spirit for no good I am satisfied you are anxious to do all you can for the Loyal people of Ky Every part and from what I have seen from you you have a particular regard for the border The state guard law is made for the state and not for any particular county. There has been some efforts made to get up a company in this county and only about 35 have as yet volunteered</p>
<p>I have talked with some I thought<pb/>
<lb/>ought to volunteer The first excuse is my crop is now on hand and nearly completed if I leave it I cant hire any one to finish it and I dont know how my wife &amp; children are to live with out it. When I consider that scores of families in our couny are without meat or bread I cant see how we are to <hi rend="str">leave</hi> makeout if we leave our crops now but in three weeks this excuse will be to agreat extent removed. Another <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> Excuse or objection I will give that I hope you will consider particulary. Our Col gives his understanding of the law and course to be pursued in this way, That The company to be organized will be armed and six days in each month drilled The remainder of the time they will be at home unless the Col or commander shall deem it necessary to call them together. Men living within ten <hi rend="str">m</hi> or twelve miles of the line say they would be in danger all the time if at home for there are frequently small Raids say form 5 to 10 gurillers in the south portion of our county and they would visit and perhaps punish each volunteer they found at home and if they did not inflict heavier punish ment They would rob such men of all they could use and destroy the balance they say they would prefer if it is possible they could be kept together all the time at least half the company and all if possible (Those who have ^volunteered live nearly all in the south part of the county^) There is truth in their argument I believe the company would be finished by volunteering if the people could be <hi rend="str">allowed</hi> <hi rend="str">to</hi> satisfied the company could remain together but Our Col tells them ^as^ above stated<pb/>
<lb/>Since Monroe has furnished all the men up to now ^that^ have been required by volunteering I hope she will fill this call Therefore I wish you to write to me the remedy for these difficulties if you know of any And if our Col is mistaken I would be glad to know in what respect He is young &amp; inexperienced I hope he anxious to do all ^he^ can for our suffering people</p>
<p>I will only add for your information that there are not now <hi rend="str">300 Malitia</hi> of the original citizens in Monroe county one third as many <hi rend="str"><unclear/> the</hi> malitia anew in this county (In my judgment) as have volunteered from this county but that number appears much larger from the reports on account of the refugees in our county They have come claiming to be Union men we have taken them in and divided of what we had on hand ^with them^ many of whom since they were enrolled have gone back to Tennessee from whence they came I regret to trouble ^you^ to read a letter of such length but could make it no shorter and give the facts Much more I would be glad to say but will close Hoping you will answer <hi rend="str">at</hi> as soon as possible</p>
<p>Yours with Respect <date when="1864-06-22">June 22<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>R J Maxey<pb/></p>
<p>1 Ky. State Militia
<lb/>Tompkinsville Monroe Co.
<lb/><date when="1864-06-22">June 22<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> 1864</date><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Maxey R. J.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>To the Gov. and by him referred <hi rend="str">Giving</hi> stating the loyalty of his Co. and giving the evidence thereof. Giving the number of Vols from his Co. and the Regts in which they Vol. Showing that it has heretofore responded to every call. They have tried to raise a State Guard Company but only 35 men have Volunteered. In about 3 weeks (as the agricultural labor will then be over) he thinks there will be no difficulty in filling up this Co. provided the men, or at least <hi rend="str">that portion</hi> those that reside in the Southern part of the county, will be permitted to remain in camp or on active duty. Otherwise the members of the company will be liable to be injured in person and property by the small bands of Grllas who are constantly in his county. The Col of The E. M. of Monroe County says if the company is organized it will be armed and drilled 6 days in each month; if the Col is right, the evils above mentioned will follow He wants some steps taken to guard against them.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Answered <date when="1864-06-25">June 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi>/64</date> on letter book Page 448<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Rec. I. G. O. <date when="1864-06-25">June 25 1864</date></p>
<p>Inspector Gen'l</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
