<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0425"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">E. B. Begley to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9893</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-161 to MG18-162</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Owsley County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-11-06">6 November 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency
<lb/>B M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin Esq
<lb/>Governor of Ky</p>
<p>Your petitioners beg leave to represent to your honor that on the present <hi rend="str">term</hi> <date when="1860-10">oct Term</date> of the owsley Circuit Court E R Begley was fined fifty dollars and costs <hi rend="str">by the verdict of the Jury</hi> by the owsley Circuit Court on the trial of an indictment on said Court against Begley charging him with Carrying concealed a pistol</p>
<p>The circumstances were about these Begley Carried the pistol concealed but he did so in good faith for the protection of his person for his proper defense that he had been put upon that is imposed upon and actually Knocked down by a very violent man sinking him with a rock that his life had been threatened and was actually in danger of being taken or great harm inflicted on him that he could have proven all these facts and that there had been no reconciliation but he forgot the case being engaged in business his witness promissed to attend court that owing to that he failed to have them sumond and he was forced into trial not having used such diligence as the law required that your petitioners are sure such was the fact<pb/>
<lb/>that he was warranted in carrying the pistol under the circumstances they State Begley is a good orderly citizen that he is a poor man of large helpless family that in all good conscience the fine ought to be remitted which they hope your excellency may see proper to do and as good &amp; Loyal citizens wil ever pray &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi> &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi></p>
<p>Sworn to by E B Begley before me this <date when="1860-11-06">6 day of nov 1860</date></p>
<p>att H F Hensley P J c c</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>John H Brandenburgh
<lb/>Asa Smith
<lb/>W S Hurst
<lb/>Abe, Vanderpool
<lb/>Shelton White
<lb/>W. Willimas
<lb/>E Winn
<lb/>W. H. Glass
<lb/>John C. Cole
<lb/>Andrew Steel
<lb/>W W Treadway
<lb/>A Bowman
<lb/>Isaac Thomas
<lb/>Samuel Gum
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H. Carson
<lb/>H B Hampton
<lb/>L L Marnous
<lb/>John H, Boling
<lb/>John, B, Phillip
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Alex Lafond
<lb/>Wm,, Shelton
<lb/>J. N. Cardwell
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>, I. Daniel
<lb/>H F Hensley<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Boonville Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1860-11-04">Nov 4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1860</date>
<lb/>Dear Gov.</p>
<p>I have read the statement of <hi rend="str">G</hi>Judge Pearl and endorse them fully -- I was also present at the time that He Begley was struck with a rock -- I believ that He would have been acquited if Had gone into a Trial -- I am informed by Mr. Begley that His Lawyer did not understand Him, that when He plead guility -- He only ment that He had carried the pistol -- not that He was guilty of an offence or violation of Law -- </p>
<p>John Dishman<pb/></p>
<p>Boonville <date when="1860-11-03">Nov 3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> 1860</date>
<lb/>Gov Magoffin</p>
<p>Dear sir M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Eliza Begley was Indicted in the owsley circuit Court for carrying concealed a pistol he plead guilty and the law and facts being submited to the court Judgment was rendered for fifty dollars against him he had a difficulty with one W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> B Mize I saw a fects of that difficulty this was at a circuit Court and Mize struck him with a glass rumle as I thought without any cause and hurt Begley very badly at the next court Mize who lived in Madison county come to the court Begley armed himself with a pistol let it fall from his person and he was Indicted for it this is no dout the whole case I know Begley well and he is a prudent clever man and a good citizen and does not carry generally deadly weapons this is the first offence ever charged agnst him I hope you will remit the fine Yours respt</p>
<p>Granville Pearl</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M.
<lb/>Is<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1861-01-03">Jany 3. 1861</date>
<lb/>Owsley Cir. Ct.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
