<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1958"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George Bunch and L. D. Sutton to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6595</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-90 to BR14-91</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-06-14">14 June 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To the Excelence the Govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentuckey your petitianer George Bunch and L. D. Sutton Wold Respectfull Represent to your Excalence that <hi rend="str">some</hi> at the <date when="1865-03">March Turm of the Whitley Circuit Courte 1865</date> that the Courte Renderdd Judgement against George Bunch for $40,00 for gaiming and that said bunch was a pore man and had alarge famley and that he was at that time unable to pay the same and that to Keepe him out of Jail that L. D. Sutton Replevd the said Judgements and that the said sutton is a pore mand ^&amp;^ has alarge famley and not a man that evr is guilty of gaiming and that unless your Excelence enterpose they will have the Judgements to pay</p>
<p>The primis conciderd the prayers of your Petitioners is that your Excelence remit the fine and set asid the Judgement and Replevin Bond and for all Proper Releaf</p>
<p>Gorge Bunch &amp; L D Sutton</p>
<p>sworn to be fore me by George Bunch and L D Sutton this <date when="1865-06-14">14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of June 1865</date></p>
<p>D H Leforce J P<pb/></p>
<p>The under signed says that they beleave it wold be an act of Charity to Remit the fine and set a sid the Judgement &amp; Replevin Bond</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>Isom Jones
<lb/>Joseph Rakr
<lb/>Y. R Harman
<lb/>Ransom Stanford
<lb/>James Janoby
<lb/>James, M Larmance
<lb/>Alex'r Litton
<lb/>T J meddow
<lb/>D H Leforce
<lb/>E E Leforece
<lb/>G B Baines
<lb/>J W. Quentemus
<lb/>T. J. Cox
<lb/>John Smith
<lb/>John T Smith
<lb/>S P Brawner
<lb/>G Litton s w c
<lb/>James M Adkins
<lb/>W C Cox
<lb/>A, R, Barton
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/>Tyrel Faley clerk
<lb/>of the Whitley county cour
<lb/>Jessa Desham
<lb/>E F Adkins
<lb/>J, S, P, of w<hi rend="str">ff</hi> c
<lb/>P w woods</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
