<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2929"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. M. Bush to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7566</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-260 to BR17-261</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Smithland, Livingston County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-12">12 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Smithland Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-12-12">Dec<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>.
<lb/>Govn<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Bramlett,
<lb/>Dear Sir,</p>
<p>Permit us to represent to your honor. That there was at the November term of Crittenden Circuit Court an indictment found against James C Guess of the 20 Ky Regt, for the Murder of <gap/> Eliott. The facts of said Case are these, to wit. Guess was with the 17<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Cavalry &amp; assisted in driving from Crittenden County, Websters Guerilla band, of which Eliott was a member, after they were driven out -- Guess was permited to return home, together with Knight" (of same regiment, &amp; there an acting soldier) when to their surprise they found Eliott, &amp; five more of said Webster gang, in wait for them, M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Ghee, &amp; family went to Guess &amp; told him &amp; Knight, That Eliott with these other Guerillas was there &amp; said they intended to hunt them up &amp; Kill them, Guess &amp; Knight were thus put on their Guard, &amp; on returning home was confronted with Eliott, who came running from a house on the wayside when they shot &amp; Killed him. Now Sir they had orders to Capture or Kill these men from Lt James T Guess of the 17<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Cavly. &amp; one was an acting soldier &amp; because they Killed a bold &amp; notorious Guerilla, they must be indicted, incarcerated, in Dungeon's &amp; expiate a murderous death, for, displeasing Rebels. You may Kill a federal soldiers<pb/>
<lb/>you please, &amp; be recomended for it But We be unto the Blue Coat who dares to Kill a Guerilla, The hangman's Knot is ever ready for his neck, &amp; eternal destruction awaits his future destiny, Sir these facts Can be sustained by <hi rend="sup">3</hi>/<hi rend="sub">4</hi> of the Union men of this County &amp; adjoining Sections, But Sir I have seen proper to refer your honor to Nathan R Black, of the Senate, John Yandell, F, Gardner &amp; Capt Finney of the Lower house, Judge R K Williams "will tell you of my standing" (of <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>Court of Appeals,) Please grant this old man now veteran, a Pardon &amp; relieve the Rebel element of that unearthly glee they now so much enjoy,</p>
<p>With every regard
<lb/>I am Sir your 
<lb/>Obdt Servant
<lb/>J M Bush Late
<lb/>Capt Co G 48<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky vols<pb/></p>
<p>Genrl Palmer
<lb/>Comdg Dept Ky</p>
<p>Sir Be not angry with me in again begging your aid in behalf of one of the noblest soldier of the old War from 20th Ky regt, Who by Rebel influences and packed juries has been indicted for Murder please sign, &amp; assist in the obtaining of a Pardon &amp; oblige</p>
<p>Resp I Am your
<lb/>Eternal Freind
<lb/>J M Bush Late Capt Co G 48<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Infty<pb/></p>
<p>Smithland. Ky. <date when="1865-12-12">Dec 12/65</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Bush J. W.
<lb/>Capt C<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi> G' 48<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky. Vol.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>States the case of <hi rend="underline">James</hi> <hi rend="underline">C</hi>. <hi rend="underline">Guess</hi> of the 20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky. Infantry, imprisoned for the Killing of One <hi rend="underline">Elliot</hi> a notorious Guerilla &amp; Rebel.</p>
<p>Stating, that the Killing was done in selfdefence, and that the deed was more the performance of a soldiers &amp; loyal man duty, than a spontaneous action, he pleads strongly the cause of the Union people in Kentucky &amp; appeals to the chief Magistrate for justice &amp; protection<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>B. #602 -- Vol 2 -- D. K -- <date when="1865">65</date>
<lb/>Rc<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> -- D K. -- <date when="1865-12-14">12 -- 14 65</date></p>
<p>Headquarters Depart<hi rend="sup">mt</hi> of Ky
<lb/>Louisville Ky. <date when="1865-12-15">December 15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi>/65</date>
<lb/>L R</p>
<p>Respectfully referred to His Excellency, Thomas E Bramlette, Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Jef C Davis
<lb/>Bv<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Major General, Comdg<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Crittenden Ct Ct
<lb/>vs 
<lb/>J C Guess</p>
<p>Refer to Gov Bramletter
<lb/><hi rend="str">for <unclear/></hi> -- </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
