<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0003-092-0134"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">C. Lewis to J. Stoddard Johnston</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14424</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>George W. Johnson Papers</collection>
      <idno>Folder 6</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-04-17">17 April 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Franklin Co <date when="1862-04-17">April 17<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 62</date>
<lb/>My Dear Sir</p>
<p>I have received your note in relation to the funeral of my esteemed friend Mr Geo Johnson and am very sorry that it finds me in such a condition that is so impossible for me to speak. I got wet some days since in returning from Lexington &amp; have been in consequence suffering with an affection of my throat, to which I am subject, &amp; have been almost unable to make myself understood untill yesterday &amp; there attempting to read for a few moments at a prayer meeting I became so hoarse as to be scarcely able to speak atall. I know that were I to attempt it I should break down &amp; perhaps produce permanent disease of my throat. It will give me a mournful satisfaction to go to the burial if the weather permits, but you will have to get some other speaker<pb/>
<lb/>I have been this morning informed that the Pastor of Georgetown Church told a minister a short time since who sympathizes with the South that the Church would not permit him to ask that minister unto his pulpit &amp; I very much fear that you will be denied the use of the house. I hope however for the sake of humanity &amp; and the good name of Christianity that no objection may be made. I will go or send to see Mr George Hewet this evening &amp; get him to attend &amp; I have no doubt he will take pleasure in officiating sh<hi rend="sup">d</hi> you wish it.</p>
<p>Please say to Mr<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Johnson that she has my heartfelt sympathy. I know that no earthly consolation can reach her sorrow &amp; I w<hi rend="sup">d</hi> not mock her with this offer. But I trust she has an interest with him who has said he is a husband to the widow.</p>
<p>May God protect her noble boys who are battling for their homes.</p>
<p>Very truly yrs
<lb/>C. Lewis<pb/></p>
<p>Mr J Stoddard Johnston
<lb/>Present</p>
<p>It will not do to rely on the uncertainty of George Hunt's acting, especially from the feeling which prevails in his Church averse to it.</p>
<p>I shall immediately write to D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Rankin to see Mr Mcginn the Pastor of the Reformed Church. I know he will take pleasure in officiating.</p>
<p><hi rend="str">J.</hi> <gap/>J.S J.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
