<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2058"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. H. Thacker to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9134</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-80 to MG24-81</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Barren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-05-02">2 May 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner William H Thacker a resident Citizen of the County of Edmondson &amp; Commonwealth aforsaid, aged twenty five years, and a married man with four small children, would respectfully represent that at the last term of the Equity &amp; Criminal Court in &amp; for said county of Edmondson Judgements were rendered agst him in three cases, one for obstructing the high way and the other two for gaming. In the case for obstructing the high way the facts were that he had simply removed his fence thirty six feet upon better ground so as to put the road upon the line -- As it had seen before it left a very small fraction of his land in the shape of an elipse, across the road -- He made the removal with the consent of his neighbors &amp; of the Magistrate of the District at the time when Magistrates were suffered to have jurisdiction over roads, He did no injury to the road to the neighborhood or the publick and ^was removed^ with no intent to do wrong to any body. he <unclear/> an individual quite unfriendly to him, caused him to be indicted by the Grand Jury, not only in the road case, but in the two cases for gaming, as aforsd. And the fines were assessed as aforsd. The two gaming cases were for mere sport -- without the base spirit of gain -- and at which perhaps not a half<pb/>
<lb/>dollar changed hands -- and was intended as the mere innocent amusement of the parties upon a social occasion. It was made the subject of the Malicious information of an enemy &amp; the result aforsd <unclear/> -- Your Petitioner is no gambler -- And the fines aforsaid to one, <hi rend="underline">very</hi> <hi rend="underline">poor</hi> just starting in life -- with a young &amp; helpless family, is a Misfortune which he hopes yr Excellency may have never experienced -- Which he fears you can hardly realize in times so hard as these -- and Which he hopes you will be pleased to remit -- And as in duty yr Petitioner will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p>W H Thacker</p>
<p>Barren Couty Sct</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by W H Thacker this <date when="1862-05-02">2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> May 1862</date></p>
<p>W E Manford cc</p>
<p>We whose names are here under written write with W H Thacker in the prayer of the foregoing Petition</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Charles Denton
<lb/>Thos T Denton
<lb/>C L Heir
<lb/>J H Juband
<lb/>J. S. Perkins
<lb/>George Whillock
<lb/>D B Denton
<lb/><cb n="2"/>W S Underwood
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Sam</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> W Brents</hi>
<lb/>J. Williams
<lb/>B Lawless Jr
<lb/>V H Fores
<lb/>R T Hucker
<lb/>Sam Jones
<lb/>J. R. Dearing<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>D C Denton
<lb/>g S Page
<lb/>A H Cole Jr
<lb/>Jno E Nohner
<lb/>H M Canath
<lb/>M Beck
<lb/>B M Barren
<lb/>S A C Harrod
<lb/>R W Dougherty
<lb/>L S Beck
<lb/>L. D. Bridges
<lb/>W. D. Wade
<lb/>C. H Musgrave
<lb/>A. Crenshaw
<lb/>Elisha Spalding
<lb/>J Matison
<lb/>D Manfield
<lb/>A.. Moore
<lb/>C S Spradling
<lb/>W C Johns
<lb/>H M Cochran
<lb/>W. B. Jurham
<lb/>J. M. Stone
<lb/>Prior Spradling
<lb/>F. N. Brashear
<lb/>A G Clark
<lb/>J C Jeffryes
<lb/>B. H. Jameson
<lb/>William Dinneson
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Carel Gipson
<lb/>Berry Williams
<lb/>W H Williams
<lb/>Joseph Williams
<lb/>Jas. M,, Jones
<lb/>S Magers
<lb/>W Widing
<lb/>W Magers
<lb/>L S Poarkins
<lb/>W Michel
<lb/>S. Moore
<lb/>J Moore
<lb/>George W. Williams
<lb/>G. H. Gipson
<lb/>J Moore
<lb/>E D Metgers
<lb/>T Touray<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Remit the road case &amp; Respite 12 Mo the others.
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>W H Thacker
<lb/>Edmunson Eq &amp; Crim ct</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-07-22">July 22<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1862</date></p>
<p>Direct to
<lb/>W H Thacker
<lb/>Bowling Green 
<lb/>Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
