<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0560"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">F. L. Shields et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4679</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-388 to BR9-389</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Green County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-03">March 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Green county Ky <date when="1864-03">March 1864</date></p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Green county &amp; neighbors of Elijah Sympson would respectfully present to his Excellency Governor Bramlette, our appeal on behalf of said Sympson and if consistent with your Excellencys notions of Property to remit the amount of the Judgement rendered against him at the <date when="--02">February Term</date> of the Green Circuit Court for the alledged offence of retailing or selling spiritous Liquor The Judgment the small ($20.00 ^cts^) will under the circumstances of this case: the dependent condition of the Deft. and his helpless family, be a heavy burden for him to bear with the cost of the prosecution he is a poor (very poor) man. with a large &amp; helpless family on his hands that need all. the help and assistance that he can give. He is a peacible orderly quiet man, and this is his first offense. and this with the proof before the Jury was for once selling only. one quart to one of his neighbors for a house raising occasion he <unclear/> your Excellency will relieve this poor man by remitting said Judgement</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>F J Shields
<lb/>Alfred D Fires
<lb/>Jesse Curry
<lb/>Rye Curry
<lb/>G J Simpson
<lb/>George Simpson
<lb/>Jackson Simpson
<lb/>Andrew C Dewen
<lb/>James simpson
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Winson Simpson
<lb/>David Gudd
<lb/><unclear/> Higgasen
<lb/>H C Higgasen
<lb/>D W Higgasen
<lb/>J <unclear/>
<lb/>Leroy H Patterson
<lb/>James. D. Mays<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>A. C. Higganson
<lb/>Nathaniel Sudd
<lb/>R W Lile
<lb/>Benjamin Shadion
<lb/>Gall Atwell
<lb/>George M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Preit
<lb/>W E Clark
<lb/>P B Peayle
<lb/>Bibb Ward
<lb/>George Brown
<lb/>E Moran
<lb/>G. Forbes
<lb/>Marsfield Howe
<lb/>A W Elkton
<lb/>Wm Judd
<lb/><cb n="2"/>William Elkton
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>John <unclear/>
<lb/>Eligay.. Jeffers.
<lb/>G.. G.. Haetheherson
<lb/>M. Harlan
<lb/>J W P Jeffreys
<lb/>Crace Wray
<lb/>Jacob Judd
<lb/>Benjamin Judd
<lb/>W T Devenport
<lb/>Joseph Devenport
<lb/>Thomas Berry
<lb/>Henry J Wright esq<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Greensburg Ky <date when="1864-03-23">March 23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency Governor Bramlette</p>
<p>I take the liberty to send the indorsed petition to you on behalf of Elijah Sympson The offense for which he has been find ($20) was simply for selling on one occasion 1 quart of Spirits to a neighbor on the occasion of a house raising. This it is true was a violation of law but under the circumstances I respectfully suggest to your Excellency I think there are some Extinuating features in his case. he is a very poor man. and a very illitterate man; a peacible quiet Sober &amp; hard working man. &amp; as he tells me. he did not know that simply selling 1 quart of Spirits, not to be drank on the premises (and this was not) was any thing wrong. This is his first offense. he has a wife and seven little children and he is the only one to work for them &amp; it requires all his Efforts and all his time by daily toil to feed &amp; clothe them The amount is small but it will bear heavy upon this poor man to pay it. If consistent with your Excellencys notions of propriety. We should be gratified for you to remit this poor mans fine</p>
<p>I have the honor to be very respectfully your Obdt Sernt
<lb/>Saml. A Spencer<pb/></p>
<p>Green Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>E. Sympson
<lb/>Refused</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
