<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0046"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Mason Hendrick to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14075</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1864</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lewisport, Hancock County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-07-13">13 July 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Lewisport Ky <date when="1864-07-13">July 13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Gov. Thomas E. Bramlette</p>
<p>The exposed condition of this community and the recent outrages perpetrated on peaceable citizens induces me with the concurrence of many good loyal men to appeal to your excellency for aid -- We do not ask for men but we want arms -- Our impression is that great good would result from an immediate organization of the Militia of This Hancock County -- and I am willing to act as Colonel if you will give the proper Commissions W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H. Gregg would be a very suitable person for Mayor</p>
<p>If we could have the authority to raise an independent Company for this County and community we would never ask a federal soldier to leave the field to protect us</p>
<p>Last Saturday a squad of Rebles entered this town and attended a PicNic given for them and publicly recruited several men and in the evening mounted all on stolen or pressed Horses and took all the arms. amunition &amp;c that they could lay hands upon -- They also took money and goods from several persons -- Cursing and threatening several persons very severly -- The demonstration of Joy manifested by reble sympathisers was astonishing. Men and women shouting for Jeff Davis -- Drinking Healths to their success -- feeding and harboring them pointing out union men to them -- telling where guns and pistols were and many other like troubles. The same was continued on Sunday seven of them went aboard of Packet and drank -- doing as they liked<pb/>
<lb/>The sheriff of the county an old man and in feeble health was cursed and kicked and abused in his own House -- Houses were searched and threats made to such an extent that many left town and general fear every where held the citizen about 3 Oclock Cap Wilson and six men came upon them 30 in number and ran them all out of town and perhaps out of the County</p>
<p>The distance from this town is so great to where we can get assistance that we are much exposed.</p>
<p>Give us the permission to raise a company for our own defence -- give us the arms and amunition and we will defend ourselves There is about 30 good muskets belonging to the old Home Guards of this town now in Indiana for safe keeping. We want an order for them and about that many more good guns and we will do the work of a Regiment of strangers</p>
<p>As to the organization of the Militia good would be done if we could call them out at any time and compell all to drill and bear arms in time of danger and I do not think that it will do much in any other way but an Indepdendent Company of State guards stationed here will be the safe guard of the whole Country round -- Let us mount ourselves and fight them where and when we meet them with this authority I can make a company in one week<pb/>
<lb/>This humble appeal does not loose any degree of urgency by the awkward manner of its styled hope -- We want help so that we can help ourselves If you approve of the Indepdenent Company form give your authority in that way or if you do not approve of the plans suggested gives your own so that we can be protected in <hi rend="str">y</hi>our persons and property We prefer any life rather than be running from our homes and daily occupations before a gang of cut throats thieves and robbers -- and all we want is the power to keep the peace</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>Mason Hendrick former Capt 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky. Cav<pb/></p>
<p>Ky State Militia
<lb/>Lewisport Hancock Co. Ky.
<lb/><date when="1864-07-13">July 13<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Hendrick Mason (formly) Capt 12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky Vol Cav.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>States the necessity for organizing the E. M. of his county. Will accept the Colcy -- recommends a Major. Wants authority to organize an independent company -- Says he can raise one in a week. Gives the reasons why such a company should be raised -- and gives also a detailed account of the acts and doings of Guerillas in his Section. This communication was to the Gov. and referred by him with his endorsement thereon<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Commission ordered and letter answered on L. B. Page 508 on this <date when="1864-07-20">July 20-64</date></p>
<p>Rec. I. G. O. <date when="1864-07-15">July 15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date></p>
<p><date when="1864-07-15">July 15<hi rend="sup">th</hi></date></p>
<p>I have authorized Capt Hendrick raise Company of "active volunteer Militia" to serve as <unclear/> &amp; promised to have blank muster rolls &amp;c sent -- State Guard <unclear/> &amp;C -- Have authorized him to get the 30 muskets &amp; promised when he reports his Rolls &amp; organization to send Comt &amp; Arms &amp;c. upon requisition. The further Organization of the Militia to be attended to by Genl Lindsey when he returns home.</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
