<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-019-0078"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">M. H. Wright to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1384</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG5-144 to MG5-145</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Columbus, Hickman County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-07">7 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><hi rend="underline">Capt Wright to Gov. Magoffin</hi>.
<lb/>Columbus, Ky <date when="1861-06-07">June 7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Govr B. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin
<lb/>Dear Sir,</p>
<p>I have been for some time making up a company of Independent Rangers. I ordered them into camp about six miles above this place, with the ^view^ of Drilling, Hunting &amp; fishing, for a few days. <hi rend="str">o</hi>On arriving at the place appointed, we found the House we expected to occupy, in possession of an other person, and it being verry rainy weather, my men, in my absence, concluded to move higher up the River to Elliott's Mills, some three miles from the River, on Mayfields creek. They went to Elliotts mills on the <date when="1861-06-03">3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> inst.</date> &amp; we remained there untill wednesday evening, the <date when="1861-06-05">5<hi rend="sup">th</hi></date>, at 2 oclock, and arrived at home at 5 oclock P. M. On the next morning, we were surprised to<pb/> 
<lb/>to learn from a Citizen of the neighborhood in which we had been, that during the night after we left the mills, about two hundred &amp; twenty five men came down the River from Cairo, armed with Miney ^Minie^ Rifles &amp; Sword sabres, and landed opposite where we had camped; took the longer portion of their men &amp; marched out to the mills &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi> They first, on their way, went to Dr. Horthorn's, waked up the family &amp; placed a guard around the house; thence to Mr Cooks &amp; did the same; then to Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Richardsons &amp; did the same thing at his house; thence to Mr Wright's, who lived at the mill; made a charge on the mill, for the purpose of Capturing us; not finding us, they then searched Mr Wrights house; then<pb/>
<lb/>went back to Mr Richardsons &amp; requested him to raise a union ^flag^ and they would protect it; <hi rend="str">Mr</hi> ^he^ refused to do so, when they requested him to take an oath to support the constitution of the United States and that he would not fight against the northern army; he refused to do that, as he had already done so &amp; was &amp; had been an officer for seven years, &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi> They then left &amp; returned to Cairo.</p>
<p>On to day, I went upon the ground and learned the above facts from Dr. Horthorn, Mr Wright, Mr Smith, &amp; Mr Daugherty, the two last named living with Mr Richardson.</p>
<p>I thought proper to inform you of the above facts, for your consideration</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>M. H. Wright<pb/></p>
<p>Capt Wright -- 
<lb/>Columbus -- </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
