<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1530"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Sam Morton et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10998</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-130 to MG22-131</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Madisonville, Hopkins County, Kentucky </placeName>
    <date when="1861-11-06">6 November 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Madisonville Ky <date when="1861-11-06">Nov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> 6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Hopkins County</p>
<p>Miles Malin says that at the last May Term of the Hopkins Circuit Court a fine of sixty dollars has adjudged against him for the alledged Crime of Keeping a <hi rend="underline">Tipling</hi> <hi rend="underline">house</hi>. He states that he was a Merchant in good faith and sold liquor by the quart, that if any of the same was ever drunk upon his premises he did not know it and it has was so done if done at all, contrary to his expressed directions -- but finding that some of the witnesses would prove the charges upon him that they had bought the liquor and had drunk the same on the premises without the authority of Affiant, and being advised by his Counsel that that would Convict him and that it would be better to let Judgment go and appeal to the Executive, he did confess Judgment and that is the only foundation for said Charge and Judgment -- He says that he had Merchants License to sell Liquor, at the date of the alleged Charge</p>
<p>He therefore prays your Excellency to remit said fine as he was guilty of no intentional Offence against the laws</p>
<p>Miles Malin<pb/></p>
<p>Subscribed &amp; sworn to before me by Miles Malin the <date when="1861-11-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of Nov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>Sam Morton P. J. H. C. C.</p>
<p>State of Ky
<lb/>County of Hopkins</p>
<p>David Gibson says that he was one of the witnesses for the Comth vs Miles Malin for keeping a Tipling house judgt at <date when="1861-05">May Term 1861</date> I have <hi rend="str">off</hi> often known him to sell liquor but never in <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> less quantity than a quart and when he did sell he usually told the buyers that the liquor must be taken off and must not be drunk upon his premises</p>
<p>David Gibson</p>
<p>Subscribed &amp; sworn to before me by Daniel Gibson this <date when="1861-11-06">Nov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> 6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>Sam Morton P. J. H. C. C.</p>
<p>Hopkins Cir. Ct.</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B.M</p>
<p>$60 } Tipling
<lb/>Miles Malin
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-11-29">Nov. 29. 1861</date><pb/></p>
<p>To his Excellency B. Magoffin
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> of the Comth of Ky.</p>
<p>The undersigned petitioners would respectfully represent unto your Excellency that Miles Malin is a quiet orderly good citizen and full faith &amp; credit is due to his statements on oath -- that we have heard his affidavit read and believe it to be true. we further State that he is a very poor man very needy has a blind wife and two children at least She is so nearly blind as to be unable to do any family work</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>John P. Price 18
<lb/>O. Waddell 19
<lb/>John. G. Bailey 20
<lb/>G. C. Bronaugh ^clk^ 21 
<lb/>J. M. Carlise 22
<lb/><unclear>Terry</unclear> W Witt 23
<lb/>John G. Morton 24
<lb/>A. E. Earle 25
<lb/>J H Wilson 26
<lb/>James R Cargile 27
<lb/>Granville Holton 28
<lb/>R M King 29
<lb/>Sam Hedger 30
<lb/>C H trent 31
<lb/>Daniel Peyton 32
<lb/>John B Morril ^33^ 34
<lb/>J R Hibbs 35
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J B Earle 1 
<lb/>R. J. Rutherford 2
<lb/>T. E. Davis 3
<lb/>J f Gipson 4
<lb/>Z Mcking 5
<lb/>J Lynn 6
<lb/>Mn Vickers 7
<lb/><unclear>Biga</unclear> Groves 8
<lb/>W. F. Curneal 9
<lb/>F. P. Curneal 10
<lb/>Samuel Groves 11
<lb/>James Cook 12
<lb/>Milton Yates 13
<lb/>J K Shackelford 14
<lb/>J G Gorden 15
<lb/>W H Neal 16
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/> 17<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>J E Vickers 36
<lb/>M. M. Disk 37
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Hall 38
<lb/>C. T. Masencuss 39
<lb/>J. Wingo 40
<lb/>R. H. Robertson 41
<lb/>William Julian 42
<lb/>William Wilibs Sr ^43^ 44
<lb/>William Harned 45
<lb/>F Wicks 46
<lb/>J Hill 47
<lb/>W R Baker 48
<lb/>T Lindsay 49 </p>
<p><cb n="2"/>there is now an Execution in my hands for collection against Miles Malin for a fine Judgt rendered at last May Term of Hopkins Circuit Court, the Judgt was for $60. and Cost the Circuit Court Clerk for this County and all of his deputies are Absent from this County &amp; have been for some time past &amp; there is no probabilty of their being here soon.</p>
<p>W R Baker S H C</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
