<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1025"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Landaff W. Andrews, H. B. Dobyns, and E. Logan to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10493</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-98 to MG20-99</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-05-16">16 May 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Frankfort. <date when="1861-05-16">May 16<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>To His Exc.<hi rend="sup">l</hi> B. Magoffin.</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of the County of Fleming, would respectfully represent that more than <hi rend="str">Six</hi> Twelve months since Henry C Helvestine, a native of the county of Fleming was convicted in the Mason Cir Cout under Indictment charging him with having in his possession counterfeit Bank notes. with intent to utter and pass the same. We would respectfully represent. that while the facts suffecnlly conduced to them that such was the fact. The same facts conclusively Shew that Helvestine, for much of his life had been industrious humble man and of good character, untill he had be debauched. by men of more posetion than himself and being <unclear>leader</unclear> in crime used Helvestine through his ignorance as a tool: The facts<pb/>
<lb/>are clear that older and far more guilty partys as principals used him Helvestine has a wife and famly of children. very poor. absolutley needing these trying and distressing hardness of the times his aid, We believe that Helvestine is greatly <unclear/> and that the Law has been fully vindicated and that it will be a most judicous and Just exercise of Executive Clemency. to Pardon Said Henry C Helvestine. And that such act will be fully approved by all the people in that section &amp; it will restore him to his famly. and that for the future he will act with more proprety and further we hope he may be the <unclear/> of being to the light and final <unclear/> the Leeder of this conduct in that section</p>
<p>your frnds
<lb/>L. W. Andrews
<lb/>H. B. Dobyns
<lb/>E. Logan<pb/></p>
<p>Helvestines Case
<lb/><unclear>Penty</unclear> Mason Co</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
