<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0551"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. W. Kirby to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4670</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-371 to BR9-373</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-02-23">23 February 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>Thomas E. Bramlett
<lb/>Govr. of the Comth. of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner the Subscriber would respectfully represent &amp; state that he was raised in the County of Simpson in this State, that he is now a citizen of Louisville Ky. When the Rebels invaded this state &amp; took possession of Southern Kentucky, business of every kind was more or less suspended. Your petitioner was out of business &amp; the Rebel authority tendered your petitioner the office of gun-inspector &amp; without any intention, as his part thereby to commit the offense of treason against his State, he has been indicted therfor in the Simpson Equity &amp; Criminal Court for the serious offense of treason. He is now Satisfied he committed a very grave error. he has however done all in his power to repair the wrong by executing bond &amp; taking the oath of allegiance. Your petitioner is advised that it is not in the power of your excellency to grant him a full ^pardon^ but can extend to him a reprieve until the close of the next meeting of<pb/></p>
<p>the General assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. which is here most respectfully prayed for. He begs leave to say that he has always been a peaceable orderly citizen &amp; intends to be &amp; remain such. He says he believes the statements contained in the forgoing petition are true.</p>
<p>Very respectfully
<lb/>yr. obt. sevt.
<lb/>W. W. Kirby</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Jefferson County Court</p>
<p>Subscribed &amp; sworn to by W. W. Kirby before me this <date when="1864-02-23">23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> day of Feby 1864</date></p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">J C
<lb/><date when="1864-02-23">Feb 23 1864</date></note></p>
<p>J G Clement. Justice of the peace
<lb/>Jeff Co Ky:</p>
<p>We <unclear/>dersigned, acquaintances of the petitioner, W. W. Kirby, cheerfully unite in the prayer of his petition &amp; respectfully ask his pardon as indicited therein.</p>
<p>David Kurly
<lb/>B C Grider
<lb/>G. W Whiteside
<lb/>J C M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Linan
<lb/>J. Bell. Fenan
<lb/>Spencer Batsel
<lb/>W. G. Wade<pb/></p>
<p>B. Green Ky <date when="1864-02-13">Feby. 13th. 1864</date>
<lb/>W. W. Kirby Esqr. Louisville, Ky.
<lb/>Dr. Sir-</p>
<p>Your <date when="---10">favor of the 10th inst.</date> is agreed in due time. Your suggestions will not be complied with by Mr. Jones. we had similar cases here &amp; he refused to dismiss in cases even where the parties, refuse petition, has been pardoned by the Prs<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> of the U.S.<hi rend="sup">s</hi> &amp; the Govr. had extended the respite prayed for in the petition herewith prepared for you. I have procured from Govr. Bramlette <hi rend="str">the</hi> a respite until the end of the next Legislature for Esqr. Jno. Burnam, Josiah Pillsberry &amp; Jas. H. Wilkins all inducted for treason in this court. You must Sign <unclear/> to the petitions. I have preparied for you on opposite page, before some Justice of the peace &amp; affix a Revised Stamp, there to &amp; get some friends, say Mr. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Ferran, Mr. Whitesides &amp; all that you can get 10 or 12 &amp; that will do_ you had but take it to the Govr. yourself you will get the pardon yourself. Call on Cols. Hawkins from<pb/></p>
<p>this county now at Frankfort &amp; he will go with you to the Govr. &amp; aid you. I have no doubt. the Colo. is is a very polite, kind Gentm. &amp; you will say so when you try him. If you get the respite I have prayed for in your petition, you can forward to me &amp; I will file it in the case at the next Court. you had best write Mr. Jones &amp; ascertain from him, if you procure the respite, if he will require you to appear at the next Court or forfeit your bond.</p>
<p>If you are respited, you can apply to the next Legislature for an act of pardon in full. the Legislature alone can grant the pardon. I have they <unclear/> you fully &amp; hope you will have no difficulty in pursuing the programs.</p>
<p>Very respectfully
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> V. Loving<pb/></p>
<p>Simpson Equity &amp; Criminal Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W. W. Kirby
<lb/>for
<lb/>Treason</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Respited</hi> until the end of the next General Assembly
<lb/><date when="1864-02-24">24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Feby/ 64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
