<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2363"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James P. Harbeson to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7000</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-272 to BR15-273</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-15">15 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville <date when="1865-09-15">Sept 15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>.
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>Thomas E Bramlette. Govenor.
<lb/>Sir.</p>
<p>At the call of the monthly docket this week of the city court of Louisville. Mary Green was fined $400<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> for keeping a disorderly house. I have refused to sign any petitions whatever. but I deem it proper in this case. <hi rend="str">I think</hi> to say that from the character of house proved it would not be improper to remit all that you can save $75.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi>.</p>
<p>I dont know that I have couched the above in proper language, but you can gather my meaning. I am not skilled a in this work.</p>
<p>There have been many and <hi rend="underline">larger</hi> fines imposed at this term. they have already had a beneficial effect. I Shall write to you only when I think proper for the good of the city and <hi rend="str">its</hi> good morals.</p>
<p>There have been two fines imposed at this term for dealing Faro. one<pb/>
<lb/>against Blakely &amp; Sloan and one against Featherly &amp; Croxton. I will not sign a petition or write to you in favor of either of them. -- </p>
<p>I would like to to say a great deal about the fines in these cases of disorderly houses, and the fines inflicted but at some time I hope to talk with you. In many cases I think the fines are excessive for the accomplishment of good. but there are several where the fine should be sufficiently large to crush out the entirety. of these I now remember Julia Dean &amp; Margaret Miles.</p>
<p>I am Sir with great respect
<lb/>Your obt Servt
<lb/>James P Harbeson</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
