<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0509"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Titsworth to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4628</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-307 to BR9-308</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-02-27">27 February 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner John Titsworth states that at the present <date when="--02">February term</date> of the Hickman Circuit Court there has been a Judgement rendered against for sixty-dollars for keeping a tippling house. Your petitioner states that although legally guilty he was not morally so nor did he intend to violate the laws of his country. He states that he applied for a obtained a license to keep a tavern in Clinton Ky and told the court that he proposed to occupy as his tavern two houses on opposite sides of the street and the license was given him with that understanding and intent. This will be seen by the explanatory order of the county Court a copy of which will be sent herewith your petitioner states that he kept a portion of his bedding and his bar in one house and his table and reception room in the other and because he kept his bar in a house different from that in which his own family resided and when his guests were fed the Indictment was found and the verdict and Judgement was given. He most solemnly assests that in this he was ignorant that he was violating the law and had the assurance of the county court that he was not. In view of these facts he would most respectfully request your Excellency to remit the judgement or so much as in your power</p>
<p><date when="1864-02-27">Feby 27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>John Titsworth<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned respectfully recommend the within petition of John Titsworth to the clemency and merciful consideration of the Governor of Kentucky. We are citizens of Hickman County and believe his case is deserving of the exercise of Executive clemency and interposition</p>
<p>A R Boon
<lb/>Resident of Graves Co
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>G W Rennick Clerk Cty Court
<lb/>G W Miller Jailor of H Cty
<lb/>A G Sims one of the jury
<lb/>T C Whayne one of the jury
<lb/>W M Samuels S H C
<lb/>Thomas G Poorochee
<lb/>Wm R. Vance
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">M</hi> M Evans one of the Jury
<lb/>W. White, County Judge
<lb/>David Lamkin one of Jury
<lb/>J. T. Reese - - one of the Jury
<lb/>Thomas Stone one of the Jury
<lb/>Joseph Spicer " "
<lb/>Thomas G. Jordan "
<lb/>Rob<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Haly "
<lb/>W. A. Elliott " "
<lb/>A S Arnold D S. H. County
<lb/>John Mcwhorter one of the Jury
<lb/><cb n="2"/>E. D. Kingman
<lb/>Fulton County
<lb/>R. W. Walker
<lb/>J M Bigger
<lb/>E. J. Bullock
<lb/>J D Norton deputy Sherif
<lb/>Fulton Co
<lb/>R H Emerson
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. S. Pennebaker J. P
<lb/>J D Hays
<lb/>J. Fineys
<lb/>J C Akin
<lb/>A J Burton
<lb/>W F Boon
<lb/>F M Roy
<lb/>C M Ashley
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Haler</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
