<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1978"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Richard H. Stanton et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11446</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Bradley Strait</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG23-435 to MG23-436</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Mason County, would state, that at the <date when="1860-04">April Term 1860</date> of the Mason Circuit Court, our Henry Helfenstien was convicted of passing counterfeit money and sentenced to the penetentiary of the state for five years, more than two of which he has now served, This Helfenstien is an ignorant illiterate man, and has doubtless been inveigled into crime by sharpers and those ^who^ wished to use him as a tool, as he has niether sense, nor education to concoct, much less carry any scheme of villainy. </p>
<p>We are informed that he is quite persistant, and promises a reformation as to his associations and habits, and are of the opinion that if he were now pardoned by the interposition of Executive clemency, his reformation, would be more certainly secured, than by his retention in prison for<pb/>
<lb/>the full period of his conviction, as he would be in prison bound to good behavior, to those friends who have interfered in his behalf -- We would therefore pray your Excellency, that said Helfenstien may be pardoned &amp; the remainder of his term of confine<hi rend="str">d</hi>^ment^ remitted and as in duty &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi></p>
<p>R. H Stanton Pros atty
<lb/>Thos J Throop County <unclear/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Emery Whitaker County Judges</p>
<p>Richard Power
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> N. Howe
<lb/>J. J. Hefferd } Jury who tried Halfenstein</p>
<p><cb n="2"/>Robt A Cochran C C <unclear/>
<lb/>Keith Berry C. M. C. C.
<lb/>S B Lyons<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Fleming county, who reside in the immediate neighborhood, when Helfenstein has lived for many years and where his family still reside would cordially endorse the above petition; and as an additional inducement, for said pardon to be extended to this unhappy man, we would state, that he has a larg and helpless family, entirely dependent upon him for a support; that they are by his confinement reduced to the greatest straits for a subsistence being extremely poor and friendless and that by restoring him to liberty, you will enable him to earn a subsistence for his wife &amp; helpless children</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>E Logan
<lb/>D. W. Litster
<lb/>J. Cooper
<lb/>D. W. Cooper
<lb/>R. S. Jones
<lb/>J. H. Crain
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Crain
<lb/>E. Barnes
<lb/>Lewis Crain
<lb/><cb n="2"/>S L. Crain.
<lb/>L. D. Parker
<lb/><hi rend="underline">E G. Shields</hi>
<lb/>L J Jones
<lb/>Physician to his family
<lb/>Allen T Thomson
<lb/>James M Evans
<lb/>George Havens
<lb/>James V Payne<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Issue Pardon
<lb/>B. M.</p>
<p>Mason Cir Ct
<lb/>H C Helserstine
<lb/>5 yrs Penty
<lb/>Felony
<lb/>Pardon Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-08-11">Aug 11 1862</date></p>
<p>Send answer to to S. M. Cox
<lb/>Flemingsburg<pb/></p>
<p>James Eaton
<lb/>Marshal Crain
<lb/>Howard M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clain
<lb/>Matt G. Jones
<lb/>David Shrout
<lb/>Manley B Vanlandingham
<lb/>A. F.. Day
<lb/>Thomas Barbour
<lb/>R M Thomas
<lb/>A. Rawlings
<lb/>I T Eden
<lb/>D B Sheperd
<lb/>Isaac B Pearl
<lb/>Geo. M. Vansandt
<lb/>J W Crain -- </p>
<p>The names signed to the foregoing two petitions are the names of some of the most respectable and upright citizens of the counties of Mason and Fleming <date when="1862-06-12">June 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1862</date></p>
<p>L M Cox
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> H Cord</hi>,
<lb/>Flemingsburg Ky.</p>
<p>Flemingsburg <date when="1862-05-29">May 29<hi rend="sup">th</hi>/62</date></p>
<p>I have on file in the Executive office a Written application Signed by myself Dr E. Logan &amp; H B Dobyns Esq Soliciting the pardon of Henry Helnestine I take this occasion to <unclear/> it and most respectfully urge the Govenor to Pardon Mr H. No public good can be accomplished by his longer confinement. and he has a family actually suffering</p>
<p>Your friend
<lb/>L W Andrews</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
