<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0538"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. W. Lawes et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4657</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-349 to BR9-350</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Hon Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. E. Bramlett Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> of the Commonwealth of Kentucky -- We the jurors and citizens of the City of Louisville, would most respectfully ^Solicit^ at your hands, the pardon of John Cosden, who was convicted of Larceny, at the <date when="--01">January Term</date>, of the Jefferson Circuit Court, and Sent up for one year, to the Penetentiary at Frankfort_ We pray his release, from further punishment, for said offences because there were two parties to the offence, and some of the jury believed that the most guilty party was not before the Court -- The wife and mother, in order to provide for the family, has by exposure, during the cold weather, had her hands So badly frosted, that She is almost disqualified for any buisness, and especially washing and Serving, which was her accustomed vocation -- We plead for these reasons And for pitys Sake, his reprieve</p>
<p>Resply &amp;c your petitioners
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Jurors names
<lb/>W. W. Lawes 1
<lb/>C Henry Finnell 2
<lb/>3
<lb/>4
<lb/>5
<lb/>6
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Jurors names
<lb/>Wm Winston 1
<lb/>W. Billings 2
<lb/>J. H. Myers 3
<lb/>James Hughes -- 4
<lb/>L. P. Garrett
<lb/>S A Hartwell 6<milestone unit="column" n="1"/>
<lb/>Citizens on the other side<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Citizens names
<lb/>W. H. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Clish
<lb/>C. Kosh
<lb/>Geo. Koch
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Citizens names
<lb/>A. B. Miller
<lb/>G. W. Miller
<lb/>T. C. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cay
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Heever
<lb/>Francis Donahue
<lb/>W.. M.. Jexeson
<lb/>William Waddle
<lb/>A A Chreckering<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>I am not in the habit of signing petitions for Pardon_ but in this instance for the sake of the <hi rend="underline">wife</hi> I have been induced to request that your excellency will Pardon Jno Cosden whose wife will have to suffer a great deal by his confinement</p>
<p>J R Dupuy Com' atty</p>
<p>Under all the circumstances I ask, very respectfully, the pardon of Jno. Cosden</p>
<p><date when="1864-02-24">Feb. 24<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>P. B. Muir
<lb/>Juror M. Billings</p>
<p>P.S. Your Excellency will perceive, that four of the Jurors names are wanting to the petition. Two of them reside in the county, and remote from the city, And the other two are absent also, which makes it impossible to see them, except upon great delay, and considerable cost_All signatures hereunto affixed, have been cheerfully and willingly given, And hundreds more could be had_</p>
<p>Respty &amp;c
<lb/>J. H. Myers<pb/></p>
<p>F H Kendricks J P</p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John Cosden
<lb/>Pardoned
<lb/><date when="1864-02-29">29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Feby 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
