<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2161"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">L. A. Wood and W. B. Hoke to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6798</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-393 to BR14-394</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thos. E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov. of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your petitioners respectfully represent, that at the <date when="1865-05">May term of the Jefferson Circuit Court ^for 1865^</date> a Judgment was rendered against them Jointly, as the Bail of one M. E. Baldwin, (who Stood indicted in Said court for felony.) for the Sum of $400, -- having at the <hi rend="str">January</hi> <date when="--10">^Oct <hi rend="str">term</hi>^ term</date> previous, became his bail in that Sum.</p>
<p>Your petitioners Say, at the time they went his bail, the <hi rend="str">was</hi> Said Baldwin was under bonds to answer in another charge for Mallicious Shooting, and that one Mr Gazlin was his bondsman, and his Baldwin's brother had indemnified Gazlin against all loss that he might Sustain by reason of his failure to appear. We knew these facts; and believing that Baldwin would certainly be aquitted when tried in both cases, and believing that he was an honorable young man, who had unfortunately go into these troubles innocently; and believing that he would certainly appear in both cases -- and especially did we believe that he was too honorable to allow either his brother or us to lose or Suffer by him, we being his counsel through Sympathy for<pb/>
<lb/>him whom we believed to be an innocent, and persecuted young man, became his bail without any indemnity <hi rend="underline">except</hi> $50, which he left with us. His brother was not a resident of the State, nor was he here at the time, and he could not, at the time get any other bail.</p>
<p>We did not become his bail to prevent to prevent him from being tried and punished; nor with any other expectation than that he would appear and Stand his trial; and we believe he would have done So but for the fact that when he appeared to answer the case wherein Mr Gazlin was bail, the Judge of the court -- believing as we did -- that he was honest -- trusted him -- <hi rend="str">to</hi> after Gazlin had Surrendered -- to go out of the court-house alone, to hunt up his bail, or other bail. When he got out, and Saw Mr Gazlin he refused to go on his bond again; and he knew that if he returned and gave himself into court again he would have to go to Jail -- ; and instead of doing this he gave us all "leg Bail," and we have not heard of him Since. We think he could have gotten bail agin, he would not have left, and that he ran away not So much form the fear of punishment as the dread of lying in Jail<pb/>
<lb/>He was an energetic, industrious, business-like young man, and was at the time making money, and we had no idea of having a bond to pay when we went on it. We know that this no legal <hi rend="str">excuse</hi> reason why we Should not pay it; but in view of all the foregoing facts, and e<hi rend="str">x</hi>specially the fact that his looks, appearance &amp;c, were calculated to deceive the court, and did deceive the court; and as we are poor men, illy <hi rend="str">un </hi>able to pay $200 each, we pray your <hi rend="underline">Excellency</hi> will interpose and <hi rend="str">rem</hi> <hi rend="underline">remit</hi> <hi rend="underline">it all</hi> except the Commonwealth's atty's fee and court costs.</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>L. A. Wood
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W. B. Hoke</hi></p>
<p>We the undersigned, thinking this a case of merit pray the Governor to remit the Judgment to the extent of his power</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/><hi rend="underline">James R W Smith</hi>
<lb/>Hugh Hays
<lb/>J, B, Ehrich
<lb/>John Lamtoon
<lb/>James T. Kelly
<lb/><cb n="2"/>W K Thomas
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Sam</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> Matlock</hi>
<lb/>Jos. Clement.
<lb/>James S Pirtle.
<lb/>Ben M. Harney
<lb/><unclear>Selby</unclear> Harney<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>M. A. Walker
<lb/>E. R. Wong
<lb/>C. T. Taylor
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Ro. F. Baird</hi>
<lb/>W. G. Reasor
<lb/><hi rend="underline">S. S. English</hi></p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>L. A. Wood &amp; W. B. Hoke
<lb/>$400,
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-08-10">10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Aug /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
