<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1397"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Joshua Bingham to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10865</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-346 to MG21-347</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Prestonsburg, Floyd County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-08-20">20 August 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Prestonburg Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-08-20">Aug 20th 1861</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>Beriah Magoffin Govener of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Joshua Bingham would Respectfullly Represent that he is a poor man with a large Family that he has only one leg and is a criple for life, that the county court of Floyd County in order to prevent your petitioner becoming a c<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi> charge and in order to keep your petitioner from the poor house Gave him a Licence to Keep a tavern after the expiration of his Licence, he did sill serve Liquor before he renewed his Licence for which he has been endicted in the Floyd circuit court<pb/>
<lb/>of Floyd County: He says <hi rend="str">He</hi> He will be unable to pay the fine &amp; costs. That he has always preserved Good order about his house, as all his neighbours will testify He therefore asks your Excellency: to remit sd fine and for all proper Relief</p>
<p>Joshua Bingham</p>
<p>We the undersigned have examined the foregoing petition and can say with truth that the statements in the same are true,, that the Petitioner keeps an orderly house,, that we live in a mile from him and hope you will Remit the fine</p>
<p>John M. Burns
<lb/>John M. Elliott<pb/></p>
<p>From information that can be relied on I have no doubt of the Truth of the within</p>
<p>John Dishman</p>
<p>Floyd Co
<lb/>Joshua Bingham
<lb/>To } Petition
<lb/>Governer</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-09-17">Sept 17. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
