<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0037"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. William M. Bartley, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4156</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-54</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mason County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Mason Circuit Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>Against
<lb/>William M. Bartley
<lb/>Indictment</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Mason County, in the name, and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, accuse William M. Bartley of the crime of Grand Larceny, committed as follows: The said William M. Bartley on the <gap/> day of <date when="1863-06">June 1863</date> at the county aforesaid feloniously took and carried away one coat &amp; one pocket book the personal property of R. W. Watkins of the value of more than four Dollars against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Geo. M Thomas
<lb/>Attorney for the Commonwealth.</p>
<p>The following verdict was rendered herein, to wit: "We the jury find the defendant guilty and fix his punishment at one year confiement in the Penitentiary, and we recommend to the Governor to pardon him before the close of his term. We do this in view of the circumstances disclosed on the trial.</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi>. Bickley Foreman
<lb/>A copy attest
<lb/>Jno. M. Duke Jr Clerk
<lb/>Mason Circuit Court<pb/></p>
<p>The Comlth of Kentucky
<lb/>vs
<lb/>William M. Bartley
<lb/>Indictment for Grand Larceny
<lb/>Copy Examined</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
