<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1117"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">David Blevins et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10585</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-227 to MG20-228</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency B. Magoffin
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioners David Blevins &amp; John Blevins would respectfully inform your Excellency that at the <date when="1861-04">April Term of the Harlan Circuit Court 1861.</date> Your Petitioners was find the sum of $100.<hi rend="underline">00</hi> for not appearing before the Harlan Circuit Court in a Peace Bond; Your Petitioner states that their Bonds was forfeited and judgment rendered on the same, and your Petitioner in the state of Virginia, and that as soon as it was made known to your Petitioners that said Judgement was rendered, against them the immediately came to Harlan C H. Ky and, enquired into the matter, but was unable to get said Judgement set aside</p>
<p>Your petitioners states that there was no notice served on them that they Judgement was rendered unbenowings to your Petitioner when in fact they had a lawfull excuse for not attending</p>
<p>Your Petitioners states that they are poor men and was unable to prosecute an appeal in said case, ,, They therefore prays, that your excellency will take<pb/>
<lb/>into consideration their large. families and poor condition and, their excuse, and give them the indulgence of the Executive</p>
<p>David Blevins
<lb/>John Blevins
<lb/>Noble Smith
<lb/>G. W. Ball
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Turner
<lb/>Hiram Jones
<lb/>Geore B Turner
<lb/>James B. Howard clk
<lb/>J. G. Howard
<lb/>E. W. Ceriller
<lb/>M. G. Jones
<lb/>Gibson Ball
<lb/>C B Brittain
<lb/>Heizikiah Gings
<lb/>John. B. Lytle<pb/></p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Issd <date when="1861-05-31">May 31 1861</date></p>
<p>Harlan Cir. Ct</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
