<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0017"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Charles J. VanderEspt, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4136</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Jesse Nasta</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-28</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-09-08">8 September 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The Affiant, <persName ref="cwgk:N00002942">Charles J. VanderEpst</persName>, states that he was residing at <placeName ref="cwgk:P00003061">New Haven, Nelson County</placeName> at the time <persName ref="cwgk:N00003057">Paul Garis</persName>, was living there, and was in his employment, at the time he was arrested, in the charge of an attempt to a<hi rend="str">d</hi>bduct <persName ref="cwgk:N00002938">a slave</persName>, belonging to <persName ref="cwgk:N00003058">Jack Dawson</persName>. He states that he was and is intimately acquainted with the whole circumstances, and that the charges in said indebtments are wholly groundless. He states that the charge orginated in the mind of Dawson the Prosecuter, from a jealeusy he had against said Garis, for cuckolding him Dawson, with the said negro, and done for the purpose of getting rid of Garis as well as some suit that had arisen <unclear>between</unclear> <persName ref="cwgk:N00003059">a son of Dawson</persName> and Gar<unclear>is.</unclear> Garis <unclear>being</unclear> a Frenchman and ignorant of the law, <hi rend="str">became frightened, and</hi> Dawson taking. advantage of this thought that he could get him away. Garis, before the war broke out, being a millwright, was induced to engage in work at <placeName ref="cwgk:P001003">Memphis</placeName>, at his business, and went away with the intention of returning to the trial but the war broke out, and he being in the rebel lines, could not get back. <hi rend="str">His surety <persName ref="cwgk:N00004234">Jos Henin</persName></hi> ^Garis^ employed <persName ref="cwgk:N00002299">Genl Rousseau</persName>, to go up to <placeName ref="cwgk:P00004617">Bardstown</placeName> to defend for him, and went once but the case was continued, afterwards his attorney was called into the military service, and could not attend. Garis being away, no appearance was made<pb/>
    <lb/>Upon the forfeiture, the said Henin has already paid about $3<hi rend="str">2</hi>70 -- The said Garis and Dupere are poor men, and the payment of the executions will be very oppressive. Dupere <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> and Henin are loyal men -- Dupere has had three sons in the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00001186">Federal army</orgName> for two years or more and now has two remaining in the army. He is in hopes that the Gov will in the exercise of your Executive clemency, <hi rend="str">will</hi> grant remission of the fines. Dupere is now sick and has no dependence for a living upon his sons who are away. It will indeed be very oppresive for him to pay it -- indeed it will be impossible.</p>
<p>Cha<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> <unclear>J. VanderEspt</unclear>
 <lb/>Vice <unclear>Counsul of</unclear> <orgName ref="cwgk:O00006447">Belgium</orgName></p>
   <p><placeName ref="cwgk:P001800">State of Kentucky</placeName>
    <lb/><placeName ref="cwgk:P001005">Jefferson County</placeName></p>
<p>Charles J. VanderEspt states he believes the statements contained in the foregoing affidavit are true</p>
<p>Chas J Vandrepst</p>
<p>sworn to before me this <date when="1863-09-08">8 Sept 1863</date></p>
   <p><persName ref="cwgk:N00004236">Jeff Brown</persName> N. P. J C,</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
