<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2065"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John H. Phillips to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6702</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-256 to BR14-257</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Edmonton, Metcalfe County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-07-20">20 July 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Edmunton Ky. <date when="1865-07-20">July. 20/65</date>
<lb/>Gov. T E. Bramblette
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>At our last Curcuit Court there was a judgment obtained vs. E. R. Nance for $25.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> for trespass -- Nance is a poor ignorant hard working and inoffensive man has a large family of small children to Support which he does by his daily labor. I understand the Case to be that Nance had rented a field adjoining a Mr. Wilkison who was one of ^these^ Cunning muddlesome fellows and when Nance was from home he would contrive to get his hogs in Nance's field. About the <date when="--09-08">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of Sept</date> whilst Nance was at a house-raising Nance's son descovered W.<hi rend="sup">s</hi> hogs in the field and took his dog<pb/>
<lb/>which was a severe one and in getting the hogs out one was severely injured and whilst some say the hog died others say that W<hi rend="sup">=</hi> eat it Be that as it May, Wilkison in Court proved by his son that Nance injured the hog. So it died As Nance was a poor ignorant man did not Know how to manage his Case judgement went against him and I think it would be an act of charity and no detriment to the Commonwealth to remit the judgment</p>
<p>Your Friend Truly
<lb/><hi rend="underline">John H Phillips</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Metcalfe Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>E R Nance
<lb/>$<hi rend="str">60</hi>. 25,
<lb/>Trespass
<lb/><date when="1865-10-05">5 Oct/65</date>
<lb/>Sent for fee <date when="--09-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sept</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
