<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2834"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John F. Fleming and John M. Gray to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7471</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-116 to BR17-117</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency the Gov of Ky</p>
<p>The undersigned beleave that the ends of Justice has been accomplished in the punishment of James Weaver a Citizen of Fleming County who is now incarcerated in the Penitentiary and would earnestly request your clemency and pray his release for the following reasons -- His Stealings -- if that is the appropriate term was not done or enacted for the purpose of gain -- He was a private Soldier in Col Beards Reg Ky Cav and his companions in arms will certify to his gleantry as a Soldier, he reenlisted as a vetran was granted leave of absence for thirty days -- came home and very generously gave most of his earnings to his old Mother and little sisters, but from influences thrown round him by the enemies of our Government he did not return to his Reg. but "in time" he enlisted in the 54 -- we think -- Reg Ky Cav. joined his regiment &amp; in a few months deserted, taking with him a fine Gray Horse belonging to &amp; branded for the Gov of the U S. he came to his home and then<pb/>
<lb/>commenced a series of "<hi rend="underline">frolicks</hi>" -- in a short time his Horse was taken from him <hi rend="str">and</hi>by some unknown persons and shortly after was found dead. <hi rend="underline">shot</hi> in a thick wood near where he was stolen -- Weaver learning -- as he believed some of the parties who had stolen &amp; shot his horse, in a spirit of retaliation took -- in daylight -- or <hi rend="underline">pressed</hi> a horse belonging to Mr John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Carty, that horse he rode until he gave out, he was then turned loose or the horse was sent back. -- at any rate M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Carty got his horse again, the next horse he <hi rend="underline">pressed</hi> was from a Mr Kirk, he rode <hi rend="underline">that</hi> horse until <hi rend="underline">he</hi> gave out -- the next one taken or pressed was from a Mr Lander, then his career of <hi rend="underline">pressing</hi> came to an end he was taken into custody by the officer of the law and sent to the Penitentiary. All his stealings clearly showing that it was not done for the sake of gain but in a spirit of retaliation -- he is a man without education, deserved punishment ^no doubt^ by the military authority of our Government, but we think the punishment has been sufficient and therefore would pray for his release</p>
<p>Jno F Fleming
<lb/>John M Gray<pb/></p>
<p>I remember the case of Weaver when tried in our Court it was at a time when there much excitement in the County in reference to Stolen horses. Weaver was in bad company others who Stolen horses under more felonious circumstances were tried at the Same Court. I am not familiar with the circumstances of his case but know Doctr Jno F Fleming to be a gentle of the highest respectability and inteligance and I know from his locality in the County enjoy oportunity of being familar with the circumstances of the case. I therefore concur with him in Soliciting the interposition of Executive clemency in behalf of Weaver</p>
<p>John S Botts</p>
<p>My recollection is that Weaver was sent for the term of four years -- and was sent at the <date when="--05">May</date> term of the Fleming Circuit Court Horse Stealing</p>
<p>Jno F Fleming<pb/></p>
<p>Fleming Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Jas Weaver
<lb/>Horse Stealing
<lb/>4 yrs
<lb/>sentenced <date when="1865-05">May term/65</date>
<lb/>Pardoned <date when="1865-12-15">15 Dec<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
