<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2025"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John F. Fisk to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9101</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-26 to MG24-27</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-06-26">26 June 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Cov Ky <date when="1862-06-26">June 26/62</date>
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>Gov Magoffin
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>I was one of the attorneys of John Mullins. and are thoroughly satisfied from his statements and the evidence in the case that he knew nothing of the cutting of M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cullough until after it was done -- He was simply guilty of committing a breach of the peace and should only be punished for that. He struck no blow until after he was struck in the month with a two pound weight. He was simply<pb/>
<lb/>entering a butcher's shop against his consent, he being on a drunken spree and was struck by the butcher with the weight and fell and the butcher upon him, and while in this position the butcher was stabbed by another, from which slight wound he died as his bowell was severed of rather <hi rend="underline">encised</hi> about one half inch in length, and after ten or twelve days he died, Mullins turned the butcher, and got up -- and struck the butcher once in the mouth after he got up -- not knowing as I verily believe that the butcher had been stabbed. He did not know the butcher<pb/>
<lb/>nor did the butcher know him. There was no ill feeling between them.</p>
<p>It was an unfortunate thing that the two had not been left alone. They would each have had a bloody nose and nothing more, I feel well assured that you ought to exercise your high perogative in this case</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>Yours
<lb/>John F. Fisk</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
