<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2898"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Barbara Shipp, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7535</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-217 to BR17-218</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-22">22 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Bramlette
<lb/>Govenor of the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>The petitioner the undersigned would respectfully represent. that on the <gap/> day of <gap/> Her husband (who was a german man industrious, and continually at labor for the support of his family,) was charged in the City of Louisville with stealing some scraps of Iron from Ainslee &amp; Cochrans: and that He was required to give Bond to answer to the charge ^in the sum of $300 is^ in the Jefferson Circuit Court, and that in order to give Security in a Bond for his appearance. He made a mortgage on a small piece of land in the State of Indiana to Chris Wright, who was an acquaintance to secure him against loss: and said Chris Wright procured one Rinehardt Planz to become bound in the Bond He ^the^ said <hi rend="str">Chris</hi> <hi rend="str">Wright</hi> Rinehardt Planz not Knowing my said husband Conrad Shipp.</p>
<p>Your petitioner states that her husband became alarmed and has fled from the Country leaving her &amp; her children to shift for themselves;</p>
<p>She states that if the said Judgment upon the said Bond which was rendered in the Jefferson Circuit<pb/>
<lb/>Court on the <date when="1865-09-23">23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> day of Sept<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 1865</date> ^for the sum of $300 00 &amp; costs^ is enforced it will Strip her of every thing in the world She states that her husband as she veryily believes was not guilty of stealing the Iron, but a timid and unlearned man and unable to speak except in the german language, he became troubled in his mind, and from trouble and fear he went off aband<hi rend="str">ing</hi>oning the Country and all he had:</p>
<p>Your petitioner humbly prays that you will interpose executive clemency towards her and remit the amount of the Judgement to R Pflanz rendered as aforesaid in the <date when="1865-09-23">23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> day of Septr 1865</date>. in the Jefferson Circuit Court and will every pray &amp;c</p>
<p>Barbara <unclear>Shipp</unclear> </p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Jefferson Circuit Sct</p>
<p>Barbara Ship says that the above petition is true</p>
<p>Barbara <unclear>Shipp</unclear></p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Barbara Shipp this <date when="1865-12-22">22<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> Debr A D 1865</date></p>
<p>S. A. Atchinson jr
<lb/>N. P J C.<pb/></p>
<p>Rinehart Pflanz states that He resides in the City of Louisville and that on <gap/> day of <date when="1865">1865</date>, Mr Chris Wright asked affiant to go security for the appearance of Conrad Shipp in the Jefferson Circuit Court, in a Bond for $300 that He was unaquainted with Shipp but Mr Chris Wright who was known to affiant to be a reliable man; making a representation to him about the matter and agreeing to pay the amount if Shipp did not appear He signed said Bond as aforesaid He states that said Shipp had a good report from his neighbors and he believed then and now that he was not guilty of Stealing the iron</p>
<p>Rinehard Pflanz</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this <date when="1865-12-28">28th day of December 1865</date></p>
<p>Jo<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Clement. Justice of the peace Jeff Co Ky</p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><stamp>J C
<lb/><date when="1865-12-28">De 28
<lb/>1865</date></stamp></p>
<p>From the statements made to me by Mr Geo Ainslie (of the firm of Ainslie &amp; Cochran) I believe the bond in the case ought to be remitted &amp; that there is more merit in the case than almost any other petition I have signed</p>
<p>J R Dupuy
<lb/>Com' atty -- 
<lb/>Geo W. Johnston ct Judge Com' atty -- <pb/></p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Rinehard Pflanz
<lb/>$300,
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1866-03-03">3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Mch 1866</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
