<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0369"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky vs. George W. Dobson, Isaac Gore, and R. S. Thomas, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8821</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-93 to R4-98</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hart County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-05-22">22 May 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Please before Charles Green Judge of the Hart Equity &amp; Criminal Court at the Court House in Mumfordville <date when="1860-10-09">October 9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1860</date>,
<lb/>Commonwealth Plaintiff
<lb/>Against } Indictment for violating Tavern Bond.
<lb/>George W Dobson Isaac Gore and R S Thomas } Defts</p>
<p>Be it remembered that heretofore to wit on the <date when="1859-10-13">13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of October 1859</date> the Grand Jury of Hart County came into Court and by their Foreman in their presents <hi rend="str">returned</hi> presented to the court a number of Indictments one of which is against G W Dobson &amp;c for violating Tavern Bond which went ordered to be filed. Said Indictment reads to wit:</p>
<p>Hart Equity and Criminal Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>Against
<lb/>George W Dobson Isaac Gore &amp; R S Thomas</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Hart County in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky accuse George W Dobson of the offense of violating his tavern bond or covenant committed as to wit the said George W Dobson on the <gap/> day of <date when="1859-06">June 1859</date> and at the <date when="1859-06">June Term 1859</date> of the Hart -- Court in the County aforesaid and at<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">2</note>
<lb/>The Court house in said County on his instance to and before the County Court of said County said Court then being in session procured said court to Grant to him the said George W Dobson a license permitting and authorizing him the said Dobson to keep a Tavern with the privilege of retailing Spirituous liquors at his residence in Hart County for 12 months which order and license of the said County Court is in substance following to wit:</p>
<p>"Hart County Court <date when="1859-06">June Term 1859</date> on motion of George W Dobson it is ordered that a license issue to him to keep a tavern (with the privilege of retailing Spirituous liquors at his residence in Hart County for 12 months from this date, He having this day paid in Court the state tax taken the oath and together with Isaac Gore &amp; R S Thomas as his sureties entered into and acknowledged covenant to the Commonwealth of Kentucky conditioned as prescribed by law"</p>
<p>And the Grand Jury aforesaid charge that upon the day aforesaid before said County Court he the said George W Dobson as a tavern keeper under and by virtue of said order and license executed his covenant to the Commonwealth with Isaac Gore R S Thomas his sureties which is the<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">3</note>
<lb/>same bond refered to in the foregoing order and reading in substance as follows to with,</p>
<p>"Tavern Keepers Bond
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Whereas George W Dobson has obtained a license to keep a Tavern at his Residence in the County of Hart Now we George W Dobson principal and R S Thomas Isaac Gore Surety do hereby covenant and agree that the said Dobson shall Continually find and provide in said Tavern good wholesome cleanly lodging and diet for travelers and stabling and provender or pasturage for horses or mules during the period the license remains in force and that he will not suffer any gaming in his house or on his premises and will not suffer any person to tipple or drink more than is necessary in his house or on his premises or at any time suffer any scandelous or disorderly behaviour in his house or on his premises,</p>
<p>Given under our hands this <gap/> day of <date when="1859-06">June 1859</date>
<lb/>G W ^his X mark^ Dobson 
<lb/>Isaac W Gore
<lb/>R S Thomas</p>
<p>Attest the Grand Jury aforesaid<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">4</note>
<lb/>aver and charge that he the said George W Dobson in the County aforesaid on the <gap/> day of <date when="1859-10">October 1859</date> and on divers other days before then since the issuing of said license and the execution of said Covenant violate his said covenant in this to wit</p>
<p>That he suffered and encouraged divers persons to game by playing cards in his house and on his premises upon which game or games money or property was bet won and lost and that he suffered and permitted persons to tipple and drink more than was necessary in his house and on his premises and that he suffered and permitted scandalous and disorderly -- in his house and on his premises the said house and premises being the place house and premises where he was licesnsed to keep and did keep said Tavern and the same styled in said order and in said bond as his residence against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>W B Jones Atty for the Commwth</p>
<p>And on the said <date when="1859-10-13">13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of Oct 1859</date> at the Court House aford</p>
<p>"It is ordered that a Bench warrant issue against Deft Dobson for his<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">5</note>
<lb/>arrest herein endorsed that he may be admitted to bail in the sum of $300, &amp; that summons issue against the other defendants returnable to the next term of this court.</p>
<p>Upon which a Bench warrant &amp; summons issued Returned by the Sheriff executed of G W Dobson &amp; R S Thomas &amp; not found as to Isaac Gore.</p>
<p>And afterwards to wit on the <hi rend="str">5</hi><date when="1860-10-08">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of October 1860</date> at an Equity &amp; Criminal Court Commenced and held for Hart County at the Court afsd</p>
<p>"This day came the surities of Defendant on his Bail Bond herein and surrendered him to the custody of the Court declining to stand bound further as his surities whereupon on motion of Deft It is ordered that he be permitted to give bail in the sum of $300, and thereupon Thomas Bale of Hart County Ky and John Walters of LaRue County Kentucky appeared personally in Court and acknowledged themselves jointly indebted to the Commonwealth of Kentucky in the sum of Three hundred Dollars to be void however if George M Dobson shall appear in the Hart Equity &amp; Criminal Court on the said day of its present Term to answer the indictment for a violation of Tavern Bond found in said Court against him &amp;c and shall not depart<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">6</note>
<lb/>without leave of the court and shall at all times render himself amenable to the orders &amp; process of said Court in the prosecution of said charge and if convicted shall render himself in execution thereof"</p>
<p>And on the <date when="1860-10-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of Oct 1860</date> at said Court continued &amp; held at the place afsd</p>
<p>"This day came the atto for the Commonwealth and the Deft Dobson appeared in discharge of his recogce and Deft Thomas having been duly summoned a Jury was Empannelled and sworn to wit 1 John Smith 2 Elijah Moss 3 Robt Moss 4 W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Hill 5 Nathan Yoveb 6 A T Burd 7 W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Gore 8 W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Craddock 9 H B Wilson 10 Jas T Lively 11 W J Keith 12 Porsser Cornice who after hearing the evidence and argument returned into Court the following verdict to wit "We of the Jury find the defendant George W Dobson guilty of the offense charged in the within indictment as therein charged <hi rend="underline">H B Wilson foreman</hi>. It is therefore adjudged by the Court that the Plaintiff recover of the Defendants Geo W Dobson &amp; R S Thomas the sum of <hi rend="underline">Three Hundred Dollars</hi> and the costs of this prosecution and said Dobson may be taken &amp;c</p>
<p>One of the casas issue on the foregoing Judgment reads as follows to wit</p>
<p>"The Commonwealth of Kentucky to<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">7</note>
<lb/>the Sheriff of same County Greeting We command you that you take Geo W Dobson late of your Bailiwick if he may be found and him safely keep so that you have his body before the Judge of our Hart Circuit Court at the Court House in Mumfordville on the saturday after the first Monday of June next to satisfy the Commonwealth of Kentucky of the sum of Three Hundred Dollars which the said Commonwealth lately in our said Court recovered against him &amp;c for her fine upon a certain Indictment for a violation of Tavern Bond also the sum of $17.15 which in the same Court was adjudged to said Commonwealth for his costs in that behalf expended whereof he is convicted as appears of record and that you have the said sums of money before the Judge of our said Court at the Court House aforesaid on the Saturday after the first Monday in <date when="--06">June</date> next to render to the said Commonwealth of the fine and costs aforesaid and have then there this writ, Witness George S Ward Clerk of our said Court at the Court House aforesaid the <date when="1861-04-13">13 day of April 1861</date> and in the 69 year of the Commonwealth</p>
<p>G S Ward C H C C
<lb/><unclear>Repl</unclear> <date when="1861-04-17">April 17 1861</date> &amp; Repleved in office
<lb/>Att Jas H Compton D C<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">8</note>
<lb/>The Replevin Bond Reads as follows to wit</p>
<p>Commonwealth Plff
<lb/>Against } Upon Indictment for violation of Tavern Bond
<lb/>George W Dobson R S Thomas &amp; Isaac W Gore } Defts</p>
<p>This day came the defendants George W Dobson &amp; R S Thomas together with Thomas Bale their security before me George J Wood clerk of the Hart Equity &amp; Criminal Court and undertook that they would satisfy and pay the Plaintiff the Commonwealth of Kentucky her fine including costs amounting to three hundred and seventeen Dollars and sixty five cents ($317.65) rendered in her favor against the said defendants George W Dobson &amp; R S Thomas by this Court within Three months with legal interest from this <date when="1861-04-17">17<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of April 1861</date></p>
<p>Geo W ^his X mark^ Dobson 
<lb/>R S Thomas
<lb/>Thomas Bale</p>
<p>Att
<lb/>Jno C Compton D C
<lb/>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Hart Equity &amp; Criminal Court sct</p>
<p>This day Thomas Bale appeared before me and made oath that after payment of all his<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">9</note>
<lb/>Just debts and legal liabilities he is able to pay the amt of the within bond <date when="1861-04-17">April 17 1861</date></p>
<p>Geo J Wood Clk</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Hart Equity &amp; Criminal Court sct</p>
<p>I James H Compton Clerk of the Hart Equity &amp; Criminal Court Do certify that the foregoing is a true copy of Indictment orders Judgment Case &amp; Replevin Bond in the case of the Commonwealth of Kentucky against Geo W Dobson &amp;c</p>
<p>Given under my hand this <date when="1863-05-22">22d day of May 1863</date>
<lb/>Jas H Compton Clk
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Hart Equity &amp; Criminal Ct</hi>
<lb/><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp"><unclear/></note><pb/></p>
<p>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Transcript
<lb/>Geo W Dobson &amp;c
<lb/>For T Bale
<lb/>Fee $3.00</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
