<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1260"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Alexander Long to L. A. Wood</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5897</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-441 to BR11-442</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Cincinnati, Hamilton County, Ohio</placeName>
    <date when="1864-10-18">18 October 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Cincinnati <date when="1864-10-18">Oct. 18<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>L. A. Wood Esqr
<lb/>Louisville K.y.
<lb/>My Dear Sir:</p>
<p>Understanding that you acted as counsel for the son of M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi>. Eliza Benson, who was convicted of the crime of Larceny, in your Criminal Court and Sentenced to the state Prison, where he is now confined; &amp; that M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi>. B. is anxious to make an appeal to the Governor of the State, to interpose executive clemency in his behalf, I am induced to address you this note, to advise you of the good character, pecuniary condition and feeble health of Mrs. Benson.</p>
<p>I have known M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi>. B. and her family for the past twenty=four years; some fifteen years since, by the death of her husband, She was left destitute with a family of five Small children, dependent upon her for Support; by industry, economy and perserverence, She managed to keep her family together until the commencement of the present war, when her four sons went into the Service<pb/>
<lb/>leaving herself and her daughter alone. She is now unable to go to Louisville, or Lexington, as well for want of means to do so, as from ill health and while I know nothing about the case of her son, I am impelled Solely from a Sense of justice to a worthy, deserving and exemplary mother, grieving and pining over the misfortune of an erring, but as I am informed repentant Son, to address you this note in her behalf and ask on the Score of common humanity, that you will use your influence, as the Counsel of her Son, so far as you can honorably and consistently with the duty of your profession, to procure his pardon and restore him again to his family and friends</p>
<p>I am
<lb/>Very Respectfully Yours
<lb/>Alexander Long<pb/></p>
<p>Cheviot <date when="1864-10-19">Oct 19<hi rend="sup">th</hi>/64</date>
<lb/>L. A. Wood Esq.
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>I fully concur with the Hon<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Ale<hi rend="sup">x</hi> Long in his statement in regard to Mrs Eliza Benston and family, and join in soliciting your exertions in procuring a pardon for her son, adding that I am, and have been for the last fifteen years, the family physician of Mrs Benston.</p>
<p>Yours Respectfully
<lb/>E. D. Crookshank MD</p>
<p>Cheviot <date when="1864-10-19">Oct 19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> L A Wood
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>Having been acquainted with the family of M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> Eliza Benson for the past twenty years. I can fully endorse the statement of Hon A Long. and Doctor Crookshank. and hope you may succede in your worthy endeavors. in the Release of William Benson. believing that he will make a worthy citizen</p>
<p>Yours Respectfully
<lb/>Thomas Wills P. M.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
