<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0046"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">C. M. Davis et al. to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9514</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17A-116 to MG17A-117</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-02-05">5 February 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Whereas Thomas Wadlington has been sentenced to be han^g^d on the <date when="--03-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> day of March</date> for the killing of a certain Cartwright about 12 months since. Now therefore we the people of Charleston and its vicinity, beleveing that the criminal should be entirely pardoned recommend him to the mercy of your own eccellency, as to the morality and good form of said Wadlington, none stands higher, this is the only dificulty we have ever heard of his geting in, during a considerable age.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>C <hi rend="str">D</hi> M Davis
<lb/>James C Sofel
<lb/>H A Parish
<lb/>John M <unclear>Hyden</unclear>
<lb/><unclear>T M Younger</unclear>
<lb/>A O Bobb
<lb/>John OBryan
<lb/>H C OBryan
<lb/>N. B. Earle
<lb/>H Sister
<lb/>J F Hobb
<lb/>V P Hardwick
<lb/>F F Fowler
<lb/>T H Wowney
<lb/>Henry Doaksy
<lb/>John Bergenson
<lb/>A Mahn
<lb/><cb n="2"/>David N Davis
<lb/>E Jones
<lb/>Milton Tery
<lb/>James A Franklin
<lb/>James E Miller
<lb/>Wooding P long
<lb/>A D Scot
<lb/>James T Mitchell
<lb/>David Long
<lb/>H. R. Lindsey
<lb/>Obadiah <unclear>wilson</unclear>
<lb/>Davis Light
<lb/>Joseph C Hill
<lb/>David Wright
<lb/>E. G. Stearn
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>David M Hawkins<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Albert Major
<lb/>H H Morton
<lb/>A, L, Stevens
<lb/>H C M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Euen
<lb/>W, B, Laffoon
<lb/>John, H, Laffoon
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Oliver W M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Euen
<lb/>A B Ames
<lb/>A W Reay<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Sir ^your^ Honor may not conclude that because this sheat is not filled with petitioners that we could get no more but we conclude we have enough. When a thousand or too men have <hi rend="str">been</hi> raised there voises to you in behalf of inocenc it seems useless to annoy you with ^more^ and if you will turn a deaf year and a colt heart to your petitioners and Wadlington should be hung, his bood will be sprinkled on the mouths of the doors of Princeton Court house, The base within will be in <unclear/> stain with a christions Blood and all the <unclear/> will wear the aspect of mornful drapery. whilst the verry pillers of the might building<pb/>
<lb/>utter groans of Lamentations for the cruelty of the execution.. Sir in a previous letter that I directed to your honor, I did not have the evidence of the case before me, but have adverted to it in remarks, beleaving I had been correctly informed. The great wonder is that your many petitiones had not prayed for young Wadlington to be released from penatitiary who was in the same charge of Thomas W his father,</p>
<p>A few verses next</p>
<p>O cruel fate if he should die
<lb/>on a degarded cross,
<lb/>for doing what all men would do
<lb/>That was not made of dross
<lb/>for God has planted in the heart
<lb/>Of every man of sense
<lb/>A will to take anothers life
<lb/>When in his own defefense
<lb/>Especially when weapons were
<lb/>In his assailants hand
<lb/>should he forsake his premises 
<lb/>And leave his house and land
<lb/>And leave his home and hide ^his^ face
<lb/>In some secluded place
<lb/>and <hi rend="str">leave</hi> yeald claims manliness
<lb/>and bear the worlds disgrace
<lb/>Whilst life shall last, false well but
<lb/>He will defend himself, It is a wright due
<lb/>to him his children and his wife</p>
<p><date when="1861-02-05">Febr 5 -- 1861</date>
<lb/>George Ligon<pb/></p>
<p>I requested you to send my letter back to Madisonville to G Ligon please send this, Sir will not trubble you more, But will allways admire and love you</p>
<p>George Ligon</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
