<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0393"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">G. M. Huggans et al. to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8845</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-135 to R4-136</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lyon County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-05-07">7 May 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To Honorable James Robinson.
<lb/>Governor of the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned petitioners would respectfully solicit your attention to the subjoined facts -- relating to the forfeiture of a bond to the Com<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> of Five hundred dollars. One Charles Braswell of the County of Lyon Kentucky, was indicted in the Circuit Court of said County for Larceny commited by stealing a watch, He was but fifteen year's of age &amp; belonged to a very respectable family, of people -- His father permited him to go to jail, &amp; remain for the space of two days &amp; nights, when him &amp; one other person went his bail, His father N T Braswell (&amp; security) gave him permission after his release from Confinement to go to St Louis, to see a brother he has living there -- with the distinct understanding that he return prior to the term of the Court at which he was under bond to appear, which was the <date when="1860-06">June term of 1860</date> Said Boy went to St Louis, and did not return in time for above named term of the Court, in consequence of severe illness, that said Boy was very sick, &amp; like to have died, &amp; was in said Condition at the time of said Court &amp; had been several weeks before -- That his sureties were not aware of above fact at the time of court named -- &amp; said bond was taken as forfeited. That he wrote to St Louis time &amp; again, between the time said bond was forfeited &amp; the Court succeeding, but<pb/>
<lb/>from some unknown ^cause^ unless it was the disturbed Condition of the Country, he could never hear from his boy -- &amp; that said bond was taken as finally forfeited, <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> an execution of Scrie facius issued against this surety, for the above named money -- That they have learned that it was morally &amp; Phisically impossible for the boy to have been in attendance at the time prescribed in said bond &amp; therefore they ask that under existing circumstances, deeming it contrary to the spirit and intention of the law, to compel a man to pay a bond of Five hundred dollars for the appearance of an individual in a certain Court -- when it was physically and morally impossible to have complied, That Justice &amp; equity demands a release, &amp; we rely upon your generous spirit, for justice in the premises -- with much regard. This <date when="1863-05-07">7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> May 1863</date> -- </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>G, M, Huggans
<lb/>A. Brock
<lb/>Jas M Bigham
<lb/>G Z Smith
<lb/>T J Hollman
<lb/>Horace A. Howard
<lb/>F. Marhen
<lb/>Thomas Love
<lb/>Lewis Evans
<lb/>J, H, Hunter
<lb/>F M Browning
<lb/>M E Bridges
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J T Young Shf
<lb/>J. W. Clark
<lb/>J Morris
<lb/>James H. Holloway
<lb/>W, K, Bigham
<lb/>W W Heldath
<lb/>W W. Pinney
<lb/>W A M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Quigg
<lb/>A. H Dudley
<lb/>O M. Jenkens
<lb/>Robert Boyd
<lb/>Henry Mayer
<lb/>John Boyd<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>James H Catlett
<lb/>A, M, Fleming
<lb/>H. K S Gateware
<lb/>R, L, Rowlands
<lb/>G, C Holloway
<lb/>W. Y. Smith
<lb/>C. L. Boone
<lb/>J. W. Smith
<lb/>Wm Jones
<lb/>J W Grifin
<lb/>David Boone
<lb/>Jas Marum
<lb/>Levi Jones
<lb/>Geo W Hayward
<lb/>T, F, Settles
<lb/>John Mayhew
<lb/>John Bean
<lb/>W B Wadlington
<lb/>J Boston
<lb/>Jos Cummingham
<lb/>John Hayes
<lb/>J. N. Halloway
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Wood
<lb/>C H Jones
<lb/>C H Boyd
<lb/>L. M. Cobb
<lb/>A. Hunter
<lb/>S. P. L. Marshall Jr.
<lb/>B Ennis
<lb/>P M <unclear/>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">John Stacker Jr</hi>
<lb/>David Down
<lb/>Wm Moneymaker
<lb/><cb n="2"/>William Settles
<lb/>J S Brown
<lb/>Wilson Hail
<lb/>T. A. Hammond
<lb/>S L Jenkins
<lb/>John M Brown
<lb/>Henry Lady
<lb/>J W Ethridge
<lb/>H, P Smith
<lb/>Thomas W Gainer
<lb/>L A, Cummins
<lb/>W H Long
<lb/>Robert A. Dickson
<lb/>Joseph C. Casidy
<lb/>David <unclear>Russels</unclear>
<lb/>D, L, Gardner</p>
<p>Examine this and the one for N K. Barnes also as soon as possible &amp; oblige your's</p>
<p>Respt of J W Bush -- <milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Lyon Cir. Ct.
<lb/>$500. } For</p>
<p>The forfeiture in this case is respited for three months to enable the young man to appear &amp; stand his trial If he does so the forefeiture will then be remitted</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J F Robinson</hi>
<lb/>N. T. Braswell &amp; others
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-05-18">May 18<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
