<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1850"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Wiley Green to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6487</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-417 to BR13-418</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlette Governor of Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>your Petitioner Wiley Green would respectfully represent unto your Excellency that at at the <date when="1864-08">August term of the Laurel circuit court 1864</date> he was indicted for Keeping a Tipling house That at The Present <date when="1865-03">March Term of said Court 1865</date> He Entered a plea of guilty of Retailing and Judgment went against him for twenty dollars &amp; costs The circumstances under which he was Indicted and find as aforesaid were as follows viz He was a refugee from Tennessee &amp; had no means here of making a living but by hard work and hired to work at a Military Post near London &amp; was at the time working for the Government of the United States &amp; was in John Pitmans Bar room ^he being a Licensed Tavern Keeper^ one day when his Clerk steped out the clerk requested your Petitioner to wait upon any one calling at the bar while he the clerk was gone &amp; your Petitioner did so without being sworn &amp; sold one glass or drink of ardent Spirits for the man Pitman without realizing or Expecting or intending to realize one<pb/>
<lb/>cent for his own use &amp; did not know or<hi rend="str">of</hi> think of having violated law until a bench warrant was Executed on him He Says that he is a poor man having a family to Support and and has been driven from his home in Tennessee by this ruthless rebellion for no other reason than His loyalty to the Government of the united States That unless your Excellency should interade He will be compeled to pay said fine or permit his Suarities to pay it or let his family suffer The Circumstances considered the prayer of your Petitioner is that you remit said fine for which He will ever feel greatful</p>
<p>Wiley Green</p>
<p>The undersigned believe the Statements in ^the^ foregoing Petition are true &amp; Join in the prayer thereof</p>
<p>R. Boyd
<lb/>H F Finley
<lb/>Wm T. Moren
<lb/>C B Faris clk
<lb/>Laurel Cir Court
<lb/>M. L. Rice
<lb/>Robert Mays
<lb/>H K Wilson
<lb/>John H Wilson
<lb/>John Farmer
<lb/>David Y Lyttle<cb/>
<lb/>A Aithman
<lb/>John. H. Carrier
<lb/>John Burnett
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W. H Randall</hi></p>
<p>Gov Bramlett
<lb/>Dear sir I hope that you will remit this fine</p>
<p>yours Truly
<lb/>G Pearl<pb/></p>
<p>Laurel Co
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Robt Davis
<lb/>$20
<lb/><date when="1865-05-04">4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> May/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
