<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1740"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. E. C. Lusk et al., Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6377</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-245</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>McCracken County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Cracken Circuit Court
<lb/>Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against
<lb/>E. C. Lusk Jas Newberry W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Wallace, W R Babb A. L. Banks &amp; Jasper Babb</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracken County in the name &amp; by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky accuse E C Lusk Jas Newberry W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Wallace, W R Babb, A. L. Banks &amp; Jasper Babb of the crime of Horse stealing committed as follows, Viz. The said Lusk Newberry Wallace Babb Banks &amp; Babb did no the <date when="1865-04-14">14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of April 1865</date> in the county aforesaid feloniously take and carry away one horse of the value of one hundred dollars the personal property of Franklin Harris -- The Grand Jury aforesaid charge that at the time and place aforesaid the said E. C. Lusk &amp; A L Banks took and carried away one horse of the value of one hundred dollars the personal property of Franklin Harris &amp; the said Jas Newberry W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Wallace W R Babb &amp; Jasper Babb were accessories before the fact by aiding abetting counselling &amp; encouraging the said theft -- The Grand Jury aforesaid charge that at the time and place aforesaid the said Jas Newberry W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Wallace &amp; Jasper Babb feloniously took &amp; carried away one horse of the value of one hundred dollars the personal property of Franklin Harris &amp; the said E C Lusk. W. R Babb &amp; A. L. Banks were acessories before the fact by counselling aiding abetting &amp; encouraging &amp; advising in the said theft -- all against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">P D Yeiser, Coml atty</hi></p>
<p>Witnesses
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> <hi rend="underline">Hull</hi>, Franklin Harris
<lb/>Sterling Sheron Jacob Roark
<lb/>Ed Moore of Graves Co</p>
<p>A Copy -- attest
<lb/>B Small clk
<lb/>By H. C. Yeiser D C<pb/></p>
<p>"Bail is fixed on this indictment at Five hundred dollars for each deft</p>
<p>C. S. Marshall Judge"</p>
<p>"W R Babb ^has been^ discharged by order of court -- </p>
<p>B Small Clk
<lb/>By H C Yeiser D. C"</p>
<p>M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracken Cir Ct
<lb/>Coml 
<lb/>v } Horse stealing
<lb/>E. C. Lusk &amp; others<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>A true bill
<lb/>J G Cole
<lb/>foreman<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Filed <date when="1865-04-26">26<hi rend="sup">th</hi> April 1865</date>
<lb/>Bch Wart</p>
<p>E Moore </p>
<p>Copy
<lb/><hi rend="str">Clk</hi> <hi rend="str">fee</hi> <hi rend="str">340.</hi> <hi rend="str">cts</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
