<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0518"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. H. Schmoddle to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8970</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Hannah M. O'Daniel</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-323</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-08-06">6 August 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency, <persName ref="cwgk:N001004">James F Robinson</persName>--<lb/>Governor of <orgName ref="cwgk:O001025">Kentucky</orgName>:</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00000457">Your Petitioner</persName> respectfully represents that he is the Driver or Agent for <persName ref="cwgk:N00000458">C. W. Roback</persName> in the Sale of "Roback's Bitters", and was arrested while so employed in the <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000936">City of Covington</placeName> and fined $50 and costs. He showed a City License to C W Roback to peddle said Bitters in said city on which was an endorsement that Petitioner was the Agent of said Roback. The Magistrate however decided that no one but Mr Roback himself could drive the waggon and furnish said Bitters in said City, and differed with the <persName ref="cwgk:N00000961">City Mayor</persName> in the Construction of the City ordinance. Petitioner sends herewith the statements of the Mayor, Magistrate and Hon <persName ref="cwgk:N00000460">J F Fisk</persName> the acting County Attorney, who Join in the prayer of <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>this Petitioner to have said fine cancelled and <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>your Petitioner pardoned. <persName ref="cwgk:N00000457">Your Petitioner</persName> was tried before <persName ref="cwgk:N00000960">B Eggleston</persName> J. P, <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000645">K C</orgName> and it is admitted that if said magistrate decided the law correctly, that the offence was caused by the mistaken advice<pb/>
<lb/>of the Mayor who issued the License. The establishment of <persName ref="cwgk:N00000458">C. W. Roback</persName> is in <placeName ref="cwgk:P00001208">Cincinnati, Ohio</placeName>, and Petitioner acted as his driver in bringing over his Bitters to various persons in the <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000936">City of Covington</placeName>, and believed that under the License of Mr Roback which Petitioner carried with him, and on which was endorsed that he was the Agent of Mr Roback, that he was legally authorized to do so under the instructions of the Mayor.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner respectfully prays that said penalty or fine be cancelled by the exercise of the Executive Clemency. And your Petitioner will ever pray -- 
<lb/>Covington <date when="1863-08-06">August 6, 1863</date>.</p>
<p>W. H. <unclear>Schmoddle</unclear></p>
<p>I was acting for the County Atty in prosecuting the defendant, The facts are correctly set forth in the above. I am of the opinion that petitioner's employer was misled by the Mayor-- that had he not been informed that his driver could peddle under his employer's License &amp; that the offense would not have bean committed hence I ask that the fine be remitted.</p>
<p>John F. Fisk</p>
<p>Wm. Shmoddle Pettn
<lb/>fine remitted
<lb/>J F Robinson</p>
   <p>send <persName ref="cwgk:N00000459">John P. Harrison</persName>
<lb/>Covington</p>
<p>Kenton J P Ct.
<lb/>$50 } Peddling
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1863-08-15">Aug 15 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
