<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1842"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Edward P. Campbell to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6479</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-404 to BR13-407</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hopkinsville, Christian County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-05-18">18 May 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">(<hi rend="underline">N</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> 1</hi>)</note>
<lb/>Hopkinsville Kentucky <date when="1865-05-18">May 18<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>To his excellency
<lb/>Gov Thomas.. E.. Bramlette
<lb/>Frankfort Ky
<lb/>Dr Sir</p>
<p>At the <date when="1863-11">November Term 1863</date> of the Muhlenberg Circuit Court the <hi rend="underline">Grand</hi> <hi rend="underline">Jury</hi> returned 5 Indictments against James W Sullivan chargeing him with the crime of <hi rend="underline">Forgery</hi> Bail was required in the sum of $1000x in each case.. to answer said indictments and in <date when="1864-01">January</date> Or <date when="1864-02">February 1864</date> James.. W.. Sullivan was arrested in Louisville and was delivered Over to the Sheriff of Breckinridge County and by him delivered to the <hi rend="underline">Jailor</hi> of Muhlenberg County and confined in <hi rend="underline">Jail</hi> and on the <date when="1864-02-23">23<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> February 1864</date> sued out a writ of <hi rend="underline">habeas</hi> <hi rend="underline">corpus</hi> and offered his father Raughley Sullivan as <hi rend="underline">his</hi> <hi rend="underline">bail</hi> and his father was accepted as his bail in each bond 5 in all,, each bond for $1000x James.. W.. Sullivan ran off and as I am informed is now in <hi rend="underline">Calafornia</hi> Or in <hi rend="underline">Canada</hi>,, he failed to appear and his <hi rend="underline">bail</hi> bonds were declared forfeited at <date when="1864-05">May Term 1864</date> of said court,, Summons issued against his bail and at the <date when="1864-11">November Term 1864</date> of said court,, <hi rend="underline">five</hi> <hi rend="underline">seperate</hi> judgments were rendered against Raughley Sullivan his bail for $1000x in each case amounting to sum of $5000x in all,, Executions have been issued on said Judgments and <hi rend="underline">have</hi><pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">(<hi rend="underline">N</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> 2</hi>)</note>
<lb/>been returned by sheriff of Muhlenberg County,, No <hi rend="underline">Property</hi> <hi rend="underline">found</hi> out of which to make said <hi rend="underline">executions</hi> and and this occurs from this <hi rend="underline">reason</hi>,, Raughley Sullivan stated <hi rend="underline">under</hi> <hi rend="underline">oath</hi> at the time he was accepted as bail for his son that he was worth in property over and above all debts and liabilities of $<hi rend="underline">5000</hi>x and I presume at the time from all the <hi rend="underline">information</hi> I have that he was not embarassed or in debt and was worth about $10,<hi rend="underline">000</hi>x but a part of his Estate consisted of 8 or 10 negroes and they are now <hi rend="underline">worthless</hi> and on the <date when="1864-05-03">3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> day of May 1864</date> Raughley Sullivan in order to prevent the collection of these <hi rend="underline">Judgments</hi> against him when <hi rend="underline">rendered</hi> and in order to <hi rend="underline">defraud</hi> the <hi rend="underline">Commonwealth</hi> and <hi rend="underline">avoid</hi> his liability on said bonds as <hi rend="underline">bail</hi> as I am informed from rumor and as I <hi rend="underline">believe</hi> sold and conveyed all his landed Estate to John,, S,, Eaves Jr for $5000x and executed Deed to said Eaves for the same and also sold off all his <hi rend="underline">personal</hi> <hi rend="underline">Estate</hi> and rendered himself <hi rend="underline">insolvent</hi> and <hi rend="underline">worthless</hi>,, divers of persons <hi rend="underline">believe</hi> the Deed to Eaves fraudulent,, but I have used proper exertion to find out and I am by no <hi rend="underline">means</hi> certain that I can <hi rend="underline">establish</hi> the <hi rend="underline">fraud</hi> by proof,, my Opinion is Sullivan has converted all he had into money,, and his <hi rend="underline">money</hi> is beyond the limits of the state where I can not find out,,</p>
<p>Raughley Sullivan is an <hi rend="underline">Old</hi> <hi rend="underline">Man</hi> about 65 years of age and his neighbors and acquaintances say he has ever borne the reputation of an honest sober industrious good citizen and in fact had as good a <hi rend="underline">character</hi><pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">(<hi rend="underline">No 3</hi>)</note>
<lb/>as any man in Muhlenberg County,, and all he had -- he had made by honest industry and hard licks,, But his son James,, W,, Sullivan is no doubt an <hi rend="underline">infamous</hi> and <hi rend="underline">splendid</hi> <hi rend="underline">scoundrel</hi> and ought to be in the <hi rend="underline">Penetentiary</hi> and if he had remained to be tried he would have been found <hi rend="underline">Guilty</hi> as I believe in each and all of said <hi rend="underline">indictments</hi> Raughley Sullivan has 2 small children On his hands one a son in bad health the other a little daughter and his wife is <hi rend="underline">dead</hi> and he informs me that he is anxious to educate his little daughter,, he says if he pays said Judgments to the Commonwealth for $<hi rend="underline">5000</hi>x it will take all the means he has and leave him and his 2 children destitute and pennyless,, He informs me that he is willing and anxious to pay to the Commonwealth $500x and the Commonwealth attys fees in said cases amounting to sum of $1,<hi rend="underline">500</hi>x and Sheriffs and clerks fees if you will release him of the balance of said Judgments amounting to sum of $<hi rend="underline">3000</hi> -- and I believe he will do all he promises,, and if he will do this I believe it will be better than an <hi rend="underline">Everlasting</hi> <hi rend="underline">Law</hi> <hi rend="underline">Suit</hi>,, with him to set aside <hi rend="underline">fraudulent</hi> <hi rend="underline">deed</hi> and by Bills of <hi rend="underline">Discovery</hi> to get at his <hi rend="underline">means</hi>,, I am opposed to his <hi rend="underline">dictating</hi> <hi rend="underline">Terms</hi>,, but the question is can we do better than submit under all the circumstances,, I am interested in this matter to the extent of $1,<hi rend="underline">500</hi>x and have a wife and children to provide for,, though I am neither a <hi rend="underline">Begger</hi> or a <hi rend="underline">Pauper</hi> and have been robbed and harassed by this <hi rend="underline">infernal</hi> <hi rend="underline">Rebellion</hi> and the accursed Rebels and <hi rend="underline">Guerrillas</hi> <hi rend="underline">until</hi><pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">(<hi rend="underline">No 4</hi>)</note>
<lb/>that amount of money $1,<hi rend="underline">500</hi>x would keep me considerably,, I have endeavored to state the facts and would not make mistatement willfully and Knowingly for the whole amount and <hi rend="underline">Ten</hi> times the amount x and if you should deem it improper to <hi rend="underline">remit</hi> and <hi rend="underline">release</hi> <hi rend="underline">Raughley</hi> <hi rend="underline">Sullivan</hi> of the $<hi rend="underline">3000</hi>x I will go into him and worry him all I can and beat him if I <hi rend="underline">can</hi> and make him pay the whole amount if <hi rend="underline">possible</hi> But if you will remit $<hi rend="underline">3000</hi>x he will pay the balance immediately,, this course I am certain would subserve my interest best and in my <hi rend="underline">opinion</hi> <hi rend="underline">would</hi> <hi rend="underline">proove</hi> best for the interest of the Commonwealth also,, I refer you to <hi rend="underline">Senator</hi> B,, H,, Bristow as Knowing me well,, and he knows something of the <hi rend="underline">facts</hi> and statements made in this <unclear><hi rend="underline">letter</hi></unclear>,, and as to manner in which I have discharged all <hi rend="underline">duties</hi> <hi rend="underline">required</hi> of me as atty for the <hi rend="underline">Commonwealth</hi> in 2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> Judicial District }</p>
<p>I am Respectfully
<lb/>E P,, Campbell
<lb/>atty for <hi rend="underline">Comth</hi></p>
<p>P,, S,,</p>
<p>If you should remit and release Raughley Sullivan of $<hi rend="underline">3000</hi>x due on said Judgments for $<hi rend="underline">5000</hi>x please forward the <hi rend="underline">Remit</hi> to me at Hopkinsville Kentucky and much oblige }</p>
<p>Yours truly
<lb/><hi rend="underline">E P,, Campbell</hi><pb/></p>
<p>I have knowledge of most of the facts stated within by the Commonwealths attorney. Nothing can be made out of Sullivan by execution, and I believe nothing would be gained by a Bill of discovery. for I have reason to believe Sullivan would place himself beyond the jurisdiction of the Court. I have no interest whatever in the matter. but Mr Campbell who is ever remarkably vigilent in the discharge of his duties consulted me. and I urged him to save the $2000 -- if possible. I have not a doubt that it would be best for the state as well as for him</p>
<p>H. G. Petree</p>
<p>Muhlenburg Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Raughley Sullivan
<lb/>3 Judgts $1000 each</p>
<p>Remit as requested by Comths atty &amp; Judge &amp; send to Comths Atty
<lb/><date when="1865-05-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> May 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
