<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0223"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Silas Hill, James Maupin, and Thomas H. Barnes to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9691</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-186 to MG17-187</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Madison County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-12-19">19 December 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency B Magoffin
<lb/>Governor of Ky.</p>
<p>Your Petitioners Silas Hill, James Maupin and Thomas H Barnes respectfully represent. That in the Spring of the present year they entered as sureties of Joseph Williams in three bail bonds of $500<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> each, for his appearance in the Madison Circuit Court, to answer three Indictments pending against him in said Court. That said Williams shortly thereafter left the State and failed to appear in discharge of his bonds, which were forfeited, and at the present Special <date when="1860-12">December term</date> of said Court three Judgements of $500. each, besides costs, were obtained by the Commonwealth of Kentucky against Your Petititioners as sureties upon said forfeited bonds.</p>
<p>They further state that they neither aided or connived in any way at the leaving of said Williams or of his failure to appear -- They had no <hi rend="str">such</hi> intimation of his intention to leave, and have since used all reasonable exertions to ascertain his wherabouts so as to procure his arrest. They have heard that he died in the State of Indiana when on his return home to answer to the Indictments as required by his bonds. Letters to this effect have been received by his family -- Whether, however, such is really the case they have been unable to ascertain, but if true would operate to the release of your Petitioners as sureties.</p>
<p>Your Petitioners further state that at the time of entering the surety of Williams, they required him to execute to them a Mortgage upon all his estate, consisting of a small<pb/>
<lb/>tract of land and a small personalty. That said property was then considered sufficient for their indeminification, but owing to the pressure in monetary affairs, it will now be inadequate, and it is feared will fall ^far^ short. -- That said Williams was indebted to several persons, and also left his wife and several small children without any means of support other than the property embraced in said Mortgage, <hi rend="underline">every thing</hi> he possessed being thereby conveyed. Hence the Sureties will not only suffer loss, but the creditors will loose their debts, and his wife and children will be left in an utterly destitute condition.</p>
<p>These facts your petitioners believe present strong grounds for the interposition of Executive clemency. -- Wherefore they most respectfully pray your Excellency to remit so much of said judgements as may be under Your control</p>
<p><date when="1860-12-19">December 19 1860</date></p>
<p>Silas Hill 
<lb/>James Maupin
<lb/>Tho. H. Barnes</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Thomas H. Barnes <date when="1860-12-19">December 19. 1860</date>.</p>
<p>Att. <hi rend="underline">J. M. Shackelford</hi> C M C C</p>
<p>We concur in the prayer in the foregoing petition, and believe it presents strong grounds for the interpostion of your Excellency. <date when="1860-12-19">Dec 19. 1860</date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J M Shackelford</hi> C M C C
<lb/>R <hi rend="underline">Runyon</hi>
<lb/>F F Runyon M D
<lb/>E J Broaddus
<lb/>C H Breck
<lb/><hi rend="underline">C, F. Burnam</hi><pb/>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Will Rodes</hi>
<lb/>Thomas F. Stone
<lb/>W P Moore
<lb/>B. D Boatright
<lb/>Thomps. Burnam Jr
<lb/>D. Breck
<lb/>R. H. Johnson
<lb/>John Bennett
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Quincy Davis
<lb/>C. J. Walker
<lb/>Joseph Orell
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Will Meaker</hi>
<lb/>J W Crooke
<lb/>R. H Quinn
<lb/>J. B. Walker
<lb/><hi rend="underline">S. P. Walters</hi>
<lb/>John G Cole
<lb/>S. V. Rowland
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> M. Irvine</hi>
<lb/>Jas B. McCreary
<lb/><hi rend="underline">David Irvine</hi>
<lb/>P. P. Ballard
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Smith Collins
<lb/>J H Berry P M</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
