<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2643"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. W. Bush to John M. Palmer</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7280</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-225 to BR16-226</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Smithland, Livingston County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-11-19">19 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Smithland Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-11-19">Nov 19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>,
<lb/>Major Genl Palmer
<lb/>Dear Sir,</p>
<p>I hope that I will not be considered presumptuous in addressing you these few lines, for I am satisfied that in you Union soldiers always find ther most devoted friend, Capt Fontaine Hawkins Late of the United States army in incarcerated in the Crittenden County Jail for Murder -- The Circumstances are that while he was a Lieutenant in the 15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Cavalry in <date when="1862">1862</date> -- he was ordered by Major Butterfield Cmdg Post to arrest &amp; bring to Post Head Quarters, a certain man named, Brantly, a notorious rebel &amp; Compel him to submit to orders of said Head Quarters -- That in obedience to said orders he did arrest or attempt to arrest the above named, Brantly but said Brantly, resisted &amp; attempted to run to his house to get his gun, &amp; Called Hawkins a damned abolition Son-of a Bitch, that Hawkins halted him three or four times &amp; he still refused<pb/>
<lb/>to stop, when Hawkins fired upon him &amp; Killed him, Now sir it is exceedingly hard indeed, for an officer or soldier to be Compelled to do a thing by military orders &amp; then be subject to indictment &amp; punishiment for Same, Lt Guess of the 20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Rgt was also incarcerated in Said Jail for Killing a notorious Guerilla. Eliott, who belonged to Websters Guerilla band, Private Stevens of Same Regt was in like Condition but has been sent to Webster County to be tried by that Loyal element of Rebel's Such the Condition of Ky union Soliders, But Some hundred person Collected together during the sitting of Judge Fowlers Court at Said place &amp; broke the Jail open &amp; let Lt Guess out, but Hawkins &amp; stevens refused to Come out, unless releived by You or Gov<hi rend="underline">r</hi> Bramlette or the order of the Court, Such things are being done every where, Capt VanPelt of the 48<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky vols is indicted in Trigg County Six times for Killing Guerillas while in said Service. That this be the reward of Loyalty &amp; obedience to the orders of our officers, Must we be tried by Rebels for Killing rebel soldiers &amp; Guerillas while they are making war upon our Government ^they are^ trying to<pb/>
<lb/>destroy us, by Civil law, what they could not destroy by their muskets &amp; midnight assassins, Must our families be made destitute by such proscription, &amp; our children be disgraced by their Fathers expiating upon the gallows for Loyalty to our old mother Country -- God forbid Rebel soldiers stalk free, no prosecution for them, No hidden dungeons to their confinement, but eternal ruin &amp; disgrace to the Kentucky federal soldier, Our only hope is in you &amp; Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Bramlette -- I do not think that you will stand still &amp; permit such gross impositions to be practiced. upon the adherents of the Government -- May I beseech in Capt Hawkins behalf to obtain for him a Pardon from the Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> that he may be restored to his family &amp; make their desolate hearts to rejoice -- for reference to his good deportment as a union man &amp; soldier I refer your honor to Judge Black of the state senate John Gandell, of the Lower house, Capt Finney of the Same body -- Be pleased to assist his unfortunate Condition, "Gen<hi rend="underline">rl</hi> will you please send me Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Shermans &amp; Burbridges orders of 1864 (some time) to take no Guerilla prisoners" as I wish to use them<pb/>
<lb/>in behalf of Van Pelt, &amp; Guess,</p>
<p>Do not refuse me this Kindness &amp; ever accept my grateful thanks</p>
<p>I am Sir Your's
<lb/>Resp. J W Bush
<lb/>Lat Capt Cols 48<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky vols<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Smithland Ky <date when="1865-11-17">November 17<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> /65</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Bush J. W.
<lb/>late Captain, C<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi>. "G" 48<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky. Vols<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>B.# 565. -- Vol. 2. -- D. K. -- <date when="1865">1865</date> -- </p>
<p>Pleads the case of Capt <hi rend="underline">F</hi>. <hi rend="underline">Hawkins</hi> imprisoned for Killing a notorious Guerilla, whom he was ordered to arrest. -- Also reports similar &amp; unjust imprisonment and dwells strongly on the wrongs which loyal men &amp; former federal/soldiers are suffering from Rebels in this state. -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Head Qrs. Dept of Kentucky
<lb/>Louisville. <date when="1865-11-28">Nov. 28. 1865</date>.
<lb/>E and M, 209, Vol, 3, <date when="1865">1865</date>,</p>
<p>Respectfully forwarding to His Excellency Gov Bramlette and his attention called to <unclear/> I have taken the liberty of saying to Capt Bush "that Gov Bramlette will not allow the rebel <unclear>Juries</unclear> of the state to punish Union soldiers for doing their duty"</p>
<p>John M Palmer
<lb/>Maj Genl</p>
<p>Rec<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> -- D. K. -- <date when="1865-11-22">11. -- 22. -- 1865</date>.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
