<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2679"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Ford et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7316</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-306 to BR16-307</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-11-07">7 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency the H<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">on</hi></hi> Thomas E. Bramlette, Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> of the state of Kentucky your petitioners most humbly state that on or about the <gap/> day of <date when="1864-09">September 1864</date>. Jackson King was arrested and carried to Scottsville in Allen County charged with Felony or Larceny and he and Mary King were bound by a Recognizaance in the Sum of $300.<hi rend="sup"> -- </hi>that Said King would appear in said court &amp; not depart &amp;c</p>
<p>At that time the U. S A. army needed men and the Government was calling for volunteers and Jackson King propelled by a love of his country and the patriotism of a true Kentucky went forth in answer to said call and volunteered in said army and served his country well and faithfully as a good and valiant soldier while She needed assistance. He is a poor man with a wife and five little children has no lands and but little personal property.</p>
<p>Mary King is a middle aged woman and has but little property Since the date of recognizance the same has been forfeited and we pray you in view of the Hon<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">le</hi></hi> service of Jackson King in defense of the best Government of mans making and the necessities of his little children and the age and little means of Mary King that you will releive them of the burden of said recognizance In doing this we are actuated only by the feelings of Kentuckyans and the<pb/>
<lb/>Just appreciations of the Services of a man who at his country<hi rend="sup">s</hi> call will leave family and friends and meet the enemy on a tented field</p>
<p>Hoping you will grant the relief asked for we most cheerfully sign ouselves Your most humble petitioners</p>
<p><date when="1865-11-07">November 7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Thomas Ford
<lb/>Thoma
<lb/>L A Smithwick
<lb/>H Hagan
<lb/>Lewis Peck p. m.<pb/>
<lb/>Joseph Coffelt
<lb/>Isaac Coffelt
<lb/>Marlin Right
<lb/>Philip P Robinson
<lb/>William G Bowman
<lb/>Benjamin Bowman
<lb/>Willi am Copass
<lb/>Ira I Copass
<lb/>Henderso R Copass
<lb/>Thomas J Wearer
<lb/>A J Wadkins
<lb/>John D Allen
<lb/>Nathan T Jackson
<lb/>Thomas Brown
<lb/>William Brown
<lb/>Thomas Ford
<lb/>Thomas Ford
<lb/>Joanathan Eakle
<lb/>William H Eakle
<lb/>Jordin L Ford
<lb/>Jacob Coffelt
<lb/>bengamon ford
<lb/>Jackson erwin
<lb/>Ritchard Coffelt
<lb/>Jonas G Allen
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/><pb/></p>
<p>Petition
<lb/>From King
<lb/>To Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Bramlette.
<lb/>Remit forfeiture</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
