<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0571"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Richard Cates and Alexander Cates to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9023</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_2">Double Proof by:</resp>
     <name>CWGK Staff</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Hannah M. O'Daniel</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-405</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Webster County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-03-04">4 March 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><date when="1863-03-04">march 4<hi rend="sup">the</hi> 1863</date> <placeName ref="cwgk:P00002312">webster County ky</placeName>.</p>
   <p>Der <persName ref="cwgk:N001004">Sier</persName> this is to inform you that ther has bin a fine assest against mee <hi rend="str">for selling</hi> in the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000588">webster Sircu^e^t Court</orgName> for selling ardent sperits iwas fiend the full exstent of the law i thout that i was Complying with the law i was told that i Cold sell as law as a half gallon and not hav it drunk under my ruf i don so and kept good order a bout mee the man hoe present mee he fell out with a some of my famley and what he done was done throu spite he bought too gallens at one time and Carred it of and he never bught any mor the Court told mee if i had sold the hole barrel to one man that i was fin well for itiwas ingernt of ^not <hi rend="str">k</hi>^ knowing the law or is huldent done so iam a poor man i Cant hardley make a nuf to seport on and if i have this to pay it brakes mee up i have to by mee a horse or make nothing the gillers took my horses way from mee last fall and left mee afoot i have all ways benn a goverment man some Call them union men iam bothe i am for my old goverment and the union ther was a pertison got up to send to you and was left in the hand of the lawer with over one hurnd siners to it the Clirkes of the Court asined it seeing it was done through mallis the male s^t^opt and it never was sent the lawer is in the armney if you want to inqur into my standen inquer of <hi rend="str">S^t^anden</hi> <persName ref="cwgk:N00002530">Dockter ray</persName> can tell you he has known mee for upwards of twenty yars who is in your leglater i want you to parden mee this one time of this evel if you please and i never will be guiltey of the like a gane this is the first time i ever Cald on the govern for help and in so douing you will oblige your frend <persName ref="cwgk:N00002528">Richard Cates</persName> and <persName ref="cwgk:N00002529">Alexander Cates</persName> his farther i want you to right as soon as you git this and Direct your letter ^to^ webster County for give if you please<pb/></p>
<p>Pettn of Richard Cates of <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000564">Carter County</placeName> to remit fine</p>
<p>This Pettn does not show the fine &amp; no reliable grounds to remit</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
