<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-022-0011"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Oliver P. Morton, Requisition</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG2909</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Requisitions for the Return of Fugitives from Justice, 1859-1861</collection>
      <idno>MG7-174 to MG7-176</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Indianapolis, Marion County, Indiana</placeName>
    <date when="1861-07-04">4 July 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>REQUISITION FOR FUGITIVE FROM JUSTICE.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>TO HIS EXCELLENCY,
<lb/>The Governor of the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>It appears by the annexed papers, duly authenticated according to the laws of our State<hi rend="str">s</hi>, that Frank Smith stands charged by the affidavi<hi rend="str">d</hi>t of John W. Barker with the crime of Grand Larceny and it has been represented to me that he has fled from the justice of this State and has taken refuge in the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>Now Therefore, I Oliver P. Morton Governor of the State of Indiana, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and Laws of the United States, do, by these presents, demand that the said Frank Smith be apprehended and delivered to John W. Barker who is hereby authorized to receive and convey him to the State of Indiana, that he may abide his trial for the crime with which he stand charged "The State will pay no part of the expenses of the execution of this Writ."</p>
<p><figure type="seal"/></p>
<p><unclear>In</unclear> Testimony Whereof, I have hereunto set my hand and caused to be affixed the Seal of the State, at the City of Indianapolis this <date when="1861-07-24">Twenty fourth day of July in the year of the Lord one thousand eight hundred and sixty-one,</date> the forty Sixth year of the State, and of the Independence of the United States the Eighty Sixth</p>
<p>BY THE GOVERNOR,
<lb/>Oliver P. Morton</p>
<p>W. A. Peelle Secretary of State.<pb/></p>
<p>State of Indiana
<lb/>Clark County } SS</p>
<p>John W. Barker swears that on or about the <date when="1861-01-28">28<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of Jany. 1861</date> at the County &amp; State aforesaid Frank Smith &amp; William Wyatt, did feloniously Steal take &amp; carry away one copper Kettle, the personal property of Samuel H. Patterson of the value of Thirty dollars.</p>
<p>John W. Barker</p>
<p>Sworn &amp; subscribed to before me a Justice of the Peace in &amp; for said County the <date when="1861-04-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of April 1861.</date></p>
<p>Charles D. Schell J. P. <figure type="seal"/></p>
<p>State of Indiana
<lb/>Clark County SS</p>
<p>I Andrew J. Hay clerk of the Clark Circuit Court certify the foregoing to be a true copy of the affidavit of Jno W. Barker in the case of the State of Indiana vs Frank Smith &amp; W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Wyatt as the same appears on file in my office</p>
<p>Witness my hand &amp; the seal of said Court this <date when="1861-06-29">29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of June 1861</date></p>
<p>Andrew J. Hay <hi rend="underline">Clerk</hi><pb/></p>
<p>State of Indiana Clark County SS</p>
<p>John W. Barker on oath States that on on or about the <date when="1861-02-07">7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> of February 1861</date> Frank Smith the within named defender A. Escaped from the Custody of the Sheriff of Clark Clark County, Indiana, where in Confinement on a charge of Grand Larceny and that said Smith is now in the Jail of Jefferson County Kentucky awaiting a requisition of the Governor of Indiana upon the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>John. W. Barker</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me this <date when="1861-07-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day July 1861.</date></p>
<p>Oswill C. Woolley
<lb/>Mayor of the city of Jeffersonville</p>
<p><figure type="seal"/></p>
<p><hi rend="str">Issue</hi> <hi rend="str">Warrant</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="str">O</hi>. <hi rend="str">P</hi>. <hi rend="str">Morton</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Indiana<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Warrant
<lb/>Iss <date when="1861-08-03"><hi rend="str">July</hi>Aug. 3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Frank Smith
<lb/>Grand Larceny</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
