<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0681"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. Wallace Harper et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4800</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-43 to BR10-44</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Versailles, Woodford County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-04-16">16 April 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Versailles <date when="1864-04-16">April 16 1864</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency Th<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">os</hi></hi> E Bramlitte Governor of The Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Th<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">os</hi></hi> ^Buford^ states that he was indited at the last Circuit ^Court^ held in the county of Woodford and State of Kentucky by the Grand Jury of said Court for dealing faro in the town of Versailles. The facts are as follows: Some months previous to the setting of the <date when="--04">last April Circuit</date> <hi rend="str">Th</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="str"><hi rend="sup">os</hi></hi></hi><hi rend="str"> Buford</hi> ^Capt^ Thos Buford was called to the town of Versailles togeather with many other citizens of the county of Woodford for the purpose of reporting to the Military Authorities such slaves as was required by said powers to work upon the railroad and that day Th<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">os</hi></hi> Buford haveing taken too much of the ardent spirits and getting upon a jovial frollic, without intending to violate the laws of the commonwealth went with some other gentlemen to take a game of cards and <hi rend="str">it appears that</hi> Th<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">os</hi></hi> Buford dealt faro a part of the game for wich he was indited by the same Grand Jury wich is the first and only case of the kind we ever heard of his being engaged in Therefore we the petitioners hopefully and earnestly pray your Excellency to extend the kind and beneficent hand of the Executive in granting him a free and unconditional pardon from the said inditement We know and believe that the power invested in your Excellency by the constituion and laws of the noble and chivalric state of Ky will enable you to relieve an innocent offender (if he is an offender in the spirit) of the ^law^ Furthermore he is a man of rare, social <hi rend="str">frank</hi> frank generous and noble impulses he stated the whole case to the grand Jury without desiring to evade or conceal the thing.<pb/></p>
<p>J Wallace Harper
<lb/>J. B. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Grath
<lb/>Newton Scase
<lb/>Catesby <hi rend="underline">Barnes</hi> forman
<lb/>William.. Allen
<lb/>Henry Moss
<lb/>J Rowland
<lb/>John. T. Berry
<lb/>V. L. Moore
<lb/>Z Todd
<lb/>A Bohannon</p>
<p>We the undersigned members of the Grand Jury unite heartly in the pray of the above petition.</p>
<p>Woodford Circuit Court</p>
<p>I, Swift Darneal Clerk of the said Court do certify that the above named persons constitute a porition of the Grand Jury that presented an Indictment against Thomas Buford at the <date when="1864-04">April term 1864</date> of said Court. Swift Darneal Clk</p>
<p><date when="1864-04-18">April 18. 1864</date>.<pb/></p>
<p>Woodford Cir Ct
<lb/>Pardon &amp; remit the offence
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi>
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Buford
<lb/><date when="1864-04-19">19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Apl/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
