<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1346"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. S. Green to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10814</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-264 to MG21-265</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Woodsonville, Hart County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-08-19">19 August 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Woodsonville Ky <date when="1861-08-19">Aug the. 19./61</date>
<lb/>Gov Magoffin
<lb/>Dear sir</p>
<p>permit me to introduce my friend Mr Maxey the representive of Hart he is a Bachelor and wants a wife I hope you will hich him to some young Lady Gov I have to ask a favor of you about three years agoe I was present at afight and anotice was served on me to apeare at the Equity cort at Glasgowe I gave abond of $50 dollars for my apearance I clearly for got when cort was and at the last <date when="1861-06">june</date> Term of the cort they rendered judgement against me if your honor will I hope you will release me from the judgement<pb/>
<lb/>as times are hard and money cearse I have to save all I can there was no one injured in my not attending cort please write me at your Earliest convenience</p>
<p>Yours Truly
<lb/>W. S. Green</p>
<p>well Govner</p>
<p>cant you stop this dam ware it is bringing distruction on all of us I expect to start south the <date when="1861-10">first of October</date> and think I will have to get a leter as a pass from you to the Govnor of Tennessee and Mississippi</p>
<p>your frind
<lb/>W S Green<pb/></p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1861-09-02">Sept 2. '61</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
