<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2285"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">S. H. Cambron to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9361</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG25-32 to MG25-33</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>B M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Dear Sir I write you -- this in behalf of John Singer a free man of colour who together with his wife ^Ann^ and daughter Rachael &amp; son -- Charles were Indicted under a late law of the legislature for crossing the Ohio River &amp; Returning to Ky.</p>
<p>John Singer &amp; his family have in the community for a long series of years say since <date when="1836">1836</date>, supported a good character. Industrious honest prudent and <unclear>Saving</unclear>. Has made some money by his business (Barber) and so far as I know without reproach or suspicion of any citizen.</p>
<p>John Singer as I understand come to this city about the year <date when="1836">1836</date> from Virginia. The Legislature of the<pb/>
<lb/>state of Ky in the year <date when="1838-02-15">^(app<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Feby 15)^ 1838</date> passed an act authorising him to reside in this state and under the apprehension that he was not amenable to the penalties of the law under which he was indicted crossed the river &amp; returned in the ordinary ^way^ as he had been accustomed to do before passage of act under which he was Indicted I have no hesitation in saying that I believe he will in future conform to the law and not again in any way render himself liable to the penalties thereof And that the violations which have occurred were not the result of design but of Mistake as the Extent of the rights conferred by the act for his benefit referred to above If consistent with your Excellencys duties you should deem it proper to pardon him and his wife and and two ^children^ that such act of clemency upon your part would meet with<pb/>
<lb/>the approval of most citizens of this city who know the facts and ^know^ Singer &amp; his said family</p>
<p>Respectfully &amp;c
<lb/>S H Cambron</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
