<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2603"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">E. R. Wing to Andrew Johnson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7240</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-169 to BR16-170</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-09">9 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Andrew Johnson
<lb/>President of the United States</p>
<p>I have the honour most respectfully to represent that having been ever strictly &amp; devotedly loyal to the Government -- having been connected with the Federal Army -- having served upon the Staff of Gen James S. Jackson of Kentucky who fell at the disastrous battle of Perryville, -- &amp; being able to refer as to my past &amp; present status to the first men in my native state, -- chief among whom I would name The Hon James Speed, Attorney General &amp; Hon Geo. H. Yeaman, Minister to Denmark. -- I am incited most earnestly to petition that the accompanying plea for pardon be <hi rend="str">regarded</hi> <hi rend="str">with</hi> given immediate &amp; favorable reply.</p>
<p>1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> In consideration of the loyalty of the petitioners Father &amp; relatives, -- and of the fact of the long &amp; honourable service of his two brothers (the Capts Martin) in the army of the Government, -- all of whom are now in deep distress &amp; mortification over his incarceration.</p>
<p>2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> That the petitioner having borne prior to the rebellion an unexceptionable character, -- having despite his youth achieved a high reputation for daring intelligence &amp; honour among those whose cause he so erroniously espoused, -- had been paroled, taken the oath, &amp; returned to his friends with full resolution to become a law abiding<pb/>
<lb/>citizen at the time of his arrest. -- &amp; with entire faith in the <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>guarantee of safety &amp; immunity extended by his parole.</p>
<p>3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> That no matter what be the charges against him, he was during the rebellion acting under ordiers, &amp; in a subordinate capacity, &amp; could easily have escaped altogether from the consequences of <hi rend="str">t</hi>his acts or <hi rend="underline">intentions</hi>. had he not deemed the Government pledged, by the terms of surrender, to his protection in the future &amp; forgiveness for the past. All of which is respectfully submitted,</p>
<p>I have the honour to remain.
<lb/>Respy.
<lb/>Yr ob'd't S'rv't.
<lb/>E. R. Wing
<lb/>Louisville <date when="1865-10-09">Oct. 9.<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>.<pb/></p>
<p>Greenville <date when="1865-10-03">Oct 3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>To whom it may concern.</p>
<p>I live near to, &amp; have been for many years well acquainted with the family of Col Robert M Martin late of the confederate army. His Father is a very worthy citizen and has ever been a firm union man, and two of his Brothers (one of whom Lieutenant Templeton is the bearer of this note) served with credit in the Federal Army.</p>
<p>Robert when quite a youth entered the Confederate service, and however mistaken in his policy, <hi rend="str">obtained</hi>, by his activity and gallantry obtained promotion &amp; distinction in the South. His conduct before the war was ever irreproachable</p>
<p>He was included in Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Johnson's capitulation to Gen. Sherman -- came home avowing his determination to bear full &amp; true allegiance to the Government -- was arrested &amp; carried away. His health is bad from the effects of the severe wounds &amp; his relations believe he cannot survive a vigorous confinement</p>
<p>Some consideration is due to the loyalty &amp; services of his family, who would be saved from deep distress and affliction by the interposition<pb/>
<lb/>of Executive clemency.</p>
<p>Edward Ramsey</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
