<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2140"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Samuel Baer et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9216</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-222 to MG24-223</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Owen County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Owen County Kentucky
<lb/>To his excellency Beriah M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Goffin
<lb/>Govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky,</p>
<p>The Undersigned would respectfully represent in behalf of Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Sebree convicted of the crime of Manslaughter on the person of William Gerald, at the <date when="--09">Sept. term</date> of the Boone Circuit Court; and Sentenced to the term of 5 years laber in the Penetentiary where he now is, that the Said Sebree is and always has been regarted by thos who knew him best as an unoffencive person of Scarcely sound mind and not in any degree dangerous in his disposition to the well being of Society and also that at the time the act was done he was labering under such a degree of excitment from liquer that he was in the opinion of Dr Scott who was examined at lenght on the trial, and also of the officer Mr McNirly who made the arrest a few hours after the, deed was accomplished he was the victim of mental oberration if not of <hi rend="underline">delerium</hi> <hi rend="underline">tremens</hi> They would further represent that the said Sebree is Sixty years of age and that his wife who is still older, is devising his imprisonment dependent on charity for a living. and that he Suffered before his trial an imprisonment of Six or eight months which so broke his constitution that he now his dangerously ill in the Penitentiery unable to do any laber and if still Kept in confinement will in all human probability not survive many months certinly not to the end of his time Werefore, in view of all these facts we respectully beg that your Excellency would Graciously<pb/>
<lb/><unclear/> in this case the executive clemency and grant the said James Sebree a Pardon and immunity from all further efffets of the sentence pronounced against him by the court as above stated</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Samuel Baer
<lb/>William Roberts
<lb/>Geo. C. Roberts
<lb/>Jo<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> T. Roberts
<lb/>G Lurstey
<lb/>Lawrence Teal
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> A Smith
<lb/>Hamlet Sandford
<lb/>H T Reynolds
<lb/>J, P, Ford
<lb/>W Teal
<lb/>Ed. Lushy
<lb/>Lafayette Stout
<lb/>John Morrow
<lb/>Chs P Kneder
<lb/>Joseph Rinnoeld
<lb/>Geo Graw
<lb/>Lawrence Sandford
<lb/>Benj. H. Ford
<lb/>W F Riley
<lb/>James Havis
<lb/>G. W. Craignyler
<lb/>James Vallandingham
<lb/>John. A. Moore
<lb/>W. P. Bacon
<lb/>J A Duncan
<lb/>James M Suter
<lb/>W H Conder
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J. J. Forsee
<lb/>A. B. Ford
<lb/>George P. Ford
<lb/>M Dawson
<lb/>Ben Moore
<lb/>Joseph Blackwell
<lb/>W A. Goddard
<lb/>Tho A. Ireland M C
<lb/>thomas D Staneson
<lb/>Lewis Jefler
<lb/>Ben F Sidebottom
<lb/>W. H. Moore
<lb/>D F Stafford
<lb/>H. J. Mason
<lb/>W. H. Sandford
<lb/>John Donovan
<lb/>John Gallagher
<lb/>Jas. P. Wilson
<lb/>John Knoll
<lb/>D A Evans
<lb/><unclear/> Haydon
<lb/>Simon Tufts</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
