<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0094"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Butcher et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4213</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-141 to BR8-142</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Campbell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-09-18">18 September 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Governor Bramblette of Ky.</p>
<p>The undersigned petitioners respectfully state that at the <date when="1863-09">August Term 1863</date> of the Campbell Circuit Court Sebastian Gramer was fined for keeping a Tipling house the Sum of sixty dollars &amp; costs This is an exceedingly hard case, agst. a very poor man, and is in our judgement such as calls for Executive clemency.</p>
<p>s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Gramer is a German unacquainted with the laws of Kentucky &amp; has always looked upon <hi rend="underline">Native wine</hi> ^(as he says)^ to be as natural and innocent a drink as <hi rend="underline">water</hi>. He was keeping a small grocery in Jamestown and obtained a license to sell <hi rend="underline">beer</hi> from the Trustees. This, Gramer innocently supposed justified at least ^the sale of^ Native wine. It was proven by one witness on the trial (Charles Slain) that Gramer had let him have native wine as often as <hi rend="underline">two or three times</hi> &amp; this was all the evidence. We as jurors who tried the case and as citizens of the immediate vicinity respectfully ask the Governor to remit this fine &amp; we are satisfied that public justice will not suffer &amp; that M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Gramer will never again offend agst the law which he has innocently done as we believe in this case.
<lb/><date when="1863-09-18">Sept. 18. 1863</date><pb/></p>
<p>Campbell Circuit Court
<lb/><date when="1863-09-05">August 5th 1863</date>
<lb/>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs, On Indictment
<lb/>S. Gramer</p>
<p>The parties appeared and the defendant plead not guilty thereupon came a Jury, viz: J. O. Prather, J. Constans, P. H. Kemper, Lewis Donahower, W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> M. Neyman, S. Allen, John Butcher, John Nelson, Thos. Marston, Chas. Murnan, Geo. Summers &amp; B. Caruthers: who were sworn to try the issue after hearing the evidence returned the following verdict, viz: "We the jury find the defend't guilty of keeping a tippling house as charged in the indictment, P.A.C. Kemper, foreman." It is therefore adjudged that the commonwealth recover of the defendant a fine of Sixty Dollars, and the costs of this proceeding; and that the defendant stand convicted until the fine is paid such commutal not to exceed 30 days.</p>
<p>A Copy Attest, Gus. Arttman, C. C. C.
<lb/>by H. Sine, D.C</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Petitioners Names</hi>
<lb/>John Butcher Juror
<lb/>Thomas A Martin Juror
<lb/>Jacob Constans Juror
<lb/>L B Donahower Juror
<lb/>Geo Summers Juror<pb/>
<lb/>Charles Wetzel Juror
<lb/>J Horsfall Jailor
<lb/>Staphan Allen Juror
<lb/>Theodore Truiven Mayor of Jamestown
<lb/>John Bukemeier Truste
<lb/>Rudolfh Krune Truste
<lb/>James Feslar Trustee
<lb/>Moses R Harris Justice
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Tiemann Trustee
<lb/>Charles Kuhlmann Trustee<pb/></p>
<p>Campbell Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>S. Gramer
<lb/>Tipling
<lb/>$60 -- 
<lb/><date when="1863-11-10">10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov/ 63</date></p>
<p>Remit all except fees and costs
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
