<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0021"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Samuel D. McCullough to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14050</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1862</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lexington, Fayette County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-11-04">4 November 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Lexington Ky. <date when="1862-11-04">Nov. 4. 1862</date>
<lb/>His Ex.
<lb/>Gov J. F. Robinson
<lb/>Frankfort
<lb/>Sir,</p>
<p>My young kinsman J. Wm. Wallis, (whose Father resides in this County,) has rendered himself greatly offensive to the rebellious &amp; traitorous element in &amp; about his neighborhood, for his activity, skill, daring &amp; management, at the head of some some forty or fifty of his young Companions, in ferretting out &amp; arresting rebels, capturing hordes, &amp;c. belonging to the U. States. He &amp; his Father &amp; Brother have had to lie concealed in the mountainous portion of the state, for two months. Efforts have been made by various parties of rebel troops, to capture him &amp; his brave little volunteer partisan band of loyal young men. On his last trip to the hilly country, he discovered a drove of some 500 head of Cattle, left by the rebels, in their hasty retreat. </p>
<p>His friends, in common with myself, advise him <hi rend="underline">not</hi> <hi rend="underline">to</hi> <hi rend="underline">put</hi> <hi rend="underline">a hand</hi> <hi rend="underline">to the capture of these</hi> <hi rend="underline">cattle</hi>, nor to take any other active measures, until he had a commission in his pockets, <hi rend="underline">which</hi> <hi rend="underline">will</hi> <hi rend="underline">render</hi> <hi rend="underline">his</hi> <hi rend="underline">acts</hi> <hi rend="underline">strictly</hi> <hi rend="underline">legal</hi> <hi rend="underline">&amp;</hi> <hi rend="underline">Military</hi>. Already threats are made against him &amp; band, as marauders, not being Employed by our Government. His Father is Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> M Wallis of this County, a loyal gentle<pb/>
<lb/>and the son, J. Wm. is an Educated youth, of about 21 years of age, brave, rapid in movements, fertile in invention, &amp; seems to possess many of the qualities of his Kinsman, (&amp; Cousin) the late Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Z. Taylor,</p>
<p>This paper is to solicit for him &amp; his officers &amp; men, a <hi rend="underline">legal</hi> <hi rend="underline">recognition</hi> from you, so as to place him &amp; them ^&amp; their acts^ within the pale of legalized Warfare. He and his men are mounted on the best horses of their own, &amp; prefer to remain in the State, (&amp; Extended neighborhood, if possible) so that their services may be for their benefit.</p>
<p>Judge Buckner can tell you more of him. If a commission as Capt of a Company of mounted Rangers can not be given by you, Would an admittance on your staff, with a commission of authority as such from you, render his acts legal &amp; acceptable. Should a commission to him &amp; his officers be granted, please allow me to ask the favor to suggest to you, that the commissions be ante-dated, say to the <date when="--08-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> of August ^last^</date> about which time Morgan first came in, so as to render his acts legal from that date. -- He is jeopardizing his Safety, whilst acting by order of any of our Provost Officers. -- I am happy to say that Capt Wallis informs me that Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Gilmore fully Endorses the <unclear/> which would require a commission for him to act.<pb/></p>
<p>Young Capt J. Wm. Wallis will present This letter in person to you.</p>
<p>With high regard
<lb/>Very truly
<lb/>Sam<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> D. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cullough</p>
<p>we are neighbors of Cpt J Wm. Wallis and indose the above in full</p>
<p>Jacob Hughes
<lb/>Saml T Hayes
<lb/>Garrett Watts</p>
<p>c</p>
<p>I believe and therefore concur in the foregoing statement of facts -- and consequently I should be pleased with your giving Young Wallace any proper <unclear/> in Your power for authorising the legal effectation of his designated purposes -- </p>
<p>G Robertson
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Robinson<pb/></p>
<p>Lexington 
<lb/><date when="1862-11-04">Nov. 4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi>/62</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Robertson G. and others.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Recom<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">dg</hi></hi> J. W. Wallis.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>His Excellency
<lb/>James F. Robinson
<lb/>Gov. Ky.
<lb/>Frankfort.</p>
<p>Recommendation of G. W. Wallace for State Guard Capt.</p>
<p>G. Robertson</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
