<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0944"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">B. M. Durham to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5063</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-452 to BR10-453</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-06-28">28 June 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Bowling Green Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-06-28">June 28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>His Excellency,
<lb/>Gov Thomas E. Bramlett of Kentucky
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>Your petitioner B. M. Durham, a citizen of this place respectfully and earnestly represents the following facts for your favorable consideration: That at the <hi rend="str">time</hi> -- term of the Warren Equity and Criminal Court, he was charged, and convicted of the offence of "Carrying concealed Weapons" the facts developed in the trial were, that his young companion charged your petitioner with having no fire arms.</p>
<p>Whareupon he presented a small double barrel pistol, laid it in the fire place and never used it afterwards in any way: At that time he was very young and the motive or cause of his having the pistol was more the playful curiosity of a boy, than any contemplated use of the instrument: States also that such is his pecuniary Condition, though the fine is comparatively small his release therefrom would be a matter of greatful Consideration, while if he is compelled to pay the same it will be an entrenchment upon the sacred resources of domestic necessities: The fine was originally fifty dollars, the cost of the prosecution has been paid with the hope that your Excellency may remit, the fine thus imposed I have the honor to be your ob't Serv't &amp; c.</p>
<p>B. M. Durham<pb/></p>
<p>Warren E &amp; C Ct
<lb/>Petition of Ben M. Durham
<lb/>$50-
<lb/>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/>Tho. E. Bramlette
<lb/><date when="1864-07-02">2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> July/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
