<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2764"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">David Lock and R. J. Sanders to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7401</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-28 to BR17-29</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Edmondson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-04">4 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excelency. Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E. Bramlett Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioners David Lock, and R. I. Sanders, citizens of Barren County Kentucky would Respectfully Represent that at the <date when="1864-11">November Term of the Monroe Circuit Court 1864</date>, they became the Security of Elihu Stean. In a Reconasance, for the appearance of Said Stean, in said Court, to answer and Indictement, charging him with the offence of Stealing a Pistol a bond of 250$</p>
<p>Your Petitioners State that after they thus became the Security of Said Stean, that he went as a Soldier in the Service of the United States in the 13th Kentucky Infantry, for the Term of Twelve Months, and Served his Regular term until Discharged from the Service -- they State that at the Spring term of the Monroe Circuit court <date when="1865">1865</date> the Commonwealths attorny took the Judgment upon the Reconasance <hi rend="str">against said</hi> of said Stean against your Petitioners as his Securities for said sum of Two Hundred &amp; fifty Dollars &amp; cost, and caused Execution to be Issued on the Same, which your Petitioner Repleaved, upon this execution Issued and has been placed in the hands of Samuel Talle Sherriff of Barnes county for collection who is about to leavy the Same upon the Property of <hi rend="str">Dr</hi> Petitioners your Petitioners now State, that at the time that Said Judgment was Rendered agaisnt Said Stean, that he was serving as a soldier in the Federal army -- and the Said Stean could not have attended and answered to said charge, had not the law Excused,<pb/>
<lb/>him from So doing nether had your Petitioners any Power or authority, to controll the Person of Said Stean or to deliver him into the custody of the court he being under the Controll and direction of the military authorities. your Petitioner David Lock, States that he is a man in very limited circumstances and if Compelled to pay the amount of Said Execution It will be oppressive to himself and Family -- he states that he is now on the Employment of the Louisville &amp; Nashville Rail Road, and Engaged in sawing wood for said Road by horse Power, and by hard labor he is barly enabled to suport his Family &amp; that he Resides in Barren County, near the Edmondson County line and Fully 40 miles from the Monroe Court house and that he was unable to make Defence to the Judgment upon the Reconasance and was Informed that it was unnecessary to do so as It was not lawfull to forfeit the Reconasance of a Party while serving in the Federal army -- and but for these Reasons he is Satisfied that he could have Sucessfully, Resisted a Judgment in this cause</p>
<p>Wherefore, he, prays your Excelency to Remitt Said forfature and the Judgment &amp; Execution theron</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Edmondson county</p>
<p>I, O. P. Shackelford a Justice of the Peace within and for the County &amp; State afored<pb/>
<lb/>do. hereby. certify that. the Forgoing Petition was this day Subscribed and Sworn to before me by David Lock. With whom I am personally acquainted, and I. do. further certify that the Said David Lock is a credable and Respectable Citzen, and that his statements are entitled to Full faith and Credit.</p>
<p>Given under my hand this <date when="1865-12-04">4th day of <hi rend="str">November</hi> December 1865</date>.<pb/></p>
<p>Monroe Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>David Lock &amp; R J Sanders
<lb/>$250,
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-12-28">28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Dec/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
