<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1406"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Charles H. Meyer to Robert Elliott</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6043</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-188 to BR12-189</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-12-13">13 December 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville Jail <date when="1864-12-13">Dec 13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864.</date>
<lb/>Robert Elliott Esq,, Atty at Law
<lb/>Sir.</p>
<p>You will I hope pardon this liberty in trespassing on your valuable time, but as you are perhaps already aware I was misfortunately tried and convicted to one year in the Penitentiary, I thought I would seat myself and converse with you through the silent medium of the Pen.</p>
<p>Friend Elliott as I have now only to depend on the Mercy of his Excellency the Governor for a Pardon, and as I understand through M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Price that the Jury on my case are all willing to sign same, also my Prosecuter M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. J B. Walker and my former Employer N. &amp; W J Smith on Main Street<pb/>
<lb/>M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Price told me this evening at the Jail Gate, that if I had only some one to draw up the Petition he would issue same that I would succeed my appeal is to you Kind Sir and treat to God, the God of Justice you will not refuse to write up a Petition in so doing God will bless you for the act, dear Sir you are the only one that I can look to now for help, oh God do not refuse me this favor and save me from utter ruin and disgrace, if I have comitted this deed think of this motto.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">It</hi> is <hi rend="underline">human</hi> <hi rend="underline">to</hi> <hi rend="underline">err</hi>, <hi rend="underline">but</hi> <hi rend="underline">christian</hi> <hi rend="underline">to forgive</hi></p>
<p>You will please go and see M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> W. J. Smith of the Firm of N. &amp; W. J Smith my former Employer he will I Know give you all assistance you need, and my Friend H<hi rend="sup">on</hi> Judge Drane, has vollenteered<pb/>
<lb/>to take it up to Frankfort. and do all in his power for my release</p>
<p>Mrss<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. John Snyder Firm of J Snyder &amp; Co
<lb/>" Clark Smtih " " <unclear>Littghow</unclear> &amp;Co
<lb/>" A Barrie on 3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Street
<lb/>" Speed " Hemming &amp; Speed
<lb/>and others I cant recollect where on my Jury.</p>
<p>For the love of God and old Friendship sake M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Elliott do all you can in my behalf, I dont Know if we are sent up to morrow morning as Wednesday if not please come and see me.</p>
<p>Hoping and trusting to God that you will not forget this kind and humble call for help.</p>
<p>My kindest and honest Regard and well wishes for your Prosperity</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Cha</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi><hi rend="underline">. H. Meyer</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
