<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0481"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">H. Taylor to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8933</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-269 to R4-270</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Maysville, Mason County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-07-16">16 July 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Maysville Ky
<lb/><date when="1863-07-16">July 16<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1863</date> -- 
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Robinson.
<lb/>D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Sir.</p>
<p>A county man of mine, an old grey headed man 60 or 65 years of age, named Worsham P. Clayton is now in jail in this city, put in there by the sheriff under two executions for fines for $200 each, inflicted upon him for permitting unlawful gaming in his house, whilst he resided in this city. These fines were imposed some two or three years ago. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Clayton resides now in the town of Washington some 4 miles from here. He is a very quiet, harmless, inoffensive old fellow, without sufficient forces of character, or will, to refuse to allow gentlemen, who desired to amuse themselves in that way, the privilege of playing cards in his house. But that would be no ground for soliciting your clemency. I hope I will be pardoned for asking you to forgive him all that you can, upon the ground that he is old, poor, and has a large family of helpless children to support. I Know that he is unable to pay the fines. It is with great difficulty that he can maintain his family in the ordinary necessaries of life. I do not think, if he was<pb/>
<lb/>kept in jail till doomsday he could pay the fines -- unless others out of mere compassion would pay them to relieve him from confinement in jail.</p>
<p>I am loath to trouble you about the matter, but I know that unless you will interpose your authority for his relief, he will be compelled to remain in jail.</p>
<p>Yours with great respect
<lb/>Your Obt Sert
<lb/><hi rend="underline">H. Taylor</hi>.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
