<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-009-0015"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Unknown, Preamble and Resolution in relation to the adjustment and payment of Claims of Citizens of Kentucky against the United States</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1170</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR1-18 to BR1-19</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-01-20">20 January 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Proclamation/Legislation</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Preamble and Resolution in relation to the adjustment and payment of Claims of Citizens of Kentucky against the Unitest States.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Whereas, the armies of the United States, in the present war to suppress the rebellion in the Southern States, have, necessarily and rightfully, occupied the State of Kentucky, and, in so doing, have greatly damaged the property of, and otherwise injured pecuniarily, many loyal citizens thereof, by encampments being made upon farms, whereby the same have been laid waste by the taking and using of forage and subsistence, without paying or furnishing proper vouchers therefor, by the erection of fortifications, the destruction of ferries, the impressment of stock, and in divers other ways. all of which constitute just claims against the United States; and whereas, in a great majority of instances, those who sustained losses are poor persons, many of whom are reduced to absolute want thereby; and whereas, the mode, as at present provided by Congress, for the adjudication and payment of said claims, by prosecuting an action in the United States court of claims, at Washington, effectually deprives many meritorious claimants of any hope of payment, by reason of the necessary expenses attending their prosecution in that court, which would, not unfrequently, exceed the amounts of claims, and, in all cases, must result in long delay, greatly to the prejudice of the interest of claimants; therefore, be it</p>
<p>1. <hi rend="italic">Resolved by the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky,</hi> That our Senators in Congress be instructed, and our members of the House of Representatives requested, to introduce, and urge the passage of such law as will afford adequate relief to the loyal sufferers within this State, either by providing for a branch court of claims within and for the State of Kentucky, regulated as the court of claims is now, by law, regulated; or by giving to the United States District Court, for the district of Kentucky, jurisdiction in such cases, and making the necessary appropriation to provide for the immediate payment of such judgment as may be awarded thereby; or authorizing the State of Kentucky, through the medium of her own courts, to adjudicate, allow, and pay such claims of the character aforesaid, as may be just, and providing for her reimbursement.</p>
<p>2. That the Governor be requested to memorialize Congress upon the matters herein before set forth, urging attention to, and action thereon.</p>
<p>3. That the foregoing preamble and resolutions, together with the memorial of the Governor, be printed, and a copy forwarded, by the Governor, to the President of the Senate, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and to each of our Senators and members of Congress.</p>
<p>Approved, <date when="1864-01-20">20th January, 1864</date>.
<lb/></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
