<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2758"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Searcy et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7395</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-1 to BR17-2</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thomas E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Anderson County would respectfully represent, that, as shown by a copy of this indictment herewith sent, Benj Houser, James Taylor &amp; W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Harrison Terry Brown, &amp; Lycurgus Hudson were at the last <date when="--11">November</date> Term of the Anderson Circuit Court indicted for the murderr of one John Ash -- The circumstances were as follows: The said Houser, Taylor, Harrisson, Brown &amp; Hudson, are citizens of Spencer County Kentucky, and as they were passing along the road they fell in company with a detachment of Federal troops ^Cap N Collins Company 39<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Mounted Infty^ on a scout after Guerillas, in the lower part of Anderson County which was at that time a strong hold of different marauding bands then infesting the country and committing depredations of the worst character. -- As the party were going on the road near Van Buren Ash was perceived going out into the Country with a basket, and the Soldiers supposing that he was a Guerilla, halted him &amp; he ran off<pb/>
<lb/>and as he ran the Soldiers Shot &amp; Killed him, neither of the above parties having anything to do with it in any way, &amp; having no power, even if willing, to have prevented the action of the Soldiers in the premises</p>
<p>Wm Searcy
<lb/>B. L. Boston
<lb/>M V Royalty
<lb/>Ben S. Myers
<lb/>Wiley Searcy
<lb/>G L M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Ginnis<pb/></p>
<p>Such are the facts as I am informed and believes as stated in the foregoing petition I further state that they were acting under the command as I believe of a superior federal officer and as such are not amenable and are therefore entitled to Executive clemency</p>
<p>C H Fenwick<pb/></p>
<p>M<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Eden Spencer County Ky<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/><unclear>Refused</unclear></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
