<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1141"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. G. Carlisle to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10609</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-285</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-21">21 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Covington Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-06-21">June 21 1861</date>
<lb/>Dear Governor:</p>
<p>Jos. Blackwell has been fined $200 for keeping a tippling house for three months, and will,l I am informed, present a petition to have the fine, or a portion of it, remitted -- I know nothing whatever concerning the facts of the case, not having heard the trial -- There was, I am told, but one witness against him -- one Chas. Blinn -- and I have been requested to make a statement as to his character. I knew Blinn by rep=<pb/>
<lb/>utation, and as a witness in our courts, and am satisfied that he is vindictive, unscrupulous and utterly unreliable in every case where he feels any interest either pecuniary or otherwise -- He is notorious as a worthless and reckless fellow.</p>
<p>John P Harrison, Esqr, who was counsel for Blackwell, will write a statement of the case, and you may rely upon his candor and truthfulness -- </p>
<p>Yours &amp;c
<lb/>J G Carlisle</p>
<p>Hon. B Magoffin
<lb/>Frankfort Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
