<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2613"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Smith Craig et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7250</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-181 to BR16-183A</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Boone County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-08-18">18 August 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency Thome E Bramlett
<lb/>Govenor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned petitioners would respectfully represent That on <date when="1864-03-08">8 day of March 1864</date> H M Bruce was arrested on a charge of Larceny and held in the sum of Five Hundred Dollars for his appearance in the Boone Circuit Court on the first day of its <date when="1864-04">April term 1864</date> To answer the said charge Whereupon James H Bruce became the surety to ^the^ commonwealth in the bond for said sum for the appearance of H. M Bruce at the time &amp; place above stated Your petitioners further represent that Said H M Bruce was indicted by the Grand jury of Boone county at <hi rend="str">the</hi> <date when="1864-04">Aprile term of the Boone Circuit ^1864^</date> upon the charge for which he had been held (the specific charge <hi rend="str">Horse</hi> stealing a horse) when Said H M Bruce being called failed to appear according to the covenants of said bond when the commonwealth took a forfeiture upon the same and earned a summon to issue thereon which was duly executed on said James H Bruce and on the last day of the last Aprile term of Said court a judgment was<pb/>
<lb/>given in behalf of the Commonwealth on Said forfeitur against James H Bruce for the Sum of Five Hundred Dollars with costs &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi> for which execution ^(capias profine)^ has issued</p>
<p>Your petitioners State that James H Bruce entered into Said bond in good faith intending and believing that it would secure the appearance of H M Bruce at the proper time to answer said charge; but they State that contrary to ^the^ wish of James H Bruce &amp; without his knowledge H M Bruce Shortly after the execution of the Said bond enlisted into the Military Service of the United States and was Carried beyond the jurisdiction of the court &amp; without the limits of the State. as to the precise period for which said Bruce So enlisted And to what points he was taken in the service James H Bruce nor your petitioners are not positively advised; But they state ^that^ Since H M Bruce went into Said ^military^ Service, he has not been in the State except for a very few days ^immediately^ after said enlistment, Your petitioners Say that it <hi rend="str">has</hi> was <hi rend="str">uterly</hi> impossible for James H Bruce to have H M Bruce in attendance as specified in Said ^bond^ <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>because of ^his^ Said ^enlistment^ in the<pb/>
<lb/>in the said Service Your petitioners Say that H M Bruce has not been in the state to their knowledge since he left as before stated They say they know that James H Bruce was anxious to have Stand his trial in the circuit court, And that H M Bruce <hi rend="str">did</hi> did absent himself in the manner befor stated contrary to the wish of James H Bruce You petitioners Say that James H Bruce ^is^ a poor honest &amp; hard working man And is now near fifty-five years of age has a wife and a large family of children mostly Small depending upon his labor for support, <hi rend="str">That the only property he has is a house and a small pece of land not <unclear/> Six hundred Dollars</hi>, Your petitioners Say that to enforce the payment of Said forfeiture in full woul break up &amp; probably ruin James H Bruce And as they are now informed the atty's fee for the Commonwealth ^costs^ will be about One Hundred &amp; Fifty-Dollars which sum ^must be paid &amp;^ will greatly embarrass Bruce <hi rend="str">to pay</hi>. They <hi rend="str">therefore</hi> present this case which under all the circumstances They believe is one that will justify the interposition of executive clemency And therefore pray ^your^ excellency to remit So much of the fine<pb/>
<lb/>&amp; costs as does not go ^to^ the Commonwealth's Atty <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>and officers of the court</p>
<p><date when="1864-08-18">August 18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date></p>
<p><note place="left margin">All the list are Bruces Neighbors</note>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Smith Craig
<lb/>Henry, J, Sulliven
<lb/>R M Johnson
<lb/>Y. Johnson
<lb/>Thomas Goodridge
<lb/>James jarrell
<lb/>J M. Riddell
<lb/><unclear>Pheacboel</unclear> Barnes
<lb/>J P Scott
<lb/>A. R. Manfield
<lb/>Owen Miner
<lb/>James Calvert
<lb/>B F Stevenson
<lb/>William Goodrich
<lb/>Gabe Gaines
<lb/>Wm Harrison
<lb/>Henry W Jarrell
<lb/>Joseph, J, Lillard
<lb/>Reuben Jarrell
<lb/>Jasper Sullivan
<lb/>William H. Hensley
<lb/>John H. Jarrell
<lb/>Ansalem Jarrell
<lb/>Asa. S, Cason
<lb/>James Tolan
<lb/>William Sullivan
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Robt F Coleman Judge B. C. C.
<lb/>Lewis W Webb Clerk B. C. C.
<lb/>Edw<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Webb, Dep. C. B. C. C.
<lb/>M W Akin
<lb/><hi rend="underline">A. G. Winston</hi>
<lb/>R C Green County atty
<lb/>H. J. Foster
<lb/>G W. Chamblin
<lb/>N E Hawes
<lb/>A. D. Egelston
<lb/>Robt M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Muir
<lb/>E. E <unclear>Reitz</unclear>
<lb/>John H Smith
<lb/>Benj. Sandford
<lb/>B. O. Brasher
<lb/>Samuel Butts
<lb/>Perry A Butts
<lb/>Geo W. Tilley
<lb/>John H. Barnett
<lb/>Sam Cowen
<lb/>H J Burkart
<lb/>J, H, Brooking
<lb/>Almorien Perkins
<lb/>J. Kirkpatrick
<lb/>Thomas Underhill
<lb/>Mills Wilks
<lb/>Richard White<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/><unclear/> <unclear>Geher</unclear>
<lb/>Simon S Balaor
<lb/>N. Carpenter
<lb/>Nicholas Carpenter
<lb/>Robert Mosby
<lb/>S, G, Botts, ast assesser
<lb/>W Wingate
<lb/>W, W, Smith
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> S. Grant
<lb/>F. M Carson
<lb/>John Norris
<lb/>H. W Sebree
<lb/>Geo <unclear>Carnes</unclear>
<lb/>Richard Parker
<lb/>J H <unclear/>
<lb/>John Fitzpatrick
<lb/>R, J, Rice
<lb/>Perry M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Neely
<lb/>J, A, Gaines
<lb/><unclear/> H Voshill
<lb/>J G Gaines
<lb/>Geo K, Loder
<lb/>Thos W Cox
<lb/>J N Early
<lb/>D. B. Tilley
<lb/>A M Hyatt
<lb/>Fidelius Huber
<lb/>John Weindel
<lb/>J E Duncan
<lb/>C. Campbell
<lb/><cb n="2"/><unclear/> Auvill <unclear/>
<lb/>William T Smith
<lb/>G A <unclear/>
<lb/>M. L. Graves
<lb/>J C Jenkins
<lb/>Dillen Bradley
<lb/>Caleb Hurd
<lb/>L. A. Loder
<lb/>A. K. Johns
<lb/>J. N. Green P. M.
<lb/>A Rucker
<lb/>W. H Chapin Sr
<lb/>J C Stephens
<lb/><unclear/> S Burkshire
<lb/>Philip Bolander
<lb/>Wm E. Wels
<lb/>Jacob Bolander
<lb/>John Alloway
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> M Perks
<lb/>C N Alloway
<lb/>P. W. Snelling
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> A Norris
<lb/>Samuel Hernsley
<lb/>George, C, Gibbs
<lb/>John Carson
<lb/>B R Graves
<lb/><unclear/> <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi><pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Adress
<lb/>"James H Bruce
<lb/>Burlington
<lb/>Boone Co
<lb/>Ky"</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
