<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2362"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James Douglas et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6999</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-270 to BR15-271</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Eccelency Thomas E. Bramlett. Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner James Doughlass would respectfully state. That he has been fined in the Police Court of the City of Louisville in three several cases of the Commonwealth against him on the charge of renting a house to persons of Evil fame for the purpose of prostitution. He states that he did rent the houses to the presons as charged; but at the time of the renting he supposed and had good reason to beleive that they were persons of good and unexceptionable character When he found out to the Contrary, he made every effort in his power to get them out. The parties also tried to get out, but owing to the unprecedented scarcity of tenements in this city, they were unable to do so; He hesitated through feelings of humanity from having them thrown into the street, owing to the fact of they having several small children,</p>
<p>It was in proff before the Court, on trial of said causes that they had been making evry effort to find another place, and get out of his houses He states that he has allways deported himself as a peaceable and lawabiding citizen, He respectfully asks your Honor to extend to him Executive pardon of the portion of said fines as are within your controll,</p>
<p>Said fines are for the sum of one hundred dollars each besides the costs as will more fully appear by refference to abstracts herto attached</p>
<p>Appended herto are the personal signatures of the friends and acquaintances of your petitioner who Join with him in asking you to extend to him the Clemency of your pardoning<pb/>
<lb/>power in the cases</p>
<p>James Douglas
<lb/>Geo W. Doane
<lb/>J Cormell
<lb/>J. P. Gaillbreath
<lb/>F P. Neal
<lb/>J, B, Fisher
<lb/>Peter Riley
<lb/>Camron
<lb/>Gardner
<lb/>P P Roberts
<lb/>Jacob Unz
<lb/>D, S. Avery
<lb/>W. H. Smith
<lb/>Jo<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> P. Flint
<lb/>H C Russell
<lb/>R, A, Bell</p>
<p>Louisville City Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Jas Douglass
<lb/>$300.
<lb/><date when="1865-09-13">13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sept 1865</date></p>
<p>Remit 3 Judgts for $100. each</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
