<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2017"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">State of Indiana v. Samuel Allen, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9093</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-17 to MG24-18</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Corydon, Harrison County, Indiana</placeName>
    <date when="1862-06-09">9 June 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Indiana,
<lb/>Harrison County } SS.</p>
<p>Be it remembered that at a term of the Circuit Court within and for the County and state aforesaid, began on the <date when="1862-03-24">24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of March, A D 1862,</date> and continued from day to day by adjornment, before the Hon. George A. Becknell, sole Judge of the 2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> Judicial Circuit of said state was found by the Grand Jury for said Term, among other Indictments, the following, to wit:
<lb/> 
<lb/>"State of Indiana
<lb/>Harrison County } SS.
<lb/>Harrison Cicruit Court,
<lb/><date when="1862-03">March Term, 1862.</date></p>
<p>The State of Indiana
<lb/>vs.
<lb/>Samuel Allen</p>
<p>The Grand Jurors for the county of Harrison and State of Indiana upon their oath charge and present that at said county on the <date when="1862-01-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of January, in the year<pb/>
<lb/>1862,</date> Samuel Allen did, in a rude, insolent and angry Manner, unlawfully, feloniously, purposely and Maliciusly touch, strike and beat William Moore, with a club, which said Samuel Allen then and there had and held in his hands, and also said Samuel Allen in manner &amp; form aforesaid unlawfully assaulted the said William Moore, by shooting at him with a shot gun loaded with powder &amp; shot with the intent then and there, by beating him said William Moore with said club, and shooting at him with said shot gun, unlawfully, feloniously, purposely &amp; maliciously to kill &amp; murder the said William Moore, contrary to the form of the statute in such. cases made and provided and against the peace and dignity of the State of Indiana" 
<lb/>(signed) "A. B Carlton
<lb/>Pros. Atty."</p>
<p>On the back of the foregoing indictment, is endorsed the following, to wit:
<lb/>"Harrison Circuit Court
<lb/><date when="1862-03">March Term 1862</date>
<lb/>The State of Indiana
<lb/>vs } A &amp; B with intent to murder
<lb/>Samuel Allen<pb/></p>
<p>Indictment
<lb/>a true Bill
<lb/>Franklin M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Rae
<lb/>foreman
<lb/>Witnesses,
<lb/>William Moore, John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cuen, Robert Sonner, Harmon Stephens, Daniel <hi rend="underline">M</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi><hi rend="underline">Carty</hi>.
<lb/>A. B. Carlton, Pro<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Atty."</p>
<p>State of Indiana
<lb/>Harrison County } SS</p>
<p>I, David M Jones, clerk of the Circuit Court, within and for said County and State, hereby certify that the above and foregoing is a true and complete copy of the Indictment against said Samuel Allen, so found by said Grand Jury, at the <date when="1862-03">March term ^1862^</date> of said Circuit Court, as the same remains on file in My <unclear/></p>
<p><figure type="seal"><ab> HARRISON CIRCUIT COURT
<lb/>INDIANA</ab></figure></p>
<p>In testimony whereof, I hereunto <unclear/> my name, and affix the <unclear>seal</unclear> of said Court, at My office in Corydon, this <date when="1862-06-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of June, A. D 1862</date></p>
<p>David M Jones, clerk
<lb/>Har Cir Court</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
