<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0469"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John B. McHatton et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4588</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-236 to BR9-237</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Owen County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-01-01">1 January 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky County of Owen
<lb/><date when="1864-01-01">January 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>To the Honorable Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>" E. Bramlett Governor of Kentucky -</p>
<p>The undersigned your petitioners would most respectfully represent that they are the Securities in a bail bond, for one Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>" P. Herndon, who was indicted Some time Since the Grand Jury empanneled (at the <gap/> term <gap/> of the Circuit Court) for Owen County. They become the bail of Said Herndon at the <date when="1861-11">November ^term^ 1861</date> of Said Court; That on the <date when="1862-05">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of the May term 1862</date> of Said Court they produced the body of the Said Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>" P. Herndon in open Court, and Surrendered him up to the custody of the Court, and on the <date when="1862-05">5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of the Said May Term</date>, (the cause having been continued to that day by the Court on motion of the Commonwealth) they again produced the Said Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>" P. Herndon in Court and Surrendered him up to the Custody of the Court, who took possession of him by its officer, when upon the Motion of the Attorney for the Commonwealth without the consent of petitioners the case was continued until the next term of Court, without renewing, or continueing the bail.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth took no further steps in the case until the <date when="1863-05">May Term 1863</date> of Said Court, when the attorney for the Comlth: moved the Court to forfeit the recognizance of<pb/></p>
<p>the Said Herndon, upon which an order was caused to be entered, forfeiting Said recognizance, and a Summons awarded against these petitioners.</p>
<p>Your petitioners would further represent, (And State as the reason why they could not produce the body of the Said Herndon at the <date when="1863-05">May Term 1863</date> of Said Court) that for some time prior to the <date when="1863-05">May term 1863</date>, the Said Herndon was evading the Search of Federal Soldiers, And his whereabouts was unknown to these petitioners; Sometime in the Month of <date when="--07">July</date> or <date when="1863-08">August 1863</date> the Military Authorities of the United States took posession of Said Herndon, and have ever Since held him in custody; Consequently these petitioners could not produce him in Court, <hi rend="str">because</hi></p>
<p>Your petitioners would further State that they are both men of but little means, and with large families to Support, and if Judgment goes against them upon Said recognizance, it will result in utter ruin to them and family pecuniarily.</p>
<p>In view of the foregoing facts your petitioners do most respectfully, and Sincerely ask, that your Honor grant them, Such relief as you deem Just.</p>
<p>They pray to be released from any responsibility on account of their Securityship as bail for the Said<pb/>
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> P. Herndon as aforesaid.</p>
<p>As in duty bound they will ever pray -
<lb/>John B M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Hatton
<lb/>J. H. Threlkeld</p>
<p>State of Kentucky County of Owen</p>
<p>Personally appeared before me the above named John B. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Hatton and John H. Threlkeld and Severally made oath that the Statements contained in the foregoing petition are true.</p>
<p><date when="1864-01-01">January 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1864</date>.
<lb/>W. B. Roberts
<lb/>Pre: Judge of Owen County</p>
<p>To the Honorable Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>" E. Bramlett Governor of the State of Kentucky-</p>
<p>The undersigned Citizens of Owen County, would most respectfully represent, that we are intimately Acquainted with the foregoing petitioners Jno. B. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Hatton, and Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi>" H. Threlkeld, that they are both men of good Standing, and reputation; of limited Means, and both men of large families to Support; The arrest of the Said Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>" P. Herndon (refered to in the foregoing petition) and his evading the Federal authorities is within our personal Knowledge. We believe the Statements in Said petition to be true. In view of the facts contained in the foregoing petition of Said McHatton And Threllkeld, we do most respectfully<pb/>
<lb/>ask, that their prayer for relief may meet your favorable consideration.</p>
<p><date when="1864-01-01">Jany 1, 1864</date>
<lb/>Geo. C. Roberts Depuity Collector. Internal Revnue</p>
<p>W. B. Roberts Co Judge
<lb/>F. W. Staiar
<lb/>W. P. Bacon. P. M.
<lb/>C. B. Snell
<lb/>Dep. Pro. Marshal County of Owen
<lb/>W. H. Sandford clk Owen Circuit Court
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> A. Berryman
<lb/>J. D. Lillard
<lb/>Jas M Brorar Sheriff</p>
<p>Owen Circuit Court
<lb/>Refused</p>
<p><hi rend="str">Respite 12 months to give opportunity to produce prinicpal What if Owen will ensure a Remission
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>John B. McHatton
<lb/>&amp;
<lb/>J. H. Threlkeld
<lb/>Bail Bond</hi>
<lb/><date when="1863-05"><hi rend="str">May term/63</hi></date>
<lb/><date when="1864-02-09"><hi rend="str">9</hi><hi rend="str"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi><hi rend="str"> Feby 1864</hi></date></p>
<p>Respited for 12 months
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>$1.000. Bail Bond</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
