<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1434"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. John J. McAfee, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10902</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-399</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jessamine County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-09-21">21 September 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>"Examination held in the Case of J. J. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Afee for Shooting:</p>
<p>"John Cobb was in town on Monday sitting at Mrs Brown's, saw W. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Dowell, Dr. Mat Young gave him a pistol, the Crowd opened and M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Dowell <hi rend="underline">fires</hi> a little first, Daniel fired immediately afterward, Came near the pump, they had by this time fired out all their shots; M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Dowell changed his pistol &amp; walked up towards M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Daniel, M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Daniel presented his pistol &amp; Snapped. They came together and clinched &amp; M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Afee came up as if to give a pistol, Then M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Daniel seemed to shrink which turned M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Dowell's side <hi rend="underline">toward</hi> M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Afee who then presented his pistol &amp; fired -- M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Afee then threw up his pistol and walked away. -- </p>
<p>D<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Mizener -- 
<lb/>M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Dowell has two wounds -- one in his back, the other in the right leg, he is improveing, though still dangerous, looks as if he might get well -- the paralysis might kill him -- wound is in the back, Ball entered the Skin an inch or so from back bone, couldn't trace the ball, near the Spine in the Small of the back -- Thinks may be the ball is in the Spine --. Wound looks well so far as inflamation is Concerned -- If he Continues to improve the chances are in his favor -- "</p>
<p>Endorsed -- "Substance of evidence for Comlth: -- Commonwealth -- "John J. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Afee"<pb/></p>
<p>Jessamine Circuit Court Sct:</p>
<p>The foregoing is a true Copy of all the written evidence of Witnesses returned &amp; filed in my office with ^the^ papers under the Prosecution in the name of the Commonwealth of Ky -- against John J. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Afee for shooting &amp;c. this <date when="1861-09-21">21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Sept 1861. -- </date></p>
<p>attest M. T. Lowrey c. J. c. c. </p>
<p>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Copy Evidence
<lb/>Jno. J. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Afee<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>To accompany the Petition To Governor for Remission of Bail -- </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
