<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3486"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">N. A. Humber et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5605</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-417 to BR42-417A</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The undersigned would respectfully represent to his Excellency Gov Thos E. Bramlette of Ky. that there are many considerations why Amanda Thomas a woman of color ^now confined in State Prison^ should receive Executive clemency- Promenint among these are 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> that she was not principle in the matter (the charge was larceny) but was over reached by a cunning &amp; designing negro girl Ellen Bascom (who died shortly after conviction) This latter girl behaved in so insolent a manner upon the trial interrupting the witnesses, insulting the court &amp;c as to greatly increase &amp; aggravate the verdict. Both being tried together the Jury were of the opinion that they could not be convicted for different terms 2<hi rend="sup">ndly</hi> She is a young woman &amp; the mother of two small children, wholy dependent upon her aged mother for support There is much ^reason^ hope to believe that she is now repentant &amp; wil not <hi rend="str">again</hi> by evil associations be indu-ced to sin again <hi rend="str">in that respect</hi> but will act in a manner worthy of her former self</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>H Barhaw
<lb/>G W Doney
<lb/>E T Bannon
<lb/><cb n="2"/>N. A. Humber (Atty)
<lb/>J. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Carthy (atty)<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>L Dorsey
<lb/>R Dossey
<lb/>K Williams X
<lb/>H Williams X
<lb/>N Williams X
<lb/>S Watkins X
<lb/>L Thornton X
<lb/>S Brown X
<lb/>J Williams X
<lb/>N Mala X<pb/></p>
<p>Rev Mr. Merritt states that he knows the former master of the girl in question Mr. Levin Dorsey who is one of the signers of this petition that he has seen the girl about the House <unclear/>True to <unclear/> for a number of years and that so far as he knows she was a good girl, that her husband was in the army of the U. S and there died, that He is informed that she has never received anything for his service, and that her children are now dependent on the girls mother for support, who is living at her former masters -- </p>
<p>D. S.</p>
<p>A Thomas</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
