<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0834"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George W. Perkins to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4953</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-286 to BR10-287</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-05-07">7 May 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the govnor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner George W. Perkins states that his 2 boys Jackson and Charles Perkins and a hired boy was in his field at work on the <date when="1864-04-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of April 1864</date> when one Bell Brown came into the field and his Son Jackson who is 15 years old got into a Quarrell and Bell Brown Struck him in the face and he Jackson perkins hit the Said Brown three times over the close with a Switch after ordering him to go out of the field for which my said son was taken up for a breech of the peace and arrested by a peace officer of Shelby county at the home of E. Lea in Franklin county and taken to consolation in Shelby county and tried before Cary White a Justice of the peace for Shelby county Ky the proof in the case on the trial was as above stated with the further fact that she said Bell Brown had been ordered not to come into the field of your Petitioner Several times before and that the Said Brown cursed and abused the Said Jackson &amp; he was fined $8<hi rend="sup">50/100</hi> on the <date when="1864-05-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi><pb/>
<lb/>day of May 1864</date> he further states that he has been confined to his room for 12 months the <date when="---24">24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day</date> of this month with an absess in his Side that has been opened every other day until about 2 weeks ago an that he is Still confined to his Rooam and has Spent his means in paying Drs and is unable to pay said fine for his son and he needs his Sons assistance at home and dose not want him incaserated in Jail for So Small an offence </p>
<p>Wherefore he pray that your honor will Remit Said fine against Jackson Perkins as aforisad and for all proper relief.</p>
<p>George. W. Perkins</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by George W Perkins this <date when="1864-05-07">7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of May 1864</date>. E. A. W. roberts N. P. f. C</p>
<p><hi rend="str">Personally appeared before me Charles Kenny and others Jurors who tried the above cause and all Say that the Statments of facts Set fourth in the foregoing Petition are as proven before us</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Justice Peace
<lb/>Shelby Co
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Pet by his Fathers
<lb/>Jackson Perkins, a minor<figure type="hr"/>$8.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">50</hi></hi> assault
<lb/>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/><date when="1864-05-11">11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> May
<lb/>1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
