<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1241"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. H. Calvert to James W. Tate</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10709</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-100</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Princeton, Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-07-24">24 July 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Princeton, Ky <date when="1861-07-24">July 24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>James W Tate Esqr
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>Yours of <date when="1861-07-08">July the 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi></date> is before me, requesting more information in regard to the case against George Jenkins &amp; W H Calvert Admin of John T Calvert The case was originally an Indictment against D B Calvert for an affray and was Tried at the <date when="1858-03">March Term of our court 1858.</date> and the comth recovered a Judgement against him for $300.00 and D B Calvert Took on appeal and J. T. Calvert and George Jenkins went his security upon the Bond D B Calvert was killed in two days after Executing the appeal Bond his securities prosecuted the appeal -- the record was lost or mislayed in the court of appeals so that the same could not be found when it was called up for trial and the court dismissed the appeal after which the attorney for the comth brought not on the appeal Bond, and before Judgement was had I petitioned the governor and he released the securities upon said Bond and the <unclear/> of the Govorner has never come to bond at the last June term of the court<pb/></p>
<p>The case of the comth v Jenkins and J T Calverts <unclear/> upon said Bond came up for trial The Remitter of the Govornor was placed in Bar of the action against said securities. But it was not here and could not be filed a demurrer was entered agaisnt the answer which was sustained by the court and an appeal was prayed and we need the remitter to fill in the court of appeals in order to perfect the record that the action of the govornor may be Judicially examined by the court But I am compelled to send the partial Record in said case to the office of the clerk of the court of appeals by the same Mail that I send this to you so that it may be filed in time please file the remitter in the case in the court of Appeals for me when you find it -- I have been somewhat particular in discribing the case, according to your request But if I have faild I refer you to the record which will be filed in the court of Apeals when you find the case please make me out two coppys file one in the case in the court of appeals, and send me the other as I will have to file it in the court here under <unclear/></p>
<p>W H Calvert</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
