<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2200"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Walton Griffith et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9276</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-324 to MG24-325</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your petitioners whose names are hereto annexed would most respectfully represent to yoru honor, that we are well acquainted with both Darius Powers who was convicted at the <date when="--02">February term last</date> of the Graves Equity and Criminal Court, and sentenced to one years confinement in the Penitentiary of this state, and also with Frank Dunning the witness, &amp; the only eye witness, introduced by the state on the trial of the charge, whereto was this striking maliciously with intent to kill, the said F Dunning by said Powers</p>
<p>Powers is a small man, and we can with truth say, by no means malicious but has generally born the character of a peaceable quiet man &amp; good Citizen. Dunning the witness is universally understood to be a quarrelsome overbearing turbulant Bully, greatly superior in size &amp; Strength, to said Powers, and fully able pleasurably to overmaster him in a personal encounter, It was proved on the trial that Dunning has threatened the life of Powers saying that he would kill him on sight, and that he on the same day of the difficulty and but a short time prior to the encounter left with his gun to search ^Powers^ up and carry into effect his bloody struck against him It was further proved that Powers used the Gun of Dunning in inflicting the striking complained of the whole evidence, (except that Deposed by Dunning himself) circumstantial it is true, tended strongly to show that Dunning &amp; not Powers, was the party most to blame, and that<pb/>
<lb/>in fact, Powers done what was done in self defence and because he was compelled to so do to avoid <unclear>great<hi rend="str">t</hi></unclear> bodily harm at least, and possibly death at the hands of said Witness Dunning.</p>
<p>Your petitioners would further state, that said Powers is a very poor man, not long married, and has a wife &amp; two small children that he has no means except his own personal labor for their support -- that his wife is very feeble corporally &amp; wholly unable to procure even the commonest necessaries of life by her own labor, for herself &amp; little children, that she is sick now, &amp; without Bread meat or any thing else for sustenance except as it is furnished to her by the charitable hand of some kind neighbor and must &amp; will starve together her children unless sustained by the interposition of persons residing near her, for she has no one save the aged and penniless father of her husband to whom she can turn for assistance in this her hour of trial.</p>
<p>We therefore for the above reasons, &amp; for the sake of his starving wife &amp; innocent babies, beg that your Excellency will exercise the constutional power so wisely entrusted to you for his relief and extend to said Powers that executive clemency, <hi rend="str">whish</hi> which his condition so much needs by granting to him a pardon &amp; release from his present Bonds.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>walton Griffith
<lb/>L C Womble
<lb/>R. W Shelbourne
<lb/>R G Middleton
<lb/>C T. Womble<cb n="2"/>
<lb/>J. T. Dean
<lb/>James Carter
<lb/>John Jones
<lb/>ur<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">n</hi></hi> Holeman<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>Joseph W Stall
<lb/>M. T adams
<lb/>Gabril Jones
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> M Ransom
<lb/>J P Morgan
<lb/>H. M. farmer
<lb/>A L Farmer
<lb/>B Farmer
<lb/>E B Halsell
<lb/>William Bone
<lb/>G.. B.. Burrow
<lb/>R. M.. Ransom
<lb/>B L Moore
<lb/>J. N. Stier
<lb/>J. W. Hocker
<lb/>G. W.. Hocker
<lb/>W. H. Young
<lb/>J. W. Page
<lb/>R F Crooks
<lb/>J N Lynn
<lb/>J.. Y.. Hocker
<lb/>William Heath
<lb/>J.. A.. Ledford<pb/>
<lb/>Darius Powers
<lb/>case Pen<hi rend="sup">y</hi>
<lb/>File the Pet<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">n</hi></hi>
<lb/>B. M</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
