<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2154"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. H. Randall to James H. Garrard</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9230</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-246</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Jas H Garrard</p>
<p>I have written a Petition of Austen Reid asking the Governor to pardon him for stabbing Green. I have also included a letter therein to the Governor I would be glad you would aid <unclear/> in the matter, the Governor will not probably be ready to rely upon my statement as I am Reeds Counsel but I say to you as a gentleman I believe every statement within petition and letter to be strictly true. It is very hard under the circumstances that he should be harrassed with the burden and expense of the matter any further, it has already been an enormous expense, and it is now on the docket only to gratify Greens malice_ because Durham would have been ready and <unclear>waiting</unclear> at the last Term to let a majority of the Jury make the verdict, but Green would not commit to it, and therefore Durham would not_ they never <unclear>concurred</unclear> Reid, and there can be no wrong in the Governor's <hi rend="str">inferen</hi> ^interference^</p>
<p>Help us in this matter if you please</p>
<p>Yr Respectfully &amp;c 
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W. H. Randall</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
