<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2385"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Rothchild to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7022</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-307 to BR15-308</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Somerset, Pulaski County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-25">25 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency.
<lb/>Thos. E, Bramlette Governor of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>Your Petitioner William Rothchild would respectfully represent; that at the present <date when="--09">(Sept)</date> Term of the Pulaski Circuit Court. two Judgments were rendered against him, one for $200 the other for $50.</p>
<p>He states that he had a good defense to the indictments, under which these Judgments were rendered, but could not attend court, by reason of Sickness in his family -- He states, he is very poor man, resides in Harrodsburg Kentucky, and is unable to pay these fines -- that his property has been destroyed twice by fire, leaving him with a large and helpless family to provide for,</p>
<p>He states, that the indictments were found against him for selling liquor as a sutler at Camp Burdside in this County, when occupied by the Fedral troops -- that he sold said liquor under and by the permission and authority of the commander of said camp, &amp; that he was entirely ignorant of any violation of state Law -- He states if he had known that he was inhibited by statute law from Selling liquor<pb/>
<lb/>in camp, that he would not have done so -- </p>
<p>He states, the collection of these Judgments will be very oppressive, <hi rend="str">and</hi> if not ruinous -- He asks Your Excellency to remit his fines</p>
<p>William Rothchild</p>
<p>Sworn to by W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Rothchild before me this <date when="1865-09-29">29 Sept 1865</date>,</p>
<p>J M Sandifer P. J. T. S,</p>
<p>We believe W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Rothchild ought to have a remission of his fines; We believe he deserves the interposition of your Excellency: clemency -- and ask to remit the fines,</p>
<p>W. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee. Fox.
<lb/>J M Sandifer
<lb/><hi rend="underline">F Woodcock</hi>
<lb/>B M Burdett
<lb/>R Reynolds
<lb/>Joseph E. Hays
<lb/>J. E. Cosson
<lb/>W D Carpenter
<lb/>E L VanWinkle
<lb/>Ferd: Rothenhofer
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Samuel Dungan</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Mercer County</hi><pb/>
<lb/>W. A Hooe
<lb/>C, S, Abell clerk co Court
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Edwards P J M C C
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J,, W. Cardwell</hi>
<lb/>Chs Chinn
<lb/>L. G. Hale J. P. M. C
<lb/>J W Hale J. P. M C
<lb/>Stephen Curll, J. P. M C
<lb/>M Cummins J P M C<pb/></p>
<p>Pulaski Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Rothchild
<lb/>2 judgts
<lb/>$200,
<lb/>$50,
<lb/>Tipling
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-10-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Oct /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
