<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0787"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Byrd et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10255</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-225 to MG19-226</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency B Magoffin governor of Kentucky </p>
<p>your petitioners citizens of of Christian County would respectfully represent to your Excellency that at the <date when="--03">present March Term</date> of the Christian Circuit Court Jonathan Greer was tried on an indictement against him for murder that the Jury acquitted him for murder, but found him guilty of man-slaughter and fixed his punishment by confinement in the penitentiary for a term of five years</p>
<p>Now your petitioners will state that said Greer is an old man being about sixty years of age having a large family of children that he was involved in the fight or affray in which adison Farrell for killing of whom he was tried ^they make on the trial^ Established the fact that Stephen Shelton who was also killed in ^the^ same affray by abner greer a Son of said Jonathan greer and said Abner greer who was very dangerously wounded by shelton when Engaged firing with pistols at Each other that they both fell that Farrell after they fell was in pursuit of William Greer who was unarmed and <hi rend="str">said</hi> firing at said William <unclear/> <unclear/> <unclear/> <unclear/> a son of Jonathan Greer that Jonathan Greer the father having his rifle gun in his hands and being himself severely wounded by a pistol shot his son abner shot down and ferrell pursuing and firing at his son William who was unarmed and <hi rend="str">retiring</hi> retreating fired upon said Farrell and killed him which Ended the affray.<pb/> 
<lb/>Now your petitioners taking into consideration all the circumstances in the case the relation of father and child that existed between Johnathon Greer and his sons Abner and William and fully appreciating the parental feelings of said Jonathan Greer at the time of the killing cannot but think that is a case addressing itself with peculiar force and favor to the consideration of you Excellency and we the more readily urge his cause befor your Exellency for the reason that Jonathan Greer has lived in our midst from Early youth to old age and has Ever borne the character of a peaceable quit sober and industrious citizen a good neighbor and fine friend and kind and affectionat husband &amp; father taking all things into consideration we respectfully present his case to the favorable consideration of your Exellency and Earnestly ask for a full and free pardon believing as we do that such an act of clemency would meet with the hearty approval of an overwhelming majority of the best citizens of the country </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>John Byrd
<lb/>D. H. Taylor 
<lb/><unclear/> 
<lb/>B T Underwood 
<lb/>G. V. Campbell
<lb/>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> Byrd 
<lb/><unclear/> Henry 
<lb/>W. C. Campbell 
<lb/>M N <unclear/> 
<lb/>P. M. Gray 
<lb/>A N Long 
<lb/>W T Buckner
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J W A M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Garvy 
<lb/>Jas. M Foard
<lb/>Robt <unclear/> 
<lb/>W. B. Salman 
<lb/>Jno. W. Breathill
<lb/>Jno M Lambdin 
<lb/>Geo W D Luck 
<lb/>J. M Hopson 
<lb/>F R Campbell 
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> C Wallace
<lb/>Ben. Wood 
<lb/>J R Reynolds<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>John. O Snyder
<lb/>N. H. Woolridge
<lb/>H B Ganny 
<lb/>S. L. Wooldridge
<lb/>I. S. Rowland M D
<lb/>E R Cook M D. 
<lb/>David Fuller
<lb/>S Ray Brooks
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H. Ashford
<lb/>A Copeland 
<lb/>Robert Foard
<lb/>James Moore
<lb/>John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Giwan 
<lb/>George Poindexter
<lb/>W. A. Glass
<lb/>H. N Fleming
<lb/><unclear/> Durham
<lb/>Jno P Campbell Jr
<lb/>Thos M Buck
<lb/>Richard J. Trainman
<lb/>C. C. Thacker
<lb/>Enoch Martin
<lb/>James Butler
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Long
<lb/>James Kinkead
<lb/><unclear/> Thomas
<lb/>Peter Higgins
<lb/>H,, C,, Means
<lb/>Jno. T. Edmunds
<lb/>John M Carroll
<lb/>E. Armstrong
<lb/><unclear/> Harrison
<lb/><unclear/>
<lb/>Joseph F Anderson
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J. C. Parker
<lb/>W. H. Blythe
<lb/>J. T. Ricketts
<lb/>J R Bronaugh
<lb/>B C Ritter
<lb/>Jno. R. Ratcliffe
<lb/>A D Rodgers Judge County Ct
<lb/>Wm. M. Beam
<lb/>H. P. Owsley
<lb/>W. C. Elliott
<lb/>G. W. <unclear/>
<lb/>C. W. Gresham
<lb/>Richard Camron
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>Peter <unclear/>
<lb/>George W Fox
<lb/>William C Gray
<lb/>R H Gray
<lb/>Eli Combs
<lb/>Wm Combs
<lb/>Newton Combs
<lb/>Thos Gunn
<lb/>J D Morris
<lb/>W R Wolf
<lb/>F W Bigerstaff
<lb/>J. M. Cayce
<lb/>H,, Ricketts
<lb/>James Robbs
<lb/>D. S. Bowls
<lb/>A. J. Venable
<lb/>G. W. Heames
<lb/>J. J. Keney
<lb/>F. W. Buckner<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>charles chatman
<lb/>J. W. Brown
<lb/>Daniel Gray
<lb/>John R Green
<lb/>Elbert F Cobb
<lb/>W. F. Barm</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
