<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1446"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">F. C. Jenkins et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10914</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-7 to MG22-8</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-09-05">5 September 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Petitioner granted the<hi rend="str">se</hi>re request and in this way persons asked permission and on several occasions used the rooms for gaming purposes without however the knowledge or consent of Your Petitioner but the law requiring your Petitioner to prove a negative according to the ruling of the Court Your petitioner <hi rend="str">c</hi>was convicted when he was in fact &amp; truth ^not^ guilty. If your Petitioner had wilfully &amp; knowledgly violated the law he would submit but he utterly denies he has and therefore prays Your exellency interposition and that the fine be remitted</p>
<p>F. C. Jenkins</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by F C Jenkins <date when="1861-09-05">Sept 5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>H. W. Purdy D. C. </p>
<p>We the undersigned jurors in said case join in the prayer of Petitioner for a remission of his fine</p>
<p>E. H. O Daniel<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">
<lb/></hi></hi>Ben Wheatly 
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Jarboe
<lb/>Jas. Tylor<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned join in the prayer of Petitioner &amp; pray that the fine be remitted</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Charles Jarboe
<lb/>Pius B Odaniel
<lb/>R J O'Daniel
<lb/>Ben Spalding Jr
<lb/>Felix Smith
<lb/>N. S. Ray
<lb/>W C Jarboe
<lb/>J<hi rend="sup">a</hi> H Jarboe
<lb/>F. K. Beaver
<lb/>Ben R. Smith
<lb/>G W Riggs
<lb/>R. D. Scott
<lb/>M. T. Hardey
<lb/>Henry Beaver
<lb/><unclear/> Ballard
<lb/>M Buckler
<lb/>D B Thompson
<lb/>Frank Beaven
<lb/>C, A, Jarboe
<lb/>W T Dance
<lb/>H M Spalding
<lb/>Horace <unclear>Celee</unclear>
<lb/>W. W. Purdy
<lb/>R C Harris
<lb/>W. D. Catlin
<lb/>J C Rusell
<lb/>J. A Mattingly
<lb/>H. Johnston
<lb/><cb n="2"/>H. W. Purdy
<lb/><unclear/> Thompson
<lb/>John Shuck
<lb/>Thos. C. Woods
<lb/>C. H. Noble
<lb/>M. Kisle
<lb/>W. H. Wetherton
<lb/>G. S. Mock
<lb/>Piers Carrico
<lb/>T. J. Clark
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>A Corley
<lb/>Napoleon <unclear/>
<lb/>D. S. Coligan
<lb/>J B Wathen
<lb/>James Elder
<lb/>J. W. Chandler
<lb/>O. J. Luckett
<lb/>J. Littlefield
<lb/>D. H. Howard
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Milburn
<lb/>J H Edelen 
<lb/>Rh M Spalding
<lb/>James. M. Coun
<lb/>Geo. W. Lancaster
<lb/>Leo Beaven 
<lb/>W Medly
<lb/>F. B. Merimee<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky </p>
<p>Your Petitioner <hi rend="str">Calvin</hi>F. <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>C. Jenkins would most respectfully State that at the last August Criminal and Chancery term holden for Marion County Ky he was convicted of the charge of permitting gaming in his house and was fined by a verdict of the jury and judgement of said Court the sum of two hundred and fifty dollars -- Your Petitioners would respectfully beg the indulgence of Your Excellency while he states the circumstances under which the indictment was found and judgement rendered Your Petitioner is a poor man with a delicate wife &amp; several children and in order to make something to support himself &amp; family purchased a small lot of ground in Chicago Marion County Ky a Depot on the Lebanon Branch of the Louisville &amp; Nashville Rail Road and commenced to build &amp; has built a house (tho not yet completed) with a view of keeping a Hotel and has been keeping a Hotel for some little time past -- He had been before that time doing business in the way of selling goods in Raywick and had but a very small capital and besides what he had used to Support his family he had credited out and had all that he had in debts and as Raywick went down in<pb/>
<lb/>in consequence of the building of the Rail Road he thought the best he could do to support his family would be to trade his notes for lumber and being a cabinet workman with what he could do himself towards building a house he could build and perhaps do better as his business of Merchdising or making permiture had both failed tho his property is not yet paid for Now Your Petitioner Says he is a moral man and kepy a very quiet orderly tavern -- It is true he permitted persons to play cards and dominos in his bar room for amusement and always forbid the playing for anything not even a treat and no playing of any kind of game was ever done in the bar room for anything not even a treat nor was there any proof or pretense that any gamining for money or property was done then Your Petitioner is no gamester but in that neighborhood it ^is^ common among nearly all to play cards for amusement being a peculiar feature of the habits of that part of the County -- The manner in which Your Petitioner came to be convicted was as follows being a trading point and persons fequently desirous of doing private business would request the use of one of Petitioners upper rooms being no other private places in the place of course</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
