<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-019-0089"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas H. Hunt to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1395</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG5-162</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-15">15 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><hi rend="underline">Private</hi>
<lb/>Louisville <date when="1861-06-15">June 15 1861</date>
<lb/>My Dear Sir</p>
<p>There are 198 muskets of a lot sent to me by Doctor Blackburn when he was in Mississippi that ought to be retained in the State if possible and i don't see why they should get into the hands of the Union party -- They are first rate guns and in fine order -- Smooth bore but heavy barrels and suitable for rifling -- When they arrived supposing them to belong to the State I collected of Mr Brannin about $160 to pay freight &amp;c -- The Doctor wants to turn part of them over to a company going South and I have told him he must get your order for them which is not treating him very cleverly as all the State is out on them as the $160 above named -- He of course is entitled to the guns provided he returns the $160, under Gov. Pettis of Mississippi meant them as a present to the State -- about that you may know -- </p>
<p>Yours truly Tho H Hunt<pb/></p>
<p>Tho H. Hunt</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
