<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1247"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Mathew Mullins et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10715</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-110 to MG21-111</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Pendleton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-07-29">29 July 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To Govenor M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin</p>
<p>Your petitioners Mathew Mullins A. G. Roberts E. W Knight &amp; Samuel L Swoope would represent that judgment was rendered against them at the late <date when="1861-04">April</date> term of the Pendleton Circuit Court for five hundred dollars on their recognizance for his appearance of William Dorsey who stood charged for attempting to entice away a negro slave the property of <gap/> the said William Dorsey was from the state of Ohio a young man under the age of twenty one years. He was originally arrested brought before the Judge of the Pendleton <hi rend="str">Cir</hi> County Court, and upon the proof offered by the prossecution was held to Bail in the sum of Two Thousand dollars in default of which he was committed. He was an entire stranger here. His parents learning his condition appeared, and he was brought out upon writ of Habeas Corpus, and the most satisfactory proof was made that he was weak minded and in fact insane having wandered from home. The county Judge supposing he had no power to discharge him reduced his bail to five hundred dollars which was given by petitioners. The parents of said Dorey took him home to Ohio and caused an inquest to be held upon him and as will appear from the proceedings of the court of common <hi rend="str">please</hi> Pleas for Hancock County Ohio, he was was found to be insane, and committed to the Lunatic Assylum where he has ever since been held and hence his failure to appear. It was the general opinion and belief that Dorey was an insane person, and not capable of committing the offense with which he was charged such was the opinion of your petitioners, and they entered into the recognizance. They refer to a copy of the proceedings before the Examing Court the Circuit Court, and the<pb/>
<lb/>Court of Common Pleas of Hancock County Ohio together with a copy of certificate of the Superintendent of the Assylum where the said Dorey is held. There can be no doubt that the accused was insane. His Parents are of high standing, and would not interfere, or encourage the interference with slavery where it exists of this Your petitioners had had the most ample and satisfactory proof. They Respectfully request Your Excellency to remit the forfeiture except the costs.</p>
<p>M Mullins
<lb/>Saml F. Swope
<lb/>Edward W. Knight
<lb/>A G Roberts</p>
<p>Sworn to before me this <date when="1861-07-29">29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of July 1861</date></p>
<p>G. C. Lightfoot J. P. P. C<pb/></p>
<p>I know nothing of my own knowledge as to the facts and circumstances detailed within, many of which appear in the face of the record referred to, the sureties in the bond are gentlemen who command my highest respect and whose statements are entitled to the fullest credit. On this account I join in the prayer of the petition and I am of the opinion that the remission of the Bond as solicited by them (excepting Fees &amp; costs) would be a becoming exercise if Executive clemency</p>
<p>Very respectfully Your
<lb/>Excellencys obediant servant
<lb/>W. E. Arthur
<lb/>Atty Co<hi rend="underline">m'th</hi></p>
<p>I am well acquainted with all the facts in this case, and know the Statements of the <hi rend="str">petioners</hi> petitioners to be Substantialy true I held the Examing court, and am Satisfied that the young man was not of Sound mind. I think that this is a case calling for the exercise of Executive clemency upon Just and true grounds</p>
<p>Very Respectfully yours &amp;c
<lb/>Jas. J. Hudnall P J P C C</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
