<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0217"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James Gurlee to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4336</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-337</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Campbellsburg, Henry County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-10-25">25 October 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Campbellsburge Ky.
<lb/><date when="1863-10-25">25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Octr AD 1863</date>
<lb/>Governor Thomas E. Brambette
<lb/>Dear sir</p>
<p>I inclose you Mr. Matthew McCollister pertions for to obtain your remittance of his fine of $250. I have known M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Collister for upwards of Thirty three years, and Know him to be all that his pettition represents him to be. I have been his Family Physician for more than Twenty five years, his wife has been confined to her <hi rend="underline">bed</hi> &amp; House more than one third of that time, with <hi rend="underline">incuriable disease</hi>, he is poor and barryly makes out to live with all of his industry &amp; frugallaty, and to have the above amount to pay would compell him to sell a part of his plantation in the Hills of Trimble County. When Mr. C Scott &amp; my self<pb/></p>
<p>were in Frankfort two weeks agoe we paid Mr. J. L. Scott Prosecuting Atty. Fifty dollars in full of his Fee connecting with the fine his Fee was about $75.00 and believeing it would be opprisive he took $50, which we advanced. The subscribers to the Petition cirtafying the respectabillaty of the witnesses to the conversation which induced MCCollister to assault Horton are all good &amp; True <hi rend="underline">men</hi>: which I will refer you to M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Thomas Rodman as he is well acquainted with the most of them. and for my character I refer you to Gen Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> M Harlan, A G Hodges &amp; L. Rodman. If you remitt the fine please direct it to McCollister or myself at Campbellsburge Henry Cty. Ky.</p>
<p>I remain as ever your devoted &amp; personal &amp; Political Friend
<lb/>James Gurlee M. D.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
