<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-019-0023"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">M. O. H. Norton to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1329</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG5-68</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>New Orleans, Orleans Parish, Louisiana</placeName>
    <date when="1861">1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Telegram</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>WESTERN UNION TELEGRAPH COMPANY.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>No. 1.] TERMS AND CONDITIONS ON WHICH MESSAGES ARE RECEIVED BY THIS COMPANY FOR TRANSMISSION.</p>
<p>The public are notified that, in order to guard against mistakes in the transmission of messages, every message of importance ought to be repeated, by being sent back from the station at which it is to be received, to the station from which it is originally sent. Half the usual price for transmission will be charged for repeating the message; and while this Company will, as heretofore, use every precaution to ensure correctness, it will not be responsible for mistakes or delays in the transmission or delivery of repeated messages, beyond an amount exceeding five hundred times the amount paid for sending the message; nor will it be responsible for mistakes or delays in the transmission of unrepeated messages from whatever cause they may arise, nor for delays arising from interruptions in the working of Telegraphs, nor for any mistake or omission of any other Company, over whose lines a message is to be sent to reach the place of destination. All messages will hereafter be received by this Company for transmission, subject to the above conditions.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>A. STAGER, Gen. Sup't, Cleveland, O.
<lb/><cb n="2"/>I. R. ELWOOD, Sec'y, Rochester, N. Y.<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Forwarded from Louisville <date when="1861">186<hi rend="str">0</hi>1</date>.
<lb/>By Telegraph from New Orleans <date when="1861">30 186<hi rend="str">0</hi>1</date>.
<lb/>To Gov Magoffin</p>
<p>Telegraph of this date rec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> fifteen hundred (1500) Guns Shipped to Hunt costing about fourteen thousand (14000) Dollars &amp; I will forward today to Hunt fifteen (15) Dollars worth pErcussion Caps no more guns &amp; no powder here, Shall I order from Cuba. Blackburn cant be found. I shall draw on you a favor agent of Bank Kentucky.</p>
<p>M. O. H. Norton
<lb/>Rec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> the above &amp; answered as follows.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
