<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1031"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. W. Osborn to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5668</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR[11]-89 to BR[11]-90</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-07-07">7 July 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville
<lb/><date when="1864-07-07">July 7/64</date>
<lb/>Govenor.</p>
<p>In behalf of Mr W. G. Gray I write to beg you to remit the fine imposed on him, because of his attack on Mr Ronald, Mr Gray bought a claim of a man, Who lost the amt at cards, &amp; Who plead the gambling act to recover back, what he conceived he had been -- swindled out of, Mr -- Grays name appearing ^on the papers^ as one of the parties -- claiming the money. Mr Ronald, asserted, in the -- company of several Gentlemen, he, Gray, had plead the gambling acts, Believeing what Ronald said was true. I told the father<pb/>
<lb/>believing he would not punish his son to do such a thing.</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Gray was so much incensed at the remarks of Ronald, he sought him out &amp; I believe, hit him once or twice &amp; hence the suit, These are the facts &amp; I hope will justify your granting the petition sent you.</p>
<p>I am
<lb/>Yrs Very Respty
<lb/>J. W. Osborn</p>
<p>His Excellency
<lb/>T. E. Bramlet Esq.
<lb/>Frankfort<pb/></p>
<p>N.B.</p>
<p>Mr Gray is a very Exemplary young man, never either drinks or plays Cards, &amp; is deserving of your kindest consideration.</p>
<p>Yrs
<lb/>Very Try
<lb/>J W O</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
