<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2706"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Lewis Rose to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7343</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-350 to BR16-351</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E. Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kenty.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Lewis Rose a citizen of Louisville Ky will respectfully state that about four weeks ago one Wilson Maples. a neighbor had been in the habit of leading ^a^ <unclear>PlowHorse</unclear> on Petitioners sidewalk &amp; on the day of the difficulty hereinafter stated said Maples was in the act of again leading his horse on the sidewalk of Petitioner when he stoped him &amp; some angry words passed when your Petitioner who had a verry small cane in his hand not larger than his finger struck said Maples one blow. Inflicting no Injury whatever. &amp; your Petitioner then left to go to the <unclear/> &amp; was followed by Maples who had a pistol &amp; was prevented by the bystander from shooting Petitioner</p>
<p>Your Petitioner will further state that said Maples went before the Grand Jury of the City Court &amp; they returned an Indictment against Petitioner for the assault above stated your Petitioner being Ignorant in Law Matters &amp; Supposing that Maples <hi rend="str">Hi</hi> himself had a right to settle the matter. he applyed to him &amp; it was agreed that upon Petitioner paying the costs which he agreed to do. the suit should be<pb/>
<lb/>dismissed Your Petitioner believing the matter was settled gave no further attention to this matter &amp; was surprised this week to learn that the case had been tried at the present <date when="--09">September</date> Term of the city court and a fine assessed against him of Sixty Dollars &amp; costs. </p>
<p>Your Petitioner has set forth Truly all the facts &amp; circumstances &amp; he again states that no Injury was done to said Maples &amp; that no Tumult or disorder was occasioned thereby &amp; that he was deceived into a beleif that the whole matter was settled Otherwise he would have defended the case. Your Petitioner is a Laborer in the ship yard &amp; supports his family -- a wife &amp; Two orphan Grand children by his daily labor &amp; has no other means of support. He prays your Excellency to remit said Fine of $60. &amp; he in duty bound will &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi></p>
<p>Lewis Rose<pb/></p>
<p>The undersigned Neighbors of Lewis Rose &amp; well acquainted with him unite in the request that the fine of $60 assessed against him in the City Court be remitted. He is a man of Truth. an Industrious good Citizen quiet &amp; Peaceable. a poor man who supports a wife &amp; Two Grand children by his daily Labor.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Irwin
<lb/>M Shoder
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> T Lee
<lb/>M Woods Ferguson
<lb/>Wm. W. Martin
<lb/>John Gay
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s.</hi> Clarke
<lb/><cb n="2"/>A Gilmore
<lb/>Robt W Hays</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>&amp;#9758; The above are owners of saw mills on the river -- with whom Rose has worked as a laborer.</p>
<p>Robt W Hays</p>
<p>I unite in the petition for release of fine</p>
<p>J B Kinkaid
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> F Barret</p>
<p>I have examined &amp; inquired into the facts in this case -- I think it highly worthy of executive clemency: The man is poor innocent of any wrong intent -- </p>
<p>W. C Whitaker<pb/></p>
<p>Louisville City Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Lewis Rose
<lb/>$60,
<lb/>Assault
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-11-04">4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
