<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0614"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Price &amp; Wood to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9066</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-463 to R4-464</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency James. F. Robinson Gov. of the State of Ky.</p>
<p>The undersigned would respectfully State, that they as counsel, defended Thomas Edrington, on his trial for the murder of his wife.</p>
<p>It appeared to us on the trial of the case, that the plea of insanity was as fully, and as completely made out as it was possible to make out a case, where the party was not a raving maniac. </p>
<p>We refer to the testimony of Peter Zanane Miss Blackburn, Mrs. Edington, his mother; and Dr Owens; -- and especially the latter. His Statement Shows beyond question, that his mind was not only thoroughly worked depressed and demented; <hi rend="str">but</hi> and that it was a <hi rend="underline">hopeless case of mental imbecility</hi>; but it was also a confirmed case of <hi rend="underline">detireum tremens</hi>, or <hi rend="underline">mania poter</hi>.</p>
<p>Surely if Dr Owens' Statements are true, the man was not guilty of murder. He was wholy incapable of deliberating or forming any design to take the life of his wife. If he was not guilty of murder he, was not guilty in law of a less crime. It was either murder or nothing.<pb/></p>
<p>The verdict is a Signular one. What right or by what authority <hi rend="str">had</hi> did they to find him guilty of manslaughter. The court here agreed with us that it was <hi rend="underline">murder</hi> or no crime atall. Yet he refused to Set the verdict aside and grant a new -- trial. This Judgement of the court was as Singular as the verdict of the Jury. The verdict and Judgement are clearly illegal But the poor unfortunate man is not abble, nor has he friends that are able to appeal the case. Besides he has no assurance that the Same thing will not be repeated</p>
<p>We think this is a case, if ever there was one which demands Executive clemency. It was not possible for the man in his then condition of mind and <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>body to be guilty of any crime.</p>
<p>Yours Respectfully
<lb/>Price &amp; Wood.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
