<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-034-0011"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">State of Indiana v. John Hooper, Judgment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7739</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Requisitions for the Return of Fugitives from Justice, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-19 to R3-20</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Dearborn County, Indiana</placeName>
    <date when="1859-09-15">15 September 1859</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Indiana Dearborn County Sct
<lb/>In the common Pleas Court of Dearborn County Indiana
<lb/><date when="1859-09">September Term 1859</date>
<lb/>State of Indiana
<lb/>vs } Grand Larceny
<lb/>John Hooper</p>
<p>Be it rememberd that on the <date when="1859-09-10">10th day of September 1859</date> Being the 6th Judicial day of the <date when="1859-09">September Term 1859</date> of said court the following proceedings were had in the above cause to wit:</p>
<p>Green Durbin Esq the District Prosecuting Attorney comes and said defendant in his own proper person and by counsel comes also and said defendant withdraws his plea heretofore entered to this Information And now for plea thereto confesses that he is guilty as charged therein, Whereupon this cause is submitted by agreement to the summary dicision of the court without a Jury and the evidence being heard the court is sufficiently advised of the premises, It is therefore considered by the Court that Said defendant be imprisoned in the State prison of the State of Indiana for the term of Two years from this date that he be disfranchised and rendered incapable of holding any office of trust or profit<pb/>
<lb/>for the term of six months from this date that he make his 'fine' to the State of Indiana in the penal sum of Fifty dollars and that he pay the costs of this prosecution and Stand committed to the custody of the Sheriff until the fine and costs are paid or replevied</p>
<p>State of Indiana
<lb/>Dearborn County Sct</p>
<p>I Samuel L. Jones clerk of the common Pleas Court of said county hereby certify that the above and foregoing contain a full and true copy of the Judgment of the Court pronounced in said cause as fully as the same appears of record</p>
<p><figure type="seal"/></p>
<p>Witness my hand and the Seal of said court hereunto affixed this <date when="1859-09-15">15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of September 1859</date></p>
<p>Samuel L. Jones Clk<pb/></p>
<p>Sentence of John Hooper<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Dearborn Com Pleas.
<lb/>G. Larceny 2 years<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Sentenced <date when="1859-09-10">Sept 10 1859</date>
<lb/>Received -- 15 -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>State of Indiana
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John Hooper
<lb/>Grand Larceny
<lb/>Copy of Judgt.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
