<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2648"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George B. Kinkead to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7285</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-243 to BR16-244</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lexington, Fayette County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-11-02">2 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Lexington Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-11-02">Nov 2, 1865</date>
<lb/>His Excy
<lb/>Gov Bramlette -- 
<lb/>Frankfort Ky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>I have Known John Taylor a free man of Color, for a great many years, and have a great deal to do with him as his Counsel in his various business -- </p>
<p>About a year ago he fell under suspicion of receiving a small quantity of Stolen corn, I defended him and heard the evidence, It was Clear that the corn was stolen and was found in the Livery Stable of Taylor very early the morning after, But this was the only proof Connecting him<pb/>
<lb/>with it, And he denied most vehemently that he Knew anything about it; but said the wagon was drawn in his stable without his having any idea where the corn had been got from, He had a large livery stable in Lexington, and his story had all the appearance of probability about it, but the magistrates held him to bail &amp; he found that about that time prejudice was running very high against free Negroes and he forfeited his bail &amp; fled the Country, and has been absent since,</p>
<p>I think highly of John Taylor and I believe we never had a more orderly humble and faithful free Negro in Lexington,<pb/></p>
<p>I would be very truly gratified if you could extend him your <hi rend="str">Excellency</hi> Executive Clemency.</p>
<p>I am Very Truly
<lb/>Geo B Kinkead<pb/></p>
<p>W K Kinkeads Letter</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
