<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1164"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John B. Perkins et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10632</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-321 to MG20-322</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Green County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-13">13 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah McGoffin Governor the Commonwealth of Kentucky, Your Petitioner John Bales Perkins, commonly known by the name of Bales Perkins, would most respectfully represent to your Excellency, that he is a poor young man, making an honest living by the cultivation of the soil. having a widowed mother and several small children, dependant on him for support. that he has in times past, occasionally gambled in a small way with some of his associates and companions, but he has some time since seen the folly of it, and entirely forsaken the practice, and never intends hereafter to indulge in a habit so pernicious to youth. Last summer your petitioner was engaged in a game of cards with two of his associates Franklin Black and Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H. Morris but on that occasion had nothing at stake, and nothing on that occasion was either won or lost but it so happened that at the Circuit Court thereafter shortly held in Green County, your petitioner was presented to the Grand Jury, and a true bill found against him. by what authority, or upon what testimony your petitioner knows not. In the month of <date when="1861-05">May</date> just past, Your petitioner was served with process requiring his attendance at this the present <date when="1861-06">June</date> term of the Green Circuit Court -- and on the 4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of said term as your petitioner understood the officer. to say. Your petitioner attended punctually on the day, he understood himself to be summoned, together with witnesses, to show his inocence of the charge of Gaming made against him -- but was greatly surprised to find, that a jury had been empanneled to assess the fine, and your petitioner not having appeared and plead, a fine of fifty dollars was assed against him, without the introduction of testimony on either side. Your petitioner being young and inexperienced, and without competent<pb/>
<lb/>advice, settled with the Commonwealths attorney, his costs or interest in the Judgement. although he is now advised, that he could doubtless have obtained a new trial, had he made application in time -- Now therefore relying on the clemency of your Excellency, may you be pleased to remit the fine aforesaid, or so much thereof as may appear unsatisfied -- and as in duty bound your petitioner will ever pray &amp;c -- </p>
<p>John B Perkins</p>
<p>Jno. B Perkins personally appeared before me and made oath that the statements made above he believes to be true </p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m </hi>B Allen
<lb/>Examiner for Green County</p>
<p><date when="1861-06-13">June 13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861 -- </date></p>
<p>The undersigned concur in the above petition -- </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>C. C. Morgan
<lb/>G. Close
<lb/>Charles Blewing
<lb/>John Bloyd
<lb/>L. B. Stinnett
<lb/>W B wooren
<lb/>W C Thompson
<lb/>T A Lewis
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Barnett
<lb/>Wm S. Peace
<lb/>C. T. Cox
<lb/>S. T. Wilson
<lb/>G T Spillman
<lb/>Ar C Cox..D S.
<lb/>Y O Booker
<lb/>Thos C Edwards <unclear/>
<lb/>Robert Marshall
<lb/>Jno Moore
<lb/>W L Barnett one of jury
<lb/>S. A Spencer
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John D Scott
<lb/>W. N. Vaughan
<lb/>J. C. Edwards
<lb/>Jefferson Henry
<lb/>F L. Sidelbottom
<lb/>James A Frian
<lb/>Joseph H Graham
<lb/>E A Jones
<lb/>W H H Young
<lb/>P C Warren
<lb/>Fields Skaggs Junor
<lb/>Matthew Skaggs
<lb/>E. H. Hobson
<lb/>Henry Coner
<lb/>J Altman
<lb/>J N Reid
<lb/>John C Skaggs
<lb/>H B Skaggs
<lb/>M A Vaughn one of the jury
<lb/>D S. Caiter -- one jury<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> R Barnett
<lb/>F. T Murray</p>
<p>Govn<hi rend="sup">r</hi> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>I regard the foregoing as a meritorious case, and it would be but justice to grant the prayer of the petitioner. The petition was gotten up and signed in a few minutes by persons about the court house -- all the jurors present signed it -- the County Judge, the sheriff the Clerk, several Magistrates and other prominent citizens of our county -- The young man lives in a remote part of the county, any communication sent to him, if addressed to me at this place will be attended to -- </p>
<p>Respectfully &amp;c
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="underline">. B Allen</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
