<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3488"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. W. Muir to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5607</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-420 to BR42-421</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thos E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov. of the Com<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of Kentucky</p>
<p>The Undersigned at the earnest request of the parties interested Respectfully requests the intervention of executive clemency upon the following facts</p>
<p>Jack Barnes in a young man with a family poor and dependent upon his daily labor for sustenance and W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Wood <hi rend="str">as</hi> is a lad about 18 years of age of an honest respectable family </p>
<p>These two young men under the influence of intoxicatin stoned (in day light however) the house of Mrs Marshall in Botland in this county (Nelson) where the said Mrs Marshall keeps a liquor shop under the guise of tavern keeping</p>
<p>For this they were indicted fined one Hundred dollars each &amp; judgment of imprisonment was rendered against each for the span of three months</p>
<p>The verdict of the jury was just &amp; proper under the circumstances. Your applicant defended them &amp; cannot complain of the action of the jury in the premises</p>
<p>But Woods is a boy his parents are poor -- have nothing to spare -- the boy feels the rebuke he has received &amp; is deeply mortified at his conduct_ I believe this was his first act of dissipation &amp; he was led into what he did no doubt by Barnes_ to imprison him would be a mortification to his family &amp; would degrade the boy in his own estimation_ His parents in their poverty have nothing to spare to pay this fine for him &amp; it would have to be paid if coerced by his lying in Jail<pb/>
<lb/>His family and friends and the boy himself earnestly petition his Excellency the Govenor to remit So much of the Judgment as pertains to imprisonment &amp; fine ensuring to the Commonwealth. The Boy with tears in his eyes has promised Me that if he escapes this difficulty (Which is his first) he will never be guilty of another public offense. He evidently is a good boy, will make a good citizen</p>
<p>Barnes has been addicted to dissipation but I am informed by his neighbors he has promised a thorough reformation. He has a wife and perhaps two or three children He does not even own the roof that shelters his family. He has no money no property and if he is imprisoned his family must suffer They depend upon his daily toil for a living His wife has solicited me to make this effort for her husbands relief which I do cheerfully for her. She asks at your hands for her sake and for her little childrens sake that her husbands fine be remitted so far as lies in Executive power &amp; that the judgment for imprisonment be also remitted</p>
<p>For the faithfulness of the narration of the principal facts stated herein I respectfully refer to Judge Hardin <hi rend="str">who</hi> through whom I have the Honor to present this petition</p>
<p>Respectfully J. W. Muir<pb/></p>
<p>Nelson
<lb/>Barnes &amp; Wood
<lb/>Refused</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
