<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0097"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. G. Reasor to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8549</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-150 to R3-151</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency, Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Charles Kremer a citizen of Louisville respectfully represents that on the <date when="1862-08-18">18<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of August 1862</date>, he entered in a recognizance in the City Court of Louisville as security for one Patrick Ryan in the sum of Three Hundred Dollars; the object of the recognizance being to compel said Ryan to keep the peace and be of good behavior for six months. Petitioner says that Ryan broke his bond by having committed an assault on a negro man named James H Lewis; he thereby forefeited the bond. The injury done to Lewis was very inconsiderable, But notwithstanding proceedings are being had in said Court to subject petitioner to a payment of the recognizance. Petitioner states that he entered into the bond, alone from the motives of friendship, he having been a class mate of said Ryan. Petitioner was born and raised in this City, and has always pursued an industrious and peacable lilfe, and is unable to pay<pb/>
<lb/>the bond if it is exacted of him. If the Judgement is enforced against him, he will be compelled to go to the work-house, thereby depriving his family of support; he has a wife and three children. He therefore prays your Excellency to relieve him from paying said bond. He files herewith a copy of the Proceedings of the City Court against him.</p>
<p>On the <date when="1862-10-06">6th of October 1862</date> a Judgment was rendered in the City Court of Louisville, in the case set forth in the foregoing petition. <hi rend="str">Charles</hi> Twenty five dollars has been paid, by defts, Mr Kremer is a young man of family -- poor and industrious, and considering all the circumstances, attending his case, I cordially Join with him in asking for remission of the Judgment. He became involved for a friend, without reward.</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>W, G, Reasor.
<lb/>City Attorney</p>
<p>I concur with Mr Reasor in recommending the remission as to Kremer.</p>
<p>Geo W Johnston J. C C L.</p>
<p>We as officers cordially join in the above petition and in view of all the circustances we pray your Excellency to remit the same</p>
<p>Respectifully yours &amp;c<pb/>
<lb/>W R Hydes Marshall city
<lb/>Phil Tomppert Jr City Clerk</p>
<p>I concur with Judge Johnston, before whom the petitioner entered into the recognizance, in asking that the petition be granted</p>
<p>Nat. Wolfe<pb/></p>
<p>Louisville City Ct</p>
<p>The fine in the Pettn as to Charles Kremer is remitted except the sum of Fifty Dollars which is to be paid &amp; including any payment made <date when="1862-10-09">9" Octo 1862</date></p>
<p>J F Robinson
<lb/>$300 } Forfeiture
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1862-10-10">Octo 10. 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
