<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2669"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Michael Dietz, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7306</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-293 to BR16-294</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-11-13">13 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>City Court of Louisville</p>
<p>Pleas held before the Hon Jas P Harbeson Judge of the City Court of Louisville on the <date when="1865-08-22">22<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> day of August 1865</date></p>
<p>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Michael Dietz</p>
<p>Be it remembered that on this day the Grand Jury of this Court returned into Court the following verdict against the Defendant Michael Dietz, viz</p>
<p>"City Court of Louisville
<lb/>Commonwealth of Kentucky <date when="1865-08">August Term 1865</date>
<lb/>vs } Indictment
<lb/>Michael Dietz</p>
<p>The Jurors of the Grand Jury empannelled and sworn to enquire in and for the body of the City of Louisville in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, upon their oaths <hi rend="str">prescribe</hi>accuse Michael Dietz of the offense of selling intoxicating liquors to James E Sanders, who is a white child under the age of twenty one years, and that said selling was done without the written consent of the Father mother or guardian of said Sanders -- in said City and State on the -- day of <date when="1865-08">august 1865</date> against the Statute in such case made and provided</p>
<p>W. G. Reasor
<lb/>Comths Atty</p>
<p>Witnesses Jas E. Sanders<pb/></p>
<p>And thereafter on the <date when="1865-11-09">9<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of Nov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 1865</date>, said Indictment coming on for trial the Defendant plead not guilty, Whereupon a Jury came, who after hearing the testimony and retiring to consult &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi> returned into the Court the following verdict viz."We of the Jury find the Defendant guilty as charged in the within Indictment and assess his fine at fifty dollars to the Commonwealth of Kentucky and recommend him to Executive clemency" Whereupon it was ordered that said Dietz make his fine to the Commonwealth by the payment of Fifty dollars and all costs that may have accrued herein and that he be taken</p>
<p>A true Copy of the record <hi rend="str">in</hi> <hi rend="str">our</hi>
<lb/>Attest <date when="1865-11-13">Nov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> 13<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date></p>
<p>Phil Tomppert Jr c. c. c. L.
<lb/>by F Wobbe Depy clk</p>
<p>His Excellency,
<lb/>Goven. T E Bramlette</p>
<p>There are many circumstances in this case which prompt me to ask a remission and I dare to hope for it</p>
<p>Your obt Servant
<lb/>Jas P Harbeson
<lb/>city Judge
<lb/>W, G, Reasor
<lb/>Atty<pb/></p>
<p>Please direct to clerk of Louisville City Court</p>
<p>Phil Tompert<pb/></p>
<p>Louisville City Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Transcript
<lb/>Mich<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Dietz
<lb/>$50,
<lb/>Selling liquor to a Minor
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-11-14">14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
