<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2862"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John K. Morris et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7499</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-155 to BR17-156</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Governor of Ky -- </p>
<p>The undersigned your petitioners would respectfully request your Excellency to extend your clemency to a prisoner now in the Penitentiary by the name if John Ferrill We assure your excellency that we are influenced in the application by no motive other than a conviction that this man<hi rend="sup">s</hi> punishment has been fully adequate to his offense. John Ferrill was indicted in Fulton Circuit Court for the Murder of James <hi rend="str">Graham</hi> Campbell by stabbing at the <date when="1858-06">June term 1858</date> and was tried and convicted not of murder but of manslaughter and sentenced to penitentiary for ten years -- He has now served nearly <hi rend="str">six</hi> upwards of Seven years, years of that time, and our information is that his conduct while there has been examplary, submissive to all the requirements of prison rules, and from his letters to his friends we believe he is contrite and if permitted to return to society would make a worthy citizen. To many of us he was personally Known and he has always been reputed an honest man. There was no accusation<pb/>
<lb/>against him affecting his moral character except that he occasionally indulged to excess in the use of ardent spirits, and it was while under this influence in a moment of phrensy of Jealously he committed the deed by killing James Campbell. we beg the favor of your Excellency that you will enquire into the conduct of Ferrill during the long time he has been in the Penitentiary and if the report is as we believe it will be favorable that you will remit to him the residue of the term he has to serve and give him back to community -- There has been no previous application for his discharge and we trust that your Exclelency will look the more favorably upon this because even his friends have not interfered until he has now served an ignominious imprisonment for nearly <hi rend="str">six</hi> Eight years -- </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>John, K. Morris
<lb/>Chas H Harper
<lb/>J S Areys
<lb/>T M Kemp
<lb/>W Lindsay
<lb/><cb n="2"/>
<lb/>E. J. Bullock, <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> would respectfully urge this petition on the Governors attention -- </p>
<p>W, R, Bradley
<lb/>F M Roy.<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>N. L. Nelson
<lb/>J M Bigger
<lb/>G. W. Stubblefield
<lb/>John Smith
<lb/>John. H. Davies
<lb/>R. S. Johnson
<lb/>Q. M. T. Salmon
<lb/>R. M. Metheny
<lb/>Saml. B, Salmon
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> C. Blair
<lb/>H W Samuel
<lb/>D D Davis
<lb/>G B Jordan
<lb/>A, W, Shelton
<lb/>S W Byrd
<lb/>J, H, Fowlkes
<lb/>J D Haslem
<lb/>R A Thompson
<lb/>T. B Davis
<lb/>G W Marshall
<lb/>R. H. Reeves
<lb/>W R Oaks
<lb/>S,, S. Ingram
<lb/>W, H, Galbraith
<lb/>S Bugg
<lb/>D, P, Posson
<lb/>R. H. Emerson
<lb/>John Lewis
<lb/>S W Pennebaker
<lb/><unclear/> A French<pb/></p>
<p>Fulton Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John Ferrill
<lb/>10 years <date when="1858">1858</date>
<lb/>Manslaughter
<lb/>Pardoned
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Ferrill</hi>
<lb/><date when="1865-12-19">19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Dec 1865</date>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Pardon</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
