<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-009-0020"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Charles E. Johnson to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11487</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>45th, 47th, 48th, and 49th Regiments Kentucky Infantry Muster Rolls</collection>
      <idno>Box 41, Bundle 2</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lebanon, Marion County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-05-15">15 May 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Lebanon Marion Co Ky
<lb/><date when="1863-05-15">May 15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>The Governor of the State of Ky, </p>
<p>The undersigned would respectfully represent that on the <date when="1861-10-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of October, 1861</date> he joined at Camp Kenton Mason Co Ky the 16<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Regiment Ky Vol. Infantry Col Charles A. Marshall Since which time he has been serving with Said Regiment except when on detached service, The testimonials of all the Field and Line Officers of the Regiment can be procured certifying that I have always cheerfully and promptly discharged all the duties devolved upon me either in the capacity of a soldier or otherwise, ^,and speaking of my capacity to perform all duties of an officer^ During my connection with the Regt, I have at various times been connected with the Quarter-masters Dept, and with the Head Quarters of Commandants of Brigades in the capacity of Clerk and have thus obtained a tolerable Knowledge of the routine and minutiae of military matters. I am <hi rend="str">an</hi>or was <hi rend="str">a Lawyer</hi> at the breaking<pb/>
<lb/>of this rebellion a practicing Lawyer in Flemingsburg Ky, I am heart &amp; soul in favor of putting the traitors down; and I want to go where I can do most to aid in this much to be desired end, I honestly believe that if I had the proper authority I could recruit One or more companies of men to go to make up the Twenty thousand promised by our noble state. What I desire to Know is what steps to take to procure such authority, and for this reason I have presumed to address you. It is Evident that if I can enlist 100 men for service that I will be doing more good than as a single individual in the ranks. I confess that I have ambition but it is a laudable one that of seeing rebellion crushed and our country at peace once more I am a maternal nephew of your county man Joseph B. Kenney and would refer you to him</p>
<p>Any favor which you may be pleased to do me in this matter will be remembered with gratitude May I hope to hear from you on the subject at an Early day.</p>
<p>Your Obt Svt
<lb/>Charles E Johnson<pb/></p>
<p>Military
<lb/>Chs E. Johnston asks to recruit <unclear/></p>
<p>give him a recruiting commission 45<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Regt. Mounted Rifles and forward commission</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J. W. F</hi><pb/></p>
<p>45<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> <hi rend="underline">mounted Infantry</hi><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Charles E. Johnson. com 2 Lieut. 
<lb/>Lebanon Ky 
<lb/>date <date when="1863-05-26">May 26, 1863</date>
<lb/><note place="left margin">1, 2, 3, 4, 5,</note><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>com iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> &amp; forward <date when="1863-05-26">May 26/63</date>
<lb/>C H<pb/></p>
<p>20.000
<lb/>45: Infy<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Lt.
<lb/>Johnson<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>com iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> &amp; forwarded 
<lb/><date when="1863-05-26">May 26, 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
