<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2084"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">A. H. Nolen to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9160</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-135 to MG24-136</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Harlan County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-08-10">10 August 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Harlan C. H. Ky
<lb/><date when="1862-08-10">10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Aug 1862</date>
<lb/>Beriah Magoffin Gov,</p>
<p>Dear Sir not long since I informed you of the facts of a Judgment being rendered against Henderson Hallcum Sr and Hendersen Hallcum Jr ^for $500.^ at the <date when="1862-07">July Special Term of our Circuit Court 1862,</date> I also stated in that letter the circumstances, of the case as they exist. But for fear that information has not reached you, which is very probable on account of the irregularity of our Mails I again respectfully reitterate the same to Your Excellency. "In the winter of <date when="1861">1861.</date> Oliver Hallcum A son of Henderson Hallcum Sr and brother to Henderson Hallcum Jr was tried by an Examining Court upon a charge of Larceny and held for trial in the Harlan Circuit Court, and admitted to bail for his appearance in said Court at its <date when="1861-04">April Term 1861</date> in the sum of $500, whereupon he executed the bond with Henderson Hallcum Sr and Henderson Hallcum Jr his surities for his appearance aforesaid.</p>
<p>But before Court came on the said Oliver Hallcum Joined the confederate army under Hemphry Marshall and did not appear and at the <date when="1861-04">April Term of Said court 1861.</date> Said bond was forfeited and a Summons orders against his surities to Show Cause why<pb/>
<lb/>Judgment should not be rendered against them for five hundred dollars on account of the forfeiture of said bond, The summons was issued &amp; served upon them and at the <date when="1862-07">July special Term of the Harlan Circuit Court 1862</date> Judment was rendered accordingly.</p>
<p>Now I would humbly state to your Excellency that the said Henderson Hallcum Sr and Henderson Hallcum Jr are both very poor men. And if the Judgment should be collected of them it would entirely break them up and take all their effects both real &amp; personal. And further the said Hallcums say that it is impossible for Oliver to come as if he was to be would be arrested by the Military Authority. but that if times ever get so he can that he will come &amp; stand his trial that the charges against him and entirely groundless. I am aware that your Excellency is for strict Justice being done in the previous. But I cannot think that one occupying the high station of the Executive chair of Ky. would take pleasure in exacting an amount from Kentucky citizens that would entirely own them, As the old man has a large family besides he is very old &amp; feeble and can scarcely support them by all his industry and with what means he has, I hope Your Excellency will interpose with your Executive clemency,, And bring down upon yourself the benedictions of a family saved from ruin<pb/>
<lb/>I believe such a course was be approved by the stern Justice of heaven,</p>
<p>I know that you are aware that in such times as these it is impossible for a poor man to raise money enough to pay $500. without sacrificing his all. If you should think proper to remit the Judgment. I hope you will do it immediately before property is subjected to Execution, And send the same to Me at this place,</p>
<p>I am with considerations of the highest regard Your Humble servant
<lb/>A. H. Nolen<pb/></p>
<p>Harlan Cir. Ct
<lb/>$500. } For Recog
<lb/>Henderson Hallcum
<lb/>Henderson Hallcum
<lb/>Remission Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-08-16">Aug 16 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
