<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1421"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George W. Gilbert to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10889</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-382</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Beriah Magoffin Governor
<lb/>of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner George Gilbert would represent that he has been endicted in the Pike circuit Court for selling liquor to a miner. He states that he did sell some Liquor to a Gentleman and that a miner was in company with him and that the minor paid for the Same the adult not being able to pay for the same or not having change handy to pay for the same, He says he never has nor never did sell spiritous Liquors to a miner since the law was passed against the same; He further says that the miner or suposed miner is the Son of a widow and is a Sober discreet boy; and has been acting as an adult, and was so treated by the neighborhood as an adult nor was it Known to your petitioner at the time of the sale that he was a minor Wherefore your Petitioner Prays for a remission of sd fine and for all Proper rilief</p>
<p>Geo. W. Gilbert<pb/></p>
<p>John M. Elliott &amp; John M. Burns say that they know most of the facts stated in the written petition are true and join in the prayer for the remission of the fine</p>
<p>John M Burns
<lb/>John. M. Elliott</p>
<p>They further state that Mr. Gilbert <unclear/> is a orderly good citizen and a Hotel Keeper has never before been accused of a violation of his duties as such</p>
<p>Elliott &amp; Burns</p>
<p>Pike Co Cir. Ct
<lb/>Geo W. Gilbert
<lb/>To } Petitions
<lb/>The Governo<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><unclear/>
<lb/>$40 } Selling liquor to a minor
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi>. <date when="1861-09-14">Sept 14. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
