<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3502"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">C. B. Butner et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5621</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-439 to BR42-440</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Washington County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Martin Sally
<lb/>pryor Sallee
<lb/>James Warner</p>
<p>To his Excellency, Thomas E. Bramlett Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned Citizens of Washington County Kentucky would most respectfully represent to your Excellency That about the <date when="1859-07-21">twenty first day of July 1859</date> <gap/> Granville Sea was killed on the public highway at a public speaking</p>
<p>J. L. Davenport was indicted at the <date when="1859-11-16">november ^Term^ the 16, 1859</date> of the Washington Circuit Court for said killing the said <hi rend="str">E</hi> J L Davenport war indicted in the name of <hi rend="str">Joseph Davenport</hi> Joseph Davenport and Thomas Conder was indicted at the saime time Charged with Killing the said Granville Sea and J. L. Davenport who is indicted in the name of Joseph Davenport is a son of John Davenport an old and worthy Citizen of Mercer County</p>
<p>When the late rebellion broke out he had two sons ^in the Federal army^ including J L or Joseph Davenport<pb/>
<lb/>volunteered in the 86 Ill one son belonged to the 4 Kentucky infantry Capt <hi rend="str">G</hi> Milton Graham Company and served his time out in Capt Jinkens Company M and was honorably discharged at the end of three years </p>
<p>The second and last son that volienteered was J. L. Davenport or Joseph Davenport who entered the service as a private in Company (A) ^in^ <date when="1862">1862</date> capt Jo Major of 86 Ill Ridgement where he served untill the end of the war and was then honorably discharged</p>
<p>The killing was in a large crowd of Men and no one knows who did it from seeing it doned the proof against Thomas Conder for the same offence is wholly circumstantial and those circumstances <hi rend="str">stron</hi> strongly show that Granville Sea was the attacking party and after a most lengthy investigation before the Jury<pb/>
<lb/>in the case against Thomas Conder Charged of the said killing the Jury agreed to a verdict of not guilty</p>
<p>all the comrads of J L or Joseph Davenport in the army unite in saying that he was a most gallant solder always at his post and never disobeying orders or violating any of the armey regulations Besides that has behavioer was as orderly and good as as any man in the command </p>
<p>He is not a blood thirsty person or one who would wantonly take the life of another He is quite young <hi rend="str">an</hi> man and <unclear/> his <hi rend="str">de</hi> deportment before the war was good sence his return it has been most Exemplary he was not arrested under said indictement before he entered the service and upon his being mustered out returned to his fathers house and was arrested he did not try to avoid an arrest after his return nor before <pb/>
<lb/>He was arrested <date when="1865-10">October 1865</date> and Executed his bond to the commonwealth <date when="1865-10-13">October the 13 1865</date> and at the <date when="1866-04">Aprl Term 1866</date> and at the <date when="1866-10">October Term 1866</date> he was reder for trial and the trial has bin postpond by the Commonwealth and from the testimony in the trial against Thomas Conder charge of Killing the said Sea and from the character of the case it is most probabl that a verdict either way can never be obtained as he was in the Federal army</p>
<p>Now in view of the facts we ask his pardon</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>C, B, Butner
<lb/>William.B. Foster
<lb/>William E. Riley
<lb/>David Foster
<lb/>Cashes Hellard
<lb/>Jacob Isham
<lb/>H. C Isham
<lb/>Andrew Divine
<lb/>James Ruby
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Vandever
<lb/>Isack Huffman
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> S Taylor
<lb/>Joseph Yeast
<lb/>David Sanders
<lb/>James Huffman
<lb/>Jery Divine
<lb/>Martin <unclear/>
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Nathan Lawson
<lb/>Shelby Moore
<lb/>S Wickersham
<lb/>John Sullee
<lb/>John Elkins
<lb/>S P Debaum
<lb/>Thomas Adkison
<lb/>Robert Curry
<lb/>T J Debaum
<lb/>James M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Afee
<lb/>W. A. Burriss
<lb/>J. W. Gates
<lb/>Elias Walton
<lb/>Nathan Lawson Jr
<lb/>Jas Yeats
<lb/>M H Gabherd
<lb/>George hellard<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Thomas Darlanot
<lb/>W M Wickersham
<lb/>William Hoffman
<lb/>Soloman <unclear/>
<lb/>J. W. Eastin
<lb/>Daniel Easau
<lb/>Henry Warner
<lb/>H. S. Riley
<lb/>A J Sims
<lb/>John Carter
<lb/>William Kandles
<lb/>John Wickerson
<lb/>Robert F Smithey
<lb/>Jno M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cray
<lb/>John Corne
<lb/>James M. Reed
<lb/>James M. Sims
<lb/>John.W. Christison
<lb/>John Thompson
<lb/>Stephen Anderson
<lb/>A G Dernpent
<lb/>W. J Sims
<lb/>A M <unclear/>
<lb/>William Coslow
<lb/>R M Cury
<lb/>A J vetch
<lb/>William Moore
<lb/>D Sidney Hendren
<lb/>John Lambert
<lb/>W. L. Perkins
<lb/>G. W. Lambert
<lb/>Nimrod Hendern
<lb/>S. G. Foster
<lb/>Samuel Lambert
<lb/>William foster
<lb/><cb n="2"/>G. W. Foster
<lb/>Reuben Foster
<lb/>A. J. Heren
<lb/>James W. Colvin
<lb/>Marion Lacy
<lb/>Robert A Reed
<lb/>Marion C. Brillan
<lb/>R. B. Parker M. Gen
<lb/>Soloman Corn
<lb/>S. B. Henren
<lb/>Daniel Sanders
<lb/>John S Sanders
<lb/>Joseph Cunningham
<lb/>William H Craig
<lb/>N. H. Edwards
<lb/>J M Johnson
<lb/>John D. Alfred
<lb/>H. L. Cunninghim
<lb/>Henry Hicks
<lb/>William O Corn
<lb/>Elijah L Reed
<lb/>San Corne
<lb/>W G Ranch
<lb/>William H Potter
<lb/>Benjamin Burton
<lb/>Wm Vanfleet
<lb/><unclear/> Bell
<lb/>P W D James
<lb/>Phil. B Thompson
<lb/>W. A. Hooe, of Munroe County
<lb/>Jno. B. T. Daviess<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Washington Cr C
<lb/>vs
<lb/>J. L. Davenport</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
