<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0785"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Q. Long et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10253</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-221 to MG19-222</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency B Magoffin Govenor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Citizens of Christian County would respectfully represent to your excellency that at the <date when="--03">present March term</date> of the Christian Circuit Court Johnathan Greer was tried on an indictment against him for murder that the Jury acquitted him for murder but found him guilty of manslaughter and fixed his punishment by confinement in the Penetentiary for a period of five years</p>
<p>Now your petitioners will state that said Greer an old man being about sixty years of age having a large family of children that he was involved in the fight or affray in which Addison Ferrell (for killing of whom he was tried) was killed that the proof on the trial established the fact that Stephen Shelton who was also killed in the same affray by Abner Greer a son of said Johnathan Greer and said Abner who was very dangerously wounded by Shelton were engaged fireing with pistols at each other that they both felt that Ferrell after they fell was in pursuit of William Greer who was unarmed &amp; firing at said William (who was also a son of Johnathan Greer) that Johnathan Greer the father having his rifle gun in his hands and being himself severely wounded by a pistol shot his Son Abner Shot down and Ferrell pursuing &amp; firing at his Son William who was unarmed &amp; retreating fired upon said Ferrell and killed him which ended the affray Now your petitioners taking into consideration all the circumstances in the case the relation of father &amp; child that existed between Johnathan Greer &amp; his sons Abner &amp; William and fully appreciating the parental feelings of said Johnathan Greer at the time of the killing cannot but think that it is a case addressing itself with peculiar force and favor to the consideration of your Excellency and we the more readily urge his cause before your Excellency for the reason that Johnathan Greer has lived in our midst from early youth to old age and has ever bourne the character of a peaceable quiet sober and industrious citizen a good neighour a<pb/>
<lb/>firm friend and a kind and affectionate husband &amp; father</p>
<p>Taking all things into consideration we respectfully present his case to the favourable consideration of your excellency and earnestly ask for him a full &amp; free pardon believing as we do that such a act of clemency would meet with the hearty approval of an overwhelming majority of the best citizens of the Country.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>John. Q. Long
<lb/>R W Fields
<lb/>J T M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cullough
<lb/>W. G. Jonson
<lb/>John Llauley
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/> Boyd
<lb/>M. Mare
<lb/>W. J. Witty
<lb/>Martin henslaw
<lb/>Jacob Emsliency
<lb/>Siegmund Traube
<lb/>W. H. Troxel
<lb/>W. T. Walker
<lb/>D O Tribble
<lb/>C. A M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cullaugh
<lb/>John W Campbell
<lb/>A B Murphy
<lb/>T Rooy
<lb/>Q. M. Spurgin
<lb/>J. C. Troxcel
<lb/>J P Boyd
<lb/>Joh n Elliott
<lb/>A. F. Long
<lb/>Henry Johnson
<lb/>S Morgan
<lb/>James.A. Chernelious
<lb/><hi rend="str">R G Kind</hi>
<lb/><cb n="2"/>William Carol
<lb/>George N. Covington
<lb/>L B Steele
<lb/>G W Brene
<lb/>G P Daniel Jr
<lb/>H. S. Quisenbery
<lb/>Q. Q. Quisenbery
<lb/>F. W. Owen
<lb/>L. H. Payne
<lb/>William R. Payne
<lb/>S. T. Payne
<lb/>John W. Marquess
<lb/>F. C Grisham
<lb/>Saml Gresham
<lb/>W. H. Foster
<lb/>B. C. Foster
<lb/>Q. W. Marques,, Senr-
<lb/>John B Smoot
<lb/>J. C. Matsel
<lb/>Robert Marquess
<lb/>T J. Johnson
<lb/>T. A.. Poindexter
<lb/>B M C King
<lb/>H. H. Marquess
<lb/>L. A. Boyd
<lb/>Irvin Boyd
<lb/>W. R. Payne
<lb/>J. L. Payne<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>P. H. Gander
<lb/>H Frickie
<lb/>W H Parrish
<lb/>Lee H. West
<lb/>M. W. West
<lb/>E. C Cravens
<lb/>R H Cravens
<lb/>J D Cravens
<lb/>W. Cravens
<lb/>Y G Cravens
<lb/>Abe Cravens
<lb/>John Cravens
<lb/>G C Cravens
<lb/>Abe Cravens
<lb/>L. G Cravens
<lb/>J A Clay
<lb/>J J Foard
<lb/>B Blavanagh
<lb/>William B Turner
<lb/>N. B. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Carrier
<lb/>Y. J. Steward
<lb/>John Mcguire
<lb/>W. H. Hukmar
<lb/>S. E. Means
<lb/>G. T. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>pherson
<lb/>John D. Cloody
<lb/>James. Stone
<lb/>T. Y. brown
<lb/>Thomas Kernrey
<lb/>J. W. Wilsons
<lb/>George Mccombs
<lb/>E. P. Murphy
<lb/>Micheal Shea
<lb/>G. W. Wills
<lb/>W L Taylor
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John.B. White
<lb/>C. H. Botsford
<lb/>John..H.. Foard
<lb/>O. Doson
<lb/>F E Robertson
<lb/>P. B.. White
<lb/>Goerge Wills
<lb/>John..R.. Fleming
<lb/>H. E. Bacon
<lb/>L. M. thomas
<lb/>J. N. Metcalf
<lb/>G S Bacon
<lb/>W L Bacon
<lb/>J. C. Metcalf
<lb/>J. T. Taylor
<lb/>W. F. morris
<lb/>Jno J. Thomas
<lb/>Darwin Bell
<lb/>A. J. Montgomery
<lb/>B. D. Moose
<lb/>Jno. Q. Thomas
<lb/>R. B. Cary
<lb/>D W Quarles
<lb/>A.. C.. Jones
<lb/>M. N. Hartman
<lb/>A. G. Fraser
<lb/>T B Seargeant
<lb/>J. J. Robinson
<lb/>J Giles
<lb/>P Giles
<lb/>John Giles</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
