<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0830"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">F. M. McFall et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4949</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-280 to BR10-281</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Franklin, Williamson County, Tennessee</placeName>
    <date when="1864-05-21">21 May 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Franklin, Tenn.
<lb/><date when="1864-05-21">May 21<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1864</date>.
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>The Governor of the
<lb/>State of Kentucky,
<lb/>Sir-</p>
<p>The undersigned petitioners would most resepectfully represent unto your Excellency that some time during the <date when="1863">fall of 1863</date>, one James J. Rariden, an enlisted man in the 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Regiment of Tennessee V. Cavalry, and formerly a citizen of the state of Indiana, was indicted in the Circuit Court of Knox county, Kentucky, on a charge of having taken, by force, from a citizen of said county, Spiritous Liquor.</p>
<p>The facts in the case as we are informed and believe are as follows. Said James J. Rariden was in charge of a Wagon train going from Cumberland Gap to a point North of Barboursville to meet and lighten a train going to Cumberland Gap. The teamsters had driven all night thro' a cold rain, and on the morning of the following day stopped their teams and refused to go any further until they got "something to drink," being cold, wet and fatigued. Said Rariden went to a house near by and offered to buy the liquor, but the lady of the house refused to sell it to him, whereupon, to use<pb/>
<lb/>an army phrase, he "pressed "it." offering at the sametime to pay for it. which was refused. The Circuit Court of Knox county being in Session at the time, the case was immediately brought before the court, tried and Judgment rendered.</p>
<p>James J. Rariden is a good Soldier, and has been in the service eversince the commencement of the war. He at first enlisted in an Indiana regiment, and served a long time under Genl Lew. Wallace, being at one time his orderly, as we are informed and believe, He is also a nephew of Genl. wallace.</p>
<p>Your petitioners would further represent that in their opinion, the said Rariden is an <hi rend="underline">honest</hi> man. That the crime with which he is charged, <hi rend="str">is</hi> was only an impropriety at most, in the commission of which he was actuated by no other motive than that of serving the best interests of his county.</p>
<p>The premises considered, your petitioners pray that said James J. Rariden be released from prison and permitted to return to his command.</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>Your ob't Serv'ts
<lb/>F. M. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Fall, Capt. Co. A. 8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Tenn. V. C.
<lb/>C C Kinner Capt Co G 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Tenn Cav
<lb/>John C Moreland Lt. Co. G.
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> E Cunningham 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Lt Co G
<lb/>T A Brams Com 2 Liut Co F
<lb/>D. W. Brady Surg. 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> T. Cav.<pb/>
<lb/>John C. Bible 2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> Lieut Co. "A" 8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Tenn. Cav.
<lb/>James H. Miller 1st Liut Co "A"
<lb/><hi rend="str">James</hi> Jacob M Hendrickson 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Lt Co K
<lb/>W. W. Willis May 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ten Cav
<lb/>John R. Shults 2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> Liut C<hi rend="sup">o</hi> "K" Tenn Cav<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="3"/><cb n="1"/>HdQrs. 8" Tenn. Cav.
<lb/>&amp; Port Comds.
<lb/>Franklin, Tenn.
<lb/><date when="1864-05-21">May. 21" 64</date>.<figure type="hr"/>Petitioners 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Tenn. Cav. request that James J. Rariden an enlisted man in the 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Tenn. V. Cav. be released from the State Prison of Ky. and permitted to return to his command.<figure type="hr"/>Respectfully forwarded and Recommended</p>
<p>J. M. Sawyers Maj.
<lb/>8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Tenn. Cav. Comdg.
<lb/>Post.
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Executive office
<lb/>Nashville, Tenn.
<lb/><date when="1864-05-23">May 23" 1864</date>
<lb/>Respectfully forwarded.</p>
<p>The officers whose names are attached to this petition in behalf of J. J. Rariden, are perfectly reliable, and would make no statement They did not believe to be true. If, upon examination of this case, the record <unclear/> them out in the statement herein made, I would respectfully suggest that it might be a case wherein Executive clemency could be properly exercised</p>
<p>Andrew Johnson
<lb/>Mil. Gov'r.
<lb/><cb n="3"/>Knox Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Jas J. Rariden</p>
<p>Pardon
<lb/>granted
<lb/><date when="1864-07-11">11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> July/6<hi rend="underline">4</hi></date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
