<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0433"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John E. Reno to Edward R. Weir</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4552</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-181 to BR9-182</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Greenville, Muhlenberg County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-01-20">20 January 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Greenville Ky <date when="1864-01-20">Jany 20 1864</date>
<lb/>Edward R Weir Eqr
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>Enclosed I hand you a copy of Judgement Comw<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">h</hi></hi> by Saml Brown &amp; myself in forfeited Bond the case came up in my absence and the charge on the Petition shows that the money was dept with me which is not true my answer was prepared by some lawyer but was not sworn to on account of my absince I knowing nothing of the case at the time I dislike to trouble you or Gov Bramlette with the matter but I do not think I ought to pay it. The s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Brown who was under arrest is now in the county and has been about here for some 18 Mo<hi rend="sup">s</hi> The troubles of our country was upon us and I give but little or no attention to this matter.</p>
<p>Will you be so kind as to See Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi><pb/>
<lb/>Bramlett as him to pardon me on this matter and remit this fine I am willing at all times to do right but I must insist that to pay this debt would under all the circumstances be wrong Will you give this your attention and oblige</p>
<p>Your Friend
<lb/>Jno E Reno</p>
<p>The Jugt Shows the answers in &amp; withdrawn by deft, Which Seams an <hi rend="str">verdict</hi> admition Ch<hi rend="sup">d</hi> in Pet. that the money was left with Edm<hi rend="sup">d</hi> to Satisfy bond. I remember Eaves who had told Edm<hi rend="sup">d</hi> the bond was not good before Signing it Missled him &amp; he even did not, pay any Attention to the Summons &amp; he not being in Court, the Ans. as it purported to be but was not read Signed or Sworn to, the jugt Shows was withdrawn, but in fact it was no answer at all. And the charge in Petition is positive it was a great neglect by Ed. but he was missled by Eaves.</p>
<p>J H R<pb/></p>
<p>Frankfort Ky <date when="1864-02">Feby 1864</date>-
<lb/>Gov T E Bramlette</p>
<p>The within named J E Reno is one of our best citizens -- a true man, &amp; every statement made by him may be relied on as true. I hope the Governor will remit that portion of the judgement which is due the Commonwealth.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Edward R Weir.</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
