<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0373"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky vs. Milton Purdy, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8825</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-104 to R4-105</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Muhlenberg County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-12-08">8 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Muhlenberg Circuit Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against } Indictment for Murder.
<lb/>Milton Purdy</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Muhlenberg County in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky accuse Milton Purdy of the crime of Murder Committed as follows viz: The said Milton Purdy on the <date when="1863-03-23">23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> day of March 1863</date>, in the County of Muhlenberg state of Kentucky -- did with malice afore thought feloniously kill and murder one Webster Stewart, by shooting him with a Pistol laden with a leaden bullet or other hard substance inflicting a wound from which the said Stewart died shortly thereafter, against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>William Bell
<lb/>Foreman Grand Jury.
<lb/>J. H. Lowry Attorney for the Commonwealth, Protem</p>
<p>Information given by D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> A. M. Jackson.
<lb/>Green Martin
<lb/>Peter Rothrock.
<lb/>Sam<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Henry.</p>
<p>Bench warrant to issue &amp; bail to be fixed if at all hereafter.</p>
<p>R. T. Petree
<lb/>Cir Judge
<lb/>Muhlenberg Circuit Court
<lb/><date when="1863-05-15">May term May 15th 1863</date>.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against
<lb/>Milton Purdy, J. T. Shrewsbury, John Clark, C. B. Wickliffe, J. F. Jones, H. D. Rothrock, R. P. Kincheloe S W Kincheloe, J. R. Nicholls, Somanuel Lockery } On forfeited Recognizance Bond.</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Filed in open court <date when="1863-05-15">May 15th 1863</date>,
<lb/>Att J, H, Reno clk</note><pb/></p>
<p>Milton Purdy being in custody charged with the offense of shooting &amp; wounding in sudden heat &amp; passion &amp; intent to kill and being admitted to bail in the sum of four hundred dollars Now we <hi rend="underline">William</hi> Purdy <gap/> hereby undertake that the above named Purdy will appear in the Muhlenberg Circuit Court on the first day of its next <date when="--05">May</date> term to answer said charge, and will at all times render himself amenable to the orders and process of said Court in the prosecution of said charge; and if convicted will render himself in execution thereof, or, if he shall fail to perform either of these conditions, that we will pay to the Commonwealth of Kentucky the sum of four hundred dollars -- </p>
<p>Witness our hands this <date when="1863-03-30">30th day of March 1863</date>
<lb/>Test
<lb/>B. J. Shaver P. J.</p>
<p>Milton Purdy
<lb/>H. D. Rothrock
<lb/>J T Shrewsbury
<lb/>R. P. Kincheloe
<lb/>John Clark
<lb/>L. W. Kincheloe
<lb/>C. B. Wickliffe
<lb/>J. R. Nicholls
<lb/>J. F. Jones
<lb/>Somanuel Lockry<pb/></p>
<p>on motion of the attorney for the Commonwealth the bond of Milton Purdy &amp; others is hereby forfeited and a summons is awarded the Cometh against said defendants returnable to the next term of the Court against them to show cause if they can why judgment shall not be rendered against them for four hundred dollars the amount of their forfeited bond -- </p>
<p>summons issued thereon &amp; was returned by the sheriff of Muhlenberg County Kentucky executed on John Clark H. D. Rothrock Jno R Nicholls on <date when="1863-09-21">21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Sept 1863</date>, on J. F. Jones <date when="1863-09-28">28th Sept 1863</date>. &amp; on L. W. Kincheloe on the <date when="1863-10-14">14th of Octr 1863</date>, and the other parties not found.</p>
<p>Muhlenberg Circuit Court sct
<lb/><date when="1863-11-09">Nov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> term Nov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> 9th 1863</date>.</p>
<p>The Comth of Kentucky
<lb/>against } Summons on Forfeited Recognizance.
<lb/>Milton Purdy &amp; others</p>
<p>The defendants John Clark, H. D Rothrock, John R. Nicholls, J. F. Jones, &amp; L. W. Kincheloe having been duly summoned and failing to answer It is adjudged by the court that the Commonwealth recover of said defendants the sum of four hundred dollars that being the amount of their forefeited bail bond for the appearance of Milton Prudy in this court at the last <date when="--05">May</date> term thereof, &amp; that said defts pay the costs of this summons -- And on motion of the atty for the Comlth this cause is continued as to the defendants J. T. Shrewsbury R. P. Kincheloe C. B. Wickliffe &amp; Somanuel Lockery.<pb/></p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Muhlenberg Circuit } Sct.</p>
<p>I J. H. Reno Clerk of the Muhlenberg Circuit Court do certify that the foregoing is a true copy of the bond Indictment order forfeiting bail bond and judgment in the case of the Comlth agst Milton Purdy &amp;c in the Muhlenberg Circuit Court -- </p>
<p>Witness my hand as Clerk of said Court, this <date when="1863-12-08">8th day of December 1863</date>.</p>
<p>J, H. Reno Clk
<lb/>for Tho J. Jones D, C,</p>
<p>Comth of Ky
<lb/>vs } Copy of Indictmt judgt &amp;c
<lb/>Milton Purdy &amp; oths</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
