<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0068"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Julia Dean to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8520</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-110 to R3-111</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-09-12">12 September 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>The Governor of Kentucky:</p>
<p>Your petitioner, Julia Dean, humbly prays your Excellency's Clemency. She fears that when apprised of her situation in life, you may be disposed to turn towards her a deaf ear, yet, on the Mother's appeal to the Executive of the Commonwealth, a reference to the conduct and services of her sons in support of the Government, may not be disregarded, but serve as a <hi rend="str">favorable</hi> reason for a favorable Consideration of her prayer. Your petitioner has three sons, all of whom have been, &amp; two of them now are in the Military service of the U. S. Government.</p>
<p>The first, Sam<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Rasure, in the 19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> year of his age, belongs to the 21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Indiana Regiment, which he joined at Indianapolis a year ago last June; he was in the fight at Baton Rouge, also at the taking of New Orleans, where your petitioner believes he now is, and he is still in the U. S. service.</p>
<p>The second, David Rasure, in the 17<hi rend="sup">th</hi> year of his age, was in the 3 month's service in Virginia; &amp;, afterwards, at Indianapolis, in <date when="1861-06">June, 1861</date>, joined Capt Rabb's battery, with which he still remains as first gunner; and, during the time he has been engaged in the difficulties in Kansas &amp; Missouri.</p>
<p>Her other son, Geo W. Rasure, in the 16<hi rend="sup">th</hi> year of his age, was for two months a member of the 4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Kentucky Cavalry, but, being young &amp; too delicate to undergo the hardships of the service, was honorably discharged.</p>
<p>Your petitioner states that her conduct, in an unguarded moment, as is too often the case,<pb/>
<lb/>has brought her to lead the life she does -- yet it is uncessary to refer to the past -- she admits that her manner of life is punishable by law; her steps she can't retrace, and, though she is fallen, she keeps as well regulated a house, as any of the kind in the City.</p>
<p>She states that in consequence of an inmate of a house in her neighborhood becoming affected with liquor and boisterous in the streets, attention was called to that house, &amp; the keeper of it being indicted for keeping a house of prostitution, was fined. This led to your petitioner being also indicted for the like offense, for which, on the <date when="1862-09-03">3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> Sept, 1862</date>, she was fined, in the City Court of Louisville, the sum of $100; this fine, your petitioner, being poor, is unable to pay, and, in default, of payment, she, as your Excellency is aware, is liable to be sent to the city workhouse. She therefore humbly prays your Excellency to remit to her the Commonwealth's portion of said fine which will still leave her 30 per cent of the fine to pay to the prosecuting attorney, besides the Costs in the case, amounting, in all, to $44.<hi rend="sup">15</hi>/<hi rend="sub">100</hi>.</p>
<p>Though your petitioner can urge little in her behalf, still she hopes that the Mother will not have to be sent to the workhouse, for a debt to the Commonwealth, while her sons are in the Military service of the Government.</p>
<p>Julia Dean</p>
<p><hi rend="str">In testmo</hi> I certify that Julia Dean this day came in my Office and made oath, to the truth of the foregoing Statements</p>
<p>Phil. Tomppert Jr C. C. C. L
<lb/>for T. Wobbe -- D. C</p>
<p>Statements
<lb/><date when="1863-09-12">September the 12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1863</date><pb/></p>
<p>The undersigned In consideration of the reasons urged in the Petition Join in asking a remission of the fine therein mentioned</p>
<p>Caspar Raedhuar.
<lb/>John Hall.
<lb/>L Aronon
<lb/>W A Hall
<lb/>H C Russell Drn C C
<lb/>A Hemann</p>
<p>We are policemen in the upper part of the City where Julia Dean resides &amp; certify to the truth of the statements as to her keeping an orderly house for a house of prostitution.</p>
<p>There are few respectable residents in her neighborhood, &amp; the respectable ones have above signed her petition. We are also cognisant of the fact of her sons being in the Military Service of the U. S as she has stated, &amp; in view of all the circumstances we respectfully recommend that her fine be remitted.</p>
<p>Jesse F. Hammon
<lb/>W. E. Curry</p>
<p>Messers Hammond &amp; Curry who have signed the above are policemen in the ward in which Petitioner resides. The Gentlemen who have signed the Mem<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi> above are citizens of Louisville one of them is Deputy Marshall of the City</p>
<p>Geo W. Johnson J C C L
<lb/>W. G. Reasor City Atto<pb/></p>
<p>Louisville City Court
<lb/>Julia Dean's Petition
<lb/>$100 } Disorderly House</p>
<p>Pettn granted fine remitted <date when="1862-10-17">17 Octo 1862</date></p>
<p>J F Robinson</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1862-10-31">Octo 31. 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
