<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0877"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Edwin S. Graham to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4996</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-347 to BR10-347A</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-04-02">2 April 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His excellency Thos E Bramlette
<lb/>Govr of the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Edwin S Grayham of Meade County would most respectfully state to your Excellency that at the present term of the Meade Circuit Court the Grand Jury empanneled and sworn returned an<hi rend="str">d</hi> Indictment against him, on a charge of Keeping a tipling house. Your petitioner would state that for years past, he has been engaged in the business of selling day goods groceries &amp;c and keeping on hand a stack of whiskey which he was in the habit of selling by the barrel only and never selling in any other way nor permitting it to be drank in the store house or on the premises with his consent or knowledge. He would further state that soon after the appointment of a deputy U States Assessor for the county he took out and paid for a <hi rend="str">whole</hi> license as a whole sale dealer in whiskey &amp;c This he verily beleived at the time and so beleived untill the finding of the afs<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> indictment confered on him the right to sell and trade in the article as he chose without processing the usual license for so doing He declares most honestly and sincerely he did not know he was committing a violation of any law by selling a less quantity than by the barrel In view of the foregoing plain statement of facts he respectfully asks your Excellency to remit the penalty or fine.</p>
<p>E S. Graham</p>
<p>Ed S Grayham says the statements on the above petition are true</p>
<p>E S Graham</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by E S Grayham this <date when="1864-04-02">2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> day of April 1864</date></p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Alexander P J M C<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Meade County <unclear/> <unclear/> the above petition of E S Grayham and from our knowledge of <hi rend="str">him</hi> his honesty and integrity believe the statements in the said petition and that he would not willfully violate any known law he would further state that he is one of our best and most usefull citizens We would therefore most earnestly ask your Excellency to grant the prayer of said petitioner.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Wm Alexander Presiding Judge of Meade County.
<lb/>C. C. Fairleigh D. C. Meade Circuit Court
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Jn</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi><hi rend="underline">. C. Walker</hi></p>
<p>Mr Graham has strictly complied with all the requisitions of the Excise tax law, and I have full<hi rend="str">y</hi> confidence in his statements made above; I cheerfully join in the petition made by him.</p>
<p>Edgar Needham
<lb/>Asst Int. Revenue
<lb/>3d Dt. Ky
<lb/>Louisville <date when="1864-05-10">May 10, 1864</date>
<lb/><cb n="2"/>I am personally acquainted with E S Graham &amp; have been for some years &amp; from my knowledge of him I dont believe he has knowing violated the law in reference to the mattter for which the indcitment is found &amp; cheerfully unit in the Petition to have the penalty remitted</p>
<p>W. T. Coale</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
