<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0937"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James R. Dupuy to Joseph Holt</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5056</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-441 to BR10-442</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-07-19">19 July 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville Ky.
<lb/><date when="1864-07-19">July 19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Hon Joseph Holt
<lb/>Judge Advocate Gen'l
<lb/>Dear Sir,</p>
<p>Your communication of the <date when="1864-07-13">13<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi></date> instant has just reached me.</p>
<p>At our <date when="--05">last May term</date> of court one William Buffum claiming to be a Captain in the U.S. Army was convicted of Robbery; The Captain in company with two other soldiers (privates) entered the little Shoe Shop of a humble German of this City and demanded to look at his stock of boots. Each man took a pair. The Captain tried his on, &amp; the party were about leaving the shop, when the Shopman asked for his pay. Upon which one of the Soldiers drew a pistol (it was the <hi rend="underline">Captain</hi>) and presented it at the body of the shopman, having a moment before this, drawn his sword from the scabbard and placed it upon the counter. As the soldiers entered the Shop, Capt. Buffum told them "here was a shoe store &amp; to come in" he<pb/>
<lb/>Buffum leading the way. After the presentation of the pistol &amp; the exhibition of the sword, the German and Wife &amp; daughter (13 years of age) fled in alarm from the room, the three robbers marching off rapidly, with a pair of boots each under his arm.</p>
<p>The facts were proven by the German &amp; Wife &amp; daughter as they occurred <hi rend="underline">inside</hi> the Shop. The entrance &amp; <hi rend="underline">exit</hi>, were proven by <hi rend="underline">several</hi> neighbors &amp; Buffum was arrested with the identical Boots on his feet.</p>
<p>Buffum plead <hi rend="underline">mental derangement</hi>. His confederates have never been taken. There is another indictment pending in our Court against this same Buffum, charging him with the larceny of a <hi rend="underline">Pistol</hi> about two years ago. Buffum is a consumate scoundrel.</p>
<p>There were <hi rend="underline">no</hi> circumstances of mitigation in his case</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>(signed) J. R. Dupuy
<lb/>Com. Atty.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
