<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1187"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Edward P. Campbell to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10655</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-18 to MG21-19</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Princeton, Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-18">18 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>E. P. Campbell,
<lb/>ATTORNEY AT LAW,
<lb/>PRINCETON, KY.
<lb/>Princeton, Ky., <date when="1861-06-18">June 18" 1861</date>
<lb/>Hon B,, Magoffin
<lb/>Frankfort Ky
<lb/>Dr Sir</p>
<p>At the <date when="1861-06">June Term 1861</date> of the Caldwell -- Circuit Court a Judgment was rendered against Benjamin Armstrong as the surety of Joel H,, Armstrong in a <hi rend="underline">Bail</hi> <hi rend="underline">Bond</hi> for ($400<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi>) Joel H Armstrong is a son of Ben Armstrong -- and while attending College in Princeton as a candidate for the ministry was arrested on a charge of stealing money from his fellow students -- and was held to bail by the Examining Court in the Sum of ($400) to answer an Indictment by the Grand Jury -- and his father Ben Armstrong became his surety in the bond under a promise from his son that he would go home and go to work and stand his trial in the Circuit Court his son<pb/>
<lb/>protesting and assuring his father that he was innocent of the charge of stealing the money -- and as soon as the Bail Bond was executed Joel H Armstrong instead of going home with his father secretly slid out and made good -- his escape and was last heard from in Louisana -- an Indictment was -- found by the Grand Jury and he failing to answer his bond was forfeited and Judgment rendered thereon against his father as stated at <date when="1861-06">June Term 1861</date> -- Benjamin Armstrong is a very Old -- man about Seventy five years of age -- and <hi rend="underline">an</hi> <hi rend="underline">Old</hi> <hi rend="underline">Soldier</hi> and esteemed and regarded as an honest clever man by all his neighbors -- and -- no man could feel more Keenly or seem to be more humiliated by the rascality and conduct of his son than he does -- He owns a farm near Providence Hopkins Co Kenty -- and has a large family of children and I have -- learned from his neighbors that if he is forced to pay the Judgment for ($400)<pb/>
<lb/>in the present condition of things and the difficulty of selling property for <hi rend="underline">money</hi> it will deprive the Old man of his home and all he has and -- entail distress on him and his family and for these reasons I hereby petition you to interpose in his behalf and remit all or portion of the Judgment -- against him for ($400) the state is more able and will feel the loss -- Much less than he will -- </p>
<p>I am Yours Very truly
<lb/>E. P. Campbell atty
<lb/>For Commonwealth<pb/></p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-07-30">July 30</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
