<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0059"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">M. E. Robertson to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8511</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-95</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jamestown, Russell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-08-23">23 August 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Jamestown Ky. <date when="1862-08-23">Aug. 23<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency James F. Robertson Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> of Ky.</p>
<p>Your petitioner <hi rend="str">M</hi>. <hi rend="str">J</hi> M. E. Robertson states that a little more than a year ago. he was intoxicated and got into a little fight with one of his neighbors Elijah Blankenship for which your petitioner was tried &amp; fined $15. before the County Judge for Russell county. He replevied the fine with John Price surety &amp; immediately your petitioner &amp; said Blankenship both Joined the United States Army in <hi rend="str">the</hi> Capt. Carter Company of Col. Haggards Regiment the 5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Regt Ky. Cavalry having first made friends &amp; no injury was done in the fight. Your petitioner served in the army until he lost his health &amp; is now at home in said County with a discharge furlow &amp; unable to do anything. He has a wife &amp; family who are dependent &amp; no property or means of any sort to live on having used up in support of his family all his wages as a soldier. The execution on said fine is now out &amp; in the hands of <hi rend="str">Hugh Dockery</hi> ^J. G. Stanton^ constable of Russell Co for collection &amp; is pressing the surety &amp; unless pardoned must be collected off of P. Price. Said Price went in to save your petitioner from prison as a matter of feeling &amp; petitioner owes him much besides, that he is unable to pay, which he expected at the time to be able to pay out of his wages but which has failed by misfortune as aforesaid. He prays your excellency to pardon said Judgment &amp; fine except fee &amp; costs &amp; to send the pardon pr. mail, to the address of himself or John Price Jamestown Ky. &amp; will every pray &amp;c.</p>
<p>M. E. <hi rend="str">J.</hi> Robertson</p>
<p>I prosecuted the case of the comth. of Ky. vs. M. <hi rend="str">J</hi>E. Robertson in which the fine was assessed vs him at $15.00 as above stated and am satisfied that the facts are correctly set forth in the above petition &amp; <hi rend="str">that he should</hi> recommend him to Executive clemency. I was county atto. at the time</p>
<p>Joseph E. Hays<pb/></p>
<p>I as county Judge presided at the tiral alluded to in the foregoing petition. The main facts stated in the petition are true. and I would recommend a release of the fine</p>
<p>Wm Green P J R C C</p>
<p>Mr Price is a worthy citizen and it will be a hardship for him to have the fine to pay. He will have to pay the fee &amp; costs any way. Joseph E. Nays.</p>
<p>To his Excellency Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Robinson.</p>
<p>I supported Mr. M. E. Robertsons family while in the service until he drew wages. This was done through charity as I well knew I could never be remunerated unless out of his wages if he kept his health &amp; served. I loose much by his misfortune &amp; by furnishing his family in his absence when no one else would take the risk. The facts stated in the petition are all true &amp; I pray your Excelency to pardon the fine.</p>
<p>John Price.</p>
<p>Russell Cir. Ct
<lb/>Remitts
<lb/>J F Robinson
<lb/>$15 } Breach
<lb/>M. E. Robertson
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-08-29">Aug 29. 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
