<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1172"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Joseph Ricketts to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10640</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-334 to MG20-335</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Greenville, Muhlenburg County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-05">5 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Greenville Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1861-06-05">June 5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Beriah Magoffin Gov of Kentucky</p>
<p>Dear Sir Several weeks ago I enclosed you the Petition of G W Bryant. together with proof &amp;c asking your Excellency to relieve him from liability on a Recognizance for the appearance of Henry Taylor on the Muhlenberg Cir Court but as the Judgment was not then rendered I suppose you did nothing in the case. I inclose herewith copy of the Recognizance &amp; Judgment &amp; I Petition your Excellency to give the old man the relief asken that is ^a^ remission of the Judgment The facts are these Taylor was confined in Jail on a charge of Larceny; he was a stranger here &amp; a citizen of Illinois. He employed me as atty to defend him &amp; informed me that the Peitioner G W Bryant of M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Lean County was his uncle &amp; besought me to send for him to go his Bail I did so Bryant <unclear/> refused to go his Bail unless he would write home to his (prisoner's) father in<pb/>
<lb/>Illinois &amp; if he requested the Petitioner to go the Bail he would do so Taylor did write home &amp; received a letter from his wife inclosing one as he said from his father directing ^his^ uncle to go the Bail. I sent again for Bryant he came saw the letter &amp; went the Bail. Taylor was let out &amp; has never appeared. The letter was forged by the Prisoner Taylor himself as we were afterwards informed by some prisoners in Jail. Taylor deceived me more than any client did <hi rend="str">no</hi> before. He made a favorable impression on the whole bar &amp; on the Judge &amp; it was said generally that he could not be a thief As I was the ignorant instrument of getting the old man into it I feel a personal interest in the matter. The Petitioner Bryant is a most estimable citizen &amp; never would have gone into the business if it had not been for the forgery of the letter then matters were set forth in the papers I sent you &amp; proven by affidavit of the Jailer &amp;c but for fear you may have mislaid the paper I i<hi rend="str">nclude</hi> have made the above statements</p>
<p>Most resp yours
<lb/>Joseph Ricketts
<lb/>(Lee next page)<pb/></p>
<p>Greenville Ky <date when="1861-06-05">June 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi>/61</date>
<lb/>Gov B Magoffin
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>This is the case I explained to you when in Frankfort last and you told me it was not your custom to interfere until after Judgement had bin entered -- and as soon as it should be done in this case to send the papers up and you would attend to it</p>
<p>Your Respectfully
<lb/>B J Shaver</p>
<p><date when="1861-06-07">June 7 1861</date>
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>I have examined Judge Ricketts letter and he has Stated the facts in connection with the case, and I have no hesitation in Stating that this is One of the cases that Executive clemency might be excercised with great propriety and hope you can exercise the Same and relieve old M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Bryant concientiously</p>
<p>Your obt Sert
<lb/>Jesse N Reno Clk Cir Ct Court</p>
<p>Hon B Magoffin
<lb/>Frankfort Kenty<pb/></p>
<p><date when="1861-06-06">June the 6th 1861</date>
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>Being in the Country at the time of this transportation in which this honest and Respectable old man G. W. Bryant was involved in the unfair case set forth in the letter of Judge Jo<hi rend="sup">sh</hi> Ricketts and being acquainted, with the circumstances &amp;c I cheerful Join in the petition to your excellency for the exercie of your clemmency in the <hi rend="str">Re<unclear/></hi> Remission of the <hi rend="str">unjust debt imposed upon him said Bryant</hi> <hi rend="underline">old man of</hi> the unjust debt.</p>
<p>Yours Respectfully
<lb/><hi rend="underline">H. H. Harris</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
