<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-027-0038"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Evan Stevenson to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1271</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R2-58 to R2-61</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Benton County, Iowa</placeName>
    <date when="1862-09-09">9 September 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Inglewild.
<lb/>Benton Co. Ia.
<lb/><date when="1862-09-09">Sep<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> 9 1862</date>
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> J F Robinson,
<lb/>Dear Sir,</p>
<p>Having been notified, by Rev Edw<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Steven D D -- of Russelville Ky, now a prisoner in Camp chase Columbus Ohio, that you (with the Representative of Logan) were willing to make an effort to procure his release, I most cheerfully acquiesce in such an atttempt. I written to him in substance as I now address you. Probably I had best send you copies of my letter &amp; my Daughter Frances -- It is <hi rend="underline">lengthy</hi> &amp; a tres<hi rend="underline">pass upon your precious</hi> time, in these <unclear>perilous</unclear> days, to our loved Kentucky, I <unclear/> Country in common -- It is the best I can do under the circumstances, as an honest avowal. I congratulate you on your election to the responsible office of Governor of the Commonwealth of Ky, &amp; feel thereupon doubly assured of her eventual <unclear/>. God grant us a speedy deliverance.</p>
<p>Yours most resp'y -- Evan Stevenson -- <pb/>
<lb/>Copy of my letter to Rev<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Edw<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Stevenson.
<lb/>"Inglewild Benton Co. Ia.
<lb/><date when="1862-09-09">Sep<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> 9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>"Rev<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Edw<hi rend="sup">d.</hi> Stevenson D D"
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>Whereas you are a prisoner in Camp Chase, Columbus Ohio, I have gone to Louisville Ky, shortly after your arrest &amp; with others of your personal friends, done all we could to procure -- of Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Boyle, your release &amp; having witnessed your departure thence, for your present destination, not wishing hereby to compromise one whit the interests of the glorious Union, for which for many long months, as chaplain of the 15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Reg<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Ia v<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> U, S,A, and specially in the battle of Greenbriar W<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Va, on <date when="1861-10-04">O<hi rend="sup">ct</hi> 4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>, for four hours -- I was constantly exposed in limb &amp; life, &amp; becoming every day more &amp; more devoted to the unconditional preservation of this Union, cost what it may; I am nevertheless willing to do what I can for your honorable release, but this I must <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>be permitted to do in my own way, upon what I deem conscientious principles.<pb/>
<lb/>When I arrived in Russelville Ky, this spring, on a visit to my rapidly declining daughter (since deceased) -- I found to my sorrow, but very few remaining in your town, some calling themselves "Rebels," but generally prefering to be denominated "Southern Rights" men -- and from repeated conversations with yourself I found in you a zeelous, firm and determined "Southern Rights" man, deprecating solemly the war, &amp; the distressed state of the country, yet under the prejudice of <hi rend="str">of</hi>all others of that class, wanting that our government had <unclear/> that war. You were nevertheless in great distress that our country was involved in war &amp; regarded it as ruinous and deplorable. You told me that, you had been persuaded by union men &amp; conservative men, against your own wishes, to go into &amp; become the chairman of the "Vigilance Committee" at Russelville, while the Confederates were there and in possession of the place, and that your motive in so doing, was to save from abuse, innocent men be preserved as far as possible the peace and good order of society; and that in said committee you had exerted your influence to save from punishment<pb/>
<lb/>every Union man who had appeared before said committee, and (to the best of my recollection) had succeeded in every case but one, in which your advice had been overruled. And that on said committee, your protection against any one of said committee having any thing whatever to do with <hi rend="underline">arresting</hi> any one, upon whatever pretence. I must not hereby be understood as <hi rend="underline">Justifying</hi> your going into this Committee, as the Committee was projected (not by yourself but the Confederate Army) for the purpose of silencing known Union sentiment in and around Russelville Ky. You further assured me that some of the young ladies of your Academy (over which you presided) had unbeknown to you, erected a Confederate flag, upon your seminary dwelling or Edifice, (which is likewise your home) and that you had promptly taken it down, and put it beyond their reach -- or destroyed it, as you did not approve of such an exhibition. </p>
<p>You told me, that during my visit, one or more of your pupils had hurrahd for Jeff <hi rend="underline">Davis</hi>! in the hearing of some of our troops passing the Seminary, that you had severely reproved the guilty one or ones, &amp; that<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">(5)</note>
<lb/>one of the young ladies had taken umbrage at your reproof and determined to go to her mother and solicit her to take her from the Seminary, and she did go to her mother, but her mother told her you had done right &amp; remanded her to your controll. You further assured me that while the Confederates were in and around Russelville they had committed depradations upon your farm amounting to $2000 &amp; had paid you some Confederate scrip, which was not available at over 25 to. 50 Cts on the dollar. And that they had forcibly taken a horse &amp; kept him a long time, which was after much trouble on your part, returned. That they had wrested, perforce, from you a span of excellent mules, &amp; upon your protesting against this violent usage, you received nothing but insult; and that you told one of the Confederate Officers, who put his hand upon his sword, threateningly, when taking the mules; That you had seen the day when suc<hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>h an insult would have constrained your to blow out his brains. That thereupon you went to Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Scott (of Rebel Cavalry) &amp; remonstrated that his men were forcibly taking your mules,<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">(6)</note>
<lb/>whereupon, he swore, "he'<hi rend="sup">d</hi> be damn<hi rend="sup">d</hi>, if he died,^<unclear/>^ <unclear/> them any how." &amp; you told him, you were Southern rights in principle, but had unspeakable contempt for such conduct &amp; every thing of that class in toto disapproved of all such high-handed measures. When I went to Louisville Ky, to assist others of your <hi rend="underline"><unclear/></hi> <hi rend="underline">friends</hi> of that City, on the procurement of your release &amp; held a conversation with Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Boyle (our Commandant at that Post) Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Boyle told me you were perfectly willing to take the oath of allegiance &amp; I hope &amp; presume you are still willing not only to do so, but to stand by that obligation for all time to come, if I did not think so, I could not thus petition for your release. You are now about 65 years of age, I believe, and the close confinement to which you are subjected, will make terrible havoc of a nervous &amp; feeble constitution, &amp; I hope the authorities will kindly consider your age and accompanying infirmities &amp; permit you as taking a solemn oath to support our abused government, to return to your family and to the discharge of these spiritual funct-<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">(7)</note>
<lb/>-ing for which, to a great degree, you are eminently qualified. I have now stated the substance of what came to my hearing while I was at Russelville, excepting the declaration of your Post Master, who was under arrest &amp; before the Vigilence Committee, who told me that you made a strong and earnest appeal to him, to induce him to take the Confederate oath, that he did not take it, but was notwithstanding <unclear/> loose &amp; free. While visiting you in prison, in Louisville I several times noticed, that you repressed &amp; reproved every intemperate expression that occured on acct. of your imprisonment. I now leave room for my Daughter Fannie to express her convictions, she having just returned from the care of her sick, (but now deceased) sister in Russelville Ky, she having been in your company repeatedly since I left there. It is not covenient for her to file a regular affidavit, and all who know her will give as perfect credit to her declarations simply penned, as if they were in the regular form of legal <unclear>atterbution</unclear>.</p>
<p>Yours Most respectfully -- 
<lb/>Evan Stevenson"<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">(8)</note>
<lb/>(Copy of Frances Letter)
<lb/>"Inglewild I.a <date when="1862-09-19">Sep 19, 1862</date>.
<lb/>"Dear Uncle,</p>
<p>I am perfectly willing, to answer the questions -- you asked me, and glad I have an opportunity of doing you the favor. Thus, I am going to write -- knowing it must be the truth, the whole truth &amp; nothing but the <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>truth. -- </p>
<p>I was in attendance -- with my sister in Russelville over three months -- saw you almost every day while there, at least until you were arrested. -- I did hear you often speak of the deplorable condition of the country. I never heard any one there evince or express towards the Union party -- sentiments of mere friendship or kindness. You <hi rend="underline">did</hi> frequently in my presence <hi rend="underline">refuse</hi> every thing in sentiment and conduct on the part of the Southern Rights men, that savored of misrule &amp; violence. Finally -- you ask me, whether from all I saw &amp; heard while <hi rend="str">there</hi> Russelville, I was not deeply impressed with the fact, that your whole course during the presence for the Confederate forces was most conservative, and that I had done everything in my power for the protection of the union citizens"?</p>
<p>The Confederate forces were not there at the time I was there, but I heard of several witnesses of your protecting union men, and on two occasions, I distinctly remember hearing it spoken of, of your getting them released from confinement. This is all you ask me &amp; I truly hope it will be of some benefit to you &amp; you will speedily be released.</p>
<p>(signed) Respectfully yours, "Frances Stevenson."</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
