<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2710"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. George Johnson &amp; Co., Judgment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7347</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-357 to BR16-359</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Jefferson Circuit Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth
<lb/>vs.
<lb/>Geo Johnson &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi></p>
<p>This day came the Defts: Elisha Williams and W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Wyatt. by atty. and withdrew their defence herein It is therefore considered by the court that Plaintiff recover of said Defendants five hundred dollars. being the amount in the summons mentioned Also her costs herein expended And may have <unclear/> &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi></p>
<p>A. Copy att
<lb/>James P. Chambers
<lb/>clk<pb/></p>
<p>Commth
<lb/>vs. } Copy
<lb/>Geo Johnson<pb/></p>
<p>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlette Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioners Elisha Williams and William Wyatt would most respectfully represent to your excellency that on the <gap/> day of <gap/> 18<gap/> George Johnson was charged in the Jefferson Circuit Court with horse stealing and admitted to bail whereupon your petitioners entered as his bail in the sum of five hundred dollars Soon after which the said Johnson entered the <hi rend="str">serv</hi> Military service of the United States in the State of Kentucky as a substitute ^and did not appear in court^ Having entered as a substitute it was ruled by the circuit Judge that your petitioners as his bail were entitled to no relief under the act of the general assembly for the benefit of Soldiers and then bail and on the <date when="1865-11-28">28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> November 1865</date> Judgment was rendered by said Court on scirefacias against Your petitioners for the sum of five hundred dollars<pb/>
<lb/>your petitioners are both farmers of but small estate and both have families to support</p>
<p>In view of the premises they ask your excellency to interpose and relieve them of all of Said Judgment except costs and they will ever pray</p>
<p>Elisha Williams
<lb/>William Wyatt<pb/></p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/><hi rend="underline">The petition</hi> of Elisah Williams and Williams Wyatt<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>If he went in as substitute for either of his bail or their souls, or at their instance no relief can be given</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
