<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0811"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Hellen Goldsmith et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4930</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-252 to BR10-253</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-05-12">12 May 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville, Ky. <date when="1864-05-12">May 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Gov. Bramlette</p>
<p>We, the undersigned, most respectfully ask your Excellency to pardon Joseph Brown, who was yesterday sentenced by the Circuit Court to two years confiement in the Penitentiary for the manslaughter of Albert Goldsmith.</p>
<p>Brown is very young, only 17 years of age, and we believe that without any malice or deliberate intention to do violence, was provoked into the difficulty by deceased who was very quarrelsome and the Widow adds <hi rend="str">this</hi> her signature to this appeal for your executive clemency.</p>
<p>Hellen Goldsmith widow of the deseased
<lb/>Wade F Lane
<lb/>James W. Prather
<lb/>N. V. Gerhart
<lb/>C S Snead
<lb/>Robt F Orr
<lb/>Richard Isaacs-
<lb/>J A Sprowl
<lb/>Thos J Hackney
<lb/>Jno. N. Fletcher
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi>. E. Hughes
<lb/>Peter Pfeiffer
<lb/>Stephen Seversin
<lb/>A L Hardan</p>
<p>I James P Chambers Clerk Jefferson Circuit Court certify that eleven of the names signed to this petition are the names of jurors in the case of Commonwealth against Joseph Brown convicted of felony in this Court on <date when="1864-05-11">May 11 1864</date></p>
<p>Attest James P Chambers</p>
<p>I further certify that the name of A L Harding the twelfth juror has been subsequently added</p>
<p>att Jas P Chambers<pb/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">C B Smith</hi>
<lb/>Thead. Schwartz.
<lb/>Henry Deppen<pb/></p>
<p>To Gov. Bramlette
<lb/>Dear Sir,</p>
<p>I ask your excellency's clemency to be extended to young Brown. Seeing the name of the widow of the decease, as well as eleven of the jury who tried him to the petition for the pardon, and being asked to intercede with you for the young man, I do it without hesitation, from the high characters of the parties who ask me. If consistent with your duty it would gratify me much to have you pardon him. His youth should have much weight</p>
<p>very truly
<lb/>Richard T Jacob</p>
<p>To Gov: Bramlette</p>
<p>I was of counsel for young Brown whose petition for a pardon is on a preceding page. On the trial of the case I offered as a witness in behalf of the accused, his younger brother by name Charles Brown, who testified in the Examining Court, and whose testimony explained the cause of the shooting. It was that the deceased had kicked the accused several times on a portion of the the body and that great suffering was caused thereby and that during the difficulty Brown shot Goldsmith. The Circuit Judge excluded young Charles Brown as a witness on account of his youth and his ignorance of the nature of an oath; although he had testified as before stated in the Police Court. I unite in the petition for a pardon.</p>
<p>Respy
<lb/>Nat. Wolfe<pb/></p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Joseph Brown
<lb/>Pardon granted
<lb/><date when="1864-05-16">May 16" 1864</date>
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
