<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1276"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. S. Crumpton to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5913</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-463</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-10-29">29 October 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Covington Ky <date when="1864-10-29">Octo 29. 1864 -- </date>
<lb/>To His excellency Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky,</p>
<p>Your Petitioner. R. S. Crumpton would respectfully represent that at the <date when="1864-09">September Term 1864</date> of the Kenton Circuit Court, a Judgment was rendered against him for a fine of $50<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> for carrying concealed weapons The circumstances of the case are about as follows. One evening in the month of <date when="1863-12">December last</date> about christmas night, your Petitioner was staying all night with a friend Mr. Gedge in this City, and had his Revolver with him. it being customary with all boys during the holydays to carry a Pistol for the purpose of sport in such times, and on returning that evening your Petitioner laid the Pistol out on the Mantle. and it was seen by Gedge, and said Gedge when interrogated upon oath by the Grand Jury, whether he -- Knew: of any one carrying concealed weapons was in honor bound of course to state the facts. Your Petitioner did not carry the said Pistol for any malicious or illegal purpose but merely for sport as aforesaid, Upon the calling of the case for trial your Petitioner came into court and<pb/>
<lb/>confessed Judgment for the amount of the fine $50 -- Your Petitioner is quite a young man and can give any reference in regard to good morals, which your Excellency can wish. Your Petitioner asks that in view of the circumstances in his case that the fine be remitted &amp; he will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p>R. S. Crumpton</p>
<p>The undersigned Citizens of Covington Ky would cheerfully bear testimony to the truthfulness and good morals of R S Crumptonm and unite with him in the prayer of his petition</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">B W Foley Clk Circuit Court</hi>
<lb/>A C Ellis DC
<lb/>J. C, Gedge
<lb/>Wm, H, Gedge Manager K C R R
<lb/>Q A Keith Jr KCRR
<lb/>John B Casey
<lb/><hi rend="underline">M J Dudley</hi>
<lb/>John S. Nixon
<lb/>Levi F. Daugherty
<lb/>J. W. Stevenson</p>
<p>Kenton Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>R S. Crumpton
<lb/>$50,
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1864-12-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Dec/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
