<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2555"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Simpson et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7192</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-87 to BR16-88</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky,</p>
<p>The undersigned petitioners would respectfully state that George Davis at the <date when="--10">October</date> term of the Wayne Circuit Court tried and convicted of the crime of horse stealing and sentenced to imprisonment in the State Penitentiary for the term of four years,</p>
<p>They state that the evidence by which he was convicted was his own confessions, made as stated by the witnesses who testified against him, on the assurance that if he would confess to the act of taking the horse, he would be released and the prosecutor would discontinue all farther proceedings against him,</p>
<p>They state that no felonious intention was proven on the part of Davis, that the horse which he was charged to have stolen was found in the road, having been turned loose and clearly evidencing the fact that it was taken for temporary use. that after having been rode some six miles it had been abandonded to return to its owner</p>
<p>They state that said Davis is about twenty years of age, that he has been a soldier in the Federal army and served with gallantry as such -- </p>
<p>In consideration of the unsatisfactory testimony on which he was convicted, his past service to his country his young years your petitioners ask that he may be pardoned</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Simpson
<lb/>G. W. Hardwick
<lb/>P W Hardin
<lb/>G K Marcum
<lb/>John W Higginbotham
<lb/>J S Crutchfield
<lb/><unclear/> Mills
<lb/>J E Vickery
<lb/>J D Shearer
<lb/>F C Boyle
<lb/>A M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Beath<pb/>
<lb/>L P Franklin
<lb/>Bartholemew Lanson
<lb/>E Layder
<lb/>C A Cox
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Thornton
<lb/>M S Wihoyte
<lb/>Jno S Van Winkle
<lb/>Jno L Sallee
<lb/>Jno W Tuttle
<lb/>H M Sallee
<lb/>W M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee Fox
<lb/>F M Sumter
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi> C Washam
<lb/>H W Tuttle
<lb/>N B Stone
<lb/>James D Davidson
<lb/>H R Saufly
<lb/>H W Sanders
<lb/>J B S Frisbie
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Burnett
<lb/>A Q Spaun
<lb/>Preston Summers
<lb/>G Heath
<lb/>Berry Rogers
<lb/>Samuel Kennedy
<lb/>Isham Kernes
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> W Higgenbotham
<lb/>G Hardwick
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> S Baker
<lb/>Nathan Dabney
<lb/>James L Hardin</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
