<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2220"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. Henry Smith to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6857</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-33 to BR15-34</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>His Excellency
<lb/>Thomas E. Bramlett
<lb/>Govinor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned states that at the present term of the Fayette Circuit Court he was convicted upon trial, and sentenced to the Penetentiary for one year, for stealing a small boxe<hi rend="str">s</hi> of <hi rend="underline">cigarettes</hi> and two small bottles of <hi rend="underline">hair-oil</hi> from Fredric Rothenhoofer. The facts are about these: he was familiar in the store of Rothenhofer and had a running account with him of small amount, and while drunk from liquor got at Rothenhoofer, he took the Cigarettes &amp; hair-oil, with no intention of purloining them in day time, and three or four persons were standing by within a few feet. Directly took said articles into an adjoining room of the same house and gave them up when asked about them, and did not remove them from the house atall. He earnestly avers that he had no purpose of stealing, and believes the prosecution was set on foot to compell him to pay an<pb/>
<lb/>existing account. He knows that he is not guilty of crime, and he asks for pardon</p>
<p>R. Henry Smith</p>
<p>We the jurors of the above case who tried the above case earnestly reccomend a pardon for Smith. His case presented features extenuating guilt</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>E J Smith
<lb/>Jefferson Chrisman
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J. W. Royster
<lb/>Simon Haffer
<lb/>Pollard Echert
<lb/>Charles Hunley
<lb/>Richard Evans
<lb/>J L Keyes
<lb/>B F Lowering</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>We the undersigned reccomend and petition for the pardon of Smith</p>
<p><hi rend="str">Cha</hi><hi rend="str"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi><hi rend="str"> H Wickliffe</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="str">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="str"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi></hi><hi rend="str"> Jefferson
<lb/>B <unclear/></hi>
<lb/>Catisby Barnes Jr
<lb/>Jas. Cates<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Jno B Wilgers
<lb/>G M Adams
<lb/>J. F. Miller
<lb/>D. S. Goodloe
<lb/><hi rend="underline">John M</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi><hi rend="underline">Coy</hi></p>
<p><cb n="2"/>All the jurors that could be found cheerfully petitioned -- The other three have gone home -- </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>I defended Smith at the appointment of the Court. He had no means to pay a fee I thought he should have been acquitted This might have been the effect of defending but I do sincererly believe that <hi rend="underline">felonious</hi> <hi rend="underline">intent</hi> <hi rend="underline">never</hi> <hi rend="underline">existed</hi>. He proved a good character for honesty &amp; good conduct. Every one who knows of the case are desirous to have him released -- He is a <hi rend="underline">young</hi> man of good appearance I think he should be pardoned. He was very drunk at the time</p>
<p>Jn<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi> B Huston<pb/></p>
<p>E H. Smith
<lb/>Fayette Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>E. H. Smith
<lb/>Pardon -- 
<lb/><date when="1865-08-18">18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Aug/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
