<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1669"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Hattan Harris et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11137</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Andrew P Patrick</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-337 to MG22-338</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Marion County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-01-28">28 January 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> of Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Hattan Harris would most respectfully State to your Excellency that one A. W. Pickerel was taken up in the County of Marion charged with Stealing a pair of gloves worth 25 or 30 cents and was by the examining Court sent to the Circuit Court for trial -- That his father &amp; friends lived in Indiana and said A. W. Pickerel came to Kentucky the fall before said charge was made to go to School and did go to School through the fall &amp; winter -- He was quite young about 19 years old= He was of Sober habits but went to Raywick and was there made drunk and by some means a pair of gloves was found upon his person -- and on this charge he was had up &amp; Sent to further trial -- Your Petitioner &amp; others became his sureties for his appearance in the Circuit Court under his promise that he would appear and under the full belief of the undersigned &amp; others who went his bail that he would So appear -- His father who as before Stated lived in Indiana came in to see about it &amp; employed Counsel to defend his son saying that he should stand his trial -- He &amp; his Son both went back to Indiana and when Court came on did not appear in consequence of which the bond for his appearance was forfeited -- A summons was issued &amp; Served on your Petitoner alone and judgment was rendered against him for $100. A copy of the bond and judgment is sent herewith -- Now your Petitioner States that he is poor and not able to bear the loss of<pb/>
<lb/>$100 in these tight &amp; trying times -- He has a wife &amp; children depending on him for a support -- It is as much as he can do to support his family and pay his taxes -- He became the bail of Said Pickerel under the full belief that he would not only stand his trial but would be acquitted of the charge when he should be tried and has been disap<hi rend="str">a</hi>pointed in his failure to <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>appear and being out of the State your Petitioner has not the power to arrest him &amp; put him in the custody of the law -- It is the firm belief of your Petitoner that if he had stood his trial he would have been cleared and thinks that he failed to appear more from neglect and the distance he would have to come than from any apprehension of a conviction -- In consideration of the premisses he prays your Excellency to remit said fine or so much of it as it may be in your power to remit as the balance will be as as much as he can pay without great embarrasment</p>
<p>Hattan ^his X mark^ Harris</p>
<p>Sworn to by Hattan Harris before me this <date when="1862-01-28">28<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> January 1862</date></p>
<p>N T Berry Ck</p>
<p>I can state that the father of Young Pickerel came to me &amp; retained me to defend his son -- On that occasion I learned as I thought the facts of the case from him &amp; other sources and regarded the case as one of the most trifling character and thought that young Picken would have no difficulty in<pb/>
<lb/>getting clear and I think such was the opinion of the neighborhood -- I was not present at the Court of Inquiry -- I heartily concur in Mr Harris' application for a remission of his fine</p>
<p>John Shuck</p>
<p>We the undersigned join Mr Harris in his Petition -- We are his neighbors and believe your Excellency will not ^only^ relieve Mr Harris but do an act approved by the Community in remitting the fine -- </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Geo. W. Lancaster 1
<lb/>Augustin Mattingly 2
<lb/>R. B. Brownfeld 3
<lb/>W H Mitchell 4
<lb/>J. M. Malone 5
<lb/>James <hi rend="underline">Scott</hi> 6
<lb/>M M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Dermott 7
<lb/>S. L. D. Chastein 8
<lb/>Henry C. Wright 9
<lb/>Allen Peterson 10
<lb/>J. J. Blair 11
<lb/>Jas.. Mattingly 12
<lb/>N Costello 13
<lb/>John Brown 14
<lb/>David P Rickett 15
<lb/>Peter Martin 16
<lb/>J, C, Downs 17
<lb/>John T Bolton 18
<lb/>R, J, Scott 19
<lb/>William Scott 20
<lb/>John Williamson 21
<lb/>T. A. Williamson 22
<lb/>Charles Whitfield 23 } Raywick Marion Co Ky
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Ben Brown 24
<lb/>Elizah J Allen 25
<lb/>John M Jones 26
<lb/>John L Rhodes 27
<lb/>B Y Hall 28
<lb/>J S Scott 29
<lb/>Nathaniel Hobert 30
<lb/>Charles Graham 31
<lb/>Jo<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Graham 32
<lb/>G. W. Craven 33 } Raywick Marion Co Ky
<lb/>John B. Hall 34
<lb/>E L Hill 35
<lb/>David Miller 36
<lb/>A J Beall 37
<lb/>W P Scott 38
<lb/>Edward Carter 39
<lb/>Henry D edwards 40
<lb/>John H Carter 41
<lb/>Hugh W Garock 42
<lb/>Wilford Martin 43
<lb/>George N Pickaenel 44
<lb/>Washinton Beall 45
<lb/>Thomas Clark 46
<lb/>William <unclear>linoc</unclear> 47<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi>. F. Wright 48
<lb/>Benjamin Pickerrell 49
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> J. Pickerrell 50
<lb/>Geo W. Bray 51
<lb/>Robt E Rachford 52
<lb/>Lewis H Saddie 53
<lb/>George W. Elliott 54
<lb/>P. G. Miller 55
<lb/>James Brown 56
<lb/>Charles Edwards 57
<lb/>L. R Friend 58
<lb/>R Pery Young 59
<lb/>Isaac Mclain 60</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M.
<lb/>Marion Cir. Ct
<lb/>$100. } Recog
<lb/>H Harris
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-02-15">Feby 15./62</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
