<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3023"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. William G. McCracking, Judgment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5142</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR43-132</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Laurel County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-08">August 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky Laurel Circuit Court
<lb/><date when="1864-08">August Term 1864</date>
<lb/>Commonwealth Plff
<lb/>Against } Grand Larceny
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> G M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracking Defts</p>
<p>This day came the Attorney for the Commonwealth and the Defendant being brought into Court in custody of the Jailer and being asked if he had any thing further to urge why the Judgement of the Court shoud not be pronounced according to the verdict of the Jury Replied that he had not It is therefore adjudged by the court that the Defendant W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> G M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracking undergo Confinement in the Jail and Penetinchery of the State for and during the full Term and Period of four Years in manner and form as by the Jury in their verdict assessed That the Defendant now be remanded in custody of the Jailer to be kept by him until such time as the Sherriff of this county can remove him to the Penitinchery as aboved adjudged which shall be as soon as convenient!</p>
<p>A copy Att R L Ewell Clerk
<lb/>Laurel Cir Court<pb/>
<lb/>Laurel Cir Ct
<lb/>Commonwealth
<lb/>v } Judgement
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> G M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracking<figure type="hr"/>Refused</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
