<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0488"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Z. M. Bugg et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4607</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-274 to BR9-275</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His excelency <hi rend="str">James F Robertson</hi> ^Thomas E Bramlett^ Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, the undersigned your petitioners, would most respectfully represent that at the <date when="--03">March term</date> of the Ballard Circuit Court one H M Garner was <hi rend="str">indicted</hi> tried upon an indictment for a breach of the Peace and fined the Sum of Eighty three dollars, and two weeks confinement in the county Jail. Now the undersigned would farther represent, that Mr. Garner is a very young man, and withal as a general rule a law abiding, and orderly walking youth and could not we think have been betrayed into the commission of the Offence charged but for the presence of unfortunate circumstances of agrevation and excitement. The Offence charged, in the bill of indictment, was committed about the time of the commencement of the unfortunate dificulties which distract our unhappy Country, a time when legal and moral restraints, were everywhere thrown to the winds and all the evil passions of our nature were turned loose. Mr Garner, being a youth, at the time, and having conducted himself well, before, &amp; since the commission of the offence, and with all a poor <hi rend="str">many</hi> man, and <hi rend="str">wholy</hi> wholy unable to pay the fine, we earnestly think his case is one in which the Executive clemency should be extended. An aditional reason for Executive ^interposition^, is the fact that since the commission of the offence charged, and of which he was convicted. Mr Garner has changed his relations in life, and now has a young family dependent upon him for support, who will be disgraced by his imprisonment, and ^suffer^ great pecuniary embaresments by the riged enforcement of the law in the<pb/>
<lb/>collection of the fine. For the reasons offered above the undersigned would respectfully ask your Excellency to interpose the perogative of <hi rend="str">Mr</hi> Money as far as the Executive May in relieving the young man from fine and imprisonment and as in duty will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Z M Bugg
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H Corbett
<lb/>Jas. McCauley
<lb/>Asa Richardson
<lb/>S J Thurmond
<lb/>W. C. pairy.
<lb/>John S Ray
<lb/>W S Watson
<lb/>W. H. Watson
<lb/>Asa Richardson
<lb/>S. B. Coil
<lb/>D P Jurett
<lb/>L. R. Rich
<lb/>Thomas Garrett
<lb/>James L. Hines
<lb/><unclear>Firlih</unclear> W Underhill
<lb/>Darius Hatcher
<lb/>J. W. Holtemar
<lb/>Smith Garrett
<lb/>J Corbett
<lb/>W. W. Griffey
<lb/>W. B. Shelton
<lb/>J. R. Green
<lb/>A. P. Hall
<lb/>Henry Eleion
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Garrett
<lb/>GW Utterback
<lb/><cb n="2"/>T J Juett
<lb/>L. W. Weaver
<lb/>J. M. Tunsell
<lb/>G W Martin
<lb/>David Miller
<lb/>F. M. Harrisson
<lb/>C Armstrong
<lb/>Wesley Watson
<lb/>F M Watson
<lb/>James Muncel
<lb/>John Muncel
<lb/>Julius Bongarent
<lb/>Thomas Johnson
<lb/>Laf Rich
<lb/>G. L. Good
<lb/>G. A. Flood
<lb/>John Swofford
<lb/>J. H. Govren
<lb/>W B Lynn
<lb/>Wm. Meshew
<lb/>Thomas Flood
<lb/>J T Taylor
<lb/>Joseph Kimmel
<lb/>J. P. Edwards
<lb/>Swansen Wallon
<lb/>B.. F.. Billington
<lb/>P Peter Kaletin<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>J N Mesher
<lb/>W A Scott
<lb/>M W Jarett
<lb/>Larnes. C. Shorde
<lb/>John Dewese
<lb/>Howard Atherton
<lb/>F M Atherton
<lb/>W C atherton
<lb/>Rufus M Cavett
<lb/>James Mington
<lb/>James Derrey
<lb/>A Sunes
<lb/>Jackson Harper
<lb/>William Harper
<lb/>Urius Harper
<lb/>thomas agens
<lb/>Joseph Masters
<lb/>Richard lynro
<lb/>Jenes. Watson
<lb/>Johnson. dewese
<lb/>Gaines dwenese
<lb/>G. ash. Jinin
<lb/>J D White
<lb/>John L. Murray<pb/></p>
<p>Ballard Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Francis Garner
<lb/>$83
<lb/>Assault.
<lb/><date when="1864-02-09">9th Feby 1864</date></p>
<p>Respite 12 mots
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette</p>
<p>158A-1328H</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
