<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0347"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">E. P. Campbell to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4466</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-51 to BR9-52</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Princeton, Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-12-07">7 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Princeton Kentucky <date when="1863-12-07">December 7" 1863</date>
<lb/>Gov Thos E Bramlette
<lb/>Frankfort Ky
<lb/>Dr Sir</p>
<p>At the <date when="1863-11">November Term 1863</date> of the Caldwell Circuit Court a Judg<hi rend="underline">ment</hi> was rendered in favor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky against Newman Estes John Lewis and William Wells for the sum of <hi rend="underline">Seven</hi> Thousand Dollars $7000= as the <hi rend="underline">sureties</hi> and <hi rend="underline">bail</hi> for One James A <hi rend="underline">Johnson</hi> on a charge of <hi rend="underline">Murder</hi> = I have examined and <hi rend="underline">read</hi> the Petition of said Newman Estes John Lewis and William <hi rend="underline">Wells</hi>= addressed to you and find the statements made <hi rend="underline">therein</hi> substantially <hi rend="underline">correct</hi>= said James A Johnson was sent out of the county and then sent <hi rend="underline">South</hi> and exchanged to Military <hi rend="underline">Order</hi> as I was informed and <hi rend="underline">believe</hi>= I know that he was arrested and <hi rend="underline">carried</hi> off to <hi rend="underline">Colonel</hi> A.. P.. Henry 15 Kentucky Calvalry<pb/>
<lb/>and I afterwards <hi rend="underline">heard</hi> that James A Johnson <hi rend="underline">had been</hi> sent to Johnson= <hi rend="underline">Island</hi> and from there sent South and exchanged and I know that he has never <hi rend="underline">been back</hi> in the county since he was arrested and <hi rend="underline">carried </hi>Off to <hi rend="underline">Colonel</hi> Henry in <date when="1862-11">November</date> Or <date when="1862-12">December 1862</date> = that I have ever <hi rend="underline">heard</hi> of = and there is a report <hi rend="underline">in</hi> circulation here that said James A <hi rend="underline">Johnson</hi> is <hi rend="underline">now dead</hi> Whether time or not I am unable to say with any certainty = <hi rend="underline">William Wells</hi> one of the parties in said -- Judgment is <hi rend="underline">utterly</hi> Worthless and <hi rend="underline">insolvent</hi> and <hi rend="underline">can</hi> not pay One <hi rend="underline">Dollar</hi>= <hi rend="underline">Newman</hi> Estes is <hi rend="underline">an Old Man</hi> and has a <hi rend="underline">family</hi> John <hi rend="underline">Lewis</hi> also <hi rend="underline">has</hi> a <hi rend="underline">family</hi> = and it will <hi rend="underline">take about</hi> all <hi rend="underline">both</hi> Estes and <hi rend="underline">Lewis</hi> <hi rend="underline">have</hi> to pay said Judgment for <hi rend="underline">said</hi> sum of $7000= and there is very <hi rend="underline">little</hi> hope or chance for indemnity from <hi rend="underline">Johnson</hi> if he is <hi rend="underline">either</hi> now living Or <hi rend="underline">dead</hi> and I am <hi rend="underline">well</hi> satisfied that they have no indem<pb/>
<lb/>nity from <hi rend="underline">Johnson</hi> to serve them from coss and liability on said <hi rend="underline">bail bond</hi> and Judgment for $7000= and in consideration of the <hi rend="underline">above</hi> and foregoing <hi rend="underline">facts</hi> I <hi rend="underline">would</hi> <hi rend="underline">ask</hi> in behalf of said Newman Estes John Lewis and William <hi rend="underline">Wells</hi> Your interposition and that you = <hi rend="underline">release</hi> said <hi rend="underline">parties</hi> from the payment of said Judgment except all fees and costs <hi rend="underline">thereon</hi>=</p>
<p>I am Yours Respectfully
<lb/>E P Campbell
<lb/>Comth Atty 2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> District</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
