<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3442"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Matthew McCluer to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5561</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-351 to BR42-352</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bath County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Mathew M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cluer would humbly represent to your Excellency That there are Three Indictments in the Bath Circuit Court against him &amp; others one of the Indictments charges your Petitioner with shooting cattle the property <gap/> Crooks one Indictment charges him with horse Stealing the property of George Ewing &amp; the Third Indictment charges him with horse stealing the property of Saml Clay your Petitioner states that he went down from Morgan County to Boyd County &amp; wh<hi rend="str">ile</hi>en he was there he Rode a Brown mare that he had bought in Morgan County &amp; while there a man by the name of <unclear>Muly</unclear> Hensly told your Petitioner he had some cattle &amp; proposed to have and and hire your Petitioner to help him Drive his cattle to Bath County This same <unclear>Muly</unclear> Hensly had in his possession a Brown mare much Large than the one your Petitioner had bought &amp; sold &amp; So it turned out that a man by the name of Crooks followd after the Cattle some two weeks of the Hensley had sold them &amp; claimed the cattle &amp; your Petitioner while in boyd county before he had to drive cattle for Hensly went to Wayne County Virginia &amp; while there sold said mare &amp; was retuning home where he lived to Hensly this man- that your Petitioner had bought &amp; sold was afterward claimed by Saml Clay &amp; the mare Hensly had was claimed by Ewing so Same one send out warrants for the arest of your Petitioner &amp; there the case went to the Grand Jury &amp; indictments found your Petitioner States that he had nothing what ever to do with the mare that is called to Ewing mare never had her in possession never claimed her nor did he claim or have any thing to do with the cattle only <hi rend="str">as</hi> above Stated- he supposes the reason he is indicted that he was seen in Compay with said Hensly at Time he had the property the cattle was drove along the Publick highway in broad day light your Petitioners having no knowledge but that Hensly was the rightfull owner of the cattle, your Petitioner bought the mare he had in his possession Said Hensly. Some time before he went to Boyd supposing Hensley take to the mare was all right your Petitioner<pb/> 
<lb/>was acting good faith never for one moment did he entertain an idea that there was anything unfair about the whole transaction believe him &amp; Hensly your Petitioner asks your Excellency to pardon him- he States he is quite young man Just arrived to manhood &amp; Just married and Endeavoring to make an honest Living</p>
<p>Matthew M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cluer</p>
<p>The undersigned Joins in the above petition &amp; asks your Excellency to Pardon said Matthew M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cluer &amp; they believe the statements in the Petition are Substantially True </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Elisha Johnson
<lb/>W W. Burns
<lb/>W. M. Caskey
<lb/>Edward W Adams
<lb/>J W Fugett
<lb/>P. Z. Turner.
<lb/>Mathew Adams sr
<lb/>J. W Perry
<lb/>John Terry
<lb/>A C Neal
<lb/>M. M. Lewis
<lb/>J. M. Parry
<lb/>W R Davidson
<lb/>John Walsh
<lb/>Travis Davis
<lb/>R C Day
<lb/>Thomas Lewis
<lb/>James H Cole
<lb/>david trimble
<lb/>G W Phillips
<lb/><cb n="2"/>M W Nikell
<lb/>Solomon F Spradlin
<lb/>H. C. Lurnis Dry good merchant
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>.. R.. Oliver Photographer
<lb/>Norman Walsh
<lb/>R. F. Elam
<lb/>P K Elam
<lb/>Joseph perry
<lb/>John T Hazeligg
<lb/>William Coskey
<lb/>A J Parker
<lb/>Jill. Williams
<lb/>Andrew Womack
<lb/>T. A. Jones
<lb/>James.R. Turner
<lb/>M W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Ward Jailer Mc
<lb/>O. W. Burns
<lb/>Marian Johnson
<lb/>H H Lewis
<lb/>David C Lewis
<lb/>Thomas P Wells<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>J. H M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clure
<lb/>Marion Lewis
<lb/>W. G. Oakley
<lb/>W. H. Lewis
<lb/>Henry Lewis
<lb/>Gardner Lewis
<lb/>Thomas E Lewis
<lb/>P. J. Livingston
<lb/>J. H. Livingston
<lb/>J. M. Stamper
<lb/>A T Harnes
<lb/>W. H. Cartwell
<lb/>Mathew Adams Jr
<lb/>Amos Davis
<lb/>J N Cottle Jr
<lb/>Sanford, Davis
<lb/>Hiram Green
<lb/>S M Farrish
<lb/>Hugh W McDermete
<lb/>D G Lanter
<lb/>William Walsh<pb/></p>
<p>McCluer Petition</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
