<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0037"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James H. Seechs et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9505</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17A-100 to MG17A-101</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-01-21">21 January 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Beriah Maggoffin Govenor of The Commonwealth of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>We the citizens of Caldwell County Kentucky have long known Thomas B Wadlington &amp; he has ever been considered a good &amp; true hearted Citizen Known &amp; noted for his industry &amp; orderly conduct. The Difficulty in which he was engaged with Milton A Cartwright did not appear to us to be of his seeking nor are we satisfied that the case was presented to the Jurry as it really occurred. We hope yr Excellency will review the case &amp; give the poor man the benefit of every doubt <hi rend="str">or</hi> ^and we^ desire that his case may be judged in mercy &amp; regarded with favor, &amp; that Yr Excellency will take into consideration every circumstance that ought to opperate in his behalf -- And we desire that Yr Excellency will &amp; may be persuaded that it is consistent with Yr duty to extend to him executive clemency &amp; that his life may be sparred either by a full pardon or by a commutation of his punishment -- Yrs Respy 
<lb/><date when="1861-01-21">Jany 21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1861</date>.<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H Leech <hi rend="underline">J. P. C C</hi>
<lb/>John B. Steele
<lb/>D B Glenn
<lb/>Henry Machen
<lb/>F. Machen
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> R Mott
<lb/>F M W Dodds
<lb/>Hy. Waters
<lb/>J. C. Trayler
<lb/>Foster Mayson
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> C Kinsolving
<lb/>F W Dodds
<lb/>J Q Morse
<lb/>T J Morse
<lb/>O J Robertson
<lb/>Joseph Moore
<lb/>Jas Cantrell
<lb/>D. L. Black
<lb/>Nathaniel Martin
<lb/>J,, Kinsolving
<lb/>Joab Tison
<lb/>L. L, Oliver
<lb/>Thomas E Laws
<lb/>Spenser F Laws
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Kentucky Caldwell County.</p>
<p>F. W. Dodds says that the names of most of the subscribers to the written petition from the top to and including the name of James Cantrell are the genuine signatures they purport to be, the same being signed by them respectively or by their authority as few of them having been put to this purpose before it came to his hands, but he believes all of them are genuine.</p>
<p>F. W. Dodds</p>
<p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me by F. W. Dodds This <date when="1861-01-29">29<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> January 1861</date>.</p>
<p>J. C. Barnes D. C.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
