<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1780"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">A. J. Warden to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6417</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-304 to BR13-305</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Blandville, Ballard County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-05-23">23 May 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Blandville Ky <date when="1865-05-23">23<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> day of
<lb/>May 1865</date>
<lb/>To his Excelency Thomas E Bramlett
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned Clerk of the Ballard circuit court would beg to represent To your Excelencey That the bearer Samuel Miles is the surity of William Miles, in three Several Bail Bonds in Said Court for one thousand Dollars each; that Said Bonds were forfeited in said Court, because of the failure to appear on the part of the said William in said Court, to answer a charge of <hi rend="str">robery</hi> robbery, and that following Said forfeiture there was a Judgment on each of said Bonds for the sum of one thousand Dollars. and that of that Sum this said Samuel has paid and arragned to pay the sum of about $1.000. being a sum merly Sufficient to pay the atty for the State. and the costs of the prosecution. The undersigned would further represent that the Said Samuel Miles is a poor man, and that the Sum of $3000. is about as much as he is worth if all his effects were turned into money, that he is getting quite old and and that he is no longer able to make his living by the labor of his hands, and in the opinion of the undersigned<pb/>
<lb/>if compelled to pay the whole amount of the Said Judgements it will work the utter ruin of the Old gentleman</p>
<p>The undersigned would farther state that the old gentleman always professed to have the utmost confidence in the inocence of his son, and still thinks that he will return and vindicate himself. He is a man that Stands very high in the estimation of all good men, for truth and integrity of purpose and So far as is known to the undersigned deservedly So, and it is not believed that he would voluntarily do any <hi rend="str">thanks</hi> thing wrong. It will not be amiss <hi rend="str">to</hi> it is presumed to remind Your Excelency that a <hi rend="str">respicte</hi> respite has already been granted him So far as the claim of the state is Concerned, and that the magnaminity of a great state will not permit the idea that it can take pleasure in the ruin of any Citizen it is therefore hoped that <hi rend="str">the</hi> your Excelency will interpose the prerogative of Mercy in behalf of Samuel Miles, and remit so much of the forfeiture as may be within the power of the Commonwealth; whose representative you are. The undersigned in his <hi rend="str">capacity</hi><pb/>
<lb/>capacity of Clerk has had an excelent opportunity to become acquainted with all the circumstances of the case and is therefore able to Say to your Excelency that a more worthy object of Executive Clemency could not well be presented and that it is therefore hoped that the old gentleman -- he is 66 years of age -- may receive the Clemency to which it is believed his good Standing, and character -- as well ^as his^ circumstances in a pecuniary point of view so justly entitle him</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>A J Warden Clk<pb/></p>
<p>Ballard Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Saml' A Miles
<lb/>To his Excelency
<lb/>Thomas E Bramlett
<lb/>Governor of
<lb/>Ky
<lb/>3 judts
<lb/>$1000 each
<lb/>Remit<hi rend="sup">d</hi>
<lb/><date when="1865-06-05"><hi rend="str">3</hi>5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> <hi rend="str">M</hi>June 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
