<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2404"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. David Shroeder, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7041</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-336</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State and Commonwealth of Kentucky.
<lb/>Jefferson County and Circuit Sct.</p>
<p><date when="1862-01">January term of the Jefferson Circuit Court, in the Year of our Lord One thousand eight hundred and sixty two</date>.The Jurors of the Grand Jury, impannelled and sworn to enquire in and for the body of the County of Jefferson in the name and by the Authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky on their oath, present that David Shrader, late of said County laborer, on the <date when="1861-11-27">27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of November in the Year eighteen hudnred and sixty one</date> in the said County of Jefferson and state of Kentucky with force and Arms One Cow of the value of Twenty five Dollars, of the Goods and Chattels of George F Huber, then and there being and found, feloniously did steal, take and carry away, Contrary to the form of the statute in that Case made and provided and against the Peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>E. S. Craig, atto for Circuit 7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ju dist</p>
<p>Witnesses for the Commonwealth
<lb/>Geo F Huber
<lb/>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> Schuck
<lb/>Bernard Ilsing
<lb/>Tho Slater
<lb/>Chas Glass</p>
<p>A Copy,
<lb/>att <hi rend="underline">James P. Chambers.</hi> c<pb/></p>
<p><date when="1864-05-14">1864
<lb/>may 14th</date> stricken from docket with leave -- 
<lb/><date when="1865">1865</date> reinstated.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The striking from the Docket in the life time of the main witness for defence -- and the reinstating soon after his death has much the appearance of a vindictive watchfulness not consistent with a desire for the ends of justice -- </p>
<p>Therefore -- 
<lb/>Pardon is is granted for the offence charged in the Indictment</p>
<p>T E Bramlette
<lb/>Govr</p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>David Shroeder
<lb/>Grand Larceny
<lb/>Pardoned <date when="1865-09-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sept /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
