<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0784"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Ben Berry to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10252</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-220</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hopkinsville, Christian County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-04-11">11 April 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Hopkinsville <date when="1861-04-11">April 11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>.
<lb/>Gov B Magoffin
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>Johnathan Greer of was covicted at the last term of the Christian Circuit Court of manslauter and sentenced to the Penitentiary for the term of five years. Mr Greer is an old and rather infirm man sixty five years old. He has always borne <hi rend="str">a</hi> the character of a peaceable orderly citizen and never has been involved in difficulties or quarrels. Some year or two ago a daughter of Mr Greer married a trifling deseputed man who soon after abandoned her and the parties who were involved in the difficulty when Greer killed Ferrill slandered this daughter and justified the conduct of her husband by alledging infidelity on her part. I am informed that this lady is in every respect a prudent and worthy woman This very naturally produced bad feeling between the Greer family and the Ferrels and resulted finally in the killing of Ferrill by Greer. The circumstances attending this killing are set forth in other letters that will be handed you and are such as would naturally produce the greatest excitement in a Father and induce him in defence of the life of his child to take the life of his fellow man. I know well that the news<pb/>
<lb/>of Greer pardon would be received here with joy by almost every citizen of this county. The petition that will be handed you by Mr Bernard has been signed by the most respectable citizens of the county also by every member of the Bar &amp; the Jury that covicted him I sincerely hope that after examining the facts connected with this case you will find it consistent with your duty to pardon this old man and thus releive the distress of his aged wife and worthy family</p>
<p>Respectfully &amp;c
<lb/>Ben Berry</p>
<p>P S Since writing the above I understand that Mr Bernard will probably not be able to go to Frankfort and this letter &amp; the petitions will be handed by Mr W H Clark a reliable gentleman in whose statements you may place implicit reliance.</p>
<p>B. B.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
