<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1054"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James Alvey to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10522</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-143 to MG20-144</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-05-20">20 May 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky Your petitioner would respectfully state that at the <date when="1861-05">May term of the Grayson circuit Court 1861</date> he was fined the Sum of Sixty Dollars upon an Indictment charging him with the offense of Keeping a Tippling house a copy of the virdict and Judgment are herewith inclosed he states that he was informed that the Legislature had passed an act <hi rend="str">S</hi>abolishing the Spring term of the Court and that there would be no court held for Grayson county at the <date when="1861-05">May</date> term which commenced on the Second Monday of the Month &amp; relying upon his information as a fact he did not on that account attend court that on friday night of the <date when="1861-05">May</date> term for the first time he learned that the court was in session but would adjoin Saturday morning before he could get to court he residing at a distance of Sixteen miles from the court house he States that the finding <hi rend="str">was</hi> against<pb/>
<lb/>him was upon the testimony of <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>one witness only who entertained unfriendly feeling towards your petitioner Your petitioner States that he never sold wine or any spiritous Liquors of any Kind in less quantity than a <gap/> Gallon &amp; that he did not suffer it to be drank in his house or on his premeses or adjacent thereto but sold only to be taken home by the purchaser which he could ^have^ abundantly proven by his neighbours was his manner of doing business had he not have been deceived as to there being no court Your pititioner feeling a concieusness of his inocence and being a poor man and about 64 years of age and unable to work in justice to his family feels his duty to appeal to your Excellency for executive clemency and would most respectfully ask your Excellency to remit said find and as in duty will ever pray &amp;c
<lb/><date when="1861-05-20">May 20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>James Alvey<pb/></p>
<p>We the undirsigned concur in foregoing facts as stated by the petitioner and Join in the prayer of the petition believing as we his neighbours do his is a case well deserving executive aid.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>A. J. Smith
<lb/>S. C. Phillips
<lb/>James. M. Williams
<lb/>John. D. Lusk
<lb/>Ben Alvey
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> A Meridth
<lb/>John Logsdon
<lb/>Miles Cox
<lb/>Thomas Williams 
<lb/>James Williams
<lb/>William Logsdon
<lb/>Joseph logsdon
<lb/>T P Jarboe
<lb/>henry fenwick
<lb/>harrison Logsdon
<lb/>Wm Lusk
<lb/>Harden Campbell
<lb/>James Campbell
<lb/>Nathaniel Merideth
<lb/>John Fenwick
<lb/>Wm <unclear/>
<lb/>Charles Penick
<lb/><cb n="2"/><hi rend="str">James Alvey pett</hi>
<lb/>ransom Caswell
<lb/>Gorge Caswell
<lb/>John Caswell
<lb/>thomas Alvey
<lb/>Jerdin Smith
<lb/>Will Smith
<lb/>James Jarboe<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Grayson Cir. Ct
<lb/>James Alvey
<lb/>Petition
<lb/>Respite 12 mo
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>$60 } tipling
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-09-10">Sept 10. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
