<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0450"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. N. Turner to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8902</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-221</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Princeton, Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-06-05">5 June 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Princeton <date when="1863-06-05">June 5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency the Govonor</p>
<p>enclosed please find the petition of Esqr W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Carter which I take pleasure in recommending to you for your Kind Consideration, I am well and intimately acquainted with him and know him to be a good and true man, and a man advanced in years with a large and dependent family with limated means and if Compelled to pay the find assessed against him would work a great hardship upon himself and family. I therefore earnestly and respectfully ask that you interpose in his behalf and be releast of So much of Said find of Fine hundred dollars as you in the exercise of your executive Clemency <hi rend="str">as you</hi> may have the right to remit. Very Respectfully Yours</p>
<p>J. N. Turner
<lb/>Presiding Judge of Caldwell County Kentucky</p>
<p>P S. I have no dobt but Mr Carter has long since Regretted the part he Took in the Provincial Government of Ky at Judge of the quarterly Court yours &amp;c</p>
<p>R, B, Ratliff</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
