<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0498"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John H. Butler and Reben Butler, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8950</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-292</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Russell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-08-03">3 August 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>John Butler &amp; Reubin Butler state, that they are sureties in a bond for the appearance before the Russell Circuit Court of John Patterson, charged with Felony as stated in their petition to Govr. Robertson. They state that they are informed &amp; belive that the said Patterson is dead they having recd. direct information to that effect from the brother in law ^of S. Patterson^ James Smith of Owenton County Tenn. where the death occured. They cannot procure the testimony of said Smith, he being in the Military services of the united states &amp; his particular Regiment &amp; whereabouts unknow. all reports coroborate Smith but his is the best evidence of the fail now in their power. They cannot with any safety undertake a trip to the place of his death nor can they send for want of mails or any other mode known to them</p>
<p><date when="1863-08-03">August 3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>John. H. Butler.
<lb/>Reben. Butler.</p>
<p>This day personally appeared before me S. P. Collins presiding Judge of the Russell <hi rend="str">Circuit</hi> County Court, John Butler &amp; Reubin Butler &amp; made oath that the statements in the above affidavit over their signatures are true to the best of their knowledge</p>
<p><date when="1863-08-03">August 3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/> S. P. Collins P J R. C. C</p>
<p>Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Robertson, D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Sir, although we have no doubt of the death of Mr. Patterson; yet it is out of our power these times to furnish better proof. No prudent man would risk a trip through the dangers of the border for the amt. The country is constantly infected with guerrillas &amp; thieves &amp; murderers. I hope you will relieve us on these affidavits. We could procure many such but none better at this time. I feel such the case merits your clemency. Respectfully Please reply to me.</p>
<p>Joseph E Hays</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
