<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0866"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James B. Moore to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10334</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-363 to MG19-364</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency The Governour of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner James B. Moore, would respectfully represent unto Your Excellency that at a <hi rend="str">the</hi> special Criminal &amp; chancery term of the Green Circuit Court held in <date when="1861-02">February 1861</date> a Judgement was rendered against him for $60.00 upon an Indictment for keeping a Tippling house under the following circumstances, John M. Shirley was a Tavern keeper in the Town of Greensburg Ky, and had a license from the County Court of Green County to keep a tavern with the privilege of retailing spiritous liquors, and under an agreement with said Shirley your petitioner kept his bar and retailed spiritous liquors for several months and at or shortly before the expiration of said Shirley's license, respondent procured a license from the corporation of Greensburg, which had full legal right to grant the same, to keep a Coffee house with the privilege of retailing spiritous liquors and continued to sell under his coffee house licensse, but at the time he obtained his Coffee house license he failed to pay the state Tax and he was ignorant of the fact that he had to pay any other sum for his Coffee house license except the sum which he paid to the said Corporation, until some few weeks after he had commenced selling under his coffee house license, when he was informed by the Clerk of the County Court that he must pay the state a tax of ten dollars, which he paid immediately, he was advised by his counsel that his Coffee house license<pb/>
<lb/>would not protect him during the few weeks that he sold under his Coffee house license previous to his paying the state price, he therefore made no defense and Judgement was rendered against him by default, he states that he had a license all the time he sold spiritous liquors, and was selling under them believing that he had a right to do so and without any intention to violate any law of the land and wholly ignorant of the fact that it was a violation of any law, he applied to those for license, who he was informed had the right to grant them and paid them what they charged and he supposed those authorised to grant them had required him to pay all that he had to pay he states that he has paid the state and town authorities all that they were entitled to for the whole time that he sold liquor and he has been fined for the slight omission to pay the state ten dollars at the time he got his coffee house license, and this ten dollars he paid as soon as he was informed that it was necessary &amp; proper, he files herewith as a part hereof a copy of said Shirley's tavern license, a Copy of said Coffee house license and a statement from the Clerk of the County Court of Green County Showing that he paid the state ten dollars in a few weeks after he obtained his Coffee house license, Wherefore he prays Your Excellency to remit said fine and as in duty bound he will ever pray</p>
<p>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> B Moore<pb/></p>
<p>The undersign believe that the above case is one that calls for Executive clemency, and they pray his Excellency the Governour of Kentucky to remit said fine.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>David, M, Holland
<lb/>H T Hagen
<lb/>P M Williams
<lb/>W E Williams
<lb/>P A Williams
<lb/>T.. A. Williams
<lb/>M H Champion
<lb/>F. W. Williams
<lb/>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi>. B. Carlile
<lb/>I, W, Woodring
<lb/>O T Ward
<lb/>O P Marshall
<lb/>R, L, Moore
<lb/>J, C, Edwards
<lb/>S S Hood
<lb/>Thos C Edwards
<lb/>Royal S Noe
<lb/>R R Stearmen
<lb/>John D Curry
<lb/>William C Curry
<lb/><hi rend="underline">John. H. Cox</hi>
<lb/>Samuel H Woodring
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H Moss
<lb/>Abra<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi>. Long
<lb/>John G Smith
<lb/><cb n="2"/>James T. Goalder
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> T hard
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi>. B Allen
<lb/>Daniel P. WHite
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi>. K Barnett
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Barnett
<lb/>John A. Adair
<lb/>W R Marshall
<lb/>F T Murray
<lb/>James Anderson
<lb/>Jefferson Henry
<lb/>C. T. Cox
<lb/>Samuel. T. Robinson
<lb/>T A Lewis
<lb/>T A Spencer
<lb/>E, H, Hobson
<lb/>Josiah Mitchell
<lb/>W.. B.. Moore
<lb/>A B Gunn
<lb/>F L Sidebottom
<lb/>A W. Montgomery
<lb/>J N Reid
<lb/>Hugh Montgomery
<lb/>W H Chelf
<lb/>David. T. Towles
<lb/>David Bleakman
<lb/>W. B. Farman
<lb/><unclear>s T:</unclear> Vaughan
<lb/>D. Hudson<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>James B. Moore
<lb/>To } Petition
<lb/>His Excellency the Governour of Ky.
<lb/>Green Eq. Ct
<lb/>$60 } Tipling
<lb/>Remission Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi>
<lb/><date when="1861-03-14">Mar 14. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
