<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2890"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Henry Chandler, Sr. and Frederick Stumbo, Sr., Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7527</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-203</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Johnson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-22">22 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>We the undersigned Citizens of the County of Johnson in the state of Ky on our oaths say that we are and have for the last 5 years been well acquainted with Lewis Payne and Know him to be and always has been a Union man and a law abiding Citizen and Know he has been a scout and a leader of scouts for the U,,S, forces for which he was imprisined by the Rebels,, in Richmond 16, months that the said Lewis Payne is now Indicted for Robery in the Floyd circuit for no real cause but more from Predjudice than any other cause to Keep said Payne from sueing them for false imprisinment in sd county; we Know Mr Payne to be a correct man and a good citizen this <date when="1865-12-22">22<hi rend="sup">d </hi>Decr 1865</date></p>
<p>Henry Chandler Sr
<lb/>Frederick Stumbo Sr</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>County of Johnson</p>
<p>Frederick Stumbo and Henry chandler subscribred and made oath to the foregoing statement in my presence and I Certify they are respectable and entitled to<pb/>
<lb/>Credit on oath Given under my hand this <date when="1865-12-22">22<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Decr 1865</date> and affixed my seal of office</p>
<p>att John Hawes clk</p>
<p>Lewis Payne was a scout of the Forces of the U,, S,, and I am informed on one of his Expeditions it became necessary for him in order to comply with some militay order under which he was acting to take a horse to enable him to Reach some designated Point in due time, He took the horse and was indicted for same this is all I Know about the matter from information</p>
<p>J, M, Burns</p>
<p>this man Payne was taken by the forces under Gen H Marshall &amp; sent to the prison in Lynchburg va &amp; from there to Richmond &amp; detained for about one year I was sent after him to va, this I know</p>
<p>J M, Burns</p>
<p>Floyd Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Lewis Payne
<lb/>Indicted for Horse Stealing } Petition to
<lb/>Governor of Ky<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Pardon offence</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
