<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0068"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">N. N. Cowgill to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14097</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1865</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-05-15">15 May 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>ON BOARD THE
<lb/>Louisville, Cairo and Memphis U. S. Mail Line
<lb/>STEAMER ST. PATRICK.
<lb/>GEO. O. HART, Master.
<lb/>BRUCE ALVORD,
<lb/>J. CLEMENS, } CLERKS.</p>
<p><date when="1865-05-15">May 15. 1865</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E. Bramlette
<lb/>Gov -- </p>
<p>As a loyal suffering citizen of Fulton Co. I take the liberty ^of writing^ you on the condition of our section of country -- We are overrun by smal bands of guerillas -- say from one dozen to forty in a band -- they are eating up our substance &amp; stealing our horses &amp; mules, &amp; what ever else they can lay their hands on &amp; carry off -- They come in from the adjacent counties of Tenn. At Columbus they have no cavalry -- &amp; Paducah is some sixty miles distant, &amp; the small country force there can give us but little protection -- &amp; the citizens have no arms to protect themselves. If you could send us a company of <hi rend="underline">one</hi> <hi rend="underline">hundred</hi> good cavalry with the right kind of officers -- we could soon get rid of all those fellows, &amp; have peace &amp; quiet restored to us once more. I hope Gover<pb/>
<lb/>nor you will take this matter into serious consideration &amp; do for us what you can I have had the pleasure of meeting with Dr Scott <hi rend="str">late</hi> surgeon Genl of the state &amp; also ^late^ Adujt. Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Boyle -- they both seem to realize our condition -- And it is at their suggestion that I write to you upon the subject -- As for myself I would refer you to my friend Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Combs clerk of the Court of Appeal -- </p>
<p>most respectfully
<lb/>your obt. svt.
<lb/>N. N. Cowgill</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
