<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3273"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Spalding to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5392</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-80 to BR42-81</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thos. E. Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>The Petition of John Spalding respectfully represents that at the <date when="--01">January term last</date> of the City Court of Louisville he was presented on two indictments, one charging him with assault &amp; battery, the other charging him with shooting with intent to wound but without wounding. Upon the first his fine was assessed at $20. and upon ^the other^ the sum of $10. was assessed. Both of these matters grew out of a single transaction which was of the following character. The petitioner was at table dining with his family when his house was assaulted and the windows broken, he immediately obtained his pistol &amp; started in pursuit of the assailants who took refuge in a neighboring bar room. Upon entering he was attacked by those within and in pure self defence committed the alleged offences. He has been in the army and is now a major of the enrolled militia of this state. He has been for a long time out of employment and has a family dependent upon him for support. The costs in the above cases are unusually large<pb/>
<lb/>and it will be difficult for your petition to meet them. He respectfully prays that the above fines be remitted or that their collection may be stayed for such time as may give him some possible chance of paying them. The execution already issued will be returned on the <date when="---25">25th inst.</date> }</p>
<p>John Spalding</p>
<p>We the undersigned respectfully state that we believe the petitioner a proper subject for executive clemency.</p>
<p>A. Gorne
<lb/>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> Bull
<lb/>Nicholas Lamb
<lb/>Thomas Caine
<lb/>Patrick gonnelly
<lb/>Martin Mack
<lb/>John Caine
<lb/>Patrick Hayden
<lb/>Pat M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Donnell
<lb/>John corcoran<pb/>
<lb/>I am well acquainted with your Petitioner and know him to be an honorable man and well worthy of your favorable consideration</p>
<p>Respectfully &amp;c W R Hydes City Marshal</p>
<p>The persons who have signed the foregoing petition are the immediate neighbors of Mr Spaulding.</p>
<p>The petitioners general demeanor, is good He is a very industrious citizen</p>
<p>W. G. Reason
<lb/>city atto</p>
<p>I concur in the statement made by M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Reason
<lb/>Geo W Johnston</p>
<p>Executive clemency, I respectfuly Suggest will be proper in the above case</p>
<p>Jo. G. Wilson<pb/>
<lb/>Louisville City Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John Spalding</p>
<p>Refused</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
