<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-033-0048"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William E. Snoddy, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1511</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Apprehension of Fugitives from Justice Papers, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-80 to R3-81</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-06-16">16 June 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The State of Kentucky
<lb/>County of Jefferson. } S.S.</p>
<p>This day William E Snoddy made oath before me a Justice of the peace for said County. That on the <gap/> day of <date when="1862-12">December 1862</date> one Hugh McKenzie at Louisville in the County of Jefferson and state of Kentucky did feloniously &amp; maliciously obtain from this affiant the sum of six thousand and two hundred dollars in cash ^on^ the following false and Felonious representations. to wit, the said <hi rend="str">William</hi> Hugh McKenzie came to the Banking office of said affiant in said city of Louisville and left an order which said affiant to purchase for him the said McKenzie a certain kind of paper money purporting to be money on the Confederate states of America, He the said McKenzie at the same time intending feloniously to cheat and swindle the said affiant, did send an accomplice of him the said McKenzie to the said office of this said affiant who then and there sold to this affiant the amount of Twenty Thousand dollars of the kind of paper described in said order of said McKenzie purporting to be money or scrip of the Confederate states of America for which $20000,00 of confederate scrip as afsd, he <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> affiant paid to the accomplice of the said McKenzie the<pb/>
<lb/><unclear/> sum of <hi rend="underline">six thousand</hi> <hi rend="underline">and t</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="str">o</hi></hi><hi rend="underline">wo hundred dollars</hi>. The said twenty Thousand dollars of Confederate scrip as aforesaid turned out to be counterfit and therefore entirely worthless The said McKenzie and his accomplice having received the said six Thousand and two hundred dollars Through the said felonious and false representations have <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> absconded and the said McKenzie has never come to get the said twenty thousand dollars of Confederate scrip afsd, Affiant further states that said Hugh McKenzie is now a fugitive and at large in the city of Cincinnati in the state of ohio, afiant further states that he knows a responsible witness to show the said Hugh McKenzie voluntarily stateted that he the said Hugh McKenzie had Swindled this affiant out of the said sum of six thousand and two hundred dollars by leaving an order with said affiant to purchase for him the said McKenzie, a certain kind of Scrip on the Confederate states of America (which said kind of scrip was counterfit), and that he the said McKenzie afterwards sent his said accomplice to this affiant who sold to said affiant the aforesaid sum of $20000,00 of counterfit confederate states scrip<pb/>
<lb/>and received therefor $6200,00 He the said McKenzie well knowing at, and before the time he left the order with this affiant for the purchase of the said certain kind of Confederate state scrip or money, that the same was counterfit and worthless and in fact planed the whole transaction, deliberately to cheat and swindle this affiant out of whate net sum of money he should pay for said scrip or money.</p>
<p>Affiant asks that the Governor of this commonwealth of Kentucky do issue a requisition upon the Governor of the state of Ohio for the purpose of having said Hugh McKenzie brought to Justice. The affiant asks that said requisition be issued to him affiant.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">W. E. Snoddy</hi></p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me by W. E. Snoddy this <date when="1863-06-16">16th day of June 1863</date></p>
<p>Jo<hi rend="sup">s,,</hi> Clement J, P, J, C<pb/></p>
<p>Affidavit of W. E. Snoddy for the arrest of Hugh McKenzie a fugitive in the state of Ohio.
<lb/>Ohio<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>issue requisition
<lb/>J F R</p>
<p>Requisition
<lb/>Is<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-06-17">June 17. 1863</date>
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s.</hi> L. Ruffin
<lb/>Agent</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
