<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0036"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Stephen E. Jones to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14065</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1864</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-04-28">28 April 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Head-Quarters District of Kentucky and
<lb/>FIRST DIVISION, TWENTY-THIRD ARMY CORPS,
<lb/>Louisville, <date when="1864-04-28">April 28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>His Excellency, T. S. Bramlett,
<lb/>Governor, State of Kentucky,</p>
<p>Since it has become evident, that under no circumstances can be a sufficient garrison in this State, to protect each county from the incursions of Small guerrilla bands, horse thieves &amp; marauders, I have the honor, to request your views of the propriety of issuing a Military order, authorizing the Deputy Provost Marshals, of Counties, to call on the citizens, to assist in making such arrests as are required and in repelling threatened raids, and of notifying all citizens, irrespective of parties or sympathizers, that a failure to respond promptly and in good faith to these calls will subject them to punishment, as for a military offence. That the citizens are in themselves able, to repel these raids, even<pb/>
<lb/>when inferior in numbers, has been recently illustrated in different sections of the State. -- They only require an authorized head. I have spoken to several of the Provost Marshals on the subject, and they think, it would be production of good.</p>
<p>Of course! such an order will only be issued by your approval; if you have other plans, equally efficient for securing the same result through other officers, then the necessity of it ceases.</p>
<p>Please favor me with your views on the subject on your early leisure.</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>Your Obedient Servant
<lb/>Stephen E Jones
<lb/>Capt, A. D. G. &amp; P. M. G. Dist. of Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
