<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1553"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Mary A. Smyth et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6190</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-401 to BR12-402</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-03-29">29 March 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Mary A Smyth respectfully shews that her son Joseph Smyth was lately arrested charged with the larseny of a sow &amp; pigs and held to bail for his appearance at the next term of the Jefferson Circuit court in the penalty of $300.00 and that your petitioner became his bail for that amount.</p>
<p>Her said son is not yet seventeen years of age, and has in consequence of his association with bad boys in Louisville been a source of great trouble &amp; sorrow to your petitioner. Your petitioner soon after he was discharged for the purpose of removing him from his associations in Louisville took him with her to Cincinnati and there pursued him to be enlisted upon a U. S. gunboat for the term of two years. It was the only possible course open to her, to save him from ruin.</p>
<p>In consequence of such enlistment he will not be able to appear in discharge of his bond, and without the interposition of executive clemency your petitioner will be compelled to pay said bond -- Your petitioner has no estate other than her household furniture with some five or six hundred dollars, and if required to pay the bond she will be completely ruined and broken up -- Your petitioner is a dressmaker by occupation and depends upon the labor of her hands for her daily bread &amp; that of her family -- she prays that her liability upon said bond may be remitted -- </p>
<p>Mrs M A Smythe
<lb/><hi rend="underline">over</hi><pb/></p>
<p>The undersigned are acquainted by reputation with Mrs Smyth and are satisfied that her statements in her petition are true and would respectfully recommend in view of all the circumstances that she be relieved from the payment of said bond -- We are satisfied that she has done the best thing for the boy that she could have done in placing him on board a gunboat</p>
<p><date when="1865-03-29">Mar. 29. 1865</date></p>
<p>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> W. Gibson
<lb/>Geo W. Johnston. Judge
<lb/>City Court Louisville
<lb/>R O Priest
<lb/>Chief of Police
<lb/>Isaac Caldwell
<lb/>Geo A Caldwell
<lb/>W B Caldwell
<lb/>Will. P. Thomasson</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
