<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2681"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Enoch Harris to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7318</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-309 to BR16-310</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lawrence County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-11-25">25 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Lawrence Co Ky <date when="1865-11-25">Nov 25<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date></p>
<p>Mr Bramlett now Govenor of the sate of Ky Dear sir after my Respects to you your undersigned humble Petitioner Request your honor to Remit a fine which was adjudged against me at the Last Term of the Lawrence Circuit for the sum of twenty Dollars for selling one Gallon of whisky for which I did not know that it was a violation of the Law to sell whisky by the Gallon the whisky which I sold was not mine nethier had I any interest in it it was Brought to a mill which I am a tenant &amp; left on the account of high water &amp; by the persuasion of M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> W. Chafin the man you pardoned I let him have one Gallon for which he Endited me &amp; I was fined the above amount, Mr Drury the Commonwealths attorney agreed with with me he would take a Judgment for ten Dollars at Court &amp; told me to go home &amp; after I Returned home &amp; made no defence he took the Judgment for twenty Dollars If you will Consider my humble petition it will be an act of Lasting Gratitude Confered on me by you<pb/></p>
<p>I am in moderate Circumstances and Raising a family of orphant children which has Neither father or mother Living &amp; have no means to pay a fine which I was not proffited one cent the fine &amp; Costs is $36 Dollars against me if you in your wisdom will Remit the fine I will pay the Cost and I will Remember the great favior and do you faviors if I Can in all time to Come</p>
<p>Yout humble Petitioner
<lb/>Enoch Harris</p>
<p>I John J. Jordan certify <hi rend="str">the</hi> <hi rend="str">above</hi> that Mr Drury the Commonwealths attorney agreed with Mr Enoch Haris in my Presents that he would take a Judgment for only ten Dollars for sellling one Gallon of whisky at the last term of the Lawrence Circuit Court and told him to go home I told Mr Drury I would I would pay ten Dollars for Mr Haris &amp; when the trial came on and no defence he took the Judgment for twenty Dollars Mr Haris is a man of moderate Circumstances and had no interest Directly or indirectly in the whisky which he sold and is Raising orphant children now Govnor if in your wisdom you can Remit the fine<pb/>
<lb/>you will do what you would do if you was famillar with this case &amp; acquainted with Mr Haris an his Condition in life</p>
<p>Yours Respectfully
<lb/>John J Jordan</p>
<p>Sworn to by John J Jordan before me A Lange Justice of the peace for Lawrence Co Ky</p>
<p>A Lange j p l c</p>
<p>The above State State Statement as Regards Mr Haris being in moderate circumstances &amp; Raising orphant children is true</p>
<p>A Lange Esq<pb/></p>
<p>Lawrence Cr Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Enoch Harris
<lb/>$20
<lb/>Tipling
<lb/><date when="1865-12-02">2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Dec/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
