<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0368"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Bale to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8820</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-91 to R4-92</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Munfordville, Hart County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-05-23">23 May 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>James F Robinson
<lb/>Governor of the Commonwealth of Ky.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner would respectfully represent unto your Excellency that at the <date when="1860-10">October term 1860</date> of the Hart Equity &amp; Criminal Court, a Judgment was rendered against George W. Dobson &amp; R S Thomas his surety in favor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky upon an Indictment for "violating tavern Bond" -- That subsequently said Geo W Dobson was arrested under a ca sa which issued upon said Judgment, and your Petitioner moved by sympathy for said Dobson, who was entirely unable to pay said Judgment, in order to keep him from being incarcerated in Jail, replevied said Judgment whereby he became bound therefor -- Said Thomas the original surety being wholy insolvent The replevy Bond was Executed <date when="1861-04-17">17<hi rend="sup">th</hi> April 1861</date>, and within a few months thereafter said Dobson volunteered in the 15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Regt of Ky volunteer Infantry, where he has continually served with fidelity to the present time, in the ranks, being barely able by his pay to support his family -- and is wholy unable to pay said Judgment, and unless the Executive interpose your petitioner will be compelled to pay the amount of said Judgment, which will be a great hardship, as he is a poor <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> man &amp; compelled to support an aged father &amp; mother by his own labor. Wherefore your petitioner asks that by the interposition of<pb/>
<lb/>Executive Clemency, your Excellency remit said fine, to that extent authorized by law and will ever pray &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi></p>
<p><date when="1863-05-23">May 23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>Thomas Bale</p>
<p>Mumfordville Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1863-05-23">May 23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1863.</date></p>
<p>The undersigned beg leave to state to his Excellency, the Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky that they are personaly acquainted with Thomas Bale whose name appears to the foregoing petition, and that <hi rend="str">able</hi> we know all the facts stated therein to be true and respectfully ask his Excellency to remit the fine mentioned in the above petion.</p>
<p>Respectfully &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>
<lb/>Jas H. Compton
<lb/>A K Hart Circuit Court
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> A. Dawson
<lb/>Clk Hart County Court.
<lb/><hi rend="underline">G. T. Wood</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Hart Eq. Ct.
<lb/>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Petition of Thos Bale
<lb/>Ge<hi rend="sup">o</hi> W. Dobson &amp;c<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Pettn granted therefrom on the bond on to Thomas Bale is remitted on which statements of Colo Wood as well as this Pettn</p>
<p>J F Robinson
<lb/>$300. } Recog
<lb/>Iss <date when="1863-06-30">June 30. 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
