<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1076"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. P. Sullivan to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10544</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-174</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Elkton, Todd County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-05-03">3 May 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Elkton <date when="1861-05-03">May 3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency B Magoffin
<lb/>Governer of Ky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>Your Petitioner would respectfully state that at the <date when="1861-04">april</date> term of the Todd Circuit Court he was fined &amp; Judgment of the Court had against him for twenty Dollars for retailing spiritous Liquors, in Todd County -- </p>
<p>Your Petitioner would state that he was Jointly indicted with one Harry Mitchell for keeping a tipling house and on the trial of said indictment the proof was that your petitioner resided in Elkton and for the accomodation of the people of sharon Grove sent a small stock of staple Groceries to that point which were sold for him by said Mitchel who was a tavern keeper near said Grocery that no Liquors were kept in the Grocery House for sale that said Mitchel on <hi rend="underline">one</hi> occasion when the witness called for Liquor sold witness a pint and delivered it to him in the grocery where the liquor came from witness did not know nor did he know whose liquor it was your petitioner states that he kept no Liquor for sale nor did he authorize any person to sell or dispense of Liquors for him wherefore believing his case is such an one as to authorise the interposition of Executive power he asks it in a release from so much of said Judgment as permitted by Law Respectfully</p>
<p>J. P. Sullivan<pb/></p>
<p>Elkton <date when="1861-05-03">May 3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Gov Maggoffin
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>The foregoing petition sets out substantially the facts of M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Sullivan's Case, That he should be released from the Judgment as asked is due to him &amp; justice if the Law was violated it was by Mitchel without authority or knowledge from the petitioner who resided some ten miles from where the Grocery was kept and is in evry respect a worthy, and law abiding citizen permit <hi rend="str">me</hi> us to hope that his petition will receive the favourable attention of your Excellency</p>
<p>your Fellow Citizen
<lb/>J A Russell
<lb/>H, G, Bibb
<lb/>W B Hanyon I have no doubt but that the the indictment against Sullivan was a malicous thing gotten up by his enemies to do him an injury and that the fine ought to be remitted</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
