<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-006-0090"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">The State of Illinois v. William Hipwell, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1136</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Requisitions for the Return of Fugitives from Justice, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR6-114 to BR6-115</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Peoria, Peoria County, Illinois</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-19">19 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Proceedings at a term of the Circuit Court of Peoria County, began and held at the Court house, in the City and County of Peoria, in the State of Illinois, on the second Monday of <date when="1865-10-09">October, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and sixtyfive,</date> it being the ninth day of said month. Present the Honorable Marion Williamson, Judge of the sixteenth Judicial Circuit in said State presiding, George C. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Fadden Sheriff, and Thomas Mooney Jnr Clerk</p>
<p>Thursday <date when="1865-10-19">October 19<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> A.D. 1865.</date>
<lb/>The People of the State of Illinois on relation of Matthew Skiffington.
<lb/>vs } Application for Habeas Corpus
<lb/>William Hipwell.</p>
<p>This day came the said relator attended by W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> W. O'Brian &amp; Thomas Cratty his attorneys, and exhibits to the Court his petition for a writ of Habeas Corpus, and the Court having heard the argument of counsel, and being fully advised in the premises, do order and adjudge that said petition is insufficient to authorise the issuing of a writ of Habeas Corpus herein, and the said Skiffington is ordered into the custody of the said Hipwell, the agent of the authorities of the State of Kentucky,<pb/></p>
<p>State of Illinois
<lb/>Peoria County } S.S.</p>
<p>I, Thomas Mooney Jnr. clerk of the Circuit Court in and for said county and State, do hereby certify that the foregoing is a full and ^true^ transcript of the proceedings of said Court in the cause wherein The People of the State of Illinois on relation of Matthew Skiffington is complainant and the said William Hipwell is Defendant as the same appears of record in my office</p>
<p><figure type="seal"/></p>
<p>In witness whereof I hereto set my hand and affix the seal of said Court at office in the City of Peoria this <date when="1865-10-19">19<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of October A D. 1865.</date></p>
<p>Thomas Mooney Jnr
<lb/>Clerk</p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp"><unclear/></note><pb/></p>
<p>The People Ex. Rel.
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Hipwell</p>
<p>1865</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
