<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002633">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Edward P. Campbell </title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Krista Kinslow</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002633">
                    <persName>
                      Edward P. Campbell 
                        (Caldwell County, Kentucky, and Hopkinsville, Kentucky, commonwealth&#39;s attorney)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1832-10-21"  ><ab>1832-10-21</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1896-06-30"  ><ab>1896-06-30</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Caldwell County, Kentucky, and Hopkinsville, Kentucky, commonwealth&#39;s attorney. Caldwell County, Kentucky, native. Son of Samuel Campbell. Married to Caroline E. Taylor Campbell in 1858. Father of Edward T. Campbell. Graduated from Cumberland College in Princeton, Kentucky, in 1854. Studied law under George B. Cook in Princeton. Admitted to the bar and opened law practice in Princeton, in 1856. Commonwealth&#39;s attorney for the 2nd Judicial District of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1860 to 1868. Relocated to Hopkinsville, Kentucky, in 1865. Owned four enslaved persons in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend=”italic”>The Biographical Encyclopædia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</hi>, vol. 1 (Cincinnati: J. M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), 360. <hi rend=”italic”>Memorial Records of Western Kentucky</hi>, vol. 1 (Chicago: The Lewis Publishing Company, 1904), 321-323. <hi rend=”italic”>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedule, Kentucky, Caldwell County, Princeton, p. 112. <hi rend=”italic”>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedule, Kentucky, Caldwell County, Princeton, p. 8. <hi rend=”italic”>Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, Hopkinsville, p. 11.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
