<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00006878">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Thomas J. Whitman</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00006878">
                    <persName>
                      Thomas J. Whitman
                        (Hart County, Kentucky, farmer)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1828-06-26"  ><ab>1828-06-26</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1901-06-11"  ><ab>1901-06-11</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Hart County, Kentucky, farmer. Kentucky native. Married to America S. Whitman. Father of Zarilda A. Whitman, Isabella C. Whitman, Ellen S. Whitman, Mary J. Whitman, and Willie G. Whitman. Married to Lucinda B. Whitman. Farmer in Hart County in 1850 and 1860. Owned one enslaved person in 1850 and six in 1860.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend=”italic”>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hart County, p. 253. <hi rend=”italic”>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Hart County, p. 437. <hi rend=”italic”>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hart County, District 2, p. 126. <hi rend=”italic”>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Hart County, District 2, p. 5. <hi rend=”italic”>Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Hart County, Munfordville, p, 17. <hi rend=”italic”>Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Thomas J. Whitman (1828-1901),&quot; Memorial #76144910, http://www.findagrave.com/memorial/76144910/T-WHIT (accessed June 5, 2017).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
