<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00001651">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Jacob Swigert, Sr.</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Courtney Buchkoski</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Samuel T. Whittaker</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00001651">
                    <persName>
                      Jacob Swigert, Sr.
                        (Frankfort, Kentucky, attorney, court clerk, and judge)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1793-07"></birth>
                      <death when="1869-03-24"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Frankfort, Kentucky, attorney, court clerk, and judge. Maryland native. Son of John Swigert and Mar Swigert. Married to Emeline Weisiger Swigert in April 1825. Father of Lucy Swigert, Emma Swigert, Daniel W. Swigert, and Helen Swigert. Married to Rebecca Johnson Swigert in May 1842. Father of Jacob Swigert, Jr., Samuel M. Swigert, and Joseph Swigert. Wrote in the Office of the Clerk of the Woodford County Court and Woodford Circuit Court from 1810 to 1814. Wrote in the Office of the Clerk of the Court of Appeals of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1814 to 1815. Studied law and admitted to the bar in 1816. Attorney in Frankfort from 1816 to 1825. Clerk of the Court of Appeals of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from 1825 to 1858. Member of the Masonic Order of Kentucky from 1829 to 1869. Member of the Methodist Episcopal Church, South from 1840 to 1869. Owned twenty-five enslaved persons in 1860. Judge of the Franklin County Court from 1862 to 1869.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1850), Population Schedule, Kentucky, Franklin County, District 1, p. 72; <em>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1860), Population Schedule, Kentucky, Franklin County, Frankfort, p. 81-82; <em>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</em> (1860), Slave Schedule, Kentucky, Franklin County, Frankfort, p. 23; <em>The Biographical Encyclopædia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</em>, vol. 1 (Cincinnati: J. M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), 116-17; <em>Find A Grave</em>, &quot;Judge Jacob Swigert (1793-1869),&quot; Memorial #68832982, http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=68832982&amp;ref=acom (accessed May 24, 2017).</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
