<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000840">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Decius C. Priest</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000840">
                    <persName>
                      Decius C. Priest
                        (Henderson County, Kentucky, farmer, constable, and sheriff)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1818"  certainty="medium" ><ab>c1818</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Henderson County, Kentucky, farmer, constable, and sheriff. Kentucky native. Son of John H. Priest. Married Martha H. Butler Priest on January 23, 1855. Father of Dora Priest, Elizabeth Priest, Virginia Priest, and John Priest. Farmer in Henderson County in 1850 and 1860. Owned four enslaved persons in 1860. Constable for Henderson County from 1856 to 1857. Sheriff of Henderson County in 1861. Farmer in Henderson County in 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl>Edmund L. Starling, <hi rend=”italic”>History of Henderson County, Kentucky</hi> (Henderson, KY: n.p., 1887), 822-823, 829, 831; <hi rend=”italic”>Kentucky Birth, Marriage, and Death Records, 1852-1910</hi>, Ancestry, Marriages, Henderson County, 1855; <hi rend=”italic”>Consolidated Lists of Civil War Draft Registration Records</hi> (Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau; Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865), NARA RG 110, Records of the Provost Marshal General&#39;s Bureau (Civil War), Consolidated Enrollment Lists, 1863-1865 (Civil War Union Draft Records), Henderson County, Kentucky, July 1863, p. 18, (Accessed via ancestry.com);  <hi rend=”italic”>Acts of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, Passed at the Session of the General Assembly Which Was Begun and Held in the City of Frankfort, on Monday, the Fourth Day of December, 1865</hi> (Frankfort, KY: George D. Prentice, 1866), ch. 657, p. 579; <hi rend=”italic”>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Henderson County, District 1, p. 583; <hi rend=”italic”>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Henderson County, Division 2, p. 27; <hi rend=”italic”>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Henderson County, Division 2, p. 5; <hi rend=”italic”>Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Daviess County, Curdsville, p. 54..
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
