<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00003091">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Richard T. Petree</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00003091">
                    <persName>
                      Richard T. Petree
                        (Hopkinsville, Kentucky, attorney and judge)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1824"  ><ab>1824</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1899"  ><ab>1899</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Hopkinsville, Kentucky, attorney and judge. Todd County, Kentucky, native. Son of Hazel G. Petree, Sr. and Sarah M. Petree. Married to Mary W. Hubbard Petree in 1854. Father of Betty H. Petree, Mary D. Petree, and Newton C. Petree. Educated at an academy in Elkton, Kentucky. Studied law under Francis M. Bristow. Admitted to the bar in 1848. Relocated to Hopkinsville. County attorney for Christian County from 1851 to 1859. Law partner of Francis M. Bristow in Hopkinsville. Law Partner of Benjamin H. Bristow in Hopkinsville from 1857 to 1861. Owned five enslaved persons in 1860. Judge of the 2nd Judicial District of Kentucky from 1862 to 1868.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl>H. Levin, <hi rend=”italic”>The Lawyers and Lawmakers of Kentucky</hi> (Chicago: The Lewis Publishing Company, 1897), 448; <hi rend=”italic”>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, Hopkinsville, p. 30-31; <hi rend=”italic”>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, Hopkinsville, p. 24; <hi rend=”italic”>Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Judge R. T. Petree (1824-1899),&quot; Memorial #89558809, http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=89558809&amp;ref=acom (accessed July 26, 2017).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
