<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000439">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Daniel S. Hays</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Samuel T. Whittaker</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000439">
                    <persName>
                      Daniel S. Hays
                        (Hopkinsville, Kentucky, attorney and notary public)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1796"  certainty="medium" ><ab>c1796</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1872-12-14"  ><ab>1872-12-14</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Hopkinsville, Kentucky, attorney and notary public. Virginia native. Married to Jane Hays on January 24, 1826. Father of John W. Hays, Mary L. Hays, Martha J. Hays, Henry Clay Hays, James D. Hays, Victoria Hays, and Daniel S. Hays, Jr. Corporal in Captain George McAfee&#39;s Company of Kentucky Militia in the War of 1812 from November 1814 to May 1815. Christian County Justice of the Peace. Christian County sheriff from 1847 to 1849. Owned one enslaved person in 1850. Attorney in Christian County in 1850 and 1860.  Served as a notary public for the Commonwealth of Kentucky at-large in 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl>William Henry Perrin, ed., <hi rend=”italic”>Counties of Christian and Trigg, Kentucky. Historical and Biographical</hi> (Chicago, IL: F. A. Battey Publishing Co., 1884), p. 56-57, 95-96. Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, District 1, p. 487. Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, District 1, p. 91. Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Christian County, Hopkinsville, p. 20. <hi rend=”italic”>War of 1812 Pension Application Files Index, 1812-1815</hi>, Ancestry, roll no. 43.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
