<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002159">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">William Barret Allen</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002159">
                    <persName>
                      William Barret Allen
                        (Greensburg, Kentucky, attorney, banker, and politician)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1803-05-19"  ><ab>1803-05-19</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1882-04-22"  ><ab>1882-04-22</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Greensburg, Kentucky, attorney, banker, and politician. Kentucky native. Married to Jane Pope Helm Allen. Married to Huldah Wilcox Allen. Married to Miley &quot;Millie&quot; N. Baker Allen. Father of Jane Allen, Harriet Allen, Edward P. Allen, Mary B. Allen, and Fanny B. Allen. Attended Athens Seminary in Greensburg, Kentucky, under the Rev. John Howe. Studied under Dr. James Priestly in Nashville, Tennessee. Teacher in Greensburg. Studied law under Samuel Brents and admitted to the bar. Member of the Whig Party. Postmaster in Greensburg from 1823 to 1828. Justice of the peace in Green County from 1828 to 1829. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky in Green County from 1829 to 1831. Attorney for the Bank of the Commonwealth at Greensburg in 1829. Editor of a Whig political and literary publication in 1834. Clerk of the Bank of Kentucky branch at Greensburg from 1835 to 1839. Master in Chancery for Green County in 1843. Cashier of the Bank of Kentucky branch at Greensburg from 1839 to 1857. Member of the Masonic Order in Kentucky. Most Worshipful Grand Master of the Grand Lodge of Kentucky from 1846 to 1847. Owned fourteen enslaved persons in 1850 and ten in 1860. Colonel of the 16th Regiment of Kentucky State Militia. Attorney in Greensburg from 1858 to 1862. County attorney for Green County from 1862 to 1874.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend=”italic”>The Biographical Encyclopædia of Kentucky of the Dead and Living Men of the Nineteenth Century</hi>, vol. 1 (Cincinnati: J. M. Armstrong &amp; Company, 1878), 76-77. <hi rend=”italic”>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, District No. 2. <hi rend=”italic”>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, District No. 2. <hi rend=”italic”>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, Greensburg District No. 2, p. 88. <hi rend=”italic”>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, Greensburg District No. 2, p. 19. <hi rend=”italic”>Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;William B. Allen (1803-1882),&quot; Memorial #106115556, http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=106115556 (accessed March 10, 2017). &quot;The Grand Lodge of Kentucky F. &amp; A.M.: Past Grand Masters,&quot; (https://grandlodgeofkentucky.org/?page_id=1330&amp;gmid=41) (accessed on September 6, 2017).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
