<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000224">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Curtis Field Burnam</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000224">
                    <persName>
                      Curtis Field Burnam
                        (Madison Co. State Rep)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1820-05-24"  ><ab>1820-05-24</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1909-03-19"  ><ab>1909-03-19</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Richmond, Kentucky, attorney and politician. Richmond native. Son of Thompson Burnam and Lucinda Field Burnam. Married to Sara Rollins Burnam. Father of Anthony R. Burnam, Robert R. Burnam, and Edmund T. Burnam. Graduated from Yale University in New Haven, Connecticut, in 1840. Studied law under Daniel Breck in Richmond, Kentucky. Graduated from law school at Transylvania University in Lexington, Kentucky, in 1842. Practiced law in partnership with William Clinton Goodloe in Richmond. Member of Richmond Masonic Lodge No. 25 in Richmond. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from Madison County from 1851 to 1853 and from 1859 to 1863. Attorney in Richmond in 1860. Owned eleven enslaved people in Richmond in 1860. </p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend=”italic”>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, Town of Richmond, p. 5; <hi rend=”italic”>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Madison County, Town of Richmond, p. 3; Robert R. Burnam, <hi rend=”italic”>A history of Masonry in Madison County, Kentucky, 1812-1913</hi> (n.p., 1914), 69-71; Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <hi rend=”italic”>Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 2 (Covington, Ky.: Collins &amp; Co., 1882), 494; <hi rend=”italic”>Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;Curtis Field Burnam (1820-1909),&quot; Memorial #33344480, https://www.findagrave.com/memorial/33344480 (accessed November 21, 2017).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
