<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00002508">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Theodore Dehon Rand</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Courtney Buchkoski</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00002508">
                    <persName>
                      Theodore Dehon Rand
                        (Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, soldier and attorney)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1837-09-16"  ><ab>1837-09-16</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1903-04-24"  ><ab>1903-04-24</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, soldier and attorney. Philadelphia native. Married to Margarette Emma Belrose in 1864. Educated at the Episcopal Academy in Philadelphia. Educated at the Polytechnic College. Served in Landis&#39; Independent Battery of Pennsylvania Light Artillery. Attorney in Philadelphia in 1860. Attorney at Bullitt &amp; Fairthorne in 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl>Compiled Service Records of Volunteer Union Soldiers who Served in Organizations From State of Pennsylvania<hi rend=”italic”>, NARA RG 94, Microfilm Series M554, Roll 0098; Thomas M. Drown, &quot;Biographical Notice of Theodore D. Rand&quot;, in _Transactions of the American Institute of Mining and Metallurgical Engineers</hi>, vol. 34 (New York: Institute of Mining and Metallurgical Engineers, 1904), 695-701; <hi rend=”italic”>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Pennsylvania, Philadelphia County, The Tenth Ward of Philadelphia, p. 189.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
