<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000207">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Joshua Fry Bell</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000207">
                    <persName>
                      Joshua Fry Bell
                        (Boyle Co. politician)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1811-11-26"  ><ab>1811-11-26</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1870-08-17"  ><ab>1870-08-17</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Boyle County, Kentucky, attorney and politician. Danville, Kentucky, native. Married to Mary M. Bell. Father of Mary Bell, Francis J. Bell, Thomas Bell, and Martha Bell. Graduated from Centre College in Danville in 1828. Member of the United States House of Representatives from the 4th Congressional District of Kentucky from 1845 to 1847. Member of the Whig Party. Attorney in Boyle County in 1850. Owned four enslaved people in 1850. Appointed Secretary of State of the Commonwealth of Kentucky by John J. Crittenden in 1850. Owned fourteen enslaved people in 1860. Delegate from Kentucky to the Washington Peace Conference in 1861. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from Boyle County from 1862 to 1867.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend=”italic”>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Boyle County, District No. 2, p. 362 B; <hi rend=”italic”>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Boyle County, District No. 2; <hi rend=”italic”>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Boyle County, Unnamed District, p. 17; <hi rend=”italic”>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Boyle County, Unnamed District, p. 5-6; <hi rend=”italic”>Report of the Kentucky Commissioners to the Late Peace Conference Held at Washington City, Made to the Legislature of Kentucky</hi> (Frankfort: Jno. B. Major, State Printer, 1861);  Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <hi rend=”italic”>Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 2 (Covington, Ky.: Collins &amp; Co., 1882), 85; Z. F. Smith, <hi rend=”italic”>The History of Kentucky (Centennial Edition)</hi> (Louisville: Courier-Journal Job Printing Company, 1892), 596; 
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
