<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000259">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Jefferson Finis Davis</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000259">
                    <persName>
                      Jefferson Finis Davis
                        (CS President)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1808-06-03"  ><ab>1808-06-03</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1889-12-06"  ><ab>1889-12-06</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>President of the Confederate States. Married to Sarah Knox Taylor Davis in 1835. Married to Varina Banks Howell Davis in 1845. Father of Samuel Emory Davis, Margaret Howell Davis Hayes, Jefferson Davis, Jr., Joseph Evan Davis, William Howell Davis, and Varina Anne Davis.  Educated at St. Thomas College in Springfield, Kentucky. Educated at Jefferson College in Adams County, Mississippi. Educated at Wilkinson County Academy in Woodville, Mississippi. Educated at Transylvania University in Lexington, Kentucky. Graduated from the United States Military Academy in West Point, New York, in 1828. Served in the U.S. Army in Missouri, Illinois, Iowa Territory, and Wisconsin Territory. Served as state Democratic presidential elector in 1844. Member of the United States House of Representatives for an At-large District of Mississippi from 1845 to 1846. Colonel in the 1st Mississippi Regiment, during the Mexican-American War, from 1846 and 1847. Member of the United States Senate from the State of Mississippi from 1847 to 1851 and 1857 to 1861. Secretary of War of the United States from 1853 to 1857. President of the Confederate States of America from February 9, 1861 to  May 5, 1865. Captured by Federal forces in Irwinville, Georgia, on May 10, 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl>The Paper of Jefferson Davis, s.v. “About Jefferson Davis: Chronology,” https://jeffersondavis.rice.edu (accessed October 24, 2016); The Papers of Jefferson Davis, s.v. “Geneaology of the Davis Family,” https://jeffersondavis.rice.edu/Genealogy.aspx (accessed October 24, 2016); William J. Cooper, Jefferson Davis, American (New York: Knopf, 2000); Joan Cashin, First Lady of the Confederacy (Cambridge: Belknap Press, 2006).
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
