<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000209">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Jonas Martin</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000209">
                    <persName>
                      Jonas Martin
                        (Lyon Co. State Rep)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1834"  ><ab>1834</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Lyon County, Kentucky, representative. Caldwell County, Kentucky, native. Son of Solomon W. Martin and Altezera Martin. Laborer in Caldwell County in 1850. Farmer in Lyon County, Kentucky, in 1860. Member of the House of Representatives of the Commonwealth of Kentucky from Livingston County, Kentucky, and Lyon County from 1862 to 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend=”italic”>Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky Caldwell County, District No. 1, p. 337; <hi rend=”italic”>Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Lyon County, Unnamed District, p. 30; Lewis Collins and Richard H. Collins, <hi rend=”italic”>Collins&#39; Historical Sketches of Kentucky</hi>, vol. 2 (Covington, Ky.: Collins &amp; Co., 1882), 479.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
