<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00007004">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Romeo Ezekiel North</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00007004">
                    <persName>
                      Romeo Ezekiel North
                        (Louisville, Kentucky, newspaper correspondent)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1830-03-27"  ><ab>1830-03-27</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1880-05-22"  ><ab>1880-05-22</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Louisville, Kentucky, newspaper correspondent. Bayou Lafourche, Louisiana, native. Son of Olivia North. Graduated from Yale College in 1849. Newspaper correspondent in Louisville in 1860. Member of the editorial staff of the <hi rend="italic">Louisville Courier</hi>. Special correspondent for the <hi rend="italic">New York Times</hi>. Member of the Jefferson County delegation to the Unconditional Union State Convention in Kentucky in 1864.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl>Franklin B. Dexter, <hi rend="italic">Addresses of the Living Graduates of Yale College: June, 1872</hi>, p. 38. <hi rend="italic">Record of the Graduated Members of the Class of 1849, of Yale College</hi> (New Haven: Hoggson &amp; Robinson, 1884), 30. <hi rend="italic">Obituary Record of Graduates of Yale College Deceased during the Academical Year ending in June, 1880</hi> (New Haven: Tuttle, Morehouse, &amp; Taylor, 1880), 404. &quot;Unconditional Union State Convention,&quot; <hi rend="italic">The Commonwealth</hi> (Frankfort, Ky.), May 27, 1864, p. 2. <hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, District 2, p. 46. <hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, Ward 4, p. 94. <hi rend="italic">Ninth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1870), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Jefferson County, Louisville, Ward 6, p. 65.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
