<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00000830">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Lazarus Whitehead Powell</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00000830">
                    <persName>
                      Lazarus Whitehead Powell
                        (Henderson attorney and politician)
                    </persName>
                      <birth when="1812-10-06"></birth>
                      <death when="1867-07-03"></death>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>A Kentucky attorney and politician. Graduated from the St. Joseph College in 1833 and studied law at Transylvania University.  Admitted to the bar in 1835 and practiced law in Henderson, Kentucky. Married to Harriet Anne Jennings Powell. Father of James Henry Powell, John Rowan Powell, Anne Powell, Charles J. Powell, and Richard Powell. Owned fifty-six enslaved persons in 1860. Served as a member of the Kentucky House of Representatives in 1836. Elected as a Democratic Party presidential elector in 1844. Elected and served as governor of Kentucky from 1851 to 1855. Served the Commonwealth of Kentucky as a Democratic member of the United States Senate from 1859 to 1865.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p><em>Biographical Directory of the United States Congress</em>, s.v. “Powell, Lazarus Whitehead,” (http://bioguide.congress.gov/scripts/biodisplay.pl?index=P000481) (accessed January 10, 2017); Charles Lanman, <em>Biographical Annals of the Civil Government of the United States</em> (Washington: J. M. Morrison, 1887), 403; “John William Menzies,” (http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=7092790) (accessed January 10, 2017); “The Death of Hon. Lazarus W. Powell,” <em>Daily Courier</em> (Louisville, Ky.), July 6, 1897; “Powell, Lazarus Whitehead,” <em>The Kentucky Encyclopedia</em>, ed. John E. Kleber (Lexington: University Press of Kentucky, 1992), 731-732; Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Henderson County, District No 1 (Town of Henderson); Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Henderson County, Division No 1, p. 35; Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States (1860), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Henderson County, Division No 1, p. 33-34.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
