<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DN00007762">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">John M. S. McCorkle</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Hannah M. O&#39;Daniel</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

      <encodingDesc>
        <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
          <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="$1.xml">
          </prefixDef>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
            <keywords>
                <term type="type">Person</term>
            </keywords>
        </textClass>
        <particDesc>
                <person xml:id="N00007762">
                    <persName>
                      John M. S. McCorkle
                        (Greensburg, Kentucky, bank clerk)
                    </persName>
                        <event type="birth"  when="1799"  cert="medium" ><ab>c1799</ab></event>
                        <event type="death"  when="1875-03-05"  ><ab>1875-03-05</ab></event>
                        <trait type="race" subtype="White"/>
                      <trait type="gender" subtype="M"/>
                </person> 
        </particDesc>    
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Greensburg, Kentucky, bank clerk. Pennsylvania native. Married to Jane L. B. McCorkle. Father of Elizabeth R. McCorkle, Aylett McCorkle, Flora McCorkle, Daisy McCorkle, Louise P. McCorkle, Jennie McCorkle, Eugene McCorkle, and Viola McCorkle. Attorney in Green County, Kentucky, in 1850. Grandmaster of the Grand Lodge of Kentucky from 1850 to 1851. Owned eight enslaved persons in 1850. Bank clerk in Greensburg in 1860. Grand secretary of the Masonic Lodge of Kentucky from 1859 to 1861. Notary public in Greensburg in 1863.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, District No. 2, p. 155. <hi rend="italic">Seventh Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1850), Slave Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, District No. 2, p. 230; <hi rend="italic">Eighth Manuscript Census of the United States</hi> (1860), Population Schedules, Kentucky, Green County, Greensburg, District No. 2, p. 91-92. <hi rend="italic">Transaction of the Grand Lodge of Free and Accepted Mason of the State of Michigan</hi> (Detroit: Free Press Book and Job Printing House, 1861), p. 75. &quot;The Grand Lodge of Kentucky F. &amp; A.M.,&quot;  https://grandlodgeofkentucky.org/?page<hi rend="italic">id=1330&amp;gmid=45 (accessed on September 5, 2017). _Find A Grave</hi>, &quot;John M. S. McCorkle (1799-1875),&quot; Memorial #157586453, http://www.findagrave.com/cgi-bin/fg.cgi?page=gr&amp;GRid=157586453&amp;ref=acom (accessed September 5, 2017). KYR-0001-029-0557. KYR-0001-031-0251.
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
