<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="DO00003448">
    <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title level="a" type="main">Provisional Government of Kentucky</title>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="created">Created by:</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
          </respStmt>        
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Anthony P. Curtis</name>
          </respStmt>
          <respStmt>
            <resp n="edited">Edited by:</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
          </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
        <availability><p>All research and writing of Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition annotations was undertaken by project staff, volunteers, and interns. Each record contains citations to relevant primary and secondary source material. All annotations are copyright Kentucky Historical Society, and should be referenced as such in any published work.</p></availability>
    </publicationStmt>
    <seriesStmt>
        <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Project Director</resp>
            <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
        </respStmt>
    </seriesStmt>
    <sourceDesc><ab>Born Digital</ab></sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>

        <encodingDesc>
            <listPrefixDef xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" xml:id="inc_global_prefixDef">
                <prefixDef ident="cwgk" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="../biography_xml/$1.xml">
                </prefixDef>
            </listPrefixDef>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <textClass>
                <keywords>
                    <term type="type">Organization</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
            <particDesc>
                <org xml:id="O00003448">
                    <orgName>Provisional Government of Kentucky</orgName>
                      <event type="begun" when="1861-11-18">1861-11-18</event>
                      <event type="ended" when="1865-05-05">1865-05-05</event>
                </org>
            </particDesc>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
    <body>
        <p>Formed at a secession convention in Russellville, Kentucky, on November 18, 1861. The interim constitution called for a governor and a governing council of ten until statewide elections could be held. George W. Johnson was elected provisional governor.  The Provisional Government of Kentucky was recognized and admitted to the Confederacy on December 10, 1861. The Provisional Government governed from its capital at Bowling Green, Kentucky, until February 1862. Provisional Governor George W. Johnson was mortally wounded at the Battle of Shiloh on April 7, 1861. Richard Hawes became provisional governor at Corinth, Mississippi, on May 31, 1862. Hawes was inaugurated at the state capitol in Frankfort, Kentucky, on October 4, 1862, though Confederate forces were forced to retreat from Frankfort that day. Following the Confederate retreat from Kentucky, Hawes was never again in the state until the end of the war, residing at various times in Tennessee, Georgia, and Virginia.</p>

    </body>
    <back>
        <ab><bibl><p>J. P. Burnside and P. B. Thompson, eds., <em>Proceedings of the Convention Establishing Provisional Government of Kentucky</em> (Augusta, GA: Steam Press of Chronicle and Sentinel, 1863). Lowell H. Harrison, &quot;George W. Johnson and Richard Hawes: The Governors of Confederate Kentucky&quot; <em>Register of the Kentucky Historical Society</em> 79, no. 1 (Winter 1981): 3-39.</p>
</bibl></ab>
    </back>
</text>
</TEI>
