<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1685"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Willis G. Hughes and D. H. Hughes to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11153</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Andrew P Patrick</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-366 to MG22-367</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Morganfield, Union County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-02-08">8 February 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Morganfeld
<lb/><date when="1862-02-08">Feby 8' 1862</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency 
<lb/>Govr Magoffin
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>Vincent Shields is &amp; has been for over two years confined in the Penitentiary of this state and was sentenced for 10 years.</p>
<p>We respectfully <hi rend="str">to</hi> suggest to you that is our opinion Sheilds case is one that deserves and ought to receive Executive Clemency -- He was charged with the murder of his wife, she was found by Shields in Trade water, was pulled to shore by him, and then he went to the neighbors for assistance first going to a <hi rend="str">sh</hi> school house near by, where all of his children were at school except two small infants -- the neighbors assisted in taking the body to the house, when she was washed &amp; dressed and then a Coroners inquest held over the body, whose verdict was that she had come to her death by drowning, she was buried -- and some days thereafter the body was exhumed, and a partial indeed a very slight Post Mortem examination made and the opinion given by the physicians that her neck had been broken by violence, on this Sheilds was arrested and tried as her murderer and sentenced to the Penitentiary for 10 years If Sheilds was guilty the Gallows was too good for him, if innocent his fate is a hard one indeed -- </p>
<p>A Short summary of the evidence will show<pb/>
<lb/>in our opinion how hard the verdict was -- </p>
<p>It was in proof by many witnesses that Mrs Sheilds had been subject to verry severe <unclear/> of Insanity for over 20 years, during which no Control Could be exercised over her, and while thus afflicted she would make a great &amp; loud noise that could &amp; had been heard for miles off, as if the surest kind of punishment, was being <hi rend="str">afflicted up</hi> inflicted upon her -- this had caused many of the women in the neighborhood to conclude Sheilds was in the habit of punishing his wife very severely, and had of course murdered her, but the proof of two of his &amp; her Daughters both fully grown, and two sons nearly grown, as will as many other persons that were in the habit of visiting Sheilds house, that his treatment to her was always kind, and affectionate -- It was proven by his two Sons above refered to that on the morning of the day of her death, she went down to Tradewater her usual place of washing in Company with these sons who went along to carry the clothes &amp; <unclear/>, and to make her a fire, <hi rend="str">aft</hi> leaving her there, they returned to the house and then went to school leaving the two small children at the house, &amp; their father at work in a field nearly a mile off from the place of washing -- the two daughters above refered to were married and living off at some distance After Sheilds was arrested &amp; during his trial before the examining Court, under our advice her body was reexumed and a through Post Mortim examiniation had by those <hi rend="str">of</hi> of as able Physicians as the County afforded Howard, Say &amp; Graves all of whom testified that there was no fracture or dislocation of the neck, and that she died of drowning but on the final trial Shields was deprived of the evidence of these Physicians owing<pb/>
<lb/>to their absence -- except the evidence of Dr Howard which we read by agreement as it had been taken down at the examining Court, which was a <unclear/> meager out line.</p>
<p>Mr Sheilds Brother Mathew Sheilds of Spencer County will present to you a large Petition from the Citizens of this County, among whom are We balance of the names of all save one who took an active part in the prosecution -- And we believe it is now the universal desire of the Citizens of this County that he should be Pardoned and nearly every body believes his punishment is unjust -- </p>
<p>We send you the Petition of 9 of the Jury who tried Shields asking his Pardon, the other three are dead &amp; removed -- </p>
<p>Hoping it will meet your views to grant this Pardon we remain Respy</p>
<p>Your Friends
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Willis G Hughes</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">D H Hughes</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
