<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-027-0013"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William R. Fleming to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1246</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R2-18 to R2-19</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lexington, Fayette County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-08-21">21 August 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Hon. James. F. Robinson
<lb/>My dear Sir</p>
<p>I write you at the earnest solicitation of my My Bro-Inlaw D<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Samuel Maguire of Fleming County, who is Capt of some 65 home guards -- who are the most Loyal men of the State, and who are entirely without arms. They have in two instances been called upon to meet a rebel force passing through their County &amp; the County of Bath to join -- Humphrey Marshall -- many of them shouldered what squirrel rifles they could borrow from their neighbours with a warning of only a few hours -- many of them travelling on foot a distance of 40 miles in order to disperse the enemy, many of them applied to me in<pb/>
<lb/>person a few days since and desire if possible to have arms placed in their hands, so they can fight the battles of their Government &amp; State,</p>
<p>I know many of them personally, &amp; know that a truer or braver people does not inhabit this beautiful world of ours. Can you send them 50 stand of arms at once -- they are in my opinion entitled to them &amp; should receive them.</p>
<p>My Brother Inlaw D<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Maguire will be responsible for th<hi rend="str">em</hi>e safe return of the arms sent. They are wanted for a section of Country lying in the direction of Morgan, Carter &amp; Lawrence Counties where many rebels pass to join the Southern Confederacy -- excuse me for thus troubling you -- but my apology must be the exigency of<pb/>
<lb/>the case.</p>
<p>Congratulating you &amp; our State upon the position you have been called upon to occupy</p>
<p>I am my dear sir
<lb/>Your attached friend
<lb/>Wm. R. Fleming</p>
<p>P S. 
<lb/>The boxes containing the guns mark.
<lb/>D<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Samuel Maguire
<lb/>Poplar. Plains
<lb/>Fleming County
<lb/>Ky</p>
<p>Lexington Ky
<lb/><date when="1862-08-21">Aug. 21. 1862</date><pb/></p>
<p>Will. R Fleming
<lb/>Lex
<lb/>arms 50 asked for home guard in Fleming</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
