<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-022-0050"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">S. W. Hunt to John W. Finnell</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11975</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>37th - 76th Regiments Enrolled Militia Primary Source Documents (1861-1866)</collection>
      <idno>Box 80, Folder 862-64 HENRY COUNTY History 51st Rgt. Ky. Militia</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1862-09-11">11 September 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Head Quarters "Defenders"
<lb/>Col. Morris Three Months Men
<lb/>Camp Recovery <date when="1862-09-11">11 Sept 1862</date>
<lb/>To the Adjutant General
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>please inform his Excellency that I brought my men here last night by rail together with our arms and ammunition. Today the field piece with our cavalry arrived <hi rend="str">and</hi></p>
<p>The moment of my arrival I barricaded the entrances to this place and stationed strong guards at each ^entrance^ thereby thwarting an intruder attack by guerillas who as I learn today had arranged to enter the town ^last night^ by two or three detachments. Squards of two and three ^each^ of these marauders visted a number of places ^last night^ within four miles of this and stole horses. By a rough estimate I should say that 100 horses had been stolen from this county and 50 recruits secured for the enemy since I was called to Louisville last Saturday.</p>
<p>Our arrival produced great consternation among them<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">2</note>
<lb/>and today they are hurrying from all directions towards Frankfort. If we can gather in our forces rapidly we hope to prevent their return to this county.</p>
<p>Today I mustered in my first company, Capt G. W Sewalls. The men are chiefly from Henry Co and exiles. 2 Other companies will be ready by the <date when="---13">13<hi rend="sup">th</hi>.</date></p>
<p>We captured 2 horses (one a valuable mare) left in the neighborhood this morning by the haste of their owners who were out stealing others. If I had 200 good horsemen today I could bag a number of them</p>
<p><date when="1862-09-12">Sept 12 1862</date></p>
<p>This morning I send a detachment of 26 men under Capt Luckett to Henry Co. under the following orders.</p>
<p>"<hi rend="underline">Ordered</hi> that Lt. Luckett is hereby detached in charge of a squad for the purpose of Recruiting the First Regiment of Kentucky State<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">3</note>
<lb/>Guards encamped at this place for the ostensible purpose set forth in our bills. He is authorized to press such horses as will be suitable for cavalry service, capture arms, and arrest every man who has taken an active part in favor of the Southern Confederacy. and Report to thire Head Quarters"</p>
<p>S. W. Hunt L<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Col.
<lb/>Comg State Guards.</p>
<p><date when="1862-09-13">Sept 13. 1862</date></p>
<p>Ammunition for the field peice arrived.</p>
<p>Our detachment returned at day light bringing 3 prisoners viz James Ferguson of Henry to charged with being on his way to join the Southern Army.</p>
<p>Abbott charged with the same</p>
<p>Smith charged with abetting the rebellion.</p>
<p>Also <hi rend="str">a m</hi> 10 horses and a number of recruits. Capt Luckett raised the Union Flag in Newcastle, the previous one having been torn down<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">4</note>
<lb/>by a squad of Secessionists and used for a saddle blanket. He visited Campbellsburg and made arrangements for recruiting the Home Guards for my Regiment. Every where the loyal citizens received them with joy and ample hospitabilities were tendered him.</p>
<p>I hope to make similar demonstrations tomorrow in the direction of Shelbyville and Bedford. It is needed to remove the paralyzing fear which the guerilla system has spread over the land.</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>Rob Morris
<lb/>Col. Comg</p>
<p>Hd. Qrs. Col. Morris'
<lb/>3 mo's men.
<lb/><date when="1862-09-11">Sep. 11'62</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Morris Robt.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Affairs in the vicinity of his camp.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
