<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0054"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Mason Brown to Daniel W. Lindsey</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14083</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1864</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Paducah, McCracken County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-09-16">16 September 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Paducah Ky <date when="1864-09-16">16<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sep 1864</date>
<lb/>Dear Dan</p>
<p>The work to be done here looms up bigger and bigger daily -- I don't think that Warren Hastings administration in India could present greater enormities of oppression, outrage and wholesale plunder, than Paines brief reign of terror in this end of Kentucky. Civil officers who have, for forty years, filled office in all integrity and honor, have been cursed as a humane man would not curse a dog, and ordered with sanguinary threats to resign -- They have shown manhood enough to meet the emergency with dignity to themselves, and their people, and refuse even to plead innocent in the absence of charges. They braved Paine out; but could not, I fear, have endured much longer. Business houses were shut up, all rents of property diverted into the hands of the local military, enormous fines -- in one instance as high as 9000 dollars -- levied and only prevented from being collected by Gen Merediths providential arrival -- Men have been shot by Paine, without trial, for offences of which a regular military court had acquitted them</p>
<p>In short a reign of terror, such as no one can conceive who has not witnessed it, existed </p>
<p>We already have a mass of affidavits<pb/>
<lb/>large enough as my Quarter Master would say "to burn a wet mule. The proof will be overwhelming -- Anderson, Bolinger &amp;Co have managed very shrewdly Possibly they may escape altogether but we will if possible trip them.</p>
<p>Craddock has proved invaluable -- We could not have gotten along at all without him -- His efficiency and resoluteness cannot be too highly praised -- </p>
<p>We may be detained until <date when="--10-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Oct</date> but are straining every nerve by day and night to get through. Proof comes pouring in -- </p>
<p>Gen Paine &amp; Capt Paine (his son and A A G) have both tendered their resignations -- They left 5 or 6 hours before our arrival -- </p>
<p>Gen Meredith gives great satisfaction and talks properly -- I hope and believe he will hold out -- </p>
<p>Present my compliments to the Governor and Gen Suddarth -- Drop me a line to this place</p>
<p>Yours very truly
<lb/>Jno mason Brown<pb/></p>
<p>Paducah Ky 
<lb/><date when="1864-09-16">Sept 16" 1864</date>-<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Brown Jno. Mason<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Private<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The work to be done looms up more &amp; more daily. Paines reign was a brief reign of unequaled terror and oppression. Business houses were shut up &amp; rents of property directed into local military hands -- fines enormous, in one instance as much as $9000 was levied, but collection prevented by providential arrival of Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Meredith. Men were shot for offenses of which a military court had acquitted them. Have large mass of affidavits, proof is overwhelming. Anderson, Bolinger &amp;Co. managed very shrewdly, may escape but will trip them if possible -- Craddock has proved invaluable could not have gotten along without him. May be detained until <date when="--10-01">1" oct</date>. will get through as soon as possible Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Paine &amp; Capt Paine his son tendered resignations, they left 5 or 6 hours before we arrived. Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Meredith gives satisfaction &amp; talks properly -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>L B N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 7 -- <date when="1864">1864</date> P. 35<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Rec<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> A. G. O. <date when="1864-09-23">Sept 23" 1864</date> -- </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
