<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3471"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James W. Lyarnatt et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5590</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-396 to BR42-397</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Crittenden County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlett
<lb/>Govenor of the Commonwealth of kentucky <hi rend="str">15</hi><hi rend="str"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi></p>
<p>Your Petitioner William Morgan would respectfully represent that on the <date when="1865-11-15">15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of November 1865</date> The Grand Jury of Crittenden County in the State of Kentucky accused Franklin Gibson William Morgan the petitioner Stephen Young and George Pilant of the offence of Forciably Rescueing one James Guesst from the Jail of Crittenden county where he was lawfully detained upon a charge of Felony, Now your petitioner would State that he is in no wise guilty of the charge made against them in the sd Indictment he denies most posatively that he gave either aid, or counsel, or in anywise abetted the party who did Rescue the said Guesst, that he is not guilty of said charge in whole or in part wherefore he prays that your Excellency will interpose and grant him a full pardon against said charge</p>
<p>And we the undersigned petitioners would Represent that we are acquainted with William Morgan, who is a Young man but Just grown to manhood, Raised in this community an orphan without father or mother, has hither to bourn a good character<pb/></p>
<p>Served a term in the Federal army, was a brave and gallant Soldier, and now at home he is a peaceable quiet citizen and in our opinion is not guilty of the act charged is poor and unable to have himself properly defended Wherefore we ask for him the executive clemency</p>
<p>James W. Lyarnatt
<lb/>Leander H Hughes
<lb/>J J Hughes
<lb/>J. H. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clusky
<lb/>D. C. Baird
<lb/>James T. Jones
<lb/>W. J. L. Hughes
<lb/>J J Hughes Sen
<lb/>A Anderson Marion
<lb/>W. S. Clark
<lb/>Jesse F Paris
<lb/>L A Ghent
<lb/>Isaacs Spur
<lb/>A. J. Baker
<lb/>G. S. james
<lb/>Robt Whalen
<lb/>Jas Threlkeld
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> F Parris
<lb/>R. L. Clark
<lb/>Lewis. H. Parris<pb/>
<lb/>S. C. Young
<lb/>W J Paris
<lb/>Jesse Baird
<lb/>M S Richardson
<lb/>F A Duncan
<lb/>G Porter
<lb/>William Nothiam
<lb/>E. M Duncan
<lb/>W. B. Lernen
<lb/>H S Brainert
<lb/>R L Brainert
<lb/>F charatening
<lb/>Elisha Conger
<lb/>J T Conger
<lb/>James W Paris
<lb/>L B Hunt
<lb/>E D Brawner
<lb/>B D Brawner
<lb/>G. W. Howerton
<lb/>H B Jones
<lb/>John R Boyd
<lb/>J C Pulyers
<lb/>L. C. Travis
<lb/>F E Criden
<lb/>Nathan Gravy<pb/></p>
<p>Crittenden C't C't
<lb/>vs
<lb/>F. Gibson, W. Morgan, S. Young &amp; G. Pilant.</p>
<p>William Morgan
<lb/>} Petition</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
