<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2408"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Oliver A. Patton to Richard T. Jacob</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7045</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-347 to BR15-350</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Flemingsburg, Fleming County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-04">4 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Flemingsburg Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1865-09-04">Sep 4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>. Monday.
<lb/>Governor Jacobs,</p>
<p>I thank you from the abundance of a full heart for your Kind letter which you must suffer me to believe promises much joy to me until the effort has been made -- an fails In any event sir You have my sentiments of the most unaffected gratitude. Your sympathy for me finds its source in regard for those more-worthy than myself, and I trust when the lights are all before Your Excelency You will feel that great injustice is done me and that magnanamous spirit you have manifested toward those were once your foes in arms will open your convictions of a greater merit than some of my enemies of the Union party attribute to me If I can gain your good opinion I will feel that I have accomplished much for myself even should your efforts in my behalf prove futile</p>
<p>Governor I left my home in good faith upon the covniction that my honor &amp; duty called me to the defense of the South. By birth and education a Southerner -- the cavalier stock. I was thoroughly embued with the doctrine of Mr Calhoun of an impetuous and firey nature. A warm admirer of Genl John S Williams whom I assisted <hi rend="str">from</hi> upon the stump in the canvass for Congress in 1861.<pb/>
<lb/>against Mr Wadsworth. When Genl Williams entered the confederate army I followed him and have been immediately identified with him throughout our unfortunate career. It was my delight to conform to that gallant hero's wishes And I am sure that Your Excelency regards him if acquainted with him as a princely gentleman and honorable foe In any case is an illustration of Lord Byrons words.
<lb/>"violent things will sooner bear assuaging -- 
<lb/>Their fury being spent by its own shock"
<lb/>Twice have I bled and lingered in Military prisons. But sir I am proud to say that my treatment of fallen foes was better than that I received Many have fallen in to my hands and all of them are now my friends I know and would willingly disapprove The proceedings against me -- I am certain that there is not a soldier in the U. S. Army who regards me in any other light than that of a fair &amp; honorable foe -- I do not believe that I am vicious (you will pardon this egotism) or disposed to injure any one -- There is not a man with-in the limits of this commonwealth who believes me capable of so ignominious a crime and cowardly act as stealing the property of my fellow citizens. Your friends my mother &amp; Sisters are standing contradictions of such a presumption I have never sought to conceal any act which I have committed I am willing that the world should know and I tell<pb/>
<lb/>your exelency that I seized the horses -- and in the statement which I have prepared I tell you <hi rend="underline">why</hi>. &amp; took them the "res gesta" of any alleged crime is the '<hi rend="underline">intention, at the time</hi> <hi rend="underline">the</hi> <hi rend="underline">act</hi> <hi rend="underline">was</hi> <hi rend="underline">committed</hi>. I was acting under orders at the time of the taking. -- The taking a necessity -- it was to mount my men &amp; myself belonging as we did to the Cavalry Service -- But for all the taking I have done I have amply atoned in preventing depredations of a more serious character which many would testify to if you now constituted a court of inquiry --. Two men of rebel proclivities for personal revenge are at the bottom of the <hi rend="str">trial</hi> proceedings -- Union men denounce the trial as unwarrantable. This Col Wies my atty will say to you -- One of these men I cursed for prosecuting a rebel surgeons wife &amp; family during his absence -- The other for annoying me about the Union Mans horse which was ridden by one of my men -- It was evidently through their influence that the Grand jury took any action against me -- for I cannot believe that the union citizens generally would treat me thus after my kind disposition toward them. I rest this matter with you feeling that when you are better advised of me than you are now that you will relieve me of a burden of humiliation and unjust cruelty. And more than all cheer the Sad<pb/>
<lb/>and aching hearts that have experienced Four long years of cruel separation for a common hearth. during which time I have seen my mother &amp; sisters but once -- "My heart pants for them as the wounded hart for the cooling waterbrook" I wish to be with them and live for them a usefull and valuable member of society -- I cannot I will not haunt the declining years of my noble parents with dark green shadows of dishonor. If my fellow-men do me the injustice to determine that I am unfit for society I will add and for the world then will follow the only remedy to save my name from ignominy | shame Such a result of an investigation cannont come but the fore fact of being arraigned &amp; tried for such offences as those with which I am charged has a terror for me more dreadfull than the sally or the "charge." -- </p>
<p>By your magnanimity those who are disposed to pursue us to the scaffold for our "rebellious" acts, as a <hi rend="underline">pretext</hi> will be taught that though we overpowered "rebels" are of clay that we are not quite of mud -- And it will also gently hint to them that "urns &amp; pipkins are but fragile brothers,
<lb/>And works of the same potter bad or good
<lb/>Tho' not all born of the same sires &amp; mothers"
<lb/>As to my self (the humble subject of this annoyance to your Excelency.) I am ready to accept the new order of things and render unto the United States -- <pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">(2)</note>
<lb/>And to Kentucky all my devotion and loyalty.</p>
<p>And to the <hi rend="underline">honor</hi>, <hi rend="underline">Dignity</hi>, &amp; <hi rend="underline">interest</hi> of the old commonwealth devote myself, which I regard as entitled to her sovereign rights now as before the war. And claim the same rights which I at any time enjoyed prior to my participation in the war -- When I felt my self as I do now a Kentuckian. Such a policy as your course indicates will restore peace, harmony &amp; good will among the people of both sections the contrary will have us back again to chaos -- and create a superstratum which will over lay us -- change the nature of the southern people and they may be taught that they should bow the head an wear sack "cloth &amp; ashes."</p>
<p>Sir they honor such a spirit as yours and their gratitude wells to the throat, and strangles its own utterance The banquet to which you invite them is acceptible, and can consistently give you the fraternal hand of affection. And drink -- "The Union" But the radical doctrine of the puritans can neither persuade nor coerce -- It is a most vile and heartless foe who will not raise his prostrate enemy, even in the heat of battle. And now when time is given for reflection and consideration it must be a remorseless &amp; depraved soul who will not recognize Gods allmighty truth. that white men<pb/>
<lb/>at least are equal -- &amp; sovereign States are equal That now that the magnificent army has accomplished its destiny we occupy the same relation to the government of the United States that we did years ago. Such were the objects of the immense army &amp; treasure. The Southern people recognize the fact that was desired, and why embarrass their expression of it -- </p>
<p>There are ulcers on the political body. North &amp; South there still are still symptoms of inflammation -- That genteel class who know nothing of War. I wish these elements could be brought into conflict. I am sanguine that those who have fought would shake hands together and all cry "Lay on Macduff &amp;c. I am very anxious to see further developments of the administrative policy -- God grant that it may be conceived in justice if not in concession &amp; compromise -- </p>
<p>I did not design to bore your excellency with so long a scroll -- when I began You will please pardon a few more words in relation to my self as I have <hi rend="underline">directly</hi> asked nothing. I therefore come directly to the point And ask your excelency to influence, the chief executieve to order a Nolla prosaqui in cases No 1. No 2. No 3. No 4. No 5. Indictments found in the Fleming Circuit Court -- <pb/>
<lb/>by the Grand jury of the county of Fleming -- </p>
<p>The same in the Kenton circuit court in one case -- All of the said cases being indictments by the Commonwealth against Oliver A Patton for "<hi rend="underline">Horse</hi> <hi rend="underline">Stealing</hi>" And order my immediate release from Custody.</p>
<p>Governor I beg leave to urge the earliest possible disposition of the matter as I am very uncomfortably situated Tho' my friends have proposed to bail me I thought it politic to remain in custody in order to avoid perhaps other indictments for the same offenses as my ruthless enemies could not in the event of a trial expect a verdict of guilty &amp; they will continue satisfied so long as they can harrass me</p>
<p>Several cases of this kind have been tried in this court with-out any result the jury invariably refusing any verdict at all. and a decision in my cases would be aquitted or a hanging of the jury -- From the further annoyances incident to such results as have been always attendant. From the humiliation and embarrassment, of a trial, I pray your Excelency to have me delivered. And forever will my mother &amp; sisters My Father My Friends and my humble self bless you -- I beg this liberty of writing again in a few days -- and soon<pb/>
<lb/>will I cease to annoy you with my petty complaints</p>
<p>Again I thank you
<lb/>Your verry Gratefull &amp; Obedent Svt
<lb/>Oliver A. Patton</p>
<p>Fleming Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>O. A. Patton
<lb/>5 indictments
<lb/>Kenton Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>O A. Patton
<lb/>1 Indictment
<lb/>Horse Stealing
<lb/>Pardoned
<lb/>Offense
<lb/><date when="1865-10-05">5 Oct 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
