<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0220"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">M. Hill et al. to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8672</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-333</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Carter County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Carter County, Sct</p>
<p>To His Excellency The Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky the under signed petitioners would respectfully represent to your Excellency that James M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Glochlin of Carter County Ky. was fined $20 for retailing whisky before Isaac Burton a Justice of the peace for said County; Now we petition you to remit said fine for these reasons <hi rend="str">that</hi> (to wit) First he did not own nor never did own any whisky or in fact ever sell any whisky for himself in the County or state The facts about the selling is this Mr M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Glochlin was hired to work for a poor widow woman and she had some Little Liquor to sell maybe a half a barrel and when he was at his meals when at work there were persons came to get Some whisky and the widow Lady was at other work and he was requested by her to draw whiskey twice which he did but went away immediately to his imployment or work we further state that said M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Glochlin says that ^he^ never did sell any whisKy. for himself nor he never intends to do so in violation of the Law Mr M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Glochlin is a poor man a good Loyal citizen and we think it extremely hard for Mr M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Glochlin to ^pay^ said fine as he was not selling for a proffit nor for him self it was only an accident he <hi rend="str">sold</hi> ^drawd^ the whisky at all at the instance of the Lady and such relief we shall ever pray.</p>
<p>M Hill
<lb/>Jno Boggs<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>C P Davis
<lb/>T. Thomason
<lb/>C. M. Gee
<lb/>J T Shepherd
<lb/>Samuel Osenton
<lb/>J, B, Ward
<lb/>Moses <unclear>utterwealth</unclear>
<lb/>G, W, Everman
<lb/>Brad Elseck
<lb/>Gerg W. Moner
<lb/>W R Shepherd
<lb/>Lerzo Young
<lb/>Richard. P. Hyrne
<lb/>Wesley Vaughn
<lb/>Henry Easterling
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> V. Barnes,
<lb/>R Blankenship
<lb/>S, H, Young
<lb/>William P Scott
<lb/>Capt Jordan Neithercutt
<lb/>William young
<lb/>John H. Ramey
<lb/>B. F. Crawford
<lb/>Gr<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi> Littlejohn
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Wiley Hill
<lb/>Elihu Boggs
<lb/>Jas Flawher
<lb/>J K. Flawher
<lb/>A. J Scott
<lb/>R D Davis
<lb/>Wiley Prichard
<lb/>G W Prichard
<lb/>John Galleher<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Grayson Carter County Ky <date when="1863-02-19">Feb 19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date> To J F Robertson Governor of the Commonwealth of Ky.</p>
<p>Dear Sir You will find enclosed a petition signed by many good citizens of Our County asking you to remit a fine of $20. Now from the circumstances that Mr M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Glochlin is entirely inocent of the charge I think his case Kneeds your clemency, and I hope he will be able to receive it from you</p>
<p>Yours with due regard
<lb/><hi rend="underline">E P, Davis</hi></p>
<p>Carter J. P. Ct<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>James M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Glouchlin
<lb/>Carter County Pettn to remit fine
<lb/>J. P.
<lb/>$20 } Liquor</p>
<p>Fine all remitted except Ten dollars</p>
<p>J F Robinson
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-03-17">Mar 19. 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
