<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0493"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. F. Mitchell to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8945</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-286 to R4-287</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-07-08">8 July 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><date when="1863-07-08">July the 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>To Gov Roberson
<lb/>Frankford Ky</p>
<p>your Petitioner would respectfully state that at the <date when="--06">June</date> term of the Caldwell Circuit Court he was tried upon an indictment for a breach of the peace Committed by beating one W H Flood that your Petitioner did not appear and defend said charge from the fact that he lives in the County of Livingston that the time of holding said Court had sliped the memory of him that said Court Commenced on the second Monday of <date when="1863-06">June 1863</date> that your Petitioner thought it Commenced on the thired Monday of said Month that acting under that impression he appeared in Court on that day and then for the first time discovered his mistake that a trial of his case had already taken place and your Petitioner find $225 <hi rend="sup">00</hi>/<hi rend="sub">100</hi> that the trial was exparte that your Petitioner had already employed a lawyer to defend him who in his absense failed so to do, that you Petitioner had one witness subpeanied who was not examined on his behalf that he had two other witnesses who knew the facts as herein after stated but they have departed this life that the facts are about these the difficulty took place in your Petitioner own house that he returned home one<pb/>
<lb/>evening and found his sister Flood's wife weeping &amp; Flood with a large knife drawn saying that he had whipped her and intended to kill her that your Petitioner reasoned with him against his conduct that thereupon he threatened to kill your Petitioner and your Petitioner then beat him very badly he states that he could have proved this on the trial had it not been for the misfortune as above stated that he is a poor man with a family &amp; the fine is unjust &amp; a hardship that the facts above stated are strictly true were fore he prays that said fine be remitted</p>
<p>W F Mitchell</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to be W F, Mitchel before me this <date when="1863-07-08">8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> July 1863</date></p>
<p>A Beverly J P L.C</p>
<p>We the undersigned believe the statements above made are true that we know the Petitioner to be a sober hard working &amp; honest man &amp; join in his prayer for relief</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>C Bennett
<lb/><hi rend="underline">M. H. Carson</hi>
<lb/>N. H. Bigham
<lb/>J. L Powell
<lb/>J, H. Ford
<lb/>Benjamin Barnes
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> H,, Webb.
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Tom M Davis</hi>
<lb/>J A, f, Given
<lb/><cb n="2"/>C Haynes C J C
<lb/>L Johnson
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J. W. Richardson</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">L. B. Bohanam</hi>
<lb/>Thos Croker
<lb/>J S Bertoli
<lb/>W, C, Ellis
<lb/>J. S. Leffler
<lb/>James Stroud<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>E, R, Haynes
<lb/>J C Leech
<lb/>R. H Clopten
<lb/>A. A. Prayott
<lb/>W D Covington
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> J Jennings
<lb/><hi rend="underline">A. Larrett</hi> D. P. M.
<lb/>P W Quan
<lb/>C, R,, Hayward
<lb/>J, W, Mills
<lb/>J. Patterson
<lb/>Tylon Elliott
<lb/>William <unclear/>
<lb/>Blount Hodge
<lb/>A, Elmore
<lb/>W Beverly J P
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Jo<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> R Block
<lb/>James Stroud Jr</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Notwithstanding the said Mitchell seems to have been the better off in the affray, yet it was a kind of family quarrel &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi> as the said Flood &amp; Mitchell are Brother's in law, &amp; no doubt one was to blame as much as the other. I being well acquainted with the parties, would respectfully suggest the release of said fine if consistent with your judgment. the said Mitchell is a hard working industrious poor man of a family &amp; good character</p>
<p>W E, Mitchusson clk,
<lb/>Caldwell Co Court<pb/></p>
<p>Caldwell Cir. Ct.</p>
<p>Please answser this as soon as you can &amp; direct</p>
<p>W E, Mitchusson
<lb/>Princeton Ky
<lb/>$225. } Breach.</p>
<p>The fine in this case is remitted except the sum of Twenty five dollars &amp; costs</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J F Robinson</hi>
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-07-20">July 20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>W. F. Mitchell</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
