<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0009"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">F. H. Baker et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9477</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17A-49 to MG17A-50</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-01-22">22 January 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Beriah Magoffin Governor of Kentucky
<lb/>Dear Sir.</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Caldwell County Ky. have long known Thomas. B. Wadlington &amp; he has ever been considered a good &amp; true hearted citizen, Known &amp; noted for his industry &amp; his peaceable &amp; orderely conduct -- The difficulty in which he was engaged with Milton A. Cartwright did not appear, to us, to be of his own seeking, nor are we saitsfied, ^or do believe^ that the case was <hi rend="str">fairly</hi> fairly presented to the Jury, as it occured. We hope your Excellency will review the case, and give the poor man the benefit of every doubt. &amp; we desire that his case may be judged in mercey &amp; regarded with favor, and that your Excellency will take into consideration, every circumstance that ought to operate in his behalf, And we desire that your Excellency may be persuaded that it is consistent with your duty to extend to him Executive Clemency, and that his life may be spared, either by a full pardon, or by a commutation of his punishment -- </p>
<p><date when="1861-01-22">Jany 22 1861</date>
<lb/>Yours respectfully<pb/>
<lb/>F H Baker
<lb/>S. D. Scott
<lb/>E F Hill
<lb/>F D Wyatt
<lb/>A. G. farley
<lb/>G H Bugg
<lb/>R C Greene
<lb/>W B Bush
<lb/>A, G, Wilson
<lb/>J, H, Maxwell
<lb/>J M Moore
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> S. Johnson</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
