<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-227-0023"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William P. Pierce to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14253</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>11th Ky. Cav (US) Muster Rolls</collection>
      <idno>Flat Storage Box: 11th Ky Cav (US) Muster Rolls, Bundle 6</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Cobb County, Georgia</placeName>
    <date when="1864-06-30">30 June 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Camp 11" Ky. Cav
<lb/>Cobb County Ga <date when="1864-06-30">June 30/ 64</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>Thos E. Bramlet
<lb/>Go<hi rend="sup">v</hi> of Kenty
<lb/>My Dear Sir</p>
<p>In behalf of the Officers &amp; men of this regt I address you this letter relative to the appointment of a Lieut Col to fill the vacancy occassioned by the regination of A J Alexander,</p>
<p>It is the earnest desire of boath officers &amp; men that Maj. ^Milton^ Graham be commissioned Lt Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi> &amp; Capt Frederick Slater be commissioned Maj vice Graham, But if Graham does not accept the appointment of Lt Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi> thus the regt ardently desires that Capt Slater be commissioned Lieut Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi>. However petitions have already been sent you signed by every officer in the regt present save Maj Boyle &amp; two others, to this effect,</p>
<p>Boath Maj Graham &amp; Capt Slater have the undivided confidence of the regt and they have upon all occasions where danger presented itself acted the part of deliberate skilful &amp; brave officers, I do trust for the good of the regt &amp; the cause in which it is engaged you will most favorably consider their claims to promotion</p>
<p>It has been rumored in Camp that Maj W O boyle will be L<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Col</p>
<p>Now Go<hi rend="sup">v</hi> I do not wish to speak disrespectfully of Maj Billy Boyle for I have (found him to be a very cleaver little boy. But I do not hesitate to express my beliefs that his appointment will be disastrous to the regt You are fully aware<pb/>
<lb/>that the success of a regiment greately depends upon the confidence placed by the subordinate in their commander And I assure you that precious little if any confidence is placed in Maj<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Boyle by the Officers &amp; men of this regt in comparison to Maj Graham or Capt Slater</p>
<p>I suppose there are not half a dozen officers in the regt who recognized a superior in Maj Boyle in point of inteligence, bravery Military Skills or every thing else of worth,</p>
<p>They only recognize the unfortunate fact that luck has placed him in possession of a Majors commission,</p>
<p>Go<hi rend="sup">v</hi> I write this not that I have any ^personal^ feeling for Maj Boyle but because it is right that you should be appraised of his disrepute in the regt which together with his want of age &amp; experience renders him unfit for the responsible position of Lt Col</p>
<p>I am Go<hi rend="sup">v</hi> with much respt
<lb/>Your Friend
<lb/>W P Pierce
<lb/>Lt &amp; Adjt 11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Cav</p>
<p>Head Qrs 11 Ky Cav<hi rend="sup">y</hi>
<lb/>Cobb Co<hi rend="sup">y</hi> Ga.
<lb/><date when="1864-06-30">June 30 1864</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>W. P. Pierce
<lb/>Lt. &amp; Adjt.
<lb/> -- to -- 
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Bramlette<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>In relation to the promotion of Maj Graham to the position of Lieut Col. says that he is the unanimous choice of Officers - days that he understands that Maj. W. O Boyle has been recommended but it does not meet the approval of the Officers<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Rec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> A. G. O. <date when="1864-06">July 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
