<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0014"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Charles P. Vander Espt, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4133</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-21 to BR8-22</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-09-21">21 September 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Paul Garras, Started from Louisville to new Haven Ky, about the <date when="1860-05-21">21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> of May 1860</date>, to take possession of a grist mill leased from <hi rend="str">Jack Dawson</hi> W. Carden, &amp; located on rolling fork. When he begun at S<hi rend="sup">d</hi> mill he had a capital of $1800; he employed in the Mill Erhard Duplain and Anthony Julian, the former is a carpenter by trade, and the other (^as a Journeyman^) was in <date when="1862">1862</date>, employed as a cook for Col. Grose, of the 36<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Regt Indiana Vol. (now deceased). Chs Vander Espt was living at the time temporarily with P. Garras, and remained with him, until he left, which was towards the <date when="1861-04-18">18<hi rend="sup">th</hi></date> or <date when="1861-04-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of April 1861</date>.</p>
<p>As to the intimacy said to be existing between Garras and the Colored girl Cirilla, a slave of Jack Dawson of New Haven af<hi rend="sup">d</hi>, it is known She was washing for Paul Garras, and his hands, S<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Dawson, knew it, on the <date when="1860-12-21">21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> of Dec. 1860</date> Vander Espt got married, and occupied a rooom in Garras' House where the afor<hi rend="sup">d</hi> slave frequently called on Mrs Vander Espt to learn the making of her own dresses, about the <date when="--04-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> day of April</date> Erhard Duplain referred above made a trunk for Vander Espt, to pack in his books, which being too small was voluntarily given to S<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Cirilla to put her clothes in. Consequently P. Garras did not order the trunk, neither did he Stole the clothes &amp; Jewellery of S<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Slave, as represented on the Indictment issued by the Nelson Circuit Court, under date of <date when="1861-05-01">May 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1861</date>, this is a feeble effort on the part of Dawson, and perfectly untrue, in as much as it can be proved that Garras never intended to run off the Girl afor<hi rend="sup">d</hi>. The trunk<pb/>
<lb/>at the application of the Girl Cirilla was sent to Mrs widow Hay, Dry Goods dealer, of that locality, not far from the dwelling of J Dawson, this being from fear that her master would not allow her to retain the trunk at home, it was not intended for a mean purpose, as mentioned in the Indictment. P. Garras, furnished flour and lumber to S<hi rend="sup">d</hi> J. Dawson &amp; to his Sons amongst whom, was W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> who owed Garras a certain amount of money, which was never paid Garras intending to go to little Rock Ark., This vexed Dawson's family, and without any Just a cause, accused Garras of attempting to run away with S<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Slave. In this case, Mr. Lowell H. Rousseau was the defendor of the accused, when called into the army, he could not go and attend to this case. Shortly after the arrival of Garras in Louisville, he was arrested by policeman Kirk Patrick, and taken back to New Haven, where an infuriated mob would have hanged the accused had it not been for the intervention of Some friends, his life would have been in danger Having spent his hard earnings, and having no work in Louisville, he went to Memphis, and probably is now in its vicinity, occupied as a Mill wright; the difficulty of corresponding then, from Lousiville to Memphis, previous to the taking of this latter place, is probably the cause by which his securities were obliged to pay considering the impossiblity of the accused to appear in Court. The character of Garras is good, there as some ways &amp; means on the Indictments, which in<pb/>
<lb/>some respects, seems incomprehensible. Herein went Secy By pure humanity. It is well to represent that many persons are indebted to P Garras in New Haven perhaps it was the cause which prompted his debtors, named therein to accuse him of larceny, as represented on the Indictments whereof.</p>
<p>Louisville Ky <date when="1863-09-21">September 21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>Chas. J. Vander Espt
<lb/>Vice Counsul of Belgium
<lb/>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Jefferson County.</p>
<p>Charles J. Vander Espt states that he believes the satements contained in the foregoing and above <unclear/> <unclear/> the indictments of Paul Garis, to be true</p>
<p>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi> J. Vander Espt
<lb/>Sworn to before me by Charles J. Vander Espt this <date when="1863-09-22">22 day of September 1863</date>
<lb/>Jeff Brunn
<lb/>Notary Public Jeff Co Ky.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
