<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0629"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. S. D. Mcgowan to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10097</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-463 to MG18-464</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-03-26">26 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville <date when="1861-03-26">March 26 1861</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin Frankfort Ky</p>
<p>Dear Sir having been called upon by the friend of <gap/> Johnes to Join in a petition to your Excellency for this pardon I cherfully comply having been a citizen of the County of Warren where he was convicted and personaly acquainted with his family which is one of the best in the state I think that if the young man is premited to return to his <hi rend="str">family</hi> Relatives &amp; friends he would make a useful Citizen otherwise to remain in Prison with those that he will be compelled to asotiate with in Prison would have a diferent efect</p>
<p>I do hope after considering the petitioners there character the relatives of the young man &amp; that you will Pardon him &amp; premit him againt to the his relatives &amp; friends</p>
<p>Respectfully Yours
<lb/>W. S. D Mcgowan</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
