<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2397"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John H. Rogers to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7034</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-328</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Williamsburg, Whitley County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-05">5 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Williamsburg Ky., <date when="1865-09-05">Sept., 5th 1865</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner John Rogers would respectfully state that at the present Term of the Whitley <hi rend="str">Circuit</hi> Circuit Court He was fineed <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> twenty dollars under an indictment for gameing or rather for playing one game of Cards for money with George Bunch He states that Said indictment was found upon the information of Said Bunch He further States upon oath that he never did play the game with Bunch and that Said Bunch sware false about the matter &amp; that it was by His false swearing that said indictment was procurred and Your Petitioner fineed as afs<hi rend="sup">d</hi> He further states that He is a very poor man and has a wife and three little children to provide for and by a three years term of Service in the Union army his general Health has become exceedingly bad and He is not really able to pay Said fine without great detriment to his Family wherefore he asks your Excellency to remit the fine</p>
<p>John J Rogers</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by John Rogers this <date when="1865-09-05">5th of Sept 1865</date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J, C, Watkins clk</hi></p>
<p>We the undersigned would respectfully represent that we are well acquainted with the petitioner John Rogers that He is a respectable &amp; good citizen and intitled to credit &amp; reliance either upon his word or oath that He is poor as stated by Him and we would be much pleased if your Excellency would remit the fine according to the prayer of His <unclear>petn</unclear> -- </p>
<p>W H. Nelson
<lb/>Wm Cummins
<lb/>W, E, Manney
<lb/>D H Leforce
<lb/>G. L. Marrs
<lb/>granville Moore
<lb/>W C Gilliss
<lb/>W. H. Brafford
<lb/>H L Cox
<lb/>H. H. Randall<pb/></p>
<p>Gov Bramblet</p>
<p>Dear sir I hope that you will remit the fine against John Rodgers</p>
<p>Granville Pearl
<lb/>H F Finley</p>
<p>Whitley Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John J Rodgers
<lb/>$20,
<lb/>Gaming
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-12-06">6 Dec /65</date></p>
<p>sent for fee <date when="--10-14">1<hi rend="str">3</hi>4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Oct</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
