<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2867"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">L. A. Wood to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7504</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-162 to BR17-163</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-02">2 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-12-02">December 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 186</date>
<lb/>His Excellency Thos E Bramlette</p>
<p>Dear Sir on the other Side of this Sheet you will find the verdict of the Jury in the case of Wm Kelly You will See that the Jury reccommend him for your executive mercy for Pardon.</p>
<p>I was appointed by the court to defend him and did it without pay of course. He had been in the U. S. army for 3 years and more had been discharged, got his pay and was boarding Staying and drinking around one of those low-down Irish doggeries, and boarding houses -- had been on a drunk for 8 or 10 days, and the Irishman had got most of his money -- He got up one morning, and his panteloons, hat and boots were gone. He thought the Landlord or his wife had taken them, So he Says, and in hunting through the house for them he Saw a watch lying on the bureau He says he put it in his pocket and told the man's wife that if She would get his pants, hat, &amp;c he would find the watch -- He got his <hi rend="str">wa</hi> clothes, and then went and and got the watch and gave it up. There was no witness present at the trial but the Irish doggery Keeper and he suppress all the facts in the case except that he missed his <hi rend="str">wa</hi> and found in possession of Kelly.</p>
<p>I think the Governor that Kelly's Statements were true, and that the taking was not felonious. I trust<pb/>
<lb/>therefore you will Send me a pardon for him at once.</p>
<p>Yours Truly
<lb/>L. A. Wood<pb/></p>
<p>I do hereby certify that Wm Kelly who was Indicted in the Jefferson Circuit court for Grand Larceny and tried at the present <date when="--11">November</date> term of Said court and convicted; and that the verdict of the Jury is at follows viz:</p>
<p>"We of the Jury find the prisoner Wm Kelly guilty as charged in the within indictment and Say he Shall be confined in the Jail and Penetentiary of this Commonwealth one year, and recommend him to the mercy of the Governor for Pardon</p>
<p>P. N Frederick
<lb/>Foreman."</p>
<p><date when="1865-12-02">December 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>A Copy.
<lb/>Att Jas P Chambers clk<pb/></p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Kelly
<lb/>Grand Larceny
<lb/>1 year
<lb/>Pardoned
<lb/><date when="1865-12-04">4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Dec 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
