<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-034-0001"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Richard Yates, Requisition</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7729</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Requisitions for the Return of Fugitives from Justice, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-1</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Springfield, Sangamon County, Illinois</placeName>
    <date when="1862-12-29">29 December 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>RICHARD YATES,
<lb/><figure type="seal"><ab>STATE SOVEREIGNTY
<lb/>NATIONAL UNION</ab></figure>
<lb/>GOVERNOR OF THE STATE OF ILLINOIS,
<lb/>To His Excellency, the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>It appears by the annexed papers, duly authenticated according to the Laws of this State, that Edwin S. Piper Alias E. B. Ballard stands charged with Forgery in Cook County in this State and it has been represented to me that he has fled from the justice of this State, and has taken refuge in the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>Now, Therefore, Pursuant to the provisions of the Constitution and Laws of the United States, in such case made and provided, I do hereby require that the said Edwin S. Piper Alias E. B. Ballard be apprehended and delivered to Smith C. Storer who is hereby duly authorized to receive him and convey him to the State of Illinois, there to be dealth with according to Law.</p>
<p><figure type="seal"/></p>
<p>In Testimony Whereof, I have hereunto set my hand, and caused the Great Seal of State to be hereunto affixed. Done at the City of Springfield, this <date when="1862-12-29">29<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of December in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and sixty=two,</date> and of the Independence of the United States the eighty=Seventh</p>
<p>Rich. Yates.
<lb/>BY THE GOVERNOR
<lb/>O. M. Hatch
<lb/>SECRETARY OF STATE.<pb/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Illinois</hi>
<lb/>Warrant for E. S. Piper
<lb/><hi rend="underline">alias</hi>
<lb/>E B. Ballard
<lb/>Felony
<lb/>Is<hi rend="sup">d</hi>. <date when="1862-12-31">Dec<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 31 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
