<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0382"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Clabourn Hyten to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9850</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-87</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lawrence County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency Beriah Maggoffin
<lb/>Governor of the commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner <hi rend="underline">Clabourn</hi> <hi rend="underline">Hyten</hi> States that at the last <date when="--04">aprile Term</date> of the Lawrence circuit court there was a fine of twenty Dollars ($20) adjudged against him for gaiming he states he states that the attorney for the commonwealth Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> M Nesbitt immediately drew a Letter to your Excellency and also the Hon Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> M Rice united in the same asking the fine to be remitted which Letter in <date when="--05">May Last</date> was fowarded to your excellency your petitioner asks that you will interpose in his behalf he states that the gaiming for which he was fined took place one night in the county jail while they were guarding the Same (The other two in the game was Jesse Meek &amp; William Vinson) he states that they had no intention while in the game to Gamble for gain but and onely intended it for pastime he says the fine is oppressive and he asks your clemency and will ever &amp;c</p>
<p>Clabourn Hyten</p>
<p>We whose names are hereunto assigned most respectfully ask that the fine be <hi rend="underline">Remitted</hi></p>
<p>Jake Rice
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> M, Rice</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
