<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0414"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Ellison Carter to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4533</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-152 to BR9-153</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-01-20">20 January 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency the Governor of Kentucky: -</p>
<p>Your petitioner, Ellison Carter, States that he was recunnized in the Sum of one hundred dollars to appear in the Mercer Circuit Court at the <date when="1863-04">April Term 1863</date>, as a witness for plaintiff in the case of the Commonwealth against James Shackelford, Steven Trumans and William Faulkner. Your Petitioner further states that at said term of the Court his recognizance was forfeited, and that summons of said against him to appear at the October term, 1863, to Show cause why Judgment Should not be rendered against him on said forfeited recognizance, and that Judgment was rendered against him at said <date when="--10">October term</date> for said sum and costs.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner further states ^that^ in <date when="1862-08">August, 1862</date>, he enlisted as a Soldier in the services of the United States in the 9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Calvary commanded by Col. R. T. Jacobs and in Capt H. ^I.^ Burns <unclear>Company</unclear> of said regiment. He also state<unclear/> at the <date when="1863-04">April term, 1863</date>, wher<unclear/> was reconized to appear as <unclear/> that he was absent in the <unclear/> of the United States, and is <unclear/> impossible for him to atten<unclear/> Court in accordance with his recognizance, which was thus forfeited while he was absent on duty with his<pb/></p>
<p>regiment. Petitioner further states that while at home in <date when="1863-08">August, 1863</date>, before being mustered out of the service process was served on him to appear at the following <date when="--10">October term</date> to show cause why judgment Should not be rendered agt. him, and that he was <hi rend="str">here</hi> ^present^ during said term of the court: but in his absence from the Court House, and being ignorant of the laws and what was required of him, Judgment went against him, of which he knew nothing till executive was issued therein with which he is now being processed. He asks your Excellency to remit said Judgment.</p>
<p>Ellison Carter states that the allegations in the foregoing petition are true.</p>
<p>Ellison ^his x mark^ Carter
<lb/>Attest. Jno. G. Kyle.</p>
<p>Sworn to before me this <date when="1864-01-20">20 January</date>
<lb/>John G. Kyle P. J. H.</p>
<p>We the undersigned also petition Your Excellency to remit the Judgment against Ellison Carter.</p>
<p>John G. Kyle
<lb/>Jno R Haggin
<lb/>Tho C. Bell
<lb/>Richard Board C. M. C. C
<lb/>Thos Edwards P J M C C
<lb/>J. W. Cardwell
<lb/>O S Poston
<lb/>Russel Naperall
<lb/>Jas D S Gardire
<lb/>H. G. Burns
<lb/>C A Hardin
<lb/>W. E. Riley</p>
<p>H. J. Burns States that he was Captain in Co. R. T. Jacobs regiment, 9 Ky. Calvary; that Ellison Carter was a member of his company, and that the statements of said Carter in his affidavit about him being absent in the Service of the U. S. Service at the time aforesaid are true</p>
<p>H. J. Burns</p>
<p><unclear/> to before me this <date when="1864-01-21">21 January 1864</date>.
<lb/>John G. Kyle P. J. H.<pb/></p>
<p>Mercer Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Ellison Carter</p>
<p>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>$100-</p>
<p>Forfeited Reconigance
<lb/><date when="1864-02-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Feby 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
