<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3130"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Sanderson et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5249</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-307 to BR41-308</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Graves County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To Gov Bramlett</p>
<p>At the present <date when="--05">May term</date> of Graves Circuit Court a Judgment was rendered in favor of the Common wealth of Ky against A. C. &amp; John Rodgers for Three Hundred Dollars each on an indictment for a breach of the peace</p>
<p>The facts proved on the trial of the case were that Joshua Hall who was a Rebel Soldier &amp; Gurilla during the war took a valuable Stable horse from one Hagewood of Weakley Co Tennessee &amp; horse was taken without any order but for his own use, In the <date when="1865">Spring of 1865</date> Hagewood having claimed that J H OGynn knew <hi rend="str">an</hi> where his Said Stable horse ^was^ came to Graves Coutny from Weakley County a distance of about 20 miles in Company with Danl Abernathy a neyhbor of his and went to a OGynns who upon the <unclear/> Joshua Hall who was living with his Father about 8 or 10 miles from OGynn had taken the Said Stable horse belonging to Hagewood &amp; OGynn propsed to go with Hagewood &amp; Abernathy to the house of James Hall in order to get s horse or find out where he was in going this passed the house of Abe &amp; John Rodgers who had also lost a horse &amp; who were informed that s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Hall had taken this horse, the person above named hereto W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Waston was in company to the house of Willis Hall the Father of John Hall to get the horse above named as information as to where they were the evidence<pb/>
<lb/>showed when the partes first got to the house of Willis Hall rough language was used by some of the parties to Joshua Hall who admitted &amp; confessed to taking the Stable horse of Hall &amp; selling him &amp; who agreed to pay for him &amp; he gave his note to Hagewood for the price agreed on &amp; gave his Father ^as^ Security for the Same, the two Rodgers were convinced by the Statements of Hall &amp; his offer to go with the authorities him the man who actually took this horse <unclear/> he did not really take the horse himself although he admitted he was in Compnay with the party who did take the Rodgers horse, after the note was executed to Hagewood Joshua Hall went with s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> parties to the home of West a neighbor of Halls and the Rodgers got the horse. Willis Hall who was given as a witness testified that Abernathy done nothing &amp; said nothing to anybody &amp; are the witnesses Stated the Same thing on the evidence a verdict was rendered against the two Rodgers for the Sum of Three Hundred Dollars <unclear/> during the trial Abernathy who was not indicted was Sworn as a witness and testified Substantially as above Set forth, and after it trial of the Rodgers hes been indicted by the present Grand Jury<pb/>
<lb/>for Robbery, ^for going with s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> parties as above set forth ^ to us men under bond for his appearance to answer Said indictment at the next term of the Graves Circuit Court, the result of the verdict against the Rodgers and the indictment against Abernathy was brought about by prejudice agaisnt them on account of the fact they were Gov men during the ^war^ Jno Rodgers &amp; Abernathy belonged to the Federal army but were discharged before they went to Halls; this is a case which calls for interposition in behalf of the two Rodgers &amp; also Abernathy we therefore earnestly ask that they be relieved</p>
<p>John Sanderson one of the Jurors in above case
<lb/>Nathan Whitis one of the jurors in <unclear/>
<lb/>David Orr One of the jurors in the above case
<lb/>S. T. Hill one of the Jurors in the case
<lb/>J. O. Pryear
<lb/>L <unclear/> one of the Jurors in the case
<lb/>B. S. Dugger<pb/>
<lb/>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Graves County</p>
<p>This day J A OGynn and W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Watson made oath before me that they were present at Halls when Hagewood Abernathy &amp; others went to the house of Hall for the purposes Stated &amp; Set forth in the forgegoing Petition and they further State that the facts as Set forth in Said Petition are Substantially ^ true^ Set forth on the <unclear/> <hi rend="str">that</hi> Affiant OGynn States that he knows that Joshua Hall took the horse of Hagewood word that he done this of his will <unclear/> <unclear/> influence by G <unclear/> &amp; think he sold s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> horse &amp; Appropriated the <unclear/> to his own <unclear/></p>
<p>J H OGynn
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Watson
<lb/>sworn to &amp; <unclear/> before me by J H OGynn &amp; W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Watson
<lb/>HA Turner C G C C
<lb/>By R H Wellman D C</p>
<p>The facts as stated in the above petition are substantially what was proven on the trial of the Rodgers- I believe it is a case proper for the exercise of executive clemency, and that ^the fines against <unclear/> Rodger and ^ the offense charged against Abernathy ought to be pardoned</p>
<p>C. S. Marshall</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
