<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2653"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Andrew Shepherd et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7290</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-266 to BR16-267</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excelency
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov of Ky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> M Riddle would respectfully represent to your Excelency, that with many other natives &amp; residents of this State in the fall of <date when="1862">1862</date> he Joined Chenaults Rebel Regt 7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky Cavalry as a chaplain</p>
<p>He then resided in Irvine Estill County Ky. He went out of the State shortly afterwards, with the Rebel Forces under Kirby Smith. He remained attached to the Rebel forces a short time and after his connexion with the Rebel forces ceased. He remained in East Tennessee practicing his Proffession -- being also a Physician until last winter when he returned to Ky -- and is now residing in Richmond Madison County Ky</p>
<p>He never bore Arms against the State of Ky -- or the U States</p>
<p>For Joining &amp; going off with said Rebel Forces in the fall of <date when="1862">1862</date> he was Indicted by the Estill Circuit Court for <hi rend="underline">Treason</hi> and has given Bail for his appearance -- the case never having been tryed.</p>
<p>He was Guilty of no Crime<pb/>
<lb/>and violated none of the rules of civilized warfare while connected with the Rebel Army or at any other time. His only offence being as before stated in Joining and going off with said Rebel Troops which Act he now much regrets and having taken the oath of allegiance to the U S Government he intends in good faith to keep it &amp; hence forth to be a true Loyal citizen to the State of Kentucky and the U States</p>
<p>His life has been threated by some evil disposed persons in Estill County -- to whom he never done any injury and he is realy afraid his life will be taken by said persons if he is compelled to attend said Trial which comes off in <date when="--11">November</date> next</p>
<p>He therefore respectfully and Earnestly requests your Excelency to Grant him a Pardon, from said Indictment</p>
<p>We the undersgined Loyal<pb/>
<lb/>Union men of Estill County Ky have heard the foregoing Petition of D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> M Riddle for a Pardon read, and Unite with him in requesting your Excelency to Pardon him We know of know act of his to complain of except the fact of his Joining the Rebel Army as he has stated</p>
<p>Andrew Shepherd
<lb/>James M Witt
<lb/>Harrison Cockrill
<lb/>J. P Harris
<lb/>J H Gardner
<lb/>Ausie Daniel
<lb/>John Park
<lb/>J P Tipton
<lb/>M V Harris
<lb/>E. L. Cockrill
<lb/>F M Parks
<lb/>Simon Cockrill
<lb/>Burges Elliott
<lb/>Joel F. Reed
<lb/>T C Harris
<lb/><unclear/><pb/></p>
<p>Estill Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi>. M. Riddle
<lb/>Petition for Pardon
<lb/>Respited until end next General Assembly
<lb/><date when="1865-11-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Nov 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
