<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1070"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. David Shroeder and John Shroeder, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5707</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR[11]-151 to BR[11]-153</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky</p>
<p>Pleas before the Honorable P B Muir Sole Judge of the Jefferson Circuit Court held at the Court House in the City of Louisville on the <date when="1864-05-16">16 May 1864</date></p>
<p>Commonwealth Plff
<lb/>versus Indict for felony
<lb/>David Shroeder, John Shroeder Defts</p>
<p>Be it remembered that heretofore Towit; on the <date when="1863-10-20">20 Oct 1863</date> the Grand Jury returned an indict a true bill</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Indictment</note></p>
<p>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>versus
<lb/>David Shroeder &amp; John Shroeder
<lb/>Jefferson Circuit Court
<lb/><date when="1863-10">October Term AD 1863</date></p>
<p>The Grand Jurors of the County of Jefferson in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky accuse David Shroeder and John Shroeder of the crime of malicious stabbing with the intent to kill committed in manner and form as follows To wit </p>
<p>The said David Shroeder and John Shroeder in the said County of Jefferson on the <date when="1863-09-07">7" day of September A D 1863</date> did <hi rend="str">wickedly</hi> wilfully, wickedly, feloniously and of their malice aforethought cut and stab Andrew Dora with a <pb/>
<lb/>knife and other sharp instrument and weapon in and upon the body of the said Dora, wounding and not killing the said Dora, but with the intent to kill him, contrary to the form of the Statute in such cases made and provided and against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>J R Dupuy Comths Atty</p>
<p>And at Courts continued and held as aforesaid on the <date when="1863-10-30">30 Oct 186<hi rend="str">4</hi>3</date> <date when="1864-01-13">Jany 13 1864</date> this case was continued and deft recognized</p>
<p>And at a Court continued and held as aforesaid on the <date when="1864-05-14">14 May 1864</date></p>
<p>David Shroeder and John Shroeder who have been jointly indicted by the Grand Jury of this Circuit for felony and who are now bound by recognizance to appear here, this day appeared in discharge of said recognizance and being arraigned upon said indictment plead not guilty thereto and for their trial put themselves upon the country and the Attorney for the Commonwealth likewise and then came defts and asked and moved the Court to grant them a severance herein and said motion being heard and the Court being advised It is ordered said motion be overruled (the rule of.<pb/>
<lb/>Court often publicly announced being that when a party desires a severance said motion must be made at the first calling of the cause when a day is fixed for trial) to which ruling of the Court the defts except; Wherefore to try the issue joined let a jury come and thereupon came a jury To wit: John Price, A B Quarrier, W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Hardin, J H Myers, W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Hurst, H A Gardner, W D Smith, J M Groves, James Doglass W F Lane, J S Augustus and L Richardson who being duly elected, tried and sworn well and truly to try and true deliverance make between the Commonwealth and the accused upon oath returned into Court the following verdict We the jury find the accused David Shroeder and John Shroeder guilty as charged in the within indictment and say that David Shoroeder shall be confined in the jail and penentiary house of this Commonwealth for the term of two years -- and further say that John Shroeder shall be confined in the jail and penetentiary house of this Commonwealth for the term of one year and we recommend John Shroeder especially to the clemency of Honor the Governor</p>
<p>John Price foreman</p>
<p>And thereupon the prisoners were remanded and taken to jail and then came counsel<pb/>
<lb/>for prisoners and moved the Court for a new trial upon seperate grounds in writing filed</p>
<p>And at a Court continued and held as afsd on the <date when="1864-05-16">16 May 1864</date></p>
<p>Came the parties by Attorneys and defts filed an affidavit upon their motions for a new trial and said motions being heard were submitted and the Court being advised It is ordered said motions be overruled to which ruling of the Court the defts except and then came defts and moved the Court in arrest of judgment and said motion being heard was submitted and the Court being advised It is ordered said motion be overruled, to which ruling of the Court the defts except</p>
<p>And at a Court continued and held as aforesaid on <date when="1864-05-17">May 17 1864</date></p>
<p>David Shroeder who has been indicted jointly with John Shroeder by the Grand Jury of this Circuit for felony and found guilty thereof by a jury of the country was this day again led to the bar of this Court by and in the custody of the jailer attending the same and it being demanded of him whether he had anything further to say why the sentence of the Court should not<pb/>
<lb/>now be pronounced upon him according to law said nothing more It is therefore considered by the Court that the said David Shroeder be taken back to the jail whence he came and be thence removed with all convenient dispatch by the Sheriff or his deputies attending this Court to the jail and penetentiary house of this Commonwealth there to be confined at hard labor for the period and term of two years</p>
<p>A copy Attest
<lb/>James P Chambers
<lb/>clk<pb/></p>
<p>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Copy indict of
<lb/>David Shroeder
<lb/>for Mrs Shroeder
<lb/>copy fee 75<hi rend="sup">c</hi> paid</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
