<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0003-092-0119"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George W. Johnson to Anne E. V. Johnson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14411</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>George W. Johnson Papers</collection>
      <idno>Folder 4</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-10-15">15 October 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>74
<lb/><hi rend="underline">53
<lb/></hi>21</p>
<p>Bowling Green Ky.
<lb/><date when="1861-10-15">Oct. 15. 1861</date>.
<lb/>My Dear Ann</p>
<p>I am now at this place, and for the present, will act as General Buckner volunteer aid and I hardly know how to write you, so as to <hi rend="str">fully</hi> make you fully comprehend my feelings at our irregular separation by the present troubles.</p>
<p>Sometimes I think we owe every thing to our country, but at others, I think we should as private citizens, attend our own business and ^let^ the Government take care of itself. I am very certain that if you could get out of the state &amp; go with me to Oldtown, that I would go with you there, determined to have nothing more to do with th active management of public affairs. Willa and Madison are both here, or rather Matty is with Capt Morgan in advance of the main army at Green Brier. They are both well and Willa is inclined to return south. It seems to me, that General Anderson or Sherman would grant to you passports to join me &amp; go south. as a soldier in the ranks, I can be of little service and we are so remote from neighbourhoods where I am known, that there is little chance of my being able to raise a regiment. If you could ascertain whether such a passport would be granted, it would still be difficult and perhaps dangerous for<pb/>
<lb/>act on it. When I think of all <unclear>the</unclear> difficulties in the way of ^our^ meeting, I am disposed to be impatient at all delays to our progress. But we must both cultivate the disposition to submit to, whatever is inevitable.</p>
<p>I wrote you a long letter a few days ago which I hope you may have received. My money has melted away like water. -- Having to bear every expense of the horses by railroad. Col Preston and I conluded to sell Stoddards Horse for $175 which was paid to me in Virginia. Except for this I would now be without money, although I have bought nothing whatever that was not indispensable. Stoddard must credit this on his note to me, &amp; get it out of something which you &amp; he can sell of mine.</p>
<p>I am inclined to think my Dear Ann, that at the close of this war, I will be ruined in Kentucky and desire to leave it for Arkansas, where I hope under the favavour of God, to be able to take care of you &amp; make you happy. Those men who invoked this state in War, have the greatest crime to answer for. It was unnecessary foolish and criminal. &amp; I thank God I did every thing possible to avert it.</p>
<p>Oh my Dear Children! How I long to see them all once more! You and they are more than every thing else to me in all the world. May God bless and protect you &amp; them. I wish very much to get a letter from you, but do not know <hi rend="str">of</hi> any mode to suggest to you, by which it can be sent. Perhaps Capt Silas Miller could forward a letter to me. Try him.</p>
<p>Your Husband George W. Johnson</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
