<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0441"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky vs. Martha Williams and Nancy E. Williams, Judgment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8893</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-210</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1863-06-20">20 June 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Commonwelth plantiff Breach of the peace
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Martha Williams Nancy. E. Williams</p>
<p>The case being called defendent claimed a Separate trial which was granted by the court and the case of martha Williams took up by agreement of parties it was tryed by 8 Jurors which after hearing the testimony of witness and argument of counsel Retired and Returned with the following verdict to wit. We of the Jury find the defendant martha Williams guilty as charged in the warrant and asses her fine to the commonwelth to twenty dollars and cost Isaac Raymer one of the Jury <date when="1863-06-20">June the 20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date></p>
<p>B. J. Ray J. P E C</p>
<p>on motion of the attourney ^for^ the commonwelth the above case against N. E. Williams is dismissed with out prejudice <date when="1863-06-20">June the 20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date></p>
<p>B. J. Ray J P E C<pb/></p>
<p>A Coppy test</p>
<p>Martha Williams of Edmunson County Pettn to remit fine</p>
<p>No reliable ground shown for Exetv ruling.</p>
<p>J F R</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
