<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1126"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Richard Wathen et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5763</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-223</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-08-18">18 August 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Governor of Kentucky:</p>
<p>The undersigned were members of the Jury empannelled in the Case of the Commonwealth against John Mackin at the <date when="1864-08">August Term of the Marion Circuit Court 1864.</date> on an indictment for permitting Thomas Weatherford a minor, to play upon his Pigeon hole table, and they would say that from the Evidence they believe that at the time the playing by said Minor was done said Mackin did not know that there was any statute prohibiting it, being instructed however that ignorance of the law was no excuse for the commission of an offence, they were constrained to find him Guilty and assessed his fine at $5.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi>, they understand that his conviction works a forfeiture of his right to keep the table unless pardoned by the Governor. They would therefore ask under the Circumstances that your Excellency grant to said Mackin a full pardon -- 
<lb/><date when="1864-08">Aug 18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864 -- </date></p>
<p>Richard Wathen
<lb/>L glazebrook
<lb/>M T Burkett
<lb/>James Cresky
<lb/>Ambrose, Smith
<lb/>Howell Mills
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> M. Abell
<lb/>Albert Lee
<lb/>H P Thornton
<lb/>John Spalding
<lb/>Arnold Bicket
<lb/>A Corley<pb/></p>
<p>We were counsel for John Mackin in the case mentioned in the within petition, and fully concur with the Jury. that under the circumstances the fine and forfeiture therein should be remitted, and should your Excellency be pleased to grant Mr Mackin a pardon, You will favor him by sending ^it to^ him to <hi rend="underline">our address</hi>, at the earliest Convenience</p>
<p>Very respectfully
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Hill &amp; Knott </hi></p>
<p>Address
<lb/>Hill &amp; Knott
<lb/>Lebanon
<lb/>Kentucky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
