<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0559"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Samuel J. Vaughn and David Witt to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9011</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-387 to R4-388</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To the Governor of Kentucky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>We would respectfully represent to your honor that we are Citizens of Estell County Kentucky and are now and have been Confined in the Irvine Jail about 28 days by the military authorities at this place, without to our knowledge having committed any crime or offence against any existing laws or regulations of Kentucky or the United States, without any charges having been prefered against us or any writ having been issued as required by law, we are informed that we are held as hostages for two Citizens of this County Carried off by the forces of John Morgan when he left this State in <date when="--10">October</date> last, we had nothing to do with the arresting or carrying off of those men nor did we know anything about it untill after it was done, we are also led to believe from circumstances that we will be retained in Jail till we pay the Jailors fees for keeping us in Jail, We are both men of age being respecttively 56 &amp; 64 years old and both in bad health we believe these proceedings are unjust unfair and unlawful and appeal to you as the chief magistrate of Kentucky for clemenency in our behalf and ask to be released from prison and the payment of the Jail fees, for our character &amp; standing as citizens we refer you to M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> A A Curtis our member in the Legislature and Mr H. Cockrill of the Senate, also Mr. John<pb/>
<lb/>B. Huston Jas. H. G Bush of Clark Thomas Turner of Montgomery</p>
<p>Yours Respectfully
<lb/>Saml. J. Vaughn
<lb/>David Witt<pb/></p>
<p>Pettn of S Vaugh &amp;c confined in Estill jail under Military Arrest</p>
<p>No power in Executive to interfere only redress in Military wrote letter to Genl <unclear/> urging relief -- </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
