<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0426"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Hugh L. Gromley to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9894</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-163 to MG18-164</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Madison County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-12-23">23 December 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin</p>
<p>Your petitioner Hugh L Gromley respectfully presents the following desiring and hoping Your Excellency may find Sufficient grounds for Exorcising Executive Clemency and remitting the fine herein set forth -- </p>
<p>At the <date when="1860-09">September term of the Madison Circuit Court 1860</date>, he, together with one or two others were <hi rend="underline">indited</hi> for gaming and the circumstances under which the same took place are as follows viz</p>
<p>Some short time prior thereto he with several young gentlemen were at their hotel and to more agreeably pass off time and amuse themselves a game of Eucher was proposed and whilst thus Engaged his partner proposed <hi rend="str">to</hi> risking a small amount upon the game which was accepted by the opposite party -- For this he was indited and at the <date when="1860-12">December Special term</date> he confessed judgment for $20.<hi rend="sup">0</hi>/ and costs all of which he promptly paid Except that portion which Your Excellency has jurisdiction of -- He had no intention of gambling, Much more of violating any Statutory provision against it -- </p>
<p>Several were in the game and but one other person with him was indicted and he. (Hugh Rowland) has heretofore applied and received the benefit of Your Executive Clemency<pb/></p>
<p>He is a poor young Man of good Morals And a hard working Mechanic, a Saddler and harness maker by trade -- </p>
<p>The judgment just at <hi rend="underline">this</hi> <hi rend="underline">trying</hi> time falls with great severity upon him and your clemency is very Respectfully solicited</p>
<p>Hugh L Gromley</p>
<p>Sworn to before my by Hugh L Gromley this <date when="1860-12-23">23<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> day of December 1860</date></p>
<p>We the undersigned unite with the applicant and recommend Your Excellency to grant this prayer -- </p>
<p>John G Cole
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J M Shackelford</hi>
<lb/>J N Hill
<lb/>Geo, F. Shackleford
<lb/>P. F. Coghlan<pb/></p>
<p>Madison Cir. ct
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>Is<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1861-01-03">Jany 3. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
