<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1066"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William E. Arthur to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10534</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-163 to MG20-164</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-05-29">29 May 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Covington Ky <date when="1861-05-29">May 29<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Hon. Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Governor &amp;c.
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>The mother of the convict Hiram Alexander informs me that in a recent interview with you in Lexington, you requested her to procure a line from me touching the facts developed in the trial of her son. I respectfully submit a brief statement.</p>
<p>Hiram Alexander jointly with one Henry Slaughter was indicted and convicted of Stabbing with intent to kill one Henry Overhouse a German, They fled the night of the occurance and were subsequently arrested tried and convicted separately. Slaughter first and Alexander at a subsequent term.</p>
<p>The proof of the criminal acts was clear and conclusive, and unimpaired by any extenuating circumstances whatever. Overhouse with the other Germans in descending Bank Lick Street in this City about 9 &amp; 10 o'clock one moon light night were assailed with curses by the men on the opposite side of the street. The latter crossed over to the side of the Overhouse party jostled them and put them to flight. Overhouse was pursued and being overtaken was knocked down, twice -- and while laying<pb/>
<lb/>in the street upon his back was kicked, beaten &amp; stabbed -- the stabbing was done with a knife entering the body, some distance below the left breast and penetrating through ^into^ <hi rend="str">to</hi> the cavity of the body, inflicting a dangerous wound which might have resulted fatally to life -- Overhouse bore a good character. He swore that Slaughter knocked him down, kicked him and that Alexander stabbed him that they began the assault and that no provecation or resistance to them <hi rend="str">was</hi> <hi rend="str">were</hi> was offered. In support of this proof innumerable circumstances of corroberation were supplied by other emmintly credible and wholly disinterested witnesses -- </p>
<p>The theory of the defence was that although Alexander was at the scene of the struggle he had no hand in it -- that Overhouse had made contradictory statements as to who did the stabbing -- sometimes saying that it was Slaughter -- and at other times that it was Alexander &amp; so on &amp;c &amp;c all of which lines of defence were triumphantly rebutted, -- Such are the material facts</p>
<p>Alexanders reputation here is that of a drinking man who is quarrelsome and reckless when excited with liquor -- His reputation in other respects so far as I know or have any reason to believe is free from blemish. He is a young man of good personal presence and his appearance and demeanor during the trial were manly and prepossessing -- He persists in <unclear/> his innocence and I am informed<pb/>
<lb/>that Slaughter, who ois in the Penitentiary, acquits him of the stabbing,</p>
<p>Alexanders parents are extremely poor -- His mother seems to be a very worthy woman and very tenderly concerned for her son, whom she declares <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>she relies upon mainly for her subsistence, I sincerely sympathise with her,</p>
<p>Official fidelity requires me to say that in this community I am aware of but little if any sympathy for Alexander: -- there is however much felt for his mother and I earnestly commend her and her mission to the sympathy and respect of the Executive</p>
<p>Very truly your Excellency's
<lb/>obedient Servant
<lb/>W, E, Arthur
<lb/>Atty Com'th
<lb/><hi rend="underline">9th Ju, District</hi></p>
<p>The foregoing letter speaks for itself -- I have deep sympathy for the mother but know nothing of the son -- </p>
<p>J. W Stevenson</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
