<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2660"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. R. Robinson to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7297</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-278 to BR16-279</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-11-02">2 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Frankfort, Ky. <date when="1865-11-02">Novr 2, 1865</date>
<lb/>Gov Bramlette.</p>
<p>On the trial of the Case of Jos L. Gill in the Taylor Circuit Court I learn &amp; believe the proof in the cause was substantilly this.</p>
<p>Gill w<hi rend="str">as</hi>ho was an honorably discharged soldier from the 13<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky. Infty. went with underwood to the House of Mildred Anderson in Taylor County &amp; Knocked at the Door Mrs Anderson beleving it her son in Law opened the door, but after Gill had gotten allmost in the House Mrs Anderson then attempted to shut the door, but Gill went in, or "a man who she thought was gill." They asked for Rebel &amp; his Government Arms. &amp; search for Rosel &amp; his son's Arms, but found neither.</p>
<p>Gill &amp; underwood then left. but taking nothing with them what ever nor did they in any way mistreat or <unclear/><pb/>
<lb/>the family or any property.</p>
<p>This Mr Rosel was said to be a Desenter from some Ohio Regiment, was a stranger in that County. an order from was sent for his arrest as a Desenter but, he (Rosel) left soon after that time &amp; has not returned since.</p>
<p>I presented the petition to the Jury who signed the Petition, they are good &amp; reliable men &amp; seemed glad of the oppenty to sign a Petition for his pardon, &amp; in fact a majority of the Jury say they would have been glad to have Imprisoned him for <hi rend="underline">only</hi> <hi rend="underline">six months</hi> if they could have done so under <hi rend="str">they</hi> the law, and as he has been already in prison over seven months, that they gladly sign the Petition for his pardon.</p>
<p>You are acquainted with many of the citizens who have singed the Petition</p>
<p>It was presented to no others.</p>
<p>Most respectfully your obent Servt
<lb/>J, R, Robinson</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
