<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0846"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Andrew Sears &amp; Cornelius Sheehan, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10314</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-329 to MG19-330</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-03-08">8 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>City Court of Louisville
<lb/><date when="1861-03-08">March 8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>To the Marshal of the City Court of Louisville</p>
<p>Whereas heretofore to-wit on the <date when="1860-03-12">12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of March 1860,</date> in the City Court of Louisville Andrew Sears and Cornelius Sheehan acknowledged themselves indebted to the Commonwealth of Kentucky in the sum of One Hundred &amp; fifty Dollars, each which they agreed should be levied and made of their respective goods and chattels, lands and tenements and to the use of said Commonwealth rendered, but upon condition, and to be void on the said And Sears personally appearing in the City Court of Louisville on the first day of their next ensuing <date when="1860-04">April term,</date> and surrendering himself into custody to answer to the Commonwealth of Kentucky for a Misdemeanor with which he stands charged and not depart thence without leave of the Court Otherwise to remain in full force and virtue, which recognizance was acknowledge before the Judge of said Court, who then had competent power and authority to take the same, and which recognizance is of record and now here to the Court shown, And whereas at a court begun and held for the City of Louisville, at the court House thereof in said City, on the <date when="1860-05-08">8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of May 1860,</date> being the second term of said city Court of Louisville ensuing the date of the said recognizance, the said Andrew Sears although solemnly called to appear in discharge of said recognizance, came not, but made default against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, which is recorded and this writ awarded &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi><pb/></p>
<p>You are therefore hereby commanded, that you make known to the said And Sears &amp; C Sheehan that they be and appear before the Judge of our said Court at the Court House thereof in the City of Louisville, on the first day of our <date when="1860-06">next June</date> term, to show cause if any, they have or can, why the said Commonwealth shall not have execution against them for the said sum of One Hundred &amp; fifty Dollars each according to the form, force, and effect of the recognizance aforesaid, if it shall be deemed expedient then and there so to do; and further to do and recieve whatever else our said court shall then and there adjudge and order concerning the premises; and have then there this writ</p>
<p>Witness, Oliver H Strattan, Clerk of our said Court, this <date when="1860-05-15">15 day of May 1860,</date> and in the 68 year of the Commonwealth</p>
<p>O H Strattan Clerk
<lb/>by W Shryock D Clk</p>
<p><hi rend="str">A Copy Attest</hi></p>
<p>We of the Jury find for the Commonwealth as against the deft Cornelius Sheehan the amt of the within scirefacias, viz the sum of One Hundred &amp; fifty Dollars</p>
<p>Hiram M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Gehee
<lb/>Foreman
<lb/>O H Strattan Clk
<lb/>W Shryock D. Clk</p>
<p>A copy Attest<pb/></p>
<p>To <date when="1860-06-06">June 6. 1861</date>
<lb/>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } scifa &amp; cas
<lb/>And Sears &amp; C Sheehan</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
