<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0030"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Alanson Trigg to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4149</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-43 to BR8-44</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Barren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-09-26">26 September 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>Thomas E Bramlett
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Alanson Trigg a citizen of Barren County Kentucky respectfully represents that he has been fined by the judgement of the Warren Equity &amp; Criminal Court upon one or more Indictments for allowing as was charged two of his slaves to wit Jerry &amp; Beverly to go at large &amp; hire themselves out in violation of law The Indictments were tried at the last term of said Court when it was impossible for your petitioner now more than 70 years old to attend said Court &amp; the trial He will cause to be presented herewith a copy of the record verifying the fact that he has been fined as above stated by the judgement of said Court. Your Petitioner is informed that his said slaves have wives in Warren County where your Petitioner once owned &amp; carried on a farm, which he sold a few years ago. After the sale your Petitioner thro humanity to his slaves &amp; in order that they might remain convenient to their wives hired Jerry to John Petty &amp; Beverly to <gap/> Hendricks notes were regularly given for the hire of ^said^ slaves until <date when="1862">1862</date> &amp; <date when="1863">the present year</date> &amp; for these years he was informed by correspondence &amp; messages that said Petty &amp; Hendrick would keep the slaves on hire as they thertofore had done The troubles growing out of the situation of the Country &amp; other causes created great difficulties in the management of slave property &amp; your Petitioner readily relied on the information he received that said Petty &amp; Hendrick would keep the slaves as above stated &amp; your Petitioner did not go to Warren to see about the matter. Your Petitioner<pb/>
<lb/>states positively that it never was his intention to violate the law &amp; to allow his slaves to hire their own time &amp; to go at large &amp; hire themselves to others &amp; had he been able to attend the trial &amp; give information to the lawyer who defended him he believe the jury would not have found as they did. Under the circumstances he prays your Excellency to remit the fines. In testimony of which he hath hereto set his name this <date when="1863-09-26">26th of September 1863</date></p>
<p>Alanson Trigg</p>
<p>I request the Governor to grant the prayer of the foregoing Petition</p>
<p>J. R. Underwood</p>
<p>I know M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Trigg well &amp; somthing of the facts connected with this case &amp; I feel <hi rend="str">honorbly</hi> that it is <hi rend="underline">indeed</hi> one of the cases in which the Governor should interfere &amp; remit the fines -- </p>
<p>R. B. Hawkins<pb/></p>
<p>Warren C. C.</p>
<p>Remit fine except costs &amp; fees and send to Hon. J. R. Underwood
<lb/>Bowlingreen Ky</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov</p>
<p>Alanson Trigg
<lb/>$80 -- 
<lb/><date when="1863-10-07">7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Oct/ 63</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
