<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3373"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. N. Brown, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5492</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-236</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Union County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>William Yates is about to present a petition to the Govenor of Ky praying to be released of a fine of $40 assessed against him by the Union Circuit Court for standing a Stallion without licence- and he has called upon me to make a statement of the fact to accompany the petition which is as forthwith</p>
<p>Mr Yates was the owner of the horse and him &amp; me agreed to stand the horse in partnership that season half of the time at my house &amp; half at his house, about the time of the Commencement ^of the season^ I purchased the horse from Mr Yates &amp; stood him myself at my house &amp; Yates had nothing further to do with the horse </p>
<p>Yates and myself were indicted for standing said horse without licence, I come into court &amp; confessed Judgment for the penalty &amp; <hi rend="underline">have</hi> <hi rend="underline">paid it</hi>, Yates was also fined $40 the full amount of the penalty- the Commonwealth has all ready received the full penalty for standing one horse without licence and I request your Excellency to release Mr Yates from his fine</p>
<p>W N. Brown</p>
<p>Witnesses
<lb/>Hiram M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Elroy</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
