<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-005-0132"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George W. Gwin, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1021</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Apprehension of Fugitives from Justice Papers, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR7-204 to BR7-205</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-16">16 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Franklin County } sct.</p>
<p>Personally appeared before me a Justice of the Peace in and for the County and State aforesaid John E. Murrah, Assisstant Quarter Master of the State of Kentucky and made oath, that in <date when="1865-09">September 1865</date> he was on duty as assisstant Quarter Master of Kentucky at the then Post of Lebanon Ky he had in his employment as clerk in his office as quarter Master aforesaid C, B, Pratt, and on or about the <date when="1865-09-10">10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of September 1865</date> the said C, B, Pratt, in his capacity of clerk aforesaid had placed under his care, and received into his possession, the sum of Twenty ^one^ <hi rend="str">Nine</hi> Hundred and ^ten^ <hi rend="str">ninety nine</hi> Dollars <hi rend="str">and Sixteen cents</hi>, of money due to affiant as quarter Master aforesaid, and which said C, B, Pratt undertook and was in duty bound to pay out to affiant, but which Said Sum of Twenty one Hundred and ten dollars, said C, B, Pratt did unlawfully fraudulently and felloneously embezzle and Convert to his own use, Said C, B, Pratt received said sum of money and Embezzled the same in the County of Jefferson and State of Kentucky</p>
<p>J E Murrah
<lb/>Capt &amp; A Q M Ky Vol<pb/></p>
<p>Sworn to and Subscirbed by J.E. Murrah in due form before the undersigned a Justice of the peace for Franklin County this <date when="1865-12-16">16th day of Decr. 1865</date></p>
<p>Geo W Gwin J. P.
<lb/><stamp type="revenue"/><pb/></p>
<p>Requisition upon Gov of Louisiana for C B Pratt &amp; appt<hi rend="sup">d</hi>. Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Slater agent <date when="1865-12-16">16 Dec /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
