<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-006-0007"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas E. Bramlette, Requisition</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1053</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Requisitions for the Return of Fugitives from Justice, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR6-7 to BR6-7-1</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-11-03">3 November 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency,
<lb/>GOVERNOR OF THE STATE OF <gap/> </p>
<p>WHEREAS, Red Nichol statnds charged by the Crittenden Circuit Court of Robbery. AND WHEREAS, Information has been received at the Executive Department of this State, that the said Red Nichol has fled from justice, and is now in Fort Delaware -- and it being important and highly necessary for the good of society that the perpetrators of such offences should be brought to justice:</p>
<p>Now, Therefore, I, THOMAS E. BRAMLETTE, Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, by virtue of the authority vested in me by the Constitution and laws of the United States, do, by these presents, demand the said Red Nichol as a fugitive from the justice of the laws of this State, and made known to you<hi rend="str">r Excellency</hi> as Commander of Fort Delaware that I have appointed M. Towery my agent to receive said fugitive, and bring him to this State, having jurisdiction of the said offense, that he may abide his trial for the crime for which he stands charged.</p>
<p>In compliance with the requisitions, I herewith annex and submit to you<hi rend="str">r Excellency</hi> a copy of the Indictment upon which the demand is founded, which I certify to be authentic.</p>
<p>In Testimony Whereof, I have hereunto set my hand, and caused the Seal of the Commonwealth to be affixed, at FRANKFORT, on the <date when="1863-11-03"> 3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> day of November in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and Sixty three,</date> and in the 72<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> year of the Commonwealth.<figure type="seal"/></p>
<p>BY THE GOVERNOR: Tho. E. Bramlette
<lb/>E. L. Vanwinkle, SECRETARY OF STATE,
<lb/>By Jas R. Page
<lb/>Asst. Sec
<lb/>Commonwealth Office -- WM. E. HUGHES, State Printer.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
