<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2400"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Ann Brown, Verdict</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7037</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-331</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-06">6 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Kentucky. Jefferson Circuit Court, <date when="1865-09">Sept<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Term 1865</date>.
<lb/><date when="1865-09-06">September 6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>.
<lb/>The Com<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi>th of Kentucky
<lb/>against } Felony.
<lb/>Ann Brown</p>
<p>Ann Brown, who has been indicted by a Grand Jury of this Circuit for felony and who is now Confined in the Jail of this Circuit on said charge, was this day led to the Bar of this Court by and in the Custody of the Jailor attending the same, and being arraigned upon said indictment <hi rend="underline">plead</hi> not guilty thereto and for her trial put herself upon the Country and the Attorney for the Commonwealth likewise, wherefore, to try the issue joined let a Jury Come and thereupon Came a jury towit: W. P. Shepherd, Thos Reese, W. S. Condry, A. Martin, J. W. Prather, Sam<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Caswell, H. H. Sale, C. C. Rufer, J. W. Cowling, Jacob Attinger, Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H. Pettit and T. T. Beattie, who being duly elected tried and sworn will and truly to try and true deliverance make between the Commonwealth and the accused upon oath returned into Court the following verdict, "We of the Jury find the Defendant guilty of Manslaughter and say that she shall be Confined in the Penitentiary for the term of two Years, but in consequence of mitigating Circumstances recommend her to the Clemency of the Governor.</p>
<p>Sam<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Caswell forman."
<lb/>And thereupon the Prisoner was<pb/>
<lb/>remanded and taken to Jail accordingly"</p>
<p>A Copy, Att: <hi rend="underline">James P. Chambers Clk</hi></p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Ann Brown
<lb/>The Comth
<lb/>vs } Copy of Trial &amp; verdict Manslaughter
<lb/>Ann Brown<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Pardoned <date when="1865-09-07">7 Sept /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
