<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1109"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Joseph E. Tye et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10577</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-217</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Beriah Magoffin Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Joseph E Tye would respectfully represent that at the last term of the Whitley Circuit Court he was indicted for unlawful gaming entered his appearance &amp; confessed Judgment for $20. He says that the circumstances under which he was indicted &amp; found guilty on as follows</p>
<p>He went to where some of his acquaintances were playing in a game of cards. they were playing poker and betting Sticks. as he had frequently played the game for amusment &amp; kept the game with buttons corn &amp;c he did not suspect but that it was a game for amusement and when he was asked if he would take some sticks &amp; play he consented &amp; did play in the game He says however that it afterward turned out that they were actually playing for money and counting the sticks as being worth so much money. He says he did not win nor loose any thing in the game nor did he pay any thing for the sticks handed him when he began the game and that as soon as he learned that the game was for money he quit but he says that one of the party that was engaged in the game who understood what was being played for was called before the Grand Jury. &amp; he was indicted. He says that he is not a Gambler nor ever was that he would not have been in this game if he had have known what they were playing for. He therefore asks that your Excellency will remit the fines as he is a poor man and unable to pay the same &amp; do justice to himself &amp; he promises no more to be greatly of a like offinse</p>
<p>Joseph E Tye<pb/></p>
<p>The undersigned whose names are hereto subscribed concur in the statements so far as the facts upon which, <hi rend="str">the Petition</hi> the Petitioner was found guilty and that he is not a gambler &amp; a poor man and would join in the prayer of the Petition and ask that the fine be remitted</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>R. Boyd C C W C
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>W. L Cook Atty
<lb/>G. L. Maret
<lb/>J H Scott M. D.
<lb/>E D Wilder
<lb/>G W Reevs
<lb/>J L Crains
<lb/>C. C. Boyers
<lb/>Henry Boyers
<lb/>George Sago
<lb/>M W levin
<lb/>Mattias Prewit
<lb/>Camda Lovett
<lb/>M E Mahan
<lb/>Sam Sutton
<lb/>William Patrick
<lb/>J L Meleaty S W C
<lb/><cb n="2"/>H F Finley
<lb/>D. H. Leforce
<lb/>John Rapier
<lb/>Michael Richardson
<lb/>M. M. Buevis
<lb/>John Wood
<lb/>Evan Mahan
<lb/>Jack Dunham
<lb/>E F Adkins
<lb/>E. F. Patrick
<lb/>E. F. King
<lb/>James Adkins D. S.
<lb/>M M Ellison
<lb/>S. Denham
<lb/>G A Lyttle
<lb/>M. C. Roche
<lb/>Martin Caddell
<lb/>Jack Rain
<lb/>J M Runis
<lb/>J. A. Skeens
<lb/>Seth Freeman
<lb/>G P Caddell<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>Whitley Cir Ct
<lb/>$20. } Gaming
<lb/>Jos E Tye</p>
<p>Remitted 
<lb/>B M</p>
<p>Issd <date when="1861-05-13">May 13. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
