<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2233"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John J. Dursley et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9309</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-370</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>His excellency Beriah M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin
<lb/>Executive of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner would state for the reasons herein after named that your petitioner would ask your Executive clemency 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> a warrant was issued in the name of the Commonwealth against your petitioner John J. Dursley for Breach of the peace committed by striking one Gran Smith <hi rend="str">Th</hi>the facts are that said smith cursed abused and Badly treated your petitioner at meeting at a school house in Trigg County Ky on Sunday or Monday said smith came to the school house where your petitioner was as a schollar attending to his duties as such and being a boy of in his 18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> year your petitioner being provoked did strike said Smith, he being told by persons presant that he had a rite so to do -- on the trial your petitioner offerd to <unclear/> the insults on Sunday previous which the Magistrate Refuse to go to the Jury affidavits of same whome are here in enclosed your Petitioner being a Boy of tender years poor and the son of a widowed woman the fine assesed being $23 dollars and 5 days confinement in the county Jail is extravagant oppressive and wrong we whose names are here unto subscribed I do concur and freely ask Executive Clemency<pb/>
<lb/>and believe this to be one of those cases that not only should be asked but granted we there fore as ever pray <hi rend="str">and</hi> &amp;c.</p>
<p>John J. Dursley
<lb/>James Elliott C. T. C
<lb/>James H. Bradley Juror
<lb/>C M R Cox Juror
<lb/>Juror Drury A. Farrell
<lb/>W.. -- Bryant Juror
<lb/>Miles H Cox Juror
<lb/>S. A. Miller Juror
<lb/>G W Bryan Juror
<lb/>John Newton Juror
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Wm. H. Murrell</hi> atty
<lb/>Q. S. Spiceland Atty County
<lb/>Nathan C Foster
<lb/>W H Cato Atty
<lb/>R,, S,, Goodwin Juror
<lb/>W A Newton
<lb/>J W Brashears Juror
<lb/>S,, P,, James Juror
<lb/>David C Blankenship
<lb/>J. A Phillips one of witnesses
<lb/>H. W. Dishler Juror
<lb/>R R Turner Esqr
<lb/>G G Goodwin <hi rend="str">atty general</hi>
<lb/>W H Owen Atty
<lb/>Asa Guthrie</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B M</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
