<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2061"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Pheby Race to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9137</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-88 to MG24-89</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Exclency B Magoffin Gov of the Comth of Kentucky your Petitioner Pheby Race states that She was fined the sum of $17 before A Riley Justice of the Peace of Pendleton County Ky for breach of the peace commited by Whipping one Eliza Ralling She admits that She did give the said Eliza Ralling a Thrasing but the facts are theas she <hi rend="str">that</hi> is your Petitioner is 67 years old &amp; the said Eliza Rallings is 24 years old that the said Eliza is a Woman of Louse virtue that she came to the house of your Petitioner in the month of <date when="1862-05">May 1862</date> Drunk &amp; used very abusive Language to wit she caled your petitioner a damed old whore &amp; many other hard names untill she could shout it no longer when she gathered a bush &amp; give her a basting She pray that your Hon will Remit said fine in as much as she done no more then Any Decent woman would have don under the same circumstances</p>
<p>Pheby Race</p>
<p>B Magoffin I prosecuted the case for the Comlth vs Mrs Race &amp; the facts as as she states in her pet &amp; I was astonashed that the Jury fined her more then one cent I know Mrs Race<pb/>
<lb/>She is a Woman of Good caracture that is one of the best in the meighborhood where She lives &amp; the other woman is no better then one of the Davis Wimen of Frankfort &amp; I have no hisotation in saying that the fine should be Remited &amp; in fact I advise her to put you on the subject &amp; have it Remited for I do not think she gave her a lick amiss so I Joine in the prayrs that you Remit said fine</p>
<p>With Respect I Remaine yours
<lb/>A G Roberts Cty Atty
<lb/>protem<pb/></p>
<p>Respite 12 Mo
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Pendleton J P Ct
<lb/>$17. } 
<lb/>Pheby Race</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-07-22">July 22 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
