<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3181"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James F. Dejarnett et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5300</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-230 to BR41-231</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Crittenden County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlett
<lb/>Govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Stephen Young would Represent that on the <date when="1865-11-15">15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of November 1865</date> The Grand Jury for Crittenden county accused Franklin Gibson William Morgan Stephen Young and George Pilant with offence of forceably Rescueing from the Jail of Crittenden county, where he was Rightfully detained upon a charge of Felony one James Guest. Your petitioner States that he is not guilty of said offence either in whole or in part that he neither aided or counseled the Rescue that he is very old, and had tried to live the life of a good quiet, law abiding citizen, and now believes that this change is made to persecute him on account of his devoted Unionism, and because he expressed Sympathy for sd Guest after he had been placed in Jail who was a brave active officer in the Federal army The charge against him is false and as he believes malicious Wherefore he prays for the Interposition of the Executive clemency for a pardon and all proper Relief</p>
<p>And We the undersigned petitioners would represent that we are well acquainted<pb/>
<lb/>with the petitioner Stephen Young that we know him to be a good quiet law abiding citizen every way Reliable we do not believe him guilty of the charge made against him and in our opinion he is being charged unjustly and prosecuted without cause he is one of our oldest citizens, and we would Respectfully ask if consistent with your views of Right and Justice the interposition of Executive clemency</p>
<p>James F. Dejarnett H. C. Hill
<lb/>Leonard F Hughes
<lb/>J J Hughes
<lb/>D. C. Baird
<lb/>J. H. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clusky
<lb/>James. T. Jones
<lb/>W <unclear/> Hughes
<lb/>J J Hughes sen
<lb/>Andrew <unclear/>
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> S. Clark
<lb/>Jesse F Paris
<lb/>P A Hunt
<lb/>Isaac Sprer
<lb/>A. J. Baker
<lb/>G G Sparnes
<lb/>James H. Hinckeld
<lb/>Robt Wheeler
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> F Paris
<lb/>K L Clark<pb/>
<lb/>Lewis H. Parris
<lb/>S. C. Young
<lb/>W J Paris
<lb/>Jesse Bavid
<lb/><unclear/> S Richardson
<lb/>FA <unclear/>
<lb/>G Hunter
<lb/>William N <unclear/>
<lb/>E, M. Lernen
<lb/>W. B. Brown
<lb/>Elisha Conger
<lb/>J T Conger
<lb/>James M Paris
<lb/><unclear/> Hunt
<lb/>F Courtney
<lb/>H T Brawner
<lb/>R L Brawner
<lb/>E J D Brawner
<lb/>B B Brawner
<lb/>S H Haverton
<lb/>H. B. Jones
<lb/>John R Boyd
<lb/>J C <unclear/>
<lb/>J. N. Smith
<lb/>A. Woodall
<lb/>C. T M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>nealy
<lb/>James Butler<pb/>
<lb/>F. E. Crider
<lb/>L. C. Taurs
<lb/>Nathan Gravy</p>
<p>Stephen Young
<lb/>} Petition</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
