<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2587"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">C. S. Marshall to E. J. Bullock</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7224</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-137 to BR16-138</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Paducah, McCracken County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-11-05">5 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Paducah Ky. <date when="1865-11-05">Nov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> 5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Col. E. J. Bullock</p>
<p>Dear Sir -- I have read the correspondence between yourself and P. D. Yeiser late atty for the commonwealth, in relation to the case of W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Miles -- I presided as judge on the trial of W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Taylor &amp; Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Hudgins who were jointly indicted with W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Miles for robbery -- Taylor &amp; Hudgins were convicted in the two cases each I beleive in both the cases the proof was that there were but two persons engaged in the robbery -- I beleive from the evidence that Taylor &amp; Hudgins were the persons who did the robbery and that Miles &amp; Edwards (who was also indicted) were not present at either robbery -- They were with Taylor &amp; Hudgins during the day, before the robbery at night, and probably on the day afterwards, and were very intimate, and I think<pb/>
<lb/>were all together except Hudgins when arrested -- It is probable from the evidence that Miles &amp; Edwards Knew the robbery was intended before it was done, and very probable that they Knew of it afterwards -- I think the evidence not strong enough to convict them as principals or accessories before the fact and probably not even as accessories after the fact -- Miles give bail I think in these cases for $1000 each with his father as security -- He went off and his bond was forfeited &amp; judg<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> rendered against his father for the amount -- Old man Miles has the character of an industrious, honest man and I think is a poor man -- </p>
<p>Respectfully your friend &amp;c
<lb/>C. S. Marshall<pb/></p>
<p>Ballard Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Miles
<lb/>Pardoned
<lb/>Indicted for Robbery <date when="1863-09">Sept term/63</date>
<lb/><date when="1865-11-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
