<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0654"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Sam. C. Hughes to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4773</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-4 to BR10-5</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Morganfield, Union County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-04-23">23 April 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>SAM. C. HUGHES
<lb/>ATTORNEY AT LAW,
<lb/>MORGANFIELD, KY.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Will practice in the Courts of Union and the adjoining Counties. All Collecting Business promptly attended to.</p>
<p>Morganfield, Ky.
<lb/><date when="1864-04-23">April 23 1864</date>
<lb/>Gov. Bramlette
<lb/>D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Sir</p>
<p>Enclosed you find the petition of some of our very best citizens &amp; officers, signed in behalf of a loyal, and law abiding old Gentleman M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Joseph Sprague is the entire owner of the tavern. He will have the whole amount to pay, unless you in your clemency remit it.</p>
<p>M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Sprague is one of the tried loyal men of the county, an old gentleman of unexceptional character, and would<pb/>
<lb/>have been the last man in Union County to knowningly violate the laws of the land.</p>
<p>My uncle W G Hughes was county judge, just previous to the expiration of his license, and after his death, and before my election to the office, M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Sprague made application at a regular term of the County Court and was assured, by the acting clerk, that his application under the circumstances was sufficient and to go on in his business</p>
<p>Between that and the time of my election which was only 6 days, he was afterwards indicted<pb/>
<lb/>for keeping a tipling house.</p>
<p>The very <hi rend="str">day I was</hi> ^1st term^ I held he obtained license.</p>
<p>It would indeed be a hardship to permit this fine to be collected by capias profine under the circumstances</p>
<p>These facts of course could not go to the jury</p>
<p>Yours &amp;c
<lb/>Sam C Hughes</p>
<p>P S. Mr Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> S Chapman was the county clerk at the time, and he has signed as you will perceive the petition</p>
<p>Yours &amp;c S C H</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
