<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0567"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Jack Adams et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4686</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-400 to BR9-401</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mount Vernon, Rockcastle County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-03-12">12 March 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Mt vernon <date when="1864-03-12">March 12 64</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency Thomas E Bramlette</p>
<p>Your undersigned petitioner would respectfully State that Liberty Longford was indited in the Rockcastle Circuit Court for erecting a fince across the Public highway (a county road) and at the present <date when="1864-03">March Term of Said court 1864</date> was fined one hundred &amp; sixty two dollars.</p>
<p>The facts of the case were about as ^follows^ the road run through the lands of said Langford and he chainged said road for a small distance not exceeding 150 yards in lenth, thereby considerable shortning the distance and placing the road on the old tract orriginally establised by the County Court, but which having bein obstructed with fallen timbers, was discoontinued for several years and another way opened by the ovesreer and the said Langford believing that the old way was the best way and suiting his conveinence to the chainge it back on accont of the convenience of his farming opperation, did proced to clear off all the obstruction out of the old tract, and make it agood road, with no inconveinenve resulting to the public by the chainge he then went to the overseer and <hi rend="str">and</hi> he accepted the chainge &amp;<pb/>
<lb/>and recovered the new road as opened by Langford, he then fenced up the old road Said Langford an industrous &amp; honest man a good farmer and has a large family to support we believe that he had no intention of violating the law and that he did no damage to the Public in <hi rend="str">removing</hi> charging the tract of the road that small distance and considering it a verry great harship for him to pay it we most ernestly ask that the fine be remitted</p>
<p>Jack Adams
<lb/>H. Carpenter
<lb/>R. S. Myers, one of the Jury
<lb/>O. Adams
<lb/>David N. Williams
<lb/>Richard Singleton
<lb/>B. K. Bethurum Judge of B C C
<lb/>W Stegall
<lb/>M. J. Miller
<lb/>D G Colyer
<lb/>M. A. Brown
<lb/>John D Pursell
<lb/>Uriah Albright
<lb/>John French
<lb/>H. R. Moore
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> McClure S R C
<lb/>E T. Fish C. R. C. C<pb/></p>
<p>Refused
<lb/>Re<hi rend="str">mitted except fess &amp; costs</hi>fused
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette</p>
<p>Liberty Langford petition</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
