<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0003-106-0001"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. F. Marvin, Address of the First Kentucky Regiment on the Presentation of a Flag to Col. Bramlette, By the Ladies of Lexington</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14449</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>W.F. Marvin Address</collection>
      <idno/>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Speech</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>ADDRESS OF THE FIRST KENTUCKY REGIMENT -ON THE- Presentation of a Flag to Col. Bramlette,
<lb/>By the Ladies of Lexington.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>By W. F. Marvin.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Thou lov'd cherished Banner by beauty enrolled,
<lb/>And baring thy bosom of azure and gold;
<lb/>Float wide to the breeze in the hand of the brave,
<lb/>Till Freedom shall wave thee o'er Tyranny's grave.</p>
<p>On, on, while a foeman to Liberty's cause
<lb/>Raise a hand against thee, and our Union's laws;
<lb/>May a coward ne'er sully thy folds with his breath,
<lb/>But they stars shine more brightly o'er victory or death.</p>
<p>In the thick of the Battle we'll guard thee with pride -- 
<lb/>Though thousands may fall -- gather still by thy side,
<lb/>While <hi rend="italic">Beauty</hi> and <hi rend="italic">Duty</hi>, the watch-words may prove
<lb/>To waken each spirit to Valor and Love.</p>
<p>On, on, to the Battle, the smile and caress,
<lb/>Of youth and of beauty each Hero shall bless;
<lb/>While mothers and sweet-hearts, and sisters and sires
<lb/>Kindle widely new torches from Liberty's fires.</p>
<p>'Tis the Flag of our Fathers, the Flag of the brave,
<lb/>The Flag that still waves o'er our Washington's grave,
<lb/>The Flag that our Mothers have gazed on with pride,
<lb/>And the Flag where our bravest in victory died.</p>
<p>Though tattered and torn in the heat of the strife,
<lb/>We will treasure each shred and defend it with life,
<lb/>Though shorn of its beauty, to <hi rend="italic">your</hi> beauty true,
<lb/>We will fight for its honor, our county, and YOU.</p>
<p>With BRAMLETTE, and SCOTT, and MCKEE, and a Host
<lb/>Of Leaders as brave as the bravest can boast,
<lb/>We will follow our Banner with love and with pride,
<lb/>And return it with honor, or die by its side.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
