<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-038-0023"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. M. Hewitt, Report</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG12507</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Union Artillery, Navy and Marines Primary Source Documents ; Misc U.S.C.T. Primary Source Documents</collection>
      <idno>Box 14, Folder BTRY B - 1st REGT LIGHT ARTILLERY 2nd BTRY HISTORY</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-11-18">18 November 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Report</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville Ky
<lb/><date when="1863-11-18">November 18<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi>/63</date>
<lb/>Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi></p>
<p>I respectfully call your attention to the subjoined communication.</p>
<p>J W Walls a private in my company claims the Rank of 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Lieut and has at this time a commission duly signed, from the department of this state</p>
<p>He has certified on honor to the Dep<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> of the Cumberland, in which I have been serving since its Organization, that such is the fact; and that he was mustered the <date when="1861-08-12">12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of August (1861)</date> at Camp Dick Robinson Ky, as first Lieu<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> of Company (D) "3 Ky Reg<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Inf<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Col<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">n</hi></hi> Bramlett)' by Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Nelson. That he was afterwards Mustered by Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Thomas at the same camp on the <date when="1861-10-08">8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Oc<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> 1861</date>, as 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Lieu<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> of Company (D) 3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Ky Reg<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Inf<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">ty</hi></hi> &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>.</p>
<p>To all of this I enter a <hi rend="underline">positive</hi> <hi rend="underline">denial</hi>, and ask, that this commission he now holds hearing date <date when="1861-08-12">Augt 12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861</date> be recalled; and for these reasons.</p>
<p>1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> At the mustering in of the 3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Ky Reg<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Col<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">n</hi></hi> ^Bramlett^ Com<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> The rolls now in your Office of C<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">omp</hi></hi> (D) said Reg<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> will show that J, W Walls was mustered as a private, &amp; not as Lieutenant as he asserts.</p>
<p>2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> That G W Nell as first Lieutenant, &amp; myself as Captain, were the only Officers, so mustered.<pb/>
<lb/>3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> That at the date of said muster my company was short of the number, to entitle me to more than one Lieutenant.</p>
<p>4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> That Company (D) was mustered as an Infantry organization, and hence was not entitled to but <hi rend="underline">one</hi> 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> <hi rend="underline">Lieut</hi> even if full to the maximum.</p>
<p>5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> I positively assert that he never was a Lieu<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> in my company, though he acted, as such for a few weeks. In order to secure the best ability of my command, I would, and did appoint some member to discharge the duties of some office to be filled, when if on <hi rend="underline">trial</hi>, they proved competent, I would recommend them as suitable, if not, I would return them to the ranks, and in this way all my officers have been commissioned.</p>
<p>Mr Walls was thus <hi rend="underline">tested</hi> and in every regard proved himself unfit for the service, nor can he at <hi rend="underline">this</hi> date, drill a gun Squad.</p>
<p>6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Every Officer and private in my command will testify to the fact of his never having been mustered as a Lieu<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> and to his utter, incapacity to fill such an office.</p>
<p>He has always been mustered as a private, and without objection, been paid as such up to <date when="1863-01">January 1863</date>, when for the first time he claimed to be a Lieutenant<pb/>
<lb/>His commission was issued in this way.</p>
<p>In <date when="1862-01">January 1862</date>, Lieutenant Ellsworth, was making out the pay Rolls of the Company; for the term ending <date when="1861-12-31">Debr 31<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1861</date>. John Vanwinkle Esqr. obtained or Rather made a coppy of said rolls for the Deartment at Frankfort. On these rolls J W Walls, A, A, Ellsworth &amp; H M Turner, appear as <hi rend="underline">acting</hi> Lieutenants. Neither of them were Lieutenants by election until after the second of January, when Ellsworth was duly elected, Jr First and H M Turner, senior second Lieutenant while J W Walls was left in the rank</p>
<p>Each of the three had served two months or so, as acting Lieutenants. When the rolls were coppied by Mr Vanwinkle the remarks explaining the status of the three were not appended, the rolls were not complete. From this roll or <unclear/> on this <hi rend="underline">incomplete</hi> roll, the commissions were issued, to all three, in the care of Ellsworth &amp; Turner, <hi rend="underline">right</hi>, but not in the case of Walls, as the company had selected another in his place. In all our Ky Military organizations, the men by vote elected their commissioned Officers, in the first instance. I was to elected &amp; all the<pb/>
<lb/>Lieutenants. Govenor Bramlett, who was in command of the Regiment at the time of its being mustered in, and when it was paid off, can testify to the fact that Walls was a private, though he claims to have been mustered as a Lieutenant at the organization of the Company. I have been once Court Marshalled on the charge of withholding his commission, but the mustering officer decided that Wall was but a private, and he was ordered to the ranks. Since the Removal of Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Rosecrans, &amp; consequent changes in departments, the matter has agian been Revived, greatly to my detriment. I therefore ask the Department to recall the commission issued to J W Walls, it having been issued by error. There are other facts that I could give, but these will I think satisfy you that my request is right.</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>J M Hewett
<lb/>Captain 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Ky Battery
<lb/>Light Artillery<pb/></p>
<p>Frankfort <date when="1864-01-25">Jany 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi>/64</date></p>
<p>John Walls was never a L<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> while under my command The statements of Capt Hewett up to the time of the Co being detached as an Artillery Co. in <date when="1861-12">Dec<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> 1861</date>, are correct. When the Co. was detached by order of Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Buell, I was permitted to raise a company to fill the place which I did in a few days while at Columbia in <date when="1861-12">De<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 1861</date>. Walls was no L<hi rend="sup">t</hi> &amp; his Commission must be a fraud, &amp; should be revoked</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette</p>
<p>In obedience to the above Order -- the commission of 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Lieut. issued to private John Walls must be revoked</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">John Boyle</hi>
<lb/>Adjt. Gen of Ky</p>
<p>2 Batty<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Lieut Walls<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Com. revoked <date when="1864-01-25">Jany 25. 1864</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>1. 2.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
