<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3213"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">B. Boyd and W. H. Randall to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5332</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-396 to BR41-397</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Laurel County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thomas E Bramlette Governer of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioners W H. Randall and R Boyd would respectfully represent unto your Excellency that on the <date when="1865-11-14">14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of November 1865</date> They jointly became the Bail on the security for Thomas Peira Confined in the Jail of Laurel County charged with Horse Stealing for his appearance in the Laurel circuit court to answer said charge That Said Peira failed to appear and his bond on recognizance was forfeited and at the <date when="1866-08">August Term of the Laurel Circuit Court 1866</date> Judgment went against your Petitioners upon said forfeiture for the sum of five Hundred dollars that they were induced to go his bail first because they believed him innocent of the charge he was able to prove and brought the witness to us that he had borrowed the Horse to go to <unclear/> on and had nothing to do with the Stealing He also sent and had an other man arrested who is still in jail for Stealing the same horse that the Man, ^Thomas Peira^ had served three years in the Federal army and was Honorable discharged and while in the army contracted the disease of Rheumatism and was almost dying in the Jail from the efects of said disease and out of Simpathy for his condition<pb/>
<lb/>he having lost his health in the federal army and ^your Petitioners^ believing said Prira innocent were induced to and did go his bail <hi rend="str">and was fined</hi> as aforesaid</p>
<p>The previous considered the prayer of your Petitioners is that you remit said fine for which they will ever feel greatful</p>
<p>B. Boyd
<lb/>W. H. Randall</p>
<p>We are Satisfied that the Statements in the above petition are true and ask that the Judgment be remitted we think it ought to be done</p>
<p>M. L. Rice
<lb/>E W Miller
<lb/>N. B. Jones
<lb/>John H Carrier Jailer
<lb/>W. H. Jackson
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. J. Canifax
<lb/>T S Newcomb
<lb/>Jarvis Jackson
<lb/>J V McKee
<lb/>T T Coldwell
<lb/>H. G. Litton
<lb/>C. W. Jones
<lb/>A Allman
<lb/>J. H Faris
<lb/>J T Brown
<lb/>S C Jackson<pb/>
<lb/>Wm T Heren
<lb/>A. L. Reed
<lb/>A L Stephens
<lb/>R L Ewell C L C C
<lb/>John Pitman Clerk
<lb/>W S Pitman
<lb/>W. T. Bunter
<lb/>R. T. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee<pb/>
<lb/>Laurel Cir Ct
<lb/>W N. Randall
<lb/>&amp;
<lb/>R Boyd
<lb/>Present to
<lb/>C B Faris</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
