<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-034-0007"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">State of Indiana v. James A. Clemmons, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7735</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Requisitions for the Return of Fugitives from Justice, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-12 to R3-13</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Johnson County, Indiana</placeName>
    <date when="1863-03-12">12 March 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The State of Indiana
<lb/>Johnson County } ss.</p>
<p>In the Johnson Circuit Court <date when="1863-03">March Term 1863</date></p>
<p>The State of Indiana
<lb/>vs
<lb/>James A Clemmons</p>
<p>The Grand Jurors of the state of Indiana empanneled sworn and charged to enquire of felon<hi rend="str">ious</hi>ies &amp; offenses committed within Johnson County, upon their oath present charge and find That James A Clemmons on the <date when="1863-01-26">26" day of January 1863</date> at and in the said county of Johnson and the state of Indiana and within the Jurisdiction of this court, did feloniously purposely and with premeditated malice unlawfully kill and murder Beverly J. Dickerson by then and there shooting the said Beverly J. Dickerson with a gun wadded with powder and leaden balls contrary to the form of the statute in such case made and provided and against the peace and dignity of the state of Indiana.</p>
<p>William W Leathers
<lb/>Prosecuting Attorney</p>
<p>And upon the back of said Indictment the following endorsement appears to wit<pb/></p>
<p>Secretary of State</p>
<p>Johnson C. C.
<lb/>State of Indiana
<lb/>vs.
<lb/><hi rend="underline">James A</hi> <hi rend="underline">Clemmons</hi><pb/></p>
<p>In the Johnson Circuit Court the State of Indiana vs James A Clemmons, Indictment for murder -- a true bill James M. Kelly Foreman of the Grand Jury.</p>
<p>Witness for the State 
<lb/>Henry Whitesides John W. Kightley David Alexander Benjamin Davis A J Tucker Susan Eddy. Belle Eddy. Ann Terhune Margaret Bowen Ann Farly Caroline Bowen Nancy Hill Nancy Danshul Patrick M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Marrel John Bowen sen Louisa Gatewood Rob T Jeffry John High Jacob Aton Dr Payne Dr Hall &amp; Dr Jones. The indictment was filed in my office <date when="1863-03-11">March "11" 1863.</date></p>
<p><unclear/> Barnett clk.</p>
<p>State of Indiana
<lb/>Johnson County } ss</p>
<p>I W H Barnett Clerk of the Johnson Circuit Court in and for the County and state aforesaid do hereby certify the within and foregoing is a true copy of the Indictment wherein the state of Indiana is plaintiff and James A Clemmons is defendant as now is on file in my office.</p>
<p><figure type="seal"><ab>JOHNSON <unclear/> <unclear/> COURT
<lb/>INDIANA</ab></figure></p>
<p>In testimony whereof I have hereunto set my hand and the seal of said Franklin <date when="1863-03-12">March 12" 1863</date></p>
<p>William H. Barnett clk<pb/></p>
<p>I, William W. Leathers Prosecuting Attoney, within and for the 5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Judicial Circuit, in the State of Indiana, do hereby certify that I am informed and believe that James A. Clemmons is a futitive from justice from the state of Indiana, and has escaped into the State of Kentucky,</p>
<p>I therefore recommend that a requisition be made upon the Governor of the State of Kentucky for the said James A. Clemmons,</p>
<p>This the <date when="1863-03-12">12" day of March 1863</date></p>
<p>William W. Leathers
<lb/>Prosecuting Atty
<lb/>5" Judicial Circuit</p>
<p>The <unclear>Secretary of State</unclear> will please make out proper requisition for the arrest of James A. Clemmons upon the Governor of Kentucky, requesting that the warrant be delivered to Richard Dickerson.
<lb/>Indpls. <date when="1863-03-12">Mch 12 1863.</date></p>
<p>O. P. Morton
<lb/>Governor of Ind<hi rend="sup">a</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
