<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0562"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William S. Flora to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10030</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-372 to MG18-373</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Carlisle, Nicholas County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-01-25">25 January 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Carlisle <date when="1861-01-25">January 25. 1861</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>Berijah Magoffin</p>
<p>Your Petitioner William S. Flora states that about two years ago He lived in Fleming County and the Deputy sheriff of said County executed a writ upon him in favour of the Commonwealth for a misdemeanor. The sheriff Could not explain to him the nature of the indictment then pending &amp; on which the writ issued -- </p>
<p>Shortly afterwards he saw the sheriff &amp; told him there was a mistake, that there were other William Flora's &amp; the writ must have been intended for them, that he was not the Defendant; The sheriff being Convinced said he would alter his return &amp; make a return of not found: and relying upon him to do so he gave no attention to the Case -- Upon the indictment in the Fleming Circuit Court a judgment was rendered against him for $66.33 and upon examination ^he^ finds a William Flora, was indicted for unlawful gaming.</p>
<p>He says he went to the Deputy sheriff who told him he thought he had returned the writ "not found" -- &amp; got his statement ^appended^ hereto</p>
<p>He say he was not the Defendant &amp; not guilty of the <hi rend="str">Crime</hi> offence for which the indictment was found &amp; for which he was fined -- Lately execution issued against him to Nicholas County &amp; he was told he must go to Jail or replevy &amp; he replevied -- This Caused him to investigate the Case: before<pb/>
<lb/>he was Called on by the sheriff he did not know any judgment was had against him. He says the William Floras refered to formerly lived in Nicholas not far from the line of Fleming &amp; if any one was guilty some one of them must have been the one -- ^one^ of them now live in Bracken county</p>
<p>He says he has Consulted lawyers &amp; they say his only remedy is to Petition your Excellency to remit the Judgment which he now respectfully does &amp;<hi rend="sup">c.</hi></p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> S. Flora</p>
<p><hi rend="str">I <gap/> formerly deputy sheriff of Fleming County state that I had a summons ^From the Fleming County Circuit Court^ agt. W</hi><hi rend="str"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="str"> Flora &amp; executed it on the Petitioner -- afterwards was told by the Petitioner that he was not the man &amp; being Convinced I intended to return the writ Not Found &amp; supposed I had done it but lately at Petitioners request I examined &amp; found I had returned it executed.</hi></p>
<p><hi rend="str">I am still satisfied the Petitioner is not the Defendant.</hi><pb/></p>
<p>We recommend to the Governor to remit the fine named in this Petition -- </p>
<p>Fitch Munger
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J H Halladay</hi>
<lb/>Jno A. Campbell
<lb/>W. P. Ross
<lb/>Slavic Berry.
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W. W. Howard</hi>
<lb/>W. I. Still</p>
<p>Carlisle Nicholas co</p>
<p>David Berry says he knew William Flora of Fleming County &amp; W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> S. Flora of this County -- He says William S. Flora is not the name indicted in Fleming County -- </p>
<p><date when="1861-02-06">Feby 6. 1861</date></p>
<p>David Berry<pb/>
<lb/>Carlisle <date when="1861-02-06">Feby 6. 1861</date></p>
<p>Hon Berijah Magoffin</p>
<p>Dear sir I send you this Petition -- I am in hopes you Can grant the relief prayed for as I am satisfied it is proper to do so. by reference to the Statement of the Deputy sheriff you will see the reason Flora did not defend the suit -- David Berry says he knows Both W<hi rend="sup">m.</hi> Floras &amp; that the Petitioner was not indicted see <unclear/> State in 3<hi rend="sup">d.</hi> Page</p>
<p>Your Obt. sev<hi rend="sup">t</hi>.</p>
<p>Fitch Munger</p>
<p>Please send the remission to this ^Post^ office as Our sheriff has last execution</p>
<p>F. Munger</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> S. Flora
<lb/>Petition<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Fleming 
<lb/>Cir. Ct
<lb/>$66.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">33</hi></hi> } Gaming
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-02-15">Feby 15. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
