<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2604"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. M. Martin, Oath</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7241</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-171 to BR16-173</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-12">12 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky.
<lb/>County of Jefferson. City of Louisville.</p>
<p>I Rob't M Martin of the County of Muhlenberg &amp; State of Kentucky. do solemnly swear in the present of Almighty God, that I will henceforth faithfully support protect and defend the Constitution of the United States, and the Union of the States thereunder; and that I will in like manner abide by and faithfully support all laws and proclamations which have been during the late rebellion with reference to the emancipation of slaves.</p>
<p>So help me God.
<lb/>R M Martin</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed before me, at my Head Quarters, at the Military Prison. in the City of Louisville. County of Jefferson. &amp; State of Kentucky. Witness my hand this <date when="1865-10-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of October A. D. 1865</date>.</p>
<p>Lorenzo Day
<lb/>Capt Co F 125<hi rend="sup">th</hi> U S C I in Charge the Prison<pb/></p>
<p>To
<lb/>Hon Andrew Johnson.
<lb/>President of the United States,</p>
<p>I have the honor to make application in accordance with the provision of the Amnesty Proclamation issued under date of <date when="1865-05-29">May. 29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>. for special pardon. A portion of my ^service in the^ <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>army of the socalled Confederate States, has been classed among the exceptions of said Proclamation under the designation of "Raiders from Canada". I enlisted in the army in <date when="1861-05">may 1861</date> at the age of 21. years, and was elected Lieutenant in a company of cavalry. In <date when="--12">December</date> following, I resigned &amp; became a "Special Scout," in which service I continued until the Spring of <date when="1862">1862</date>, when I was elected Lieutenant Colonel of the 10<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Reg. Ky Cav. and thenceforth belonged to the command of Brig Gen'l John. H. Morgan. I commanded the 3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> Brigade of this command, on Morgan's raid thro' Central Kentucky in <date when="1864">1864</date>. During this raid several Staff offices &amp; a few accomplices took large sums of money from the banks at Mt Sterling &amp; Lexington, without authority, &amp; applied it to their private uses, and thro' the negligence or indisposition of Gen'l Morgan the guilty parties were never brought to justice &amp; exposed.</p>
<p>After this disreputable affair reflecting odium alike upon all in the eyes of the Southern public, I decided that if I could honorably do so I would dissovle my connection with the command.<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">2</note></p>
<p>Having information that a few young officers were operating in the Northern States in connection with a secret military organization, with a view to success of our cause and having a fondness for adventure and a partiality for secret service I at once felt that this duty would afford me the opportuity to pursue a career suited to my inclination.</p>
<p>I accordingly procured the endorsement of influential friends and made application to Hon. James. A. Seddon, Secretary of war for assignment to this service, on the grounds that my regiment having been captured on Morgan's raid through Ohio in <date when="1863">1863</date>. I was not commanding my own men.</p>
<p>My application was successful and I was ordered to the North and allowed to pass through the lines of the army <date when="1864-09-25">sept 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi>. 1864</date>. with instructions to encourage &amp; assist the organization &amp; action of the "Conservative" Northern people, and to take part in any expedition intended to release confederate soldiers from prison, or that I deemed beneficial to the cause of the Confederate States. Upon my arrival in the North I found that the organization which I had come to encourage had been exposed. the leaders imprisoned &amp; the people intimidated. I saw that any efforts in this relation would accomplish no good result, and I soon after abandoned this part of my mission.</p>
<p>Hearing that a party of confederates who had made an unsuccessful attempt on Lake Erie against John-<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">3</note>
<lb/>ston's Island, had fled to Canada, I immediately set out to connect myself with them for any similar service that might be attempted thereafter. I was not connected with nor had I any knowledge of the raid of Lt Bennett H. Young upon St Albans Vermont, but I was associated with persons (Confederate soldiers) called "Raiders," in various adventures and expeditions into the United States. none of which ever proved successful. and after several ineffectual efforts to harass and injure the Government of the United States and the people mostly upon the Northern border, I became convinced that this service was of very little benefit to the cause of the Confederate States, and decided to rejoin my old command, which had reorganized under the auspices of Brig Gen'l Basil W. Duke (Gen'l Morgan's successor). I passed through Ohio &amp; Kentucky, and found my command encamped at Abingdon Virginia, where I arrived <date when="1865-03-14">March 14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>. I was then on duty at Lynchburg, Virginia. until the summer of Gen Lee's army From there I proceeded with the retreating column Southward, and at Charlotte N Carolina, our brigade became a portion of Mr Davis escort, and accompanied him through South Carolina, and as far as the town of Washington in Georgia where we were dismissed. Here I was surrendered and paroled according to the terms of Maj Gen W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> T Sherman. I was then given transportation by the Government to Fortress Monroe, Va. Before returning to my home in Kentucky, which I did a few<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">4</note>
<lb/>since I appeared before the proper authorities in Nashville. Tennessee. and subscribed to the oath of Amnesty prescribed by the President's Proclamation of <date when="1865-05-29">May 29<hi rend="sup">th</hi>. 1865</date>.</p>
<p>To my profound surprise immediately after my return to my Father's house. -- whilst on a visit to my Father (who from "first to last" has been a staunch &amp; devoted Union man.) and two brothers both of whom have seen honourable service in the Federal Army. I was suddenly arrested by an officer at the head of a squad of armed citizens. &amp; am held now in prison, shackled, and enfeebled as I am from the effects of seven consecutive wounds. with vague charges impending over me which even were they true, I certainly feel are unauthorized &amp; impossible in the face of my parole, the pledged protection of the Government, &amp; the faith therein placed by myself, which led me so unfearingly to my boyhood's home. Above I have given a brief and correct statement of the character of the offence, which seems to exclude me from the benefit of Executive clemency as granted in the Proclamtation aforesaid.</p>
<p>I have not attempted to conceal the willingness with which for four years. I have striven to uphold the unfortunate cause of the Southern people, and you will not I trust deem me less earnest or less honest in making this application for pardon, on account of that acknowledgement; for with the same sensitive spirit of honour which nerved my fortitude during the trials &amp; privations of the war, do I now accept the result achieved by the arms of the Government of the United States, and in good faith, &amp; all sincerity, pledge myself to abide by the constitution and laws, in like manner with every citizen of the country.</p>
<p>Pardon &amp; release. I most earnestly &amp; respectfully petition.</p>
<p>I have the honour to remain,
<lb/>Respy. Yr ob'd't S'rv't
<lb/>R M Martin
<lb/>Louisville. Ky.
<lb/><date when="1865-10-10">Oct. 10<hi rend="sup">th</hi>. 1865</date>.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
