<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0817"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. A. Prall et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4936</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-263 to BR10-264</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-05-11">11 May 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Hon Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Paris would respectfully represent that Chas C Williams came here last winter a refugee from the South and engaged to work at his trade in this place as a saddler and harniss maker. After remaining here a short time he got to drinking and while in a frolic and after having been under the influence of liquor for a number of days. he was found in possession of a trunk which had been removed by a negro from Fox's Hotel to Griffith's where he boarded having knocked open the trunk and taken out the clothing and dressed himself with it and then taken his seat in the most public place he could find He was committed by an Examing Court being unable to give any explanation of the matter and not really seeming to know anything about it. At the last term of the Court he was indicted for grand Larceny but on account of the condition of the Court House no Jury trials were had and Although Anxious to have his trial he will be compelled to remain in Jail till the next term of the Court The undersigned having had their attention called to the <hi rend="str">circumstances</hi> <hi rend="str">of</hi> occurence at the time and to the demeanor of Williams since although<pb/>
<lb/>not able to furnish a satisfactory explanation of his conduct except upon the idea that his mind was crazed by intoxication. Still there was nothing in <hi rend="str">his</hi> what occurred at the time or since which has about it any appearance of real guilt on his part. He is quite young and his conduct in Jail and upon his trial has been such as to enlist the interest and excite the sympathy of all who have met with him. He is a Union man and is willing to enlist in the service of the Government and would only ask a repreive upon the condiction that he Should thus enlist and have an opportunity to atone by this service for whatever wrong he may have done. The undersigned would respectfully urge and request that upon the conditions above suggested a repreive should be granted him</p>
<p>J A Prall
<lb/>Jesse B Tallrett
<lb/>B. J. Pullen
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. H. McCann
<lb/>R. W. Smiths
<lb/>V. Kriener
<lb/>R T Davis<pb/></p>
<p>I attended the examining trial of Williams which took place before Hon W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> M Samuel Presiding Judge of Bourbon County Court as counsel for Williams. I became fully satisfied, that at the time of the alledged crime, as charged, that Williams was under delerium from use of intoxicating liquor and that he was unconscious of crime &amp; in fact that he was irresponsible and I believe so at this time, and do not doubt if his case comes to a trial before the Circuit Court that he will be fully acquitted on, the pleas of insanity from drink. we had no court for trial of Criminal &amp; Jury cases at the last Term of the Court I would recommend the Governor to pardon him upon the conditions of the petition</p>
<p><date when="1864-05-11">May 11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Sen: W. Williams</p>
<p>I concur with the above Statement</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> M Samuel P J B C</p>
<p>As County Attorney and prosecutor before the Examining Court I concur with Mess Williams &amp; Samuels in the above statement &amp; think the accused is a fit subject for executive clemency.</p>
<p>Tho. P. Smith<pb/></p>
<p>Bourbon Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Chas C. Williams</p>
<p>Pardon upon condition he immediately enlist as soldier in the U. S. Service.</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette<figure type="hr"/>Indicted for Grand Larceny
<lb/><date when="1864-04">Apl term/64</date>
<lb/><date when="1864-05-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> May/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
