<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-009-0038"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. B. Bowman et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1193</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR1-70 to BR1-71</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Harrodsburg, Mercer County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-06-24">24 June 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Harrodsburg, Ky.
<lb/><date when="1865-06-24">June 24<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>.
<lb/>Hon. Thos. E. Bramlette,
<lb/>Gov. of Kentucky.
<lb/>Dear Sir,</p>
<p>I am instructed by the curators of Kentucky University to transmit to you the following resolutions passed by them at their regular annual meeting held at this place on the <date when="1865-06-20">20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> of June 1865</date>. Resolved -- by the Curators of Kentucky University, that they do hereby assent to the provisions of an Act of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky entitled, "An act to consolidate Kentucky University and Transylvania University, approved <date when="1865-02-28">February 28<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>. -- Resolved -- by the Curators of Kentucky University, that they do hereby assent to all the provisions of an act of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky entitled, "An act to establish an Agricultural and Mechanical College in Kentucky." -- approved <date when="1865-02-22">February 22<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> 1865</date>. and that we accept said act as a part of the Charter of Kentucky University,</p>
<p>Signed -- 
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Jno. Shackleford M. D.
<lb/>Joseph Wassen.
<lb/>R. C. Ricketts Sr.
<lb/>Joseph Smith.
<lb/>D. H. Thompson.
<lb/>H. T. Moore.
<lb/>Ben. B. Groom.
<lb/>And. Steele.
<lb/>Jno. Aug. Williams.
<lb/>A. H. Bowman.
<lb/>J. B. Bowman.
<lb/><cb n="2"/>A. G. Kyle.
<lb/>R. M. Bishop.
<lb/>Geo. H. Givens.
<lb/>Richard J. White.
<lb/>H. L. Williams.
<lb/>Jno. Shackleford Jr.
<lb/>O. S. Posten.
<lb/>J. H. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Garrey.
<lb/>Jas. W. Thompson.
<lb/>C. T. Worthington.<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>The foregoing resolutions were adopted at a meeting of the Curators of Kentucky University on the <date when="1865-06-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of June 1865</date>.<pb/>
<lb/>and are now authenticated by the individual signatures of all the members of the Board present, and the official signatures of undersigned President &amp; Secretary -- <date when="1865-06-20">June 20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J. A. Williams Secretary
<lb/><cb n="2"/>C. T. Worthington President<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>I am also instructed to transmit to you the following resolutions of the Trustees of Transylvania University which were communicated to this Board,</p>
<p>Resolved -- by the Trustees of Transylvania University, that they do hereby assent to the provisions of the act of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth of Kentucky entitled, "An act to consolidate Kentucky University and, Transylvania University, approved <date when="1865-02-28">February 28<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>.</p>
<p>Resolved -- farther, that upon the assent of the curators of Kentucky University to the provisions of said act made in accordance with said act, being made known to this Board, all the property and funds of Transylvania University will be delivered to said Curators of Kentucky University as provided in said act -- </p>
<p>Signed-
<lb/>M. C. Johnson Ch<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi>.
<lb/>Benj. Gratz.
<lb/>J. J. <unclear/> ^<unclear>Hunter</unclear>^
<lb/>D. S. Gordloe.
<lb/>Geo. B. Kinkead.
<lb/>Joseph Wassen.
<lb/>W. A. Dudley.</p>
<p>The foregoing resolutions were adopted at a meeting of the Trustees of Transylvania University on the <date when="1865-06-09">9<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> of June 1865</date>. and are now anthenticated by the individual signatures of the members of the Board and the official signatures of the undersigned President &amp; Secretary,</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W. A. Dudley Secretary
<lb/><cb n="2"/>M. C. Johnson Ch<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi>.<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>The foregoing action of the two Boards of the said Universities are hereby laid before you, in accordance with the 8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Section of the act establishing the Agricultural and Mechanical College of Kentucky, and I will be pleased to receive from you, at your convenience, your official authority, as required by the same section of said Act, directing the Curators of Kentucky University to organize the Agricultural and Mechanical College in pursuance of this act,</p>
<p>Very Respectfully your obedient servant
<lb/>J. B. Bowman.
<lb/>General Agent of Ky. University. -- </p>
<p>Please address me at Lexington, Ky. -- </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
