<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-009-0035"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John G. Eve to Ephraim L. Van Winkle</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11502</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>45th, 47th, 48th, and 49th Regiments Kentucky Infantry Muster Rolls</collection>
      <idno>Box 42, Bundle 1</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Somerset, Pulaski County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-12-11">11 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Head Quarters 49<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Reg<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Ky M<hi rend="sup">T</hi> Infy Vol. 
<lb/>Somerset Ky. <date when="1863-12-11">Dec<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> 11-1863</date>
<lb/>Hon E. L. Vanwinkle</p>
<p>Your kind favor of <date when="1863-12-05">Decr 5</date> and <date when="1863-12-09">Dec 9</date>. are at hand relating to the position of Adjutant, of this Reg<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> In answer I would say that I am inclined to be accommodating to all and especially my friends. I will state our case, We appointed James H. Tinsley Adjutant on the <date when="--09-28">28. day of Sept</date> last. and sent forward the appointment properly endorsed to the Adjutant Genl at Frankfort. We desire that he shall be commissioned his commission to date and his muster to date <date when="1863-09-28">Sept 28 -- 1863</date>, He has done duty as Adjutant from that time and is still acting in that capacity. </p>
<p>Now we are Satisfied that no mustering officer will muster Tinsley back even though the govenor were to commission him, The natural inquiry would be -- why have you not been mustered? Why have you not sent forward your certificate of acceptance of the commission? Why is not your affidavit on the Commission? -- Whilst <hi rend="underline">Tinsley</hi> has been always ready to accept and comply with the law, he has never had the opportunity</p>
<p>We know then that he <hi rend="str">w</hi>could not be mustered back so as to get pay unless by order from the War Department, Gov. Bramlette, at the proper time, could get that by asking it, We feel as if we had been badly treated about this matter and are willing to believe it has all been unintentional. But is it right for Tinsley to be kept out of his rank and pay all this while and that it should Still be done? Notwithstanding all these things I am and Lieut Tinsley is also disposed to be accommodating, But you must be aware that it is a dangerous business to make such an arrangement as you Suggest. Such things are usually passed over and <hi rend="underline">forgotten</hi> in the hurry and multiplicity of business<pb/> </p>
<p>I would feel continually annoyed untill it was consumated</p>
<p>Tinsley might become restless and reasonably conclude that he would not get the possition and thus the Reg<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> loose his invaluable services, You will therefore excuse me for insisting upon the immediate Commissioning of Lt James H. Tinsley unless I have positive assurance from Gov. Bramlette that it can and will be so arranged that Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> P. Young can be discharged from the 4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky. for promotion and then commissioned as Adjutant in this Reg<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> and then decline accepting or resign immediately -- Tinsley then commissioned and mustered from the <date when="--09-28">28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sept</date> in such way as to insure his pay from <date when="1863-09-28">Sept 28. 1863</date>. Then I am willing it shall be done, and as I said the President or Secretary of War, would do this if Gov Bramlette would ask it. Write me what can be done.</p>
<p>Tinsley and myself are under obligations to you for your kind and promt attention to this matter, as are also the other men in the Regt. The name is James H. Tinsely</p>
<p>No news here. "All Tranquil on the Cumberland", What is the Legislation doing and likely to do? Who is to be U. S. Senator? Let me hear from you again Soon</p>
<p>Yours Truly
<lb/>John G. Eve Lt Col
<lb/>comdg 49<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky vols<pb/></p>
<p>The commission issued for Thos P Young was through <hi rend="str">a</hi> mistake of mine by endorsing the wrong letter. I intended to appoint him 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> L<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Co A 4 Ky Inft vice Lt Luaney resigned but endorsed the wrong letter. Let the Commission of Young as Ajt be revoked &amp; issue a commission for James H Tinsley date back to <date when="--09-28">28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sept</date>.</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette</p>
<p>49 Infy<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Adjt Tinsley<figure type="hr"/> </p>
<p>Com iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> &amp; forw<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1863-12-17">Dec<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> 17. 1863</date><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><figure type="hr"/>James H. Tinsley com Adjutant 49<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky Infy. <date when="1863-09-28">Sept. 28 1863</date>.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/><note place="body">1. 2. 3. 4. 5.</note></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
