<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1798"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Soble, Isaac Faulkner, and G. B. McGlasson to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6435</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-332 to BR13-334</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Greensburg, Green County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-05-17">17 May 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><hi rend="underline">Greensburg Green County Ky</hi>
<lb/>To His Excellency Thomas E. Bramlette Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>your petitioners William Soble Isaac Faulkner &amp; G B McGlasson residents of Green County. would respectfully represent that They are recognised to appear in the Green Circuit Court at the <date when="1864-11">November Term 1864</date> in the sum of $100 -- each as witnesses. in the case of the Commonwealth vs William Reed indicted in said Court for felony. They State that <hi rend="str">said</hi> not long before the sitting of the court at its <date when="1864-11">Nov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Term 1864</date> at which they were required to appear. the military authorities came and took said Reed out of the Jail of Green County where he was confined. and sent him off to his Regiment in the Service of the united States to which he belonged &amp; from which he had Deserted, They State that they had made all necessary arrangements to attend court in obedience of their said Recognisance. but they were informed that said Reed had been taken off and that there would be no trial of his Case and that it would be unnecessary for them to attend Court as witnesses, as there would be no use for them. the attorney for the Commonwealth well knew this. and on account of the absence of the said prisoner Reed the Cause was Continued. and your petitioners on account of this information. that they Would not be needed at the trial did not attend at the <date when="1864-11">Nov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Term 1864</date> and their recognisance<hi rend="sup">s</hi> were forfeited. and at the present <date when="1865-05"><hi rend="underline">may term of the</hi> <hi rend="underline">Green Circuit Court 1865</hi></date> Judgments were rendered against them for $100. each, making $300. &amp; the cost of the proceedings. They say that they had no intention or design to disobey their obligation to attend as witnesses in said Case but intended in Good faith to do so. -- <pb/></p>
<p>They State that they are each of them poor men with families on their hands to care for, and no one to make a living for their families Except themselves, and that by their Daily labor, two of them are aged men and one of them a wounded Discharged soldier late of the Co E. 3<hi rend="sup">d</hi>. Regt Ky Vol. Wounded at the Battle of Stone River and for his good Conduct on that field he was Complimented by his Commander. but he is now not only poor but an Invalid for life and but for the little Stipend granted him in the way of Pension by his Government. he could not support himself in any Comfort</p>
<p>They state that they will of Course. as they suppose have to pay the 30 pr cent on their several sums adjudged against them to the attorney for the Commonwealth and Cost of the proceeding Which will truly be a heavy burden upon them But they pray your Excellency to take their case into your favorable Consideration and release and remit that part of said Sums thus adjudged against them that is due to the Commonwealth and for which and as in duty bound they will ever feel grateful and thankful to your Excellency</p>
<p>William Soble
<lb/>Isaac Faulkner
<lb/>G. B. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Glasson
<lb/>by. S A Spencer for them
<lb/>and at their request<pb/></p>
<p>State of Kentucky Green county</p>
<p>I William Tucker Jailer of Green county Kentucky on my oath say. that William Reed was arrested and committed to the Jail of Green County in <date when="1864-09">September 1864</date> under a charge of felony that some time after his Commitment and before the time of the sitting of the Green Circuit Court at the <date when="1864-11">Nov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Term 1864.</date> the Said Reed was taken out of the Jail by the military authorities and sent or taken off to the army in the united States Service, &amp; from which it was said he had deserted Reed was not here at the <date when="1864-11">November</date> Term and on account of his absence no trial was had in his case &amp; the witnesses were informed that they need not attend</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Tucker J G C</p>
<p>The foregoing Statement was subscribed and sworn to before me by William Tucker Jailer of Green County who is well known to me as a man of respectability &amp; trust. and I Certify that the said Statements made above by him are true to my personal Knowledge Given under my hand this <date when="1865-05-17">17 may 1865</date></p>
<p>S A Spencer Presiding
<lb/>Judge Green Co Co Ky<pb/></p>
<p>Greensburg Ky <date when="1865-05-17">May 17. 1865</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency Governor T. E Bramlette Eq
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>I here respectfully submit to you the petition of William Soble. Isaac Faulkner &amp; G. B McGlasson. Governor. the petition Speaks for itself the facts Stated in it are true. I drew the petition for them at their Earnest request I know the petitioners personally and I know that they are not only loyal &amp; true men in truth and part. but are law abiding men. not merely in name but in reality. and that their failure to attend Court in obedience to the Bond. was not intended by them as any wanton disregard of duty. or any design to disobey the law. but Simply from the information which they received. that their attendance was not required at the <date when="1864-11">Nov<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Term</date> of said Court: I know that these are poor men &amp; very poorly prepared to pay the forfeiture I am now trying to aid this poor man William Soble in obtaining a pension on account of his wounds received in the Battle of Stone River. he is in a manner without means to Support himself comfortably</p>
<p>I respectfully submit the case to your Excellency. and hope that you will favorably Consider the Claims of these poor men The facts Stated in their petition Can be sustained by members here if necessary</p>
<p>I have the honor to be
<lb/>very respectfully your Excellencys obdt Servant
<lb/>Sand A Spencer Presiding
<lb/>Judge Green Co. Co. Ky<pb/></p>
<p>Green Cir Ct
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>Governor Bramlette<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Petition of William Soble Isaac Faulkner G B M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Glasson</p>
<p>For remission of
<lb/>Judgt. of $100 in
<lb/>each case<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Remit</hi></p>
<p><date when="1865-05-25">25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> May/65</date>
<lb/>Greensburg
<lb/>Green Co
<lb/>Ky</p>
<p>3 cases</p>
<p>sent for fee
<lb/><date when="1865-05-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> May/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
