<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2153"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Samuel Garrard to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9229</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-244 to MG24-245</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>His Excellency Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned take pleasure in recommending the bearer of this Mr Austen L Reed to the favorable regard of your Excellency. They have known him for years and most cheerfully testify to his good character and high gentlemanly bearing. They believe that he has just grounds to envoke the interposition of your Excellency in his behalf In the difficulty which took place between him and Green they believe that he did no more than a gentleman ought to do in his self defence He was not the assailant Green had attempted to shoot him two or three times before he attempted to repel the assault by cutting him, and this was done as a last resort. The evidence is insufficient to convict him and this is evidenced by a verdict in his favor in a court suit for damages instituted by Green against him, and further by the fact that in the Commonwealths case, there has been two hung juries, in the latter of which eleven were for acquittal, though the commonwealth was aided by additional counsel an notwithstanding a powerful family influence was brought to bear against him. They believe<pb/>
<lb/>that the prosecution is malicious, that a conviction will never be had, that there are no good grounds to press it farther and that it is oppressive alike upon the Commonwealth and the Defendant, that he has already incurred extraordinary cost, in his legal defence, that his means are limited, he has but recently married and is at this time doing his best to procure the means fo honorable Subsistence The undersigned are far from favoring indiscriminate executive clemency, and are in favor of street observance and execution of the laws, but they believe that the present case comes within the provision of the constitution which authorizes the Executive "to remit fines and forfeit grant reprieves and pardons, except in cases of impeachment," and they are firmly persuaded that the interest of the Commonwealth and all <hi rend="str">interested</hi> ^concerned^ will be promoted, and justice be done, should a pardon be granted to Reid. Hoping that his application will meet with favor they remain with great respect</p>
<p>Most truly
<lb/>Sam<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Garrard
<lb/>The undersigned unite in the prayer of the petitioner
<lb/>T. T. Garrard</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
