<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2182"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. John Hill, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6819</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-419</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Cumberland County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Kentucky Cumberland Circuit Court
<lb/><hi rend="str">Th</hi> <date when="1865-04">April Term 1865</date>
<lb/>The following orders was made to wit
<lb/>Comth of Kentucky Plff
<lb/>vs } Indictment for selling whiskey to soldiers
<lb/>John Hill Defendant</p>
<p>This day came the Defendant as well as the attorney for the Commonwealth and on his motion and by the consent of the attorney for the commonwealth, Confessed himself indebted to the commonwealth of Kentucky in the Sum of Ten dollars, it is therefore ordered and adjudged by the court that the plaintiff recover of <hi rend="str">the</hi> Said Defendant the Sum of ten dollars and the cost about this prossecution expended and he may be Taken</p>
<p>a copy att. J. M. Boles clk
<lb/><hi rend="str">Kentucky</hi></p>
<p>Same Plff
<lb/>v } Indictment for selling to Soldiers
<lb/>A. N. English Deft</p>
<p>This day came the Defendant as well as the commonwealth by attorney, and on motion of Defendant and by consent of the commonwealth by attorney the Defendant confessed himself indebted to the Commonwealth in the Sum of Ten dollars, it is therefore ordered and adjudged by the court that Plff recover of Deft the <hi rend="underline">Sum</hi> of Ten Dollars and the costs of this prossecution and he may be taken</p>
<p>a copy att. J. M. Boles clk<pb/></p>
<p>Same Plaintiff
<lb/>vs } Indictment for selling to Soldiers
<lb/>Charles Hill Deft</p>
<p>This day came the Defendant as well as the Commonwealth by attorney, and on motion of Defendant and by consent of the Commonwealth by attorney the Defendant acknowledged himself indebted to the Commonwealth of Kentucky in the Sum of Ten dollars, it is therfore ordered and adjudged by the court that the Plaintiff recover of the Defendant the Sum of Ten dollars and the costs about this prossecution expended and he may be Taken</p>
<p>a copy att. J, M, Boles clk</p>
<p>Same Plaintiff
<lb/>vs } Indictment for selling whiskey To Soldiers
<lb/>W, O, Hill Deft</p>
<p>This day came the defendant as well as the Commonwealth by attorney, and on motion of the Defendant by Consent of the attorney for the Commonwealth Said Defendant confessed himself indebted to the Said Commonwealth in the Sum of Ten dolllars. It is therefore orderd and adjudged by the court that the Plaintiff recover of the Defendant the Sum of Ten dollars with Costs of prosecution and he may be taken</p>
<p>a copy att. J. M. Boles clk</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
