<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1132"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">M. J. Schmidt to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5769</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-232 to BR11-233</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency,
<lb/>The Governor of Kentucky:</p>
<p>Your petitioner, M. J. Schmidt, respectfully states that, upon an indictment for Keeping a disorderly house, he has, by judgment of the City Court of Louisville, been fined One hundred dollars; which he prays your Excellency to remit, because he was not guilty of the offense, and because, being taken by surprise at the non introduction of some of the witnesses at the foot of the indictment, he was unable to prove his innocence.</p>
<p>The statements of some of those witnesses he will present herewith to your Excellency.</p>
<p>Your petitioner states that he is the proprietor of a coffee house and restaurant in the upper part of the city, to keep which he has paid his license money to the City, which license was in Existence at the time of the commission of the alleged offense, &amp; has not yet Expired. That other houses of the kind are also kept in the same neighborhood, by license from the City; that said houses as well your petitioner's have been visited by the same class of persons, many of them soldiers, who sometimes are disposed to be boisterous as is the case in houses where ardent spirits are sold.</p>
<p>But petitioner states that there has never been any disturbance in his house, nor has he ever countenanced or tolerated any boisterous conduct or any improper conduct at his house; and whenever there were any indi-<pb/>
<lb/>cation of boisterous conduct, your petitioner would close his house as soon as possible.</p>
<p>This he had to do on several occasions, when drinking soldiers would come in the neighborhood, Your petitioner prays in consideration of the circumstances, that your Excellency would remit so much of the fine as may be in your Excellency's power; &amp; even then the amount which your petitioner will have to pay in costs &amp; the attorney<hi rend="sup">s</hi> per centage of fine will amount to nearly Sixty dollars. Your petitioner will ever pray &amp;c.</p>
<p>M <unclear>J</unclear> Schmitt</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Remit</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Louisville City Ct
<lb/>Petition of M. J. Schmitt for remission of $100 fine in City Court of L'ville
<lb/>remission issued <date when="1864-08-18">18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> aug 1864</date>
<lb/>by Direction of Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi>
<lb/>ELV
<lb/>Sec Ste</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
