<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2222"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. McPeek to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9298</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-352</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Beriah Magoffin Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> of Kentucky </p>
<p>Your petitioner William M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Peek would respectfully represent that he ws fined in the city court on <date when="1860-03-06">6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> March 1860</date>, Sixty dollars for keeping a Tippling house in Louisville under the following circumstances towit He keeps a Grocery store on <gap/> street connected with a feed store &amp; supplies the neighborhood with all articles, in either line, A Young man by the name of Martin Summers a hack driver, was in the habit of getting provender for his horses there and was frequently at his store when y<hi rend="sup">r</hi> petitioner would treat him, because of his patronage, he however became troublesome &amp; was driven from the premises some time last <hi rend="str">fall</hi> ^Autumn,^ &amp; since thene has shown great resentment to the petitioner, he was the only witness examined on the trial, &amp; swore that he had bought &amp; payed for whiskey several times, this statement was wholly unexpected as he had on several occasions in the presence of the petitioner and others, said that he could not swear that he ever bought liquor from the petitioner, under the belief that he would not make a statement that would convict the Deft, he had no witnesses subpoenad in his behalf or to discredit the witness for te com<hi rend="sup">th</hi> therefore this verdict, as unexpected as it ^is^ entirely unjust was rendered<pb/>
<lb/><hi rend="str">We the</hi>Unless y<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Excellency will interpose to relieve your petitioner from this fine by remitting it he will be subjected to great loss which he at present can not well bear, he has ever borne a fair character among his acquaintances for correctness in dealing and good deportment in all the walks of life with these considerations &amp; the following recommendations to y<hi rend="sup">r</hi> favor he humbly prays y<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Excellency to remit his fine &amp; relieve him from theis great harm with great respect y<hi rend="sup">r</hi> petitioner will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p><hi rend="str">Resp</hi>W M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Peek</p>
<p>We of the Jury who tried the case referred to above also pray y<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Excellency to remit his fine</p>
<p>Respectfully y<hi rend="sup">r</hi> obt servt</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="3"/><cb n="1"/>Val. Thomas
<lb/>W H McCay
<lb/>D Lincoln
<lb/>R. H. Hernstadt
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J. Browder
<lb/>W E Cary
<lb/>H Gealding
<lb/><cb n="3"/>D Forsyth
<lb/>C C Henry
<lb/>James Kirkpatrick
<lb/>William R Rey<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>We the neighbors &amp; friends of the petitioner join in the prayer to y<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Excellency to remit <hi rend="str">petition</hi> ^his^ fine</p>
<p>with great respect y<hi rend="sup">r</hi> obt serv<hi rend="sup">t</hi></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="3"/><cb n="1"/>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> B <unclear>M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Henir</unclear> &amp; Son
<lb/>H C Thomas
<lb/>John W Bowser
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W Clark Price Jr</hi>
<lb/>W K Thomas
<lb/>Fred A. Kaye
<lb/><cb n="2"/>W P. Boone
<lb/>C D Pennebaker
<lb/>John Brown
<lb/>J. R. Brown
<lb/>W N Brown
<lb/>W. M Brown
<lb/><cb n="3"/>Charles Glass
<lb/>F. W. Quast
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> Kaye s</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">H. H. Sale</hi>
<lb/>A V Brewer
<lb/>J R Parrent<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p><note place="left margin">A Majority of the Jury. The chief of Police &amp; other officers of the city and several highly respectable citizens having signed this Petition. I unite with them
<lb/>Geo. W Johnston.</note></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
