<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1221"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Mary B. Heitzmann, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10689</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-70</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-07-17">17 July 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Mary. B. Hidsman states that she is the wife of M Hidsman who was killed by Gorge Knarr She states that its true that when Gorge Knarr left Newport for the state for Missouri he left his wife the Petitioner at the House of her said Husband that Mrs Knarr state there but a short time untill she left at the time of her leaving she give as a Reason therefore that Mr Hidsman had Insulted her that she spoke to her husband the Decesased about it he denied any thing of the kind &amp; Reparted that she was visited by other men this affiant states that she was at home all the time Mrs Knarr was at there home &amp; knows that the Report of her husband to the affect that Mrs Knarr was visited by any man while there is not true that from Remarks made before her by her Husband she is satisfied that he started the Report with the Intention of Ruining her Caracture &amp; with out any truth in the same she state she has heard him after Mrs Knarr left say at times when this affiant would Remonstrate with him as to what the concequence would be in surculating such Reports that he did not care that d<gap/>d her he intended to Ruing her for Ever that her husband was killed at the hand of the Prisoner that she did not tell what she had heard her husband say untill after the trial of Knarr &amp; would not make this affidavit did she not feel that the dificulty was<pb/>
<lb/>Caused by her Husband Hidsman &amp; not by the Prisner &amp; that she knows the whole facts was not before the Court that She thinks if the facts had of been before the Jury The Judgment would have been difrent <date when="1861-07-17">July 17th 1861</date></p>
<p>Mary B. Heitzmann.</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Mary B. Hidesman this <date when="1861-07-17">17<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of July 1861</date></p>
<p>G. G. Lightfoot J. P. P. C</p>
<p>Hidsman
<lb/>affidavit</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
