<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1255"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James B. Beck to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5892</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-431 to BR11-432</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-10-24">24 October 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Governor Bramlette</p>
<p>The petitioner Edward A Prior agent for the house of H. F. Alberti &amp; Co of Baltimore Maryland, was arrested yesterday in Lexington as a Pedler, &amp; on his own confession fined $100 -- &amp; costs, by Hon C D Carr County Judge, under the amendment to Chap. 83. of Revised Statutes. which punishes <hi rend="underline">all persons who sell or offer to sell goods by sample,</hi> as Pedlers. &amp; the fine<hi rend="str">d</hi> is fixed by subsequent act at $100. --. no discretion is allowed to the court.</p>
<p>Mr Prior's admission was the only proof. He states that he was agent for the wholesale importing House of Alberti &amp;Co. &amp; as such had in total ignorances of our law agreed to sell to George Lancaster a merchant in Lexington some goods by sample, on yesterday. as soon as he learned he had no right to do so he rescinded his agreement with Lancaster, &amp; that was his only offence. The court considered him guilty under the law, &amp; he paid $103. -- fine &amp; cost. which the Judge holds subject to your Excellency's action. <hi rend="sup">1</hi>/<hi rend="sub">4</hi>th of that goes to the attorney, &amp; our Shf claim <hi rend="sup">1</hi>/<hi rend="sub">4</hi>th of it as inform. The atty part is beyond the control of your Excellency, perhaps the inform. is, Considering it a case appealing to your Excellency's clemency. It is respectfully requested that you remit what you can of it. Mr Price has returned to Baltimore, I was his counsel &amp; agreed to petition you</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Ja</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> B Beck</hi><pb/></p>
<p>The facts stated in the above petition are substantially true, But we do not wish your Excellency to remit either the portion of the fine going to the atty or informed which is one fourth to each,</p>
<p><date when="1864-10-24">Oct 24, 1864</date></p>
<p>C D Carr Pres Judge F. C
<lb/>W D Boswell co. atty<pb/></p>
<p>Fayette Co' Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Edw<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Prior
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Refused</hi>
<lb/>Remission
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Refused</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
