<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2499"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">A. B. Blankenship to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7136</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-472</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-10-16">16 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency T. E. Bramlette
<lb/>Govenor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Respectfully represents that at the <date when="1865-10">october term 1865</date> of the Wayne Circuit court a judgment was rendered against him in favor of the commonwealth of Kentucky for the sum of Sixty Dollars upon an indictment against him for suffering gaming, He further represesents that he had in the transaction for which he was indicted no intention or belief that he was violating the laws of the State, At the game of hazard played one lb of sugar was the nominal Stake, That the game was one purely of amusement and neither money or property changed hands by reason of Said game, And in addition to these facts he did not consider that he was in any sense the lessee or occupyer of the room when said game was played, That he was induced to agree to a judgement of the aforesaid amt. to avoid danger of a large recovery as the proof in legal effect might have shown him to be one of the Controllers of Said room That not being learned in the law he did not know at the time that he could be so considered, He asks your excellency to remit Said judgment.
<lb/><date when="1865-10-16">Oct 16th 1865</date></p>
<p>A B Blankenship</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed by A B Blankenship before me this <date when="1865-10-16">16<hi rend="sup">th</hi> October 1865</date>.</p>
<p>Jno L. Sallee clk<pb/></p>
<p>We concur in the Statements of the the within petition and that it a proper case for Executive clemency</p>
<p>Jno L Sallee
<lb/>C H Buster
<lb/>L R Jones
<lb/>W. A. Buster
<lb/>J B Dick
<lb/><hi rend="underline">H, T, Hall</hi>
<lb/>James A Phillips</p>
<p>I Concur in the prayer of the Petitioner</p>
<p>Jno J Vanwinkle
<lb/>James L Hardin</p>
<p>Wayne Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>A B Blankinship
<lb/>$60,
<lb/>Gaming
<lb/>Remitted.
<lb/><date when="1865-10-19">19 Oct 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
