<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-009-0073"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Robert Gibson, Circular to the Governors and Legislatures of the Southern States</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1228</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR1-284 to BR1-285</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Broadside</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>CIRCULAR
<lb/>To the Governors and Legislatures of the Southern States.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>It has occured to me, that, in view of the disturbed condition of labor, and general depression of business, throughout the Southern States, together with the vast field of undeveloped resouces, fertile lands, agricultural and mechanical advantages which they present, some plan of systematic co-operation might be devised by them, whereby capital and labor may be secured, to aid in re-establishing prosperity, and developing the resources of the country.</p>
<p>My Scotch nativity, and extensive acquaintance in Great Britain, and Ireland, together with fifteen years experience in Kentucky, in agricultural pursuits and operations in real estate, thus becoming to a great extent, familiar with the wants and conditions of the Country, induce me to believe that I could act with efficiency in Europe, as Emigration Agent, and by establishing a General Depositry of Information, for the Southern States, and Liverpool, England, to draw the attention of capital and enterprise to the agricultural, mineral and manufacturing resources of these States, and to the highly favorable opportunity now offered to enterprise by the changed and unsettled condition of the country.</p>
<p>This could only be done by opening a first class office at the point indicated, to be supplied with the best maps, of each of the states, all printed statistics attainable, geological and other auth<hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>ortative reports, and general information bearing upon the resources, condition, productions, minerals, soil, climate, commercial advantages, necessities, &amp;c., &amp;c., of the country.</p>
<p>I could negotiate the sale of State or other stocks, the sale or settlement of lands, secure capital, send out labor, skilled or unskilled, German or British, and attend to any and all matters of interest to either of the States which might be required of me.</p>
<p>This is a mere outline of what occurs to me as a feasible plan to attain the end desired, to-wit: the revival of prosperity and the development of the immense resources in the South.</p>
<p>Such an enterprise, it occurs to me, can be undertaken and prosecuted successfully, with immense beneficial results, by the use of necessary energy and enterprise, and at a cost altogether insignificant to the States.</p>
<p>Impressed with these views, I have thought proper to call attention to them, and to propose to the following States, to wit: Kentucky, Virginia, Tennessee, North Carolina, South Carolina, Georgia, Florida, Alabama, Mississippi, Louisiana, Texas, Arkansas, and Missouri, that, should the plan appear practicable to the proper authorities thereof, to undertake the execution of the enterprise.</p>
<p>The plan I propose is, that I shall be appointed, say for the period of five years, the Agent or Commissioner of each of the States named above, for the purposes indicated, with an annual salary of say $500 (in gold,) from each of them, with such additional sum, for one year, from each State, (say $250,) as will enable me, during the first year, to advertise extensively throughout Europe, to bring the subject properly before the attention of the public.</p>
<p>In successfully conducting such an enterprise, much -- nay, almost everything -- would depend upon the personal character of the individual engaged in it, -- his social position, aptitude, knowledge of the business proposed, his sagacity, energy, and probity. Upon these points I may be pardoned for entertaining the belief that I can command satisfactory testimonials, together with such guarantees for the faithful discharge of the duties, as may be required.</p>
<p>I shall be happy to receive and answer any communications bearing upon the subject, containing either questions or suggestions, and take this means of calling attention to its importance and soliciting correspondence.</p>
<p>Address ROBERT GIBSON,
<lb/>Louisville, Ky.</p>
<p>Refer to Gov. BRAMLETTE,
<lb/>and LIEUT. GOV. JACOB, of Kentucky.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
