<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0416"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. W. Walker et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4535</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-156 to BR9-157</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-01-20">20 January 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>The Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>The undersigned, your Petitioners, will respectfully represent that at the <date when="1860-11">November Term 1860</date> of the Hickman Equity and Criminal Court a judgment was rendered in favor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky for sixty dollars against John Davis under an indictment for keeping a tippling house. John Davis keeps a hotel in the town of Clinton and has ever conducted the same in an orderly, respectable and exemplary manner and has given entire satisfication not only to the travelling public but to the citizens who live neighboring to his hotel. For the sake of perfect quiet in his house and to avoid offense to those of his guests who never indulge in ardent spirits he established his bar-room under his tavern license in a house by his hotel, but not under the same roof. By a technical construction of law in such cases he was held guilty of keeping a tippling house &amp; so fined although a regularly licensed tavern-keeper and although his bar was kept with the utmost propriety &amp; decency. We are satisfied that his infraction of the law by not having his bar-room under the same roof with his hotel, was through a pardonable<pb/></p>
<p>Ignorance of the technicality on his part and with the view to more fully meet the wishes and choice of his guests. The former Commonwealth's Atty. T. H. Corbett being fully satisfied of these facts, ordered the clerk to issue no execution for the fine until further instructions. Recently, however, a capias pro fine has issued and Davis will be compelled to pay it unless releived by Executive clemency. He has paid the costs &amp; the per centum due to the Atty for the commonwealth and we respectfully ask your Excellency to remit the residue.</p>
<p>This <date when="1864-01-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Jany 1864</date>.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>R. W. Walker.
<lb/>W. V. Bradley
<lb/>A G. Donoho
<lb/>S M Wilson
<lb/>W. A. Owsley
<lb/>J. F. Montgomery
<lb/>W.A. Beadles.
<lb/>J. B. Spillman
<lb/>D. M. Hilliard
<lb/>Robt A Galbraith
<lb/>George. F. Irvine
<lb/>Jesse Jorden
<lb/>J. W. Haggard
<lb/>W H Jordan
<lb/><cb n="2"/>W M Samuels
<lb/>N H White P.JH.CC
<lb/>E T Bullock D.C
<lb/>T. W. Ashley
<lb/>Thos Hales
<lb/>W. L. Burnett
<lb/>W. F. Wooldridge
<lb/>G. W. Galbraith
<lb/>H. P. Balridge
<lb/>J. H. Fields
<lb/>B. P. Thompson
<lb/>D. Zimmerman
<lb/>G H Wray
<lb/>J. H. Smith<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>Findley Rennick
<lb/>W. H. Smith
<lb/>F H Maupin
<lb/>Robert. M. Spillman
<lb/>James Archer
<lb/>James. P. Woodward
<lb/>John F. Woodard
<lb/>Thomas B. Osborne
<lb/>J. C Akin
<lb/>G. W. Hite
<lb/>Jno C Daily
<lb/>J. H. Jordan
<lb/>R. Johnson
<lb/>S C Robinson
<lb/>U. H. Ohfihart.
<lb/>G W Millen Jailor
<lb/>A S Arnold..D..S..
<lb/>J S Jackson
<lb/>J J Hindspeth
<lb/>D. M.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>L. Johnson
<lb/>W H Gove
<lb/>Holmes Hopkins<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Hickman Equity &amp; Criminal Court
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John Davis
<lb/>Tipling</p>
<p>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi>
<lb/><date when="1864-02-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Feby/ 64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
