<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0523"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James M. Ogden to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4642</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-328 to BR9-329</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Winchester, Clark County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-02-05">5 February 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Winchester <date when="1864-02-05">Feb. 5 1864</date>
<lb/>(Confidential)
<lb/>Gov. Bramblette</p>
<p>Sir, I have this day learned that a petition is about being presented to you, if it has not already been done, to remit the penalty of a forfeited recognizance bond. The petitioner being Claiborn Lisle of Clark County. Now Sir in behalf of a good large no. of good loyal men of Clarke Who have requested me to write -- I give you a brief sketch of this man Lisle. &amp; his relations. I care not Sir what representations may be made to you by hired Counsel. What I here say can be substantiated by all the respectable loyal men of this County. There is not to use Strong language,- between<pb/>
<lb/>Heaven &amp; Hell such a traitor &amp; rebel scoundrell as this same Claiborne Lisle -- There is a large family of them here &amp; viler traitors never breathed -- the prinicpal in this forfeited Bond -- Marquis Lisle, was killed while with Morgans horse thieves, he was Cousin to this Claib. Lisle -- a brother to this Claib. was convicted as a rebel spy -- but his sentence commuted by the President. another brother Manson Lisle now in this County, was as a guerilla concerned in the robbery of a good Union man during the invasion of Kirby Smith. Another brother Irza Lisle, has been indicted for treason in Clark Circuit Court -- &amp; lately stole a Government horse <hi rend="underline">which can be fully proved</hi><pb/>
<lb/>another cousin is in reb. army. But the leader of all this gang is this man Claib. Lisle. He is a very adroit, cunning, and dangerous man, has a considerable property -- In short this very man is one who ought to be "arbitrarily" arrested &amp; held in custody till close of the war. So far from being a proper object of executive clemency -- he is as mean a man &amp; as bad a traitor as can be found any where. I do hope sir that you will not for a moment listen to the application of such a wretch -- </p>
<p>Every word that I have write I undertake to fully substantiate. and can give as authority any no. of the best men in this county.<pb/>
<lb/>This very man Lisle is believed by many to be the captain of an extensive band of horse thieves in which one of his brothers &amp; other relations are known to be now engaged in devastating Clarke &amp; other Counties.</p>
<p>Of course what I here say is <hi rend="underline">entirely confidential</hi>, for any man who it is known should write to you such a letter would certainly be assassinated &amp; have his house burned down.</p>
<p>Very respectfully obt sert
<lb/>J. M. Ogden
<lb/>U. S. Commissioner</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
