<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0493"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William L. Turner to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4612</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-285 to BR9-286</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Campbellsville, Henry County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-02-22">22 February 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Cambellsville Ky <date when="1864-02-22">22nd. Feb. 1864</date>
<lb/>Gov. Bramlett.</p>
<p>at the last Term of the Taylor Circuit Court a fine of $50 &amp; costs was assessed against Nathaniel Tandy. for Some abusive Language used to Ben S Smith &amp; wife by a Party of drunken men who were passing sd. Smiths house in the night. Tandy was accidentally in company and Smith who has long been on unfriendly Terms with Tandy presented him to the Grand Jury with the balance -- all were tried together leaveing Tandy no opportunity to prove his Innocence -- I know the Parties well and from what I know of Smiths character &amp; disposition and the unfriendly feelings existing between the families are Satisfyed that the presentment against Tandy was a piece of little petty malice &amp; spite on the part of Smith -- </p>
<p>Tandy is a harmless Inoffensive man and poor &amp; unable to pay sd fine without great Inconvience. to himself &amp; Family -- He sent you a Petition last fall praying for a Remittance of the fine Signed by a number of the best citizens of this county but has not heard from it since.</p>
<p>Mr. Chandler made some enquiry for it in Frankfort, but it could not be found on file and has probably miscarried. I am there fore Induced to address you privately on the subject.</p>
<p>Verry Respectfully
<lb/>yours.
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi>. L Turner<pb/></p>
<p>Thos E. Bramlette Esq
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>I am Satisfied, the Statements of the within letter of Dr Turner are true, and I think he ^Tandy^ is a fit subject for Executive clemency, which I hope he will receive, He forwarded his petition numerously signed which is perhaps on file in your office. I think Col J. T. Bramlette had chge of it.</p>
<p>This Most respectfully
<lb/>Your Obdt Servant
<lb/>J H Chandler</p>
<p>Taylor Cir Court
<lb/>vs
<lb/>N. Tandy</p>
<p>Remit except fees &amp; costs -- I know Tandy well and am satisfied from my personal knowledge of the man that he took no part in any wrong</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>$50-
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1864-02-25">25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Feby 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
