<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2364"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Coleman to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9440</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG25-145</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Beriah MaGoffin
<lb/>Govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner John Coleman would most respectfully represent unto your Excellency that at the <gap/> Term of the Knox Circuit Court he was indicted for the offence of Keeping a Tipling House and at the <date when="1860-04">April Term 1860</date> he appeared in court and conferred a Judgement and he was find the sum of $60 He says that the facts are about as follows He says that he was a distiller and making liquors and only selling as authorized by law to sell that in his absence two gentleman called at his house and called for liquors and his mother who is a very old woman informed them if they could take the liquor off the premises they could get it they promised to so but when they got she could not get them to leave but they stand and drank the liqour on the premises. He says he had a fight with one of the men and he believes that it was all done through malice. He says if he had been at home he would have force them of the premises. He says that has petition your Excellency to remit the fine and you have been kind enough to respite the same that the respite is now about out. He says that he has paid the cost which amounted to the sum of $ -- <gap/> He says that<pb/>
<lb/>he is a poor young man and a cripple that he has the care of a widowed mother and aunt on his hands both of whom are very old and in fact helpless He says that he has no property of any consequence but one horse and that he is compelled to have that to attend his crop but if he has the fine to pay his horse will have to go and at a sacrifice He says that the recent unprecedented money <unclear>panic</unclear> that has vested the county has made impossible for him to get any money the premises considered He prays that your Excellency may extend to him the arm of your executive clemency. and he prays for a remission of the fine</p>
<p>John Coleman</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Knox County would like to see your Excellency remit the fine agst Mr Coleman</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>F P Stickley
<lb/>John G. Eve
<lb/>R T. Tuggle
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> B. Eve
<lb/><unclear/> H Davis
<lb/>J W Slather
<lb/>J W Anderson
<lb/>J R Heller
<lb/>G W Adams Jr
<lb/>Thomas J. Pitzer
<lb/>John M, Dickinson
<lb/>James D Megher
<lb/>Isaac Janes Se<hi rend="sup">n</hi>
<lb/>W <hi rend="underline">H</hi> Brafford
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Drury Lye. Jr
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> M, Beckel
<lb/>G. H. Downs
<lb/>J, S, Joplin
<lb/>Calvin Brogan
<lb/>C C Webb
<lb/>T, C, Burch
<lb/>Stephen Cook
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Bull
<lb/>J. M. Dishman
<lb/>Paul D Buttian
<lb/>Johnson Gibson</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
