<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0818"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Vene P. Armstrong to Richard T. Jacob</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4937</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-265</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-05-13">13 May 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>J. W. MITCHELL,
<lb/>late Mitchell &amp; Dean</p>
<p>VENE P. ARMSTRONG.</p>
<p>MITCHELL &amp; ARMSTRONG,
<lb/>General Commission and Forwarding merchants,
<lb/>NO. 222 MAIN STREET.
<lb/>Louisville, Ky <date when="1864-05-13">May 13 1864</date></p>
<p>Hon R T Jacob
<lb/>Frankfort Ky
<lb/>Dear Friend,</p>
<p>This will be handed you by Mr Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> Brown, a worthy and old citizen of Louisville who visits Frankfort to obtain from Go<hi rend="sup">v</hi> Bramlete the pardon of his son Jo<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Brown convicted of Manslaughter at the present term of our criminal court he will explain to you the full paticulars of the case and you can rely implisctly upon his Statements I know young Brown well and he has allways been considered a quiet good boy, he is verry young not yet Eighteen I udnerstand. I would write Gov B upon the Subject but have no personal acquaintance with him, any assistance you can give Mr Brown will be thankfully received by him and his distressed family</p>
<p>Your Friend Truly
<lb/>Vene P Armstrong</p>
<p>P.S. Since writing the above I learn that perhaps Miss Brown the brother of accused May visit Go<hi rend="sup">v</hi> B instead of her father if so this will be handed you by her and you can rely upon any statement She Makes.</p>
<p>Yours
<lb/>V. P. A</p>
<p>Gov Bramlette, my dear Sir, What I have learned of the circumstances of young<pb/>
<lb/>Mr Brown's case authorizes and induces me to make an earnest appeal to you for his pardon.</p>
<p>Very Truly Yours,
<lb/>Geo D. Prentice.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
