<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0591"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">E. W. Hawkins to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9043</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-432</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Campbell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency James F. Robinson Governor of Kentucky:</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Campbell County respectfully represent that George Coy and Jacob Hawthorn stand bound upon two bonds as sureties for one F. L. Grisnisier to keep the peace and as the bonds read for the appearance of the sad Grisnier at the next <unclear>business</unclear> Term of the Campbell Circuit Court upon which bonds the Com<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">ths</hi></hi> atto is asking a forfeiture upon the ground that Grisnier did not make his appearance at Court -- there is no complaint that Grisnier did any thing to break the peace but on the contrary he was a law abiding peaceful citizen and we are satisfied that Coy &amp; Hawthorn signed the bonds under the apprehension that they were only to be responsible in case that Grismier committed a breach of the peace &amp; that they did not understand that they were to be respoonsible for his appearance at Court -- We think it a proper case for his interfering clemency of the Executive &amp; ask that they the said Coy &amp; Hawthorn be relieved from the effects of the bonds if within the power of the Governor to do so -- </p>
<p>E, W, Hawkins<pb/></p>
<p>Pettn for remission of bonds of George Coy &amp; Jacob Hawthorn from Newport</p>
<p>Hold for further advice</p>
<p>I am unwilling to interfere before judgt. It is a <unclear/> <unclear/> precedent which I have now set</p>
<p>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
