<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-181-0009"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Daniel W. Lindsey, General Orders, No. 10</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG13993</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>General Orders No. 2</collection>
      <idno/>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-04-07">7 April 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Order</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Headquarters Kentucky Volunteers,
<lb/>ADJUTANT-GENERAL'S OFFICE,
<lb/>Frankfort, <date when="1865-04-07">April 7, 1865</date>.
<lb/>GENERAL ORDERS
<lb/>No. 10.</p>
<p>I. At a Military Court-Martial, which convened at Frankfort, Ky., on the <date when="1865-04-05">5th April, 1865</date>, pursuant to General Orders No. 9, dated Headquarters Kentucky Volunteers, Adjutant-General's Office, Frankfort, Ky., <date when="1865-04-05">April 5th, 1865</date>, and of which Major Charles W. Quiggins, First Kegiment Kentucky State forces, is President, were arraigned and tried -- </p>
<p>I. Private ISHAM EDWARDS, Casey County State Guard.</p>
<p>CHARGE.
<lb/>"<hi rend="italic">Absence without leave</hi>."</p>
<p><hi rend="italic">Specification</hi>. -- In this: that said ISHAM EDWARDS, private Casey County State Guard Company, having been duly enlisted into the service of the State of Kentucky, did, on or about the <date when="1865-03-11">11th day of March, 1865</date>, absent himself from his command without proper authority, and did remain away until arrested on the <date when="1865-04-01">1st day of April, 1865</date>, by Lieut. Wm. Rains.</p>
<p>To which charge and specification the prisoner, private ISHAM EDWARDS, Casey County State Guard, plead "<hi rend="italic">Guilty</hi>."</p>
<p>FINDING.</p>
<p>The Court having maturely considered the evidence adduced, finds the prisoner, private ISHAM EDWARDS, Casey County State Guard, as follows:</p>
<p>Of the <hi rend="italic">Specification</hi>, "Guilty."
<lb/>Of the CHARGE, "Guilty."</p>
<p>SENTENCE.</p>
<p>And the Court does therefore sentence him, private ISHAM EDWARDS, Casey County State Guard, "to forfeit one month's pay and allowances."<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">2</note></p>
<p>Finding and sentence in case of private ISHAM EDWARDS, Casey County State Guard, approved and confirmed. The commanding officer of the Casey County State Guard is hereby directed to make the proper charges on the rolls of his company against said private ISHAM EDWARDS in conformity with the sentence of said Court. Private ISHAM EDWARDS will be returned to his company, in charge of Lieut. Wm. Rains.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>II. Sergeant JOHN T. WRIGHT, Casey County State Guard.</p>
<p>CHARGE I.
<lb/>"<hi rend="italic">Absence without leave.</hi>"</p>
<p><hi rend="italic">Specification</hi> 1. -- That Sergeant JOHN T. WRIGHT, of Casey County State Guard Company, did, while Sergeant of the Guard, absent himself without permission from proper authority between the hours of 10 and reveille, on the night of <date when="1865-03-24">24th March, 1865</date>, violating Article 46, Army Regulations.</p>
<p>CHARGE II.
<lb/>"<hi rend="italic">Conduct prejudicial to good order and military discipline.</hi>"</p>
<p><hi rend="italic">Specification</hi> 1. -- That said Sergeant JOHN T. WRIGHT did hire another soldier to do his duty while acting Sergeant of the Guard, violating Article 47 and 48, Army Regulations.</p>
<p>To which charges and specifications the prisoner, Sergeant JOHN T. WRIGHT, plead as follows, viz:</p>
<p>To the <hi rend="italic">Specification</hi> 1, CHARGE 1, "Guilty."
<lb/>To the CHARGE 1, "Guilty."
<lb/>To the <hi rend="italic">Specification</hi> 1, CHARGE 2, "Not Guilty."
<lb/>To the CHARGE, "Not Guilty."</p>
<p>FINDING.</p>
<p>The Court having maturely considered the evidence adduced, finds the prisoner, Sergeant JOHN T. WRIGHT, Casey County State Guard, as follows:</p>
<p>Of the <hi rend="italic">Specification</hi> 1, CHARGE 1 "Guilty," (except the words "violating of Article 46, Army Regulations.")<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">3</note>
<lb/>Of the CHARGE 1, " Guilty."
<lb/>Of the <hi rend="italic">Specification</hi> 1, CHARGE 2 "Guilty."
<lb/>Of the CHARGE 2, "Guilty."</p>
<p>SENTENCE.</p>
<p>The Court does therefore sentence him, Sergeant JOHN T. WRIGHT, of Casey County State Guard Company, to be confined to hard labor for one month, and to be reduced to the ranks.</p>
<p>Finding and sentence in case of Sergeant JOHN T. WRIGHT, Casey County State Guard, approved and confirmed. The prisoner, Sergeant JOHN T. WRIGHT, will be turned over to the commanding officer of United States forces at Frankfort, Ky., with the request that he work Sergeant JOHN T. WRIGHT on the fortifications at that post during the term of his sentence.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>III. Corporal WESLEY W. HARR, Casey County State Guard.</p>
<p>CHARGE.
<lb/>"<hi rend="italic">Conduct prejudicial to good order and military discipline.</hi>"</p>
<p><hi rend="italic">Specification</hi> 1. -- That Corporal WESLEY W. HARR did, on the night of <date when="1865-03-24">March 24th, 1865</date>, accept a hire to do another man's duty, violating the 47th and 48th Articles, Army Regulations.</p>
<p><hi rend="italic">Specification</hi> 2. -- That the said Corporal WESLEY W. HARR did state that he had served three years, and had always done as he pleased, and he would be d -- d if he did not intend to continue to do so.</p>
<p>To which charges and specifications the prisoner, Corporal WESLEY W. HARR, plead as follows, viz:</p>
<p><hi rend="italic">Specification</hi> 1, CHARGE 1, "Not Guilty."
<lb/><hi rend="italic">Specification</hi> 2, CHARGE 1, "Not Guilty."
<lb/>CHARGE, "Not Guilty."</p>
<p>FINDING.</p>
<p>The Court having maturely considered the evidence adduced, finds the prisoner, Corporal WESLEY W. HARR, Casey County State Guard, as follows:</p>
<p><hi rend="italic">Specification</hi> 1, CHARGE 1, "Guilty."
<lb/><hi rend="italic">Specification</hi> 2, CHARGE 1, "Guilty."
<lb/>CHARGE, "Guilty."<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">4</note></p>
<p>SENTENCE.</p>
<p>And the Court does therefore sentence him, Corporal WESLEY W. HARR, of the Casey County State Guard, to be reduced to the ranks, and to forfeit one month's pay and allowances.</p>
<p>Finding and sentence in case of Corporal WESLEY W. HARR, Casey County State Guard, approved and confirmed. The commanding officer of the Casey County State Guard is hereby directed to make the proper charges on the rolls of his company against said Corporal WESLEY W. HARR in conformity with the sentence. </p>
<p>By order of the Governor.
<lb/>Official:
<lb/>D. W. LINDSEY,
<lb/><hi rend="italic">Adjutant General of Kentucky</hi>.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
