<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1076"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. H. Webster to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5713</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR[11]-160</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Sherburne, Fleming County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-08-12">12 August 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Sherburne Ky <date when="1864-08-12">August 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>Governor Bramlett</p>
<p>Dear sir I Just want to make a fine statement of facts to you concerning a fine or or rather fines Some time ago there was an affray between Mr Caleb Ralls and Mr W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Vice and M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Daniel Ralls &amp; M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Wm Vice &amp; Hiram Dailey for which the parties was all arrested and tried and the Jury acquited Vice in both Cases and also acquitted. Hiram Dailey and fined Caleb Ralls $4-25 cts and Danl Ralls $8-. and I was the Justice before whom the cases was tried. and I do think that the Jury acted illegal and from the testimy all parties. was equally guilty. and all of them aright to have been fine a small fine. but to acquit. one party that is equally guilty and fine the other I do not think it is wright Caleb Rall and Dan Ralles are both hard working men are very pore men and I will say to you in all cincer that they are sober discreet men and good citizens but accidently got in to this fight. and I have known the both for 12 or 15 years and this is the first fite that I ever heard of either of them gettg into</p>
<p>Therefore I would Respectfully ask you to Remit their fines of $4-25 cts &amp; $18 -- as above stated and by so doing you will not only confer a favor upon them but as I think Justice with it if you do see fit to Remit the fines please direct to W H Webster Sherburne Ky</p>
<p>Yours Fraternally
<lb/>W H Webster J. P. F C<pb/></p>
<p>Refused</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
