<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2381"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">L. J. Mossler to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9457</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG25-173 to MG25-174</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Govenor B Mogoffin</p>
<p><note place="left margin">1</note>
<lb/>Your Petitioner would respectfully represent to your Honor that he has been engaged for some five months in selling goods of various kinds at auction in the City of Lexington; He states that he made no attempt to avoid the laws of the state in regard to auctioneers -- He employed a regularly licensed auctioneer to acution his good's &amp; has regularly paid the percent both to the city and to the Commonwealth required by law -- these being the facts, he has been served with a warrant issuing from the City Court of Lexington charging him with selling with out License -- and further that he has been informed by Counsel that the Law may be against him wherefore he throws himself upon your Excellency's clemency -- and prays you to use your perogative in his case -- by a pardon before continuation -- </p>
<p><note place="left margin">2</note>
<lb/>Your Petition further states that he is a citizen of this Commonwealth and a resident of the City of Lexington; and making the above paragraph a part of this <unclear>no 2</unclear> so far as it sets forth the facts -- he would state that he has been fined in the Lexington City Court for Pedling with out license -- when he never<pb/>
<lb/>claimed to be a Pedler or so considered himself having a large store rented in the City at which house all of his goods are sold at auctin by a regularly licensed auctioneer and he sells no goods through the county or City as a Pedler -- with those facts before the Jury -- under the law they were compelled to find him -- which they did to the amount of $<hi rend="underline">100</hi> --. Your Petition under the circumstances prays your Excellency to remit said fine except fees and costs</p>
<p>all of which your Petitioner respectfully submits</p>
<p>L J. Mossler.</p>
<p>We the undersigned respectfully unite in the prayer's of the above petition</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Parker Craig
<lb/>James M. Lawrence
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Theo Steele
<lb/>M <unclear>Fraser</unclear>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> C P Breckenridge</hi>
<lb/>Robt J Breckinridge
<lb/><hi rend="underline">James B Beck</hi>
<lb/>Thos W. Bullock
<lb/>Z Gibbons
<lb/>Jn Keiser
<lb/>M G Johnson
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Cha</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> P Thomas</hi>
<lb/>Geo W D<unclear/>
<lb/>Roger W Hanson
<lb/>L P. Young
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Dan</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> Mc. Payne</hi>
<lb/>John B Payne Jr<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>R W Woolley
<lb/>J W Patterson
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Phil F Brown</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Lexington City Court</p>
<p>Respite 12 mo
<lb/>B M</p>
<p>Fine $100 -- Respite <unclear/> <date when="--02-21">Feby 21</date>
<lb/>Peddling in their license
<lb/>S J. Mossler</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
