<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2217"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Hudson to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6854</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-28 to BR15-29</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-08-01">1 August 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency Governor Bramlette, Governor of the State of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your petitioner, John Hudson, would humbly represent to your excellency That he is now held in custody in the Franklin County jail under an indictment against him in the Mercer Circuit Court for the alleged offence of stealing a horse That he has been so in custody for now some eighteen months or two years and was sent to said jail from Mercer County about fifteen months ago because that, as is said, the Mercer County Jail is untenable and unsafe That at the time he took the Horse he was laboring under the effects of liquor and was perfectly unconscious of committing a crime, that while he was yet in this state of intoxication and but a few minutes after he rode away on said <hi rend="str">said</hi> horse he was taken off said horse and the owner took the horse into possession your petitioner was carried to Harrodsburg and there incarcerated That at the time he got the horse he was a soldier in the United States Army and had been so a soldier for two years That he enlisted in the State of Indiana where he then <hi rend="str">lived</hi>resided and was a soldier in the 9<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ind Cav<pb/>
<lb/>when he took said horse That there were many Guerillas in Kentucky at the time he got said horse and was instigated to take possession of him <hi rend="str">for</hi>from fear of being captured, being then and there alone and away from his command That he <hi rend="str">had</hi>was a stranger in Kentucky and beleived he had the right to impress any horse he might find in order to save himself to his command That he <hi rend="str">is</hi>had understood that Morgan and his men took horses wherever they found them and that he had the same right. In view of this belief the state of the country and his intoxication he thus acted, wholly unconscious of having committed a crime in so doing That he is a young man 30 years of age, a stranger in a strange land that he feels repentant for what he has done and wants to become a good and useful citizen. He feels that he can do so and that he has been punished <hi rend="underline">severely</hi> <hi rend="str">for</hi><hi rend="underline">indeed</hi> for this his first offense, if offense it be,</p>
<p>That he is a machinist by trade and intends to devote his energies to the good of the community should<pb/>
<lb/>your excellency release ^him^ from custody</p>
<p>Your Petitioner would further represent that he has never been tried under said indictment and separated thus from home ^&amp;^ friends that he has been punished severly and humbly craves your excellency's interposition in his behalf and will ever pray</p>
<p>John Hudson</p>
<p>Sworn to before me this <date when="1865-08-01">first day of August, 1865</date></p>
<p>Eugene P. Moore, Examiner</p>
<p>We the undersigned join in the foregoing petition:</p>
<p>W A Gaines
<lb/><hi rend="underline">A H</hi> <hi rend="underline">Rennick</hi>
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Craik J, F, C,
<lb/>W Faulkner</p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp"><unclear/></note></p>
<p><note place="left margin">I think this a clear case for Pardon,
<lb/>John L. Scott.
<lb/>com. atty.</note><pb/></p>
<p>F
<lb/>John Hudson
<lb/>Pardon
<lb/>has issued</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
