<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1978"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John A. Taylor to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6615</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-116 to BR14-117</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-06-16">16 June 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlette Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky Your Petitioner would most Respectfully state that at the <date when="1865-06">June term 1865</date> of the Marion Circuit Court Ky <hi rend="str">a</hi>two judgements w<hi rend="str">as</hi>ere rendered against him ^one^ for $500 -- and one for $20 -- for the alledged charge of Gaming &amp; seting up a faro Bank -- Your Petitioner has paid the costs &amp; Comwths attorney part but he is unable to pay the balance without robbing his family he says he is not a gambler nor does he make his support by Gaming in any way and never has delt <hi rend="underline">faro</hi> but once and that is the offense charged &amp; then only at the solicitation of others the very men who were witnesses against him that he did not own the table Box or cards but the whole apparattus belonged to another and he dealt for those who were present Your Petitioner will say that if Your Excellency will remit the fine he will never deal again to accomodate other persons Your Petitioner most respectfully asks a remission</p>
<p>John A Taylor</p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">J A T
<lb/><date when="1865-06-17">June
<lb/>17</date></note></p>
<p>Sworn to before me by John Taylor this <date when="1865-06-16">June 16 1865</date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">T. C. Jackson Clk</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Your Petitioners most respectfully aks a remission of the two fines
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>T. C. Jackson Clk M, C, C,
<lb/><hi rend="underline">F. B. Merimee</hi>
<lb/>James M Fidler
<lb/>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi>. G. Rogers Lt Col 54 Ky Vols
<lb/>Jo<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H Chandler
<lb/>John R. Thomas
<lb/><cb n="2"/>B Spalding<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>Marion Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John A Taylor
<lb/>4500, Faro
<lb/>$20, Gaming
<lb/><date when="1865-06-27">27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> June/65</date></p>
<p>Remit</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
