<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2394"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John H. Deckard et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7031</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-324 to BR15-325</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-09-23">23 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency, Thos. E. Bramlette Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> of the State of Kentucky, your Petitioners, beg leave to make Known to your Honor, that on or about the <date when="1863-12-14">14<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of December 1863</date>, the Subscriber John H. Deckard became Surety in a bond to the Commonwealth of Kentucky for the appearance of William B. Deckard at the next Term of ^the^ allen Circuit Court charged with Robbery. That soon after the bail bond was executed Said Willim B. Deckard Joined the Federal army and became a soldier in the 52 Regt. Ky Infantry Co. "I" and <hi rend="str">at</hi> was to serve one year unless sooner discharged <hi rend="str">He</hi> <hi rend="str">says</hi> The redgment was not in the County at the next Term of the Court of allen County and the bond which was for five hundred dollars was forfeited and at the <hi rend="str">October</hi> <date when="1865-09">September Term of Said Court ^in the Year 1865^</date> Judgment was taken against Jno H. Deckard for the five hundred dollars. William B. Deckard was discharged from said service on the <date when="1865-03-12">12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of March 1865</date>. at. Bowling Green. John H. Deckard is a citizen of monroe County and quite a feeble man about 65 years of age.</p>
<p>In view of these facts we beg you humbly that you will release him of the payment of the Judgment. Hoping you will grant us our request, we with<pb/>
<lb/>pleasure subscribe our names hereto. This the <date when="1865-09-23">23<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> day of September 1865</date>.</p>
<p>John H. Deckard.
<lb/>John Welch
<lb/>Thomas. P. Comer
<lb/>Andrew Comer
<lb/>J B. Evans
<lb/>J T. Beals
<lb/>S. F. Drake
<lb/>J. Rowan, Leslie
<lb/>H, B, Marrs
<lb/>H Hagan
<lb/>L A Smithwick
<lb/>William G Patterson
<lb/>Wm G Chism
<lb/>John J, Gee
<lb/>J. C. Gist
<lb/>J.. C. Conkin
<lb/>R. H. Chism
<lb/>J. G. Bailey
<lb/>LaFayette Harling<pb/></p>
<p>A Petition To his excellency the Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. of Ky.
<lb/>Thomas E Bramlette<pb/></p>
<p>Allen Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John H, Deckard
<lb/>$500.
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-12-11">11 Dec /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
