<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1960"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Nelson to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11428</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Bradley Strait</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG23-410 to MG23-411</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-06-26">26 June 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency the Governor of Kentucky your Petitioner John Nelson would represent, that he is an old man 69 years of age. That a few weeks Since one John Gilliland in company with two persons, his son and another came to his house and in the presence of his wife and children insulted him and threatened him with a prosecution and behaved very improper in his house: he ordered him to leave but he refused and continued his abuse and finally struck his wife a woman of 54 years of age in the face your petitioner could not bear this and in attempting to put Gilliland out of the house he struck him in his own defence. Gilliland had a stick and attempted to strike your petitioner That Gilliland took out a warrant against your petitioner and a Jury was empannelled and he was forced into trial without his witnesses and against his earnest protestations on the same day the warrant was executed without giving him time to get any witnesses. That the Constable came to his house near Boston Jefferson<pb/>
<lb/>County on the <date when="1862-06-18">18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of June</date> about 9 oclock and arrested him and his wife &amp; son and carried them off to a magistrate about 4 miles from his home That by reason of his being forced into trial without his witness and without a preparation for trial the jury gave a verdict against him for a fine of $20 &amp; costs or ten days imprisonment. Your Petitioner appealed immediately for a new trial but the magistrate refused him saying that an appeal to the County Court was the only remedy your petitioner would state that he is poor and has no means to pay the fine with and is too old and infirm to endure the imprisonment; That the Jury was prejudiced against your petitioner because of political differences. He prays your Excellency to remit the fine &amp; imprisonment against him</p>
<p>John Nelson</p>
<p>Jefferson County } Sct</p>
<p>This day personally appeared before me John Nelson and made oath to<pb/>
<lb/>the statement in the foregoing Petition given under my have this the <date when="1862-06-26">26 day of June 1862</date></p>
<p>O F Stirman
<lb/>Notary Public for Jefferson County Ky<pb/></p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M.</p>
<p>Jefferson J. P. Ct
<lb/>$20 &amp; 10 days imprisonment
<lb/>John Nelson
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-07-22">July 22<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1862</date><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Send to Stirman</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
