<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0713"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. H. Calvert et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10181</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-110 to MG19-111</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioners would respectfully represent unto Your Excellency that at the <date when="1859-03">March Term of the Caldwell Circuit Court 1859</date>. The Commonwealth of Ky recovered thru Judgments against Jesse Williams as surity on three Bail Bonds, for the sum of one hundred dollars each</p>
<p>That at the <date when="1858-09">September Term of said Court 1858</date> Said Commonwealth recovered a Judgement against James Williams for the sum of one hundred and Eighty five dollars upon an Indictment for an assault</p>
<p>That at the <date when="1859-03">March Term of said Court 1859</date> said Commonwealth recovered a Judgement against John Williams for five hundred dollars upon an Indictment for Striking with the intent to kill.</p>
<p>That at <hi rend="str">said</hi> <date when="1859-09">September Term of said Court ^1859</date>^ said commonwealth recovered a further Judgement of five hundred dollars against said John Williams upon an indictment for a Breach of the Peace That at said Term of said Court, said Commonwealth recovered a further Judgement against said John Williams for twenty five dollars upon an indictment for a Breach of the Peace</p>
<p>Your Petitioners would further<pb/>
<lb/>State that since the <date when="--03">last March Term</date> of said Court Jessee Williams has been hung by a mob or in other words he was taken into custody and while his g^u^ards slept he was missing and was next day found hanging to the limb of a tree. That James &amp; John Williams was compelled to leave the state in order to save their lives and were persued with an armed force to the state line and your petitioners believe that they will never return to the State of Kentucky again-</p>
<p>That Jesse Williams left a widow and family of nine children all of whom are girls but two small Boys who are unable from their tender age to be of any service to their Mother_</p>
<p>Your petitioners State that they are informed by the daughters of said Williams Decord and by his Administrator when James &amp; John Williams left the state they took with them all the money that was on the place which was about six Thousand dollars and notes to the amount of four or five thousand dollars the principal portion of which was for debts due their Father in the state of Missouri That the Administrator has informed Your petitioners that he has written to the debtors of said Estate in the State of Missouri and that he can get no<pb/>
<lb/>Answer from them and that said Adm<hi rend="sup">r</hi> believes that the said James &amp; John has compounded with said debtors of said Estate and and collected what they could from them and given them up their notes and that the Administrator will be unable to collect any of the debts that the said James and John took away with them Your Petitioners would respectfully state that they believe the amount taken off by James &amp; John Williams togeather with the amounts that their Father paid for them in his lifetime would be an amount Equal if not larger than their distributive portions of their Fathers Estate</p>
<p>Your Petitioners would further sate unto Your Excellency that Executions have been levied by the sheriff on the interests of James &amp; John Williams in their Fathers Estate which will be sold at great sacrifice in the present uncertain and embarrassed condition of said Estate and that the rights of the inocent will be seriously effected by such proceedings</p>
<p>Your Petitioners would state to your Excellency That Jesse Williams is dead as before stated and that James and John Williams have left the state never to return again. That if they ever do<pb/>
<lb/>return your petitioners believe that they will meet the same fate of their Father That they will no more disturb the peace of the citizens of Kentucky or commit any further infractions upon the laws of the Commonwealth</p>
<p>They therefore pray your Excellency to remit so much of the fines against Jesse Williams James Williams and John Williams as are going to the Commonwealth for the benefit of the widow and her infant children for your petitioners feel that the Commonwealth more able to do without said fines than the widow and her infant children wherefore they pray your Excellency to remit said fines and this they will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W. H. Calvert. Admr
<lb/>W. H. Mott
<lb/>Geo. M. Fox
<lb/>Ben D. Terry
<lb/>John M Higgins
<lb/>Thos. W. Matlock
<lb/>T D. Pinner
<lb/>R. Barnes
<lb/>J. P. Gracey
<lb/>A. C. Black
<lb/>Ben Jones
<lb/>John Satterfield
<lb/>James M Crow
<lb/>P. P. chambers
<lb/>Will H. Miller
<lb/><cb n="2"/>E. P. Campbell
<lb/>Thos. S. Johnson
<lb/>A C Mayse
<lb/>A. N. Bozarth
<lb/>J. Z. Chambers
<lb/>J R Hewlett
<lb/>R. Wilson
<lb/>J. J. Wylie
<lb/>D. H Wylie
<lb/>A. Reynolds
<lb/>W. T. Talbott
<lb/>H. J. Evans
<lb/>M. Dudley
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Cash
<lb/>James S. Long</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
