<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2578"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George E. Roe to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7215</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-124 to BR16-125</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Grayson, Carter County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-07">7 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Grayson Carter County Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-10-07">Oct 7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Thos. E. Bramlett Esq<hi rend="underline">r</hi>
<lb/>Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Dear Sir allow me through this medium, to make useful Suggestions. in mitigation of our unfortunate Youth -- Joseph.A. Young, he was Indicted in the carter circuit Court. for Robery -- Under these circumstances -- 
<lb/>On the night of the <date when="--03-01">first of March</date> last, One W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Mobly lost $50.00 a fifty Dollar bill. Young &amp; others were there in the room after Mobly went to bed -- they had a light before them -- in the room -- Young went to the next Day to ashland &amp; Got a 50$ bill changed -- </p>
<p>Young proved, by Mrs Long that 2 weeks before the alleged Robery Young had a fifty Dollar bill -- She had the money Keeping it for Young -- that She Give him his pocket Book. with the $50 bill in it. the morning he Started to<pb/>
<lb/>Ashland. under these circumstances Young was found Guilty, &amp; Sentenced to a Years confinement in the penitierry.</p>
<p>Young is but a youth his parents are Dead. he has been in arms for the federal Government, ever since the Rebellion broke out -- until it was Suppressed -- his father was brutally Murdered by the Guerrillars,</p>
<p>I do not hesitate upon the wholy Evenglist, that from the proof in the cause three other persons, had as Great a chance if not Greater, than Young Did -- to Get the money of Mobly If it was taken at all, the proof Showed that Mobly was Drunk in a crowded Bar Room, with a number of persons Drinking with him -- I really think he ought to be pardoned</p>
<p>Yours with very great respect
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Geo, E, Roe</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Grayson Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-10-07">Oct 7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th </hi></hi>1865</date>
<lb/>Col D, W, Lindsey</p>
<p>I have written the above lines to the Governor in behalf of M<hi rend="underline">r</hi> Young for Executive Clemency The Blood of his Dead father Brutally Murdered by Guerillars calls alowed for pity and protection. M<hi rend="underline">r</hi> Young has been in armes from the first Tocsin of war, until the rebellion was Supressed he <hi rend="str">merrits</hi> Merits no Such treatment</p>
<p>Yours with very Great
<lb/>respect
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Geo, W, Roe</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Thos, E, Bramlett Esq<hi rend="underline">r</hi>
<lb/>Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
