<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-021-0034"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William K. Lay, C. Owsley, and James W. Turner to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG3104</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Apprehension of Fugitives from Justice Papers, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG8-122</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-07-06">6 July 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Ford of Cumberland <date when="1861-07-06">July 6,th, 1861</date>
<lb/>Hon McGoffin Governor of Ky,</p>
<p>Dear Sir enclosed with this you will find a record of the Circuit Court of Union County State of Tennessee: The State vs Wm, B, Chapman for fel<hi rend="str">l</hi>ony embezelment of public money: on Saturday last I arrested him in Booneville Ky, and a mob<hi rend="str">ed</hi> of Scoundrels armed took him from me as they said because I had no Warrant or requisition from your Hon, but said if I brought such authority, they would surrender him, I think this record and three honest men having to pay $1500, for this vilian will induce you to issue your Warrant for his arrest, if you will so do send it immediately to P. O. Travelers rest, Owsley County Ky, directed to Danl, B, Cass &amp; Issac Hacker: who promise to deliver him to the securities at Maynardville Union County Tennessee immediately for the reward now offered $50, I hope you will at once send your Warrant <hi rend="str">so</hi> to this place Travelers rest Ky. to Hacker &amp; Capps, that this vilian may be brought to justice and his securities released from their heavy penalty: I am their Agent &amp; employed by them if you do not give your Warrant for his arrrest write me at Maynardville immediately yours Respty</p>
<p>Wm. J Lay
<lb/>C. Owsley &amp;
<lb/>James W. Turner
<lb/>By Atty, Allen Hurst</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
