<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0466"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">P. B. Hawkins et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4585</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-231 to BR9-232</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Gov. Bramlette,</p>
<p>The undersigned earnestly request you to grant a pardon to John Burnam of Bowlinggreen Ky who is indicted in the Warren Circuit Court for Treason, based on his connexion with the so called provisional government of Kentucky, as the Custodian of their funds. They are induced to ask the interposition of executive clemency in his behalf for the following reasons.</p>
<p>First, his former and present high character as a outright Christan gentleman</p>
<p>Secondly, His uniform kindnesss and protection to Union citizens in his town while the same was under Rebel rule, as attested by the best citizens there who know the facts</p>
<p>Thirdly, He is an old man, a cripple, broken down in fortune and spirits, and deeply penitent for his past errors.</p>
<p>Upon the departure of the Rebel forces from Bowlinggreen he went South, remained some 18 months in Georgia, and in the fall of <date when="1863">1863</date> returned home, reported himself to the U.S. Military Command only of his part, executed a bond in $10000 for his future good conduct, with ample surety, and took an oath to sustain in future the Character of a true loyal citisen, his neighbors believing he will do so, and so certifying for him.</p>
<p>Fourth, Upon the foregoing statements being made known to the President<pb/>
<lb/>of the United States an unconditional pardon was granted him against all past offenses against the Federal Government. It has been thought that this pardon might not be available to Mr Burnam against the prosecution for the offense against the State of Kentucky, and it is therefore earnestly requested that your excellency will accord to Mr. B a pardon believeing as we do that you will in so doing bring peace and happiness to a distressed family, and in no wise endanger the interests of the Commonwealth</p>
<p>P. B. Hawkins
<lb/>Edward R Weir
<lb/>J. K. Faulkner
<lb/>P. Swigert
<lb/>G. T. Wood
<lb/>J. B. English
<lb/>R Tarvin Baker
<lb/>Richard T Jacob
<lb/>G S Shanklin
<lb/>W. A. Ronald
<lb/>J H Chandler
<lb/>Sam<hi rend="sup">l</hi> B. Thomas
<lb/>W R Kinney
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>J. R. Underwood<pb/>
<lb/>B. H. Bristow
<lb/>H. Taylor
<lb/>J. M. Lowry
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Bell
<lb/>Russell Hawkins C S.
<lb/>J. F. Lauck
<lb/>W H Miller
<lb/>Hugh Irvine
<lb/>Jno J. Gatewood
<lb/><unclear/> Miller<pb/></p>
<p>I had determined never to raise my hand or voice in behalf of any one in the so called Provisional Government of Kentucky, but in the case of Mr Burnam, on account of his age, &amp; the representations as to his present sentiments I depart from that resolution &amp; join in the within petition for his pardon</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Sampson</p>
<p>Warren Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John Burnam
<lb/>Indicted for Treason
<lb/>Pardoned
<lb/><date when="1864-01-28">28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Jany/ 64</date></p>
<p>This is an exceptional case. The Presd<hi rend="sup">t</hi> having Pardoned the accused it ought to be regarded as releasing him from the penalties of treason. And to save all doubt upon the subject &amp; efffectuate the pardon of the President it is ordered that a pardon issue</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
