<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2847"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. L. Phythian to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7484</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-137</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-18">18 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Frankfort <date when="1865-12-18">December 18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>Gov Bramlette</p>
<p>George Ashton a prisoner in the Kentucky Penitentiary sentenced to two years confinement for theft by the Todd County Circuit Court, is laboring under a severe and painful gun shot wound The ball entered the back, ranged upwards into the lung, and has now been extracted The wound is of such character as totally to unift him for any labor whatever, and if he should recover at all, of which there is little probability, it would be a great length of time His health is failing and the ends of Justice cannot be <unclear/> by retaining him longer in confinenent</p>
<p>J. L. Phythian
<lb/>surgeon Ky Penitentiary</p>
<p>I have examined the prisoner George Ashton referred to above, and concur fully with Dr Phythian in his opinion of the case.</p>
<p>J. M. Mills, M.D.
<lb/>Inspector Ky Penitentiary<pb/></p>
<p>This young man may be a useful Citizen if he is released from Prison if he remains in Prison will come out an accomplished rascal -- </p>
<p>H I Todd</p>
<p>Todd Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Geo Atchison
<lb/>2 years
<lb/>Pardoned <date when="1865-12-18">18 Dec 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
