<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0379"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. W. Crandell, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8831</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-112</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-05-26">26 May 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Affidavit of W. W. Crandell.</p>
<p>The affiant W. W. Crandell States that he is a citizen of Bullitt county ^and lives^ near the Jeffrason &amp; Bullitt county line, 13 miles from Louisville. I have known Joseph Shoenbergly, for about three years. He lived in my neighborhood, during the years <date when="1860">1860</date>, <date when="1861">61</date>, &amp; <date when="1862">1862</date> til October, when he removed from there. There were three or four other German families lived in the Same neighborhood, during the time. The corn-cribs and Smoke-houses ^of the neighborhood^ were robbed of their contents; and we watched for the thief but could not catch him.</p>
<p>We then adopted a plan to catch <hi rend="str">him,</hi> the thief or thieves if possible. We sent a negroe with corn and bacon, after night, to Shoenbergley's, and to the other Germans, to Sell to them. We, Some of us followed in hearing distance and watched and listened. The negroe tried to Sell the articles to S. for cash, but he would not buy them; he then offered them on a credit; but he Still refused -- but told the negroe that if he <hi rend="str">would</hi> would bring them in the day time with his master's consent or order, that he would buy them. We tried him Several times and thoroughly, but he persistently refused to buy. Two of the other Germans bought of the negroe. </p>
<p>I have known Shoenbergley, Since the year <date when="1860">1860</date>. During that time his character has been as good as any man's for honesty &amp;c. I believe him<pb/>
<lb/>to be an honest reliable trust-worthy man.</p>
<p>W W Crandell</p>
<p>State of Kentucky.
<lb/>Jefferson county Sct.</p>
<p>Sworn to before me this <date when="1863-05-26">26<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of May 1863</date>, by W. W. Crandell.</p>
<p>L. A. Wood N. P. for J. C. Ky.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
