<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0016"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas J. Peek et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9484</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17A-61 to MG17A-62</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-01-21">21 January 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency, Beriah Magoffin. Governor, of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Caldwell county Ky, have long known Thomas. B. Wadlington &amp; he has ever been considered a good &amp; true hearted citizen, Known and noted, for his industry &amp; his orderly and peaceable conduct. The difficulty in which he was engaged with M. A. Cartwright did not appear to us, to be of his seeking, Nor are we satisfied that the case was fairly presented to the jury, as it occurred -- We hope your Excellency will review the case, &amp; give the poor man the benefit of every doubt or desire, that his case may be Judged of in mercy &amp; regarded with favor, And that your Excellency will take into consideration every circumstance, that ought to operate in his behalf. And we desire and hope that your Excellency may be persuaded that it is consistent with your duty to extend to him Executive Clemency, and that his life may be spared either by a full pardon or a commutation of his punishment -- </p>
<p><date when="1861-01-21">Jany 21 1861</date>.<pb/>
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> J, Peek,
<lb/>R, H, Peek
<lb/>Thos, H, dalton
<lb/>William Tosh
<lb/>Zalarine Givens
<lb/>W M Garbin
<lb/>J, D, Jennings
<lb/>J. P. dalton
<lb/>A, J, Tosh
<lb/>J T dalton
<lb/>G, W, Tosh
<lb/>B P Peek
<lb/>W G Sanders
<lb/>John Steadons
<lb/><unclear/> Steadones
<lb/>Carver Jonass
<lb/>John: R: Fleming
<lb/>A Daum</p>
<p>State of Ky caldwell county -- The affiant R. M. Peek says he was present &amp; saw the above named persons sign the foregoing petition -- </p>
<p>R. M. Peek</p>
<p>Sworn to before my by R. M. Peek this <date when="1861-01-27">Jan'y 27 1861</date></p>
<p>W E Mitchesaon D Clk,</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
