<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1856"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. N. B. Hardwick et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11324</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Bradley Strait</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG23-254 to MG23-255</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency. Beria Magoffin 
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky </p>
<p>The undersigned Petitioners would respectfully represent to your Excellency that at the <date when="1859-03">March Term (1859)</date> of the Powell Circuit Court. Harvey Flynn was fined and Judgment rendered in said against him for $50 for recieving a bribe for his vote, the proof in the case was that he took $10. and did not vote at all <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> nor did he go to the election we believe he was entirely ignorant of the fact that he was violating the law in doing what he did, as he is an illiterate and quite ignorant man, that he is an old man (sixty or sixty five years old) and very poor has a tolerable large family who are intirely dependent upon him for their support. a portion of them badly afflicted with fits. the old man has no no property of Consequence, except a small piece of poor mountain Land, which he had to Mortgage. in order to give security to keep from going to Jail under and by virtue of Said Judgment, and we see no chance for him to get the money to pay the debt, and feeling as we do. that it is a case. (under all the circumstances) that merits the interposition of your clemency, we therefore pray your Excellency to remit said fine &amp; Judgment</p>
<p>We would further say to your Excellency that at the <date when="1858-09">September term (1858)</date> of said Court. John Woodward was fined $30<pb/>
<lb/>for illegal gaming. also <unclear>zarzimbra</unclear> Holmes was at the <date when="1861-03">March term, 1861</date>. of said Court fined $50. for carrying a concealed weapon</p>
<p>We would say to your Excellency <hi rend="str">that</hi> on the part of Mr. Woodward. that he is a clever young man and a good citizen and has reformed since said Judgment was rendered against him. that he is a poor young man. also Mr. Holmes is a good Citizen. and has a family. and we think had no evil design in carrying the weapon that he is quite poor also</p>
<p>we believe in view of all the circumstances the scarcity of money and the inability of Mr Woodword &amp; Mr Holmes to pay said fines that it is in the wish of all conversant with the circumstances. that said fines should be remitted</p>
<p>We therefore pray your Excellency to remit said fines and will ever pray &amp;C</p>
<p>J N B Hardwick County 
<lb/>Judge of Powell County 
<lb/>Y. H. Schpll clk P. C. C.
<lb/>John F Halley 
<lb/>J. H. Johns
<lb/>Benjamin Holms 
<lb/>J M Wood
<lb/>John Leonaherd 
<lb/>W R Pettit
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> H Daniel 
<lb/>I T Clark<pb/>
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> M Combs (Jailor P C)
<lb/>Tilford Welch
<lb/>Madison Stewart
<lb/>J. T. Clark<pb/></p>
<p>Powell Cir. Ct. 
<lb/>$50 } Mis. 
<lb/>Harvey Flynn
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-04-24">Apr 24. 1862</date></p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B M</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
