<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1665"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Mary F. Pulliam, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6302</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-139 to BR13-140</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Edmonson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-04-06">6 April 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Edmondson Cty. Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-04-06">Aprile 6. 1864</date></p>
<p>I were at M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Evan's three years ago last February when M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Berry and others came there and had the fight with M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Evans. I were knowing to. and saw the whole affair. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Evans had me summoned and I attended the different courts in <date when="1863">1863</date> and <date when="1864">4.</date> <date when="1864-09">last September</date> he furnished me with horse and saddle to ride from where I now live, which is on Green River in Edmundson Cty to his house, and then to Glasgow, a distance of twenty three or four miles. On teusday morning, the day we were summoned to attend court. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Evans carried with him M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Kinney Miss Martha. Evans and myself to Glasgow. Soon after our arrival at Glasgow, M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Evans came to us and informed us, that he was on the jury, and did not ^know^ when he could go home, and said to us, "that we must do the best we could for ourselves." We came back to M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Evans that evening and left him at town, he got home a while after dark that night, he started back to town verry early wednesday and came home after dark that night. Thursday morning he started again to town quite early, as usual and returned that night complaining of being quite unwell, on friday morning he said he was verry unwell, we told him he had better not start to town, he said he was compeled to go. he came home that night verry sick with headache and was sick all night, Saturday we were<pb/>
<lb/>ready to go to town, and asked M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Evans if we must go to town. he said he was sick and was in no condition to go to town. he had head ^ache^ all morning on Saturday. keep his bed, about the middle of the day, he got some better and went out to Cave City, came back that evening his head still aching. and was sick that night and next morning. &amp; M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Evans is in bad health and has been for several years, and has the worst ^spells^ of head-ache I ever saw any person have. I heard M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Evans speak of the difficulty between himself and M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Berry several times He always said he was anxious to have the trial over with, he always said if he could have a fair trial, that he had no fears of having anything to pay. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Evans was about starting to town with us, on Monday morning after the trial came off on saturday before, when he was informed that the trial was over with, therefore we did not go</p>
<p>Mary F. Pulliam</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Mary F. Pulliam this <date when="1865-04-25">25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of April 1865</date></p>
<p>J F. Dickinson J. P. <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>B. C.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
