<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-033-0041"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Joseph F. Jones, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1504</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Apprehension of Fugitives from Justice Papers, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-72 to R3-73</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Daviess County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-05-30">30 May 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Daviess County } Sct</p>
<p>This day Joseph F Jones personally appeared before me the undersigned and made oath that Charles Wheeler was guilty of the crime of obtaining property from affiant, which was the Subject of larceny, on the <date when="1861-01-23">23<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> day of January 1861</date>, by a false pretense in token, with intent to commit a fraud, and committed as follows, towit, That on the <date when="1860-12-01">first day of December 1860</date>. the Said charles Wheeler by Collusion with one James Wilcox of Lake County &amp; State of Indiana, caused the Said Wilcox to execute to him the Said Wheeler his two promissory notes one for Seven hundred and fifty dollars due in Six months after said date, and one for Seven hundred &amp; fifty dollars due in twelve months after date and both notes bearing interest from date, and one note for one thousand dollars due twelve months after date, And one note ^for one thousand dollars^ due in eighteen months after date, both bearing interest from date, and one that Said date the Said Wheeler took from the Said <hi rend="str">Wheeler</hi> Wilcox a mortgage on one hundred acres of land in Lake County Indiana to secure the payment of the first two notes and on One hundred and Sixty acres of land in Lake County Indiana to Secure the payment of the last two notes of $1000. each.<pb/>
<lb/>Affiant further Says that Said notes and mortgages were executed and certified by the said Wheeler and Wilcox with the design and intent to commit the crime afs<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> And with the full knowledge on the part of both Wheeler and Wilcox that the Said land was not worth as much as fifty cents per acre, and wholly inadequate to Secure the payment of said notes -- And the said Wheeler with the intent to commit the crime afs<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> on the <date when="1861-01-23">23<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> day of January 1861</date>, in the County afs<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> under the false pretense and token ^&amp; representation^ that Said Wilcox was good &amp; Solvent and amply responsible for said notes, and that said land was worth the amount for which the Same was mortgaged, Sold and assigned to affiant the note for Seven hundred &amp; fifty dollars due Six months after date, and the note for Seven hundred &amp; fifty dollars due twelve months after date, and the note due twelve months after date for one thousand dollars, all specified in the two mortgages af. said, &amp; for which affiant transfered and delivered to the said Wheeler in payment of said notes one wharf boat, &amp; appertenances two drays &amp; four mules &amp; harnass of the aggregate value of $2500, in actual cash, That by reason<pb/>
<lb/>of the false and fraudulent pretense and token of the Said Wheeler and his false and fraudulent representation as to the Solvency of the Said James Wilcox the maker of said notes and mortgages, &amp; his, the said Wheelers false pretense, token and representation of the value of said land, he procured from affiant the wharf boat, dray, mules &amp; harnass aforesaid, and which said property was the Subject of larceny, Affiant further says that at the time of the execution of said notes and mortgages the Said James Wilcox was hopelessly insolvant, was wholly <hi rend="str">wh</hi> worthless and a vagabond and all of which was well known to the Said Charles Wheeler, and that he was hired &amp; paid by the Said Wheeler to execute Said notes &amp; mortgages, in order to enable him the Said Wheeler to commit the Crime aforesaid, and that the Sole object, intent, and design, of said Wheeler &amp; Wilcox in the execution of said notes &amp; mortgages was to enable the said Charles Wheeler to commit the Crime aforesaid, and which was committed by the Said Wheeler in the manner afs<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> in the County aforesaid.</p>
<p>J, F, Jones<pb/></p>
<p>Daviess County
<lb/>State of Kentucky } Sct</p>
<p>The within and foregoing affidavit was this day taken subscribed and Sworn to before me the Presiding Judge of the County Court for the County afs<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> this <date when="1863-05-30">30th May 1863</date>, by Joseph F. Jones.</p>
<p>A. G Bates p j D c</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
