<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0344"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William R. Vance et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9812</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-33</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To Bariah M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin
<lb/>Govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioners respectfully represent that at the Last Term of the Hickman Criminal and Equity court held in Clinton John W, Long was indicted for the Murder of W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Long, that the indictment was found by the grand Inquest of the County at said Term and within four days therafter the defendent was placed on trial, that defendent was poor and not able to employ Counsel, that Counsel were assigned to him by the Court but from the professional engagements of his said Counsel the defendent could not avail himself of their Services in his case.</p>
<p>That defendent was placed upon trial and found guilty of Murder in the first degree and by the Judgment of the court sentenced to be hung on the <date when="--08-10">10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> dy of August next</date>, Your petitioner would respectfully call your attention to the facts of this case as the same appear from an exemplification of the Record in this case and Earnestly pray the interposition of Executive Clemency in his behalf, and that his punishment by commuted to imprisonment in the Penitentiary of this State for any term of years which to your Excellency may seem right and proper<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names,
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> R, Vance
<lb/>T B Ostrander
<lb/>Geo L Porter
<lb/>John W Slankard
<lb/>A C Yantz
<lb/>C M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kinney
<lb/>J. M. Jackson
<lb/>W. Cromwell
<lb/>R. F. Lewis
<lb/>L P Bartlett
<lb/>G H. Smith
<lb/>David Mason
<lb/>Philip Taylor
<lb/>John. V. Morton
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/>B. T,, Haile
<lb/>William R Morgan
<lb/>Geo P Heath
<lb/>S K Caldwell
<lb/>Eli Ray
<lb/>W. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>K Hubbard
<lb/>A A Gorton
<lb/>J P Ferguson
<lb/>A Russell
<lb/>W. R. Smith
<lb/>Will P. Wilkinson
<lb/>P, P, Elliott -- 
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Cook
<lb/>W. Walker Lublette</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
