<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0259"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Leander M. Cox et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4378</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-409 to BR8-410</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Flemingsburg, Fleming County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-11-12">12 November 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Flemingsburg <date when="1863-11-12">Nov<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency Thomas E. Bramlett
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky
<lb/>Sir.</p>
<p>Diana Pitt, Spinster, was fined at the <date when="--09">last September term</date> of the Fleming Circuit Court Sixty dollars and costs on an Indictment for keeping a tippling house- and not having any property subject to execution is now confined in the jail of county at county expense on a capias pro fine. She is an unmarried woman but has managed to have several children-the youngest only about six months old. She has been in jail several days and there is no probability that she can give security; and will, unless the fine is remitted have to remain for thirty days. We think that there is no public good to be attained by confining her longer in jail-and it will increase the county expense. The judgment so far as it could influence her future conduct has done all it can do. We therefore respectfully ask your excellency to remit So much of said fine as you constitutionally and legally can remit, and pardon and remit all the imprisonment annexed to the fine. We respectfully ask your immediate action on this matter</p>
<p>Your Obedient<pb/>
<lb/>Servants
<lb/>Leander M. Cox
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> H. Cord
<lb/>County attorney.
<lb/>John M. Harbeson
<lb/>M. L. Harbeson</p>
<p>P. S. If you remit mail to clerk of the court J. M. Harbeson Esq.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">L. M. Cox</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Fleming County
<lb/>Remission
<lb/>Refused
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/><date when="1863">63</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
