<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0768"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John M. Burns and Laban T. Moore to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4887</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-176 to BR10-177</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Catlettsburg, Boyd County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-04-26">26 April 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Catlettsburg Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-04-26">April 26th 1864</date>
<lb/>Governor Bramlett
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>We regret the necessity that impels ^us^ to address you these lines. C.. F.. Dyer has been tried and sentenced to the Penitentiary of this state by the verdict of a Jury of this County for the Period of one year, under a charge of Receiving Stolen horses=, We are confident the evidence before the Jury did not warrant the verdict. of Guilty. We ware present and heard all the Testimony- and the case secured so plain for the deft (Dyer) that his counsel &amp; all others who we heard speak, thought an argument to the Jury was unnecessary and therfore none was made;</p>
<p>But his innocence has been more clearly developed since his conviction of affidavits and otherwise; but discovered<pb/>
<lb/>at a period to late to avail the prisoner any thing in this Court; The only hope now left us to save an innocent man both from suffering the loss of his liberty and the Odium to him and his children attached; Is in an appeal to your clemency, and ask you to exercise in his behalf your constitutional Power of pardon;</p>
<p>Governor we would not ask you to do this ware it not that we are under the most candid conviction that Justice demands it at your hands.</p>
<p>Believing sir that neither Justice or Mercy are strangers to your composition; we have hope in asking you to Parden Mr Dyer, and save hime and his motherless Children from the heritage of infamy a heritage thy do not deserve.</p>
<p>We are Governor yours with very high Respect
<lb/>John M. Burns
<lb/>L T Moore</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
