<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1610"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Robert J. Elliott to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11078</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Andrew P Patrick</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-258 to MG22-259</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-01-14">14 January 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville Ky <date when="1862-01-14">Jany 14. 1862</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency 
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> B. Magoffin
<lb/>My dear Sir: </p>
<p>I am requested by Mr John Schwab, (who has this day been found guilty on an indictment for unlawfully &amp; maliciously stabbing Herman Hubner &amp; by the verdict his confinement in the penetentiary fixed at one year) to write to you in his behalf, he having had prepared a petition to your Excellency asking you to grant him a pardon</p>
<p>Being a stranger to you I am not aware that anything I might say would be of any service to Schwab -- but still I know your Excellency will give all proper consideration to what I may say. In the first place I would remark that I wrote the petition for Schwab, &amp; the matters therein stated as to the conduct of the trial the ruling of the Court &amp; the copy of Finster's testimony are correctly set forth &amp; I believe all the statements in the petition are true.</p>
<p>I was also the attorney who defended Schwab on the trial of the indictment &amp; was astonished at the verdict rendered against him; I do not, <hi rend="underline">on the honor of a gentleman,</hi> believe that he ought to have been found guilty on the indictment, <hi rend="underline">even on the proof Exhibited</hi>, and I feel well assured that if Finster's testimony could have been procured, the Jury would not have found Schwab guilty -- </p>
<p>Your Excellency may attach the more weight to my opinion, when I say that I believe I have had a fair opportunity of forming a correct opinion in cases of this kind, having been from <date when="1855-04">April 1855</date> to <date when="1861-04">April 1861</date>, the attorney for<pb/>
<lb/>the City of Louisville, and in that capacity have been constantly engaged in the Police Court as an Examining Court in prosecuting charges of the foregoing character -- </p>
<p>And I may be permitted further to remark that I believe the Cowlth's Atto M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Craig, who is my law partner, was, for this reason, the more vigorous in the prosecution &amp; was not so indulgent in granting a continuance as in other Cases, for fear he might be regarded as favoring me.</p>
<p>I am but partially acquainted with M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Schwab, but I believe him to be an honest, truthful man -- </p>
<p>I believe he merits the Executive Clemency which he has asked, &amp; hope your Excellency may find it consistent with your views of justice &amp; mercy to pardon him</p>
<p>Very truly Yr obdt servt
<lb/>Robt J. Elliott</p>
<p>The copy of the testimony of Albert Finster before the Examining Court, as set forth in the petition of John Schwab to your Excellency, is a true copy -- </p>
<p>It is also true that M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Elliott asked a postponement of the trial of the indictment on account of absence of s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Finster, who was represented to be a soldier in some one the regiments in Kentucky, but absent from Jefferson County -- which motion was overruled &amp; the trial was gone into.</p>
<p>C S. Craig atto for Comm &amp; <unclear/><pb/></p>
<p>The undersigned were the Jurors in the case of John Schwab referred to in the foregoing statement of M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Elliott -- Since rendering our verdict we have seen the copy of the testimony of Albert Finster, before the Examining Court; and if this testimony had been before us on the trial, our verdict would have been different -- </p>
<p>In view of the foregoing facts, we respectfully join with the petitioner in his prayer to your Excellency &amp; ask that he be <hi rend="underline">pardoned</hi> </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Marshall Halbert
<lb/>Andrew Ferguson
<lb/>Nelson Stelbing
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> W. Morris
<lb/>A D Oldham
<lb/>H. <hi rend="underline">Spalding</hi>
<lb/>S, Waters 
<lb/><cb n="2"/>P W Frederick
<lb/>R D Anderson
<lb/>Edward P Hikes
<lb/>W H Frederick
<lb/>N. Gwyern<!--Gwynn?--></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>The Jury in the case against Schwab, having, as above shown, asked your Excellency to grant Schwab a pardon, I also join with them in said prayer.</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>E S Craig atto for Comwth 7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> <unclear>Dist</unclear><pb/></p>
<p>Jefferson Cir. Ct 
<lb/>John Schwab
<lb/>Felony
<lb/>1 yr. Penty
<lb/>Pardon Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-01-17">Jany 17<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
