<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2122"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Jeff. Rogers et al., Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9198</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-189</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-05-13">13 May 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Jefferson Circuit Court
<lb/>The Comwlth
<lb/>vs } On Indictment for a Misdemeanor
<lb/>Jeff. Rogers &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi></p>
<p>The deft, Jeff Rogers, states that John Warner is a material witness for deft. on the trial of the above case, that he can prove by said Warner, &amp; it is true, that this deft. did not committ the assault charged in the indictment that said Warner was present at the time the party charged to have been assaulted, was assaulted &amp; witnessed the affair, affiant knows of no other witness by whom he can prove the foregoing fact</p>
<p>Affiant states that at the time a day was set for the trial of the above case, he at once had a subpoena issued for said Warner to attend as a witness in his behalf on the trial of this case &amp; immediately caused said subpoena to be placed in the hands of a deputy sheriff of this Court to be served but said subpoena was returned "not found" &amp; when another day was again set for the trial of this case, affiant again had a subpoena renewed accordingly for the afs<hi rend="sup">d</hi> witness &amp; immediately delivered it to a deputy sheriff of this Court to be <hi rend="str">served</hi> Executed. Affiant states that said Warner resides in Louisville Ky, and his place of residence was &amp; is known as he believes, to the officer who had said subpoena, Affiant states that he has used due dilligence to procure the attendance of s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> witness on the trial of this cause &amp; he cannot safely go to trial without having the benefit of his testimony and he believes he can procure his attendance by the next term of this Court He therefore, asks a continuance of this case that he may have a fair trial, &amp; not for the purpose of delay</p>
<p><date when="1862-05-13">May 13. 1862</date>
<lb/>Jefferson Rogers
<lb/>Att Jas P. Chambers cl
<lb/>by Lee Chambers D. C.</p>
<p>Subscribed &amp; sworn to before me <date when="1862-05-13">May 13. 1862</date>
<lb/>A Copy Att James P Chambers c<pb/></p>
<p>Comth
<lb/>vs } Copy of Affidavit
<lb/>Jeff. Rogers &amp;<hi rend="sup">c
<lb/></hi>fee 25 cts paid</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
