<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2586"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">E. J. Bullock to P. D. Yeiser</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7223</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-135 to BR16-136</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>P. D Yeiser Esqr.
<lb/>Sir.</p>
<p>I have at the request of old man Samuel Miles consented to present to Governor Bramlette a petition for the par<hi rend="str">d</hi>don of his son William Miles who <hi rend="str">is</hi> stands indicted in the Ballard Circuit Court for Robbery of M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cutchen, Dalton &amp; Brummall. As you were acting as atty for the Commonwealth when the trial of the real perpetrators <hi rend="str">were tried</hi> ^was had^ and have heard all the evidence on two defferent occasions I determined before I made any application to ask that you would give to me over your own signature a statement of the evidence and your recollection of who was certainly implicated and how far it involved William Miles -- </p>
<p>I am induced to <hi rend="str">press for</hi> petition<pb/>
<lb/>the Governor for a pardon at this time in advance of a trial for several reasons the principal of which however are, 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> that the old man his father has paid for him upwards of a thousand dollars and which has nearly beggared him and unless Bill can come home and assist him on the farm he can never recuperate and that William is willing and anxious to do so and thus by his work repay to his father in a great measure what he has caused him to pay out. The remaining and strong reason is that William Miles comes home out of the Federal army where I learn he has deported himself well as a soldier. The persons who will as a matter of Course be regarded as his prosecutors were some of them actually engaged and others favorable to the success of the Southern army You know sir how<pb/>
<lb/>anxious all of us are and with what solicitude we hope shaped our action to prevent all chances of collision or the happening of any thing that might serve to rip up old sores -- If this man in your opinion is really guilty and should be convicted and is not the victim of his confidence in others who led him even as far astray as he did go then I will not ask you to unite with me in asking Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Bramlette to interpose otherwise I hope you will and that you will write me a reply to this which I may be at liberty to enclose to the Governor for his consideration. What good can come of prosecuting a man who was not present at any of the robberies -- who evidently seperated ^himself^ from those who have been convicted as the robbers when that prosecution might<pb/>
<lb/>serve to revive in all its bitterness the angry passions of the past and throw again into turbulence and passion heated state of a year or two past a whole community now in concord &amp; harmony. Please consider of these things and send me your reply at your earliest convenience</p>
<p>Respt yours
<lb/>E J Bullock</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
