<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0156"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">C. P. Springer to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4275</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-245 to BR8-247</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mercer County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-10-29">29 October 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency the Governor of the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>C P Springer a citizen of Mercer County State of Kentucky would respectfully represent that on the <date when="1863-08-28">28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of August 1863</date> two judgments for $5 &amp; costs each were rendered against him by the Police Judge of Harrodsburg both of s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Judgments were rendered on charges of drunkenness &amp; disorder He states that he is a poor man a painter by trade and has dependent on him for support a wife and five children and an aged father and mother they are entirely dependent on your petitioner. He states that the two acts of offence for which he was adjudged to pay fines as in two cases were infact but one case of continued intoxication He states that since the said offense he has done nothing to lay himself liable to a simalar charge. That the drunkenness and disorder if any was committed in an unguarded moment, that he did not do now threaten any violence to any person or property and believes that the <hi rend="str">most</hi> only injury done at all was done to himself in the regrets &amp; most piculiar caused to his own feelings He states he is not addicted to drinking spiritous liquors as a habit He his wife &amp; children an aged mother and<pb/>
<lb/>^father^ have no means of support except from the proceeds of his daily labor and that the amount of said fines if he shall have to pay same will very much lessen his ability to discharge his so duties to his family. Wherefore he places his case before your excellency and prays that in your clemency you will remit him of said fines.</p>
<p>C. P. Springer</p>
<p>State of Kentucky Mercer County</p>
<p>I J P Haggin do certify that on this <date when="1863-10-29">29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of October 1863</date> C P Springer came before me and made oath that the statements of <gap/> foregoing petition are true to the <gap/> his knowledge &amp; relief &amp; sd Springer in my presence subscribed the said affidavit</p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">J P H
<lb/><date when="1863-10-29">Octo 29<hi rend="sup">th</hi>
<lb/>1863</date></note></p>
<p>Witness my hand this <date when="1863-10-29">Octo 29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date> as Examiner afsd</p>
<p>J P Haggin Examiner</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Harrodsburg unite in the <hi rend="str">foregoin</hi> prayer of the foregoing petition <gap/> J P Haggin</p>
<p>We the undersigned want Mr. Springer relieved of the above fines</p>
<p>A G Kyle
<lb/>C. S. Abell
<lb/>J. W. Cardwell<pb/>
<lb/>R. R. Hunt
<lb/>Thos C Beel
<lb/>Richard Board C.M.C.C.
<lb/>M. V. Bowens J.M.C
<lb/>G. W. Rose
<lb/>B. N. Brewer
<lb/>T W Batton
<lb/>P. M. Hale
<lb/>S S M Fatridge
<lb/>L G Hale
<lb/>Tho H Daviess
<lb/>W. H. Daniel
<lb/>John G. Kyle Police Judge of Harrodburg
<lb/>Thos Edward Presiding Judge of Mercer County Court<pb/></p>
<p>Merc
<lb/>vs
<lb/>C. P. Springer
<lb/><date when="1863-11-30">30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov/ 63</date> refused
<lb/>ans<hi rend="sup">d</hi></p>
<p>Mercer County</p>
<p><figure type="postmark"><listPlace><place><placeName>HARRODSBURG
<lb/><date when="--10-30">OCT
<lb/>30</date>
<lb/>KY</placeName></place></listPlace></figure></p>
<p>Pet for remission of fines-
<lb/>Harrodsburg</p>
<p>Refused
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette</p>
<p>His Excellency
<lb/>The Governor of Kentucky
<lb/>Frankfort</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
