<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3243"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas J. O'Neil et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5362</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-36 to BR42-37</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>The Govenor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioners Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> O'Neal, Lance O'Neal John Merrill and George Harman, respectfully State that various endictments for gaming have been returned against them in the Jefferson Circuit Court, as follows; Some against Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> O'Neal alone, Some against Thos O'Neal &amp; Lance O'Neal, Some against Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> O'Neal &amp; John Merril and Some against George Harman. Some of the endictments charging gaming at "Faro" and others at "Rogue èt Noir" or "Red and Black"</p>
<p>Your petitioners confess to your Excellency that they did indulge in Said games; that it was at the Race Course in Jefferson County, &amp; at Such places they have observed such things to have been hertofore permitted or prosecution not to have been had till now, hence they acted; and it is not for gaming Elsewhere that the Endictments have been returned.</p>
<p>They State to Your Excellency<pb/>
<lb/>that they are advised that the fine upon each Endictment is $500- &amp; that they are wholly unable to pay the Same; whereupon they respectfully &amp; Ernestly pray your Excellency to pardon them for the offences of their gaming, before any judgement Shall be rendered against them in the premesis. For after judgement, they are advised there would be an amount not in the power of the Executive to remit &amp; which your petitioners would be unable to pay. They State that the gaming took place during the Race weeks &amp; to return so many Endictments would be oppressive even if Your petitioners were able to pay, which they again assure your Excellency that they are not &amp; therefore they respectfully pray pardon.</p>
<p>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. J. O'Neal
<lb/>Lance.L. O'Neal
<lb/>George Harmon
<lb/>J J Merrell<pb/>
<lb/>To His Excellency the Governor of Kentucky:</p>
<p>I am personally acquainted with the young men presenting this petition for executive clemency They are charged with violating the law of Gaming and the facts seem to be that it was upon a public Race Course near the City of Louisville:</p>
<p>If I believed that the proceeding was taken against the petitioners to uphold the law in punishing the guilty and detering others from the commission of like offenses and thereby support the law and uphold public morals. I could not sign the petition: but when the prosecution appar to be, for any other purpose and in this case the great number of accusations seem not to be for such purpose: I therifore join in the prayer of the petitn</p>
<p>E S Craig<pb/>
<lb/>We are well acquainted with the Petitioners and hope Your Excellency will grant the prayer of the petition as we can see no good reason for making them an example</p>
<p>They are all poor men and totally unable to pay the fine- They have families &amp; judgments against the petitioners would result in distress to their families.</p>
<p>W. G. Reasor
<lb/>W R Ray
<lb/>J H Harvey
<lb/>Henry Dent
<lb/>D. R. Haygood</p>
<p>O'Neal &amp; others<figure type="hr"/></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
