<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1906"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Enoch Kingston to Jacob T. Foster</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6543</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-17 to BR14-18</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Smithland, Livingston County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-05-05">5 May 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Smithland Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-05-05">May 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865,</date>
<lb/>Lt Col Foster
<lb/>Comdg Post
<lb/>Smithland Ky</p>
<p>I have the honor to beg your indulgence in soliciting your influence in my behalf, I am now in the employ of the Quartermaster at this Post, but formerly served in the federal Army in the 15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Cavalry -- While in said Service, there was an order to take all double barreled Shot Guns in the County &amp; Carry them to military Post's to prevent their falling into the hands of Geuerillas or Rebel soldiers, &amp; in obedience to said order on one occasion, "near the <date when="1863-05-10">10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of May 1863"</date> while in Dycusburg Ky, I seized a Gun, of a suspicious individual, to Carry with me to the above named Post,</p>
<p>A few minutes afterwards a noted Rebel, by the name of William Henson Came &amp; demanded the Gun, of me, I refused politely, had told him to Come to Smithland &amp; probably he might get it, He swore he would have it then &amp; there &amp; Seized the Gun, to force it from me, Calling me at the same time a "damn Negro thief, In the scuffle he hurt me (&amp; while I was acting under orders;) I wrenched the gun from his hands &amp; fired at him, Some of the balls taking effect in the face, and not materially injuring him.<pb/>
<lb/>He was not prevented from labor, in consequence thereof one moment, He afterwards Carried the above named Case to the Circuit Court of his County, which is Crittenden &amp; had me indicted for shooting with intent to Kill, In the meantime I returned to Smithland &amp; turned the gun over to the Commander of the Post, Said Commander ordered me to report under arrest to Brigade Head Quarters at Henderson Ky, Col Foster, 65<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ind Commanding, I did so, under went an examination &amp; was released unconditionally, But now I am to be tried again by the Civil authorities for the same offense</p>
<p>Wherefore I beseech your influence, in getting this paper, presented, through the regular Military channels to his honor Govener Bramlette, of this state, That he <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>may ^i^nterfere by his noted clemency in my behalf, &amp; relieve me of this gross imposition, In substantiation of the above I refer you to the subscribed Certificate I am very Respty</p>
<p>Your obdt Servant
<lb/>Enoch Kingston
<lb/>Late, Private Co C
<lb/>15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Cavalry</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
