<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-023-0042"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Jenkins, C. M. Jenkins, and Simon Jenkins to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG2955</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG1-229 to MG1-230</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bowling Green, Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-03-29">29 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Bowling Green <date when="1861-03-29">29th March 1861</date>
<lb/>His Excellency Beriah McGoffin Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky:</p>
<p>The undersigned are the uncles of Henry Jenkins who was killed by Rufus Jones in the county of Warren Jones has been convicted &amp; sentenced to four years imprisonment in the Penitentiary We and friends of Jenkins prosecuted according to law. We did not persecute or design to persecute or design to persecute Jones -- nor do we now; but we beg leave to suggest to your Excellency, that <hi rend="str">an</hi>a correspondence with the circuit Judge &amp; states att'y would furnish your mind ample means to decide upon the Petition now before you for the reprieve of Jones -- besides the testimony before the examining court was principally in substance put down &amp; if it is desirable you can direct us or either of us to send you a copy -- (this copy would not embrace Wilson's testimony who was indicted as aiding &amp; assisting Jones) we think Jones had a fair trial &amp; the law ought to be executed -- !! <hi rend="str">b</hi> But we are not disposed to enter into a heated remonstrance against Jones' Petitition ^it do more harm than good^ -- You are the Governor<pb/>
<lb/>and we take it for granted you will investigate the case &amp; in the spirit of the laws and constitution do your duty as well in reference to public justice, the commonwealth as to Jones ^&amp; not act till you are fully advised.^ We should thank you very kindly to intimate to Mr Wolfe of Louisville or either of us if you would like to examine the testimony of the enquiring court. We are very respty Yours &amp;</p>
<p>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Jenkins
<lb/>C M Jenkins
<lb/>Simon Jenkins</p>
<p>P. S. We don't intend to persecute Jones or enter into an active remonstrance but cast the responsiblity upon the enlightened, <hi rend="underline">well advised mind</hi> of the Executive. We think Jones guilty!</p>
<p>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Jenkins &amp; <hi rend="underline">Co</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Jenkins in Jones' case, Pen File in the papers -- </p>
<p>B. M</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
