<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1365"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Columbus Tate et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6002</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-119-1</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bourbon County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>County of Bourbon } Sct:
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>Tho. E Bramlett
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Ky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Columbus Tate would respectfully represent that Geo Stoker (a free man of color) was at the <date when="1861-04">April Term 1861</date> Indicted in two instances for selling spirituous Liquors, that on the <date when="1862-04-16">16<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> April 1862,</date> your petitioner became the surety on 2 Recognisance' for the said George appearance at the <date when="1863-04">following April</date> term of the Bourbon Circuit Court, that on the 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> day of <date when="1863-04">said April</date> Term. he in person brought the said George into Court &amp; delivered him up to the sheriff B. f. Pullen, the cases were continued &amp; no further recognisance was required of the said George -- your petitioner after delivering said George to the court thinking that he had fully discharged his obligation upon said bonds went home -- That at the <date when="1864-10">Oct,<hi rend="sup">o</hi> Term 1864</date> of said court Judgment was rendered against him (your petitioner) in said cases for $100. each. Your petitioner Respectfully asks your Excellency to remit said Judgments (or fines) that said George is now<pb/>
<lb/>&amp; has been ever since the Indictments were found against him in Bourbon County.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Columbus Tate</hi></p>
<p>we the undersigned would respectfully state that we are well acquainted with the petitioner Columbus Tate who is an humble good citizen has a large family of children dependent upon his labor for support, has but little means &amp; a hard laboring man, honest quiet &amp; industrious. &amp; that his case is one worthy the interposition of your Excellency, which we respectfully ask on his behalf -- </p>
<p>R J Brown C B Co</p>
<p>The boy "George stoker" was brought into court &amp; delivered up to me as then S B C by the petitioner as he has stated</p>
<p>We the undersigned respectfully ask for for the fine to be remitted,</p>
<p>A, J, Thomson
<lb/><hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> J Pullen late SBC
<lb/>W W Alexander
<lb/>O. V Talbott
<lb/>P <unclear>Hail</unclear>
<lb/>Allen Bashford
<lb/>J. Ed Ray
<lb/>R W Hutchcraft
<lb/>R S Henderson
<lb/>Saml Rule Jailor BC</p>
<p>Bourbon Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Columbus Tate
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1864-12-22">22<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Dec/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
