<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2630"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">S. Netherland to W. G. Brownlow</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7267</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-219 to BR16-220</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Rogersville, Hardin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-11-13">13 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Rogersville
<lb/><date when="1865-11-13">13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov 1865</date>
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>W. G. Brownlow
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>I was on clinch mountain for the last five days and wish to call your attention to a case, that needs your interference as the first officer of the state <unclear>Coln</unclear> W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> J. Pearson a truly loyal man now dead owned in his lifetime a negro named Solomon since he was emancipated he has once robbed the house Then stole a horse from the widow, was pursued, and the horse recovered. After that and about the first of this month, he came again a stole another horse, from the widow was pursued, was found at cumberalnd Gap, but had disposed of the horse so that it would not be found -- </p>
<p>He was seen in the immediate neighborhood of Pearsons the night the horse was stolen and seen on the horse on his way towards the Gap after he stole it -- and the negro was found at the Gap -- John <unclear/> and Patrick Bray, the brother of Mr<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Pearson a man of truth &amp; loyalty who has served in the Federal army went to the officer in command at the Gap to get the negro. he refused to give him up -- because he said two negroes at the Gap said, that he was at ^the^ <hi rend="underline">Gap</hi>, the night the horse was stolen &amp; therefore he was not the theif<pb/>
<lb/>The officer Hartman, was requested to hold the negro in custody until the proof could be brought this he refused to do. But said the negro could only be taken on your demand from the Governor of Kentucky, he was then asked if he would detain the negro, until the demand would be made, he said he would not detain him an hour, the men could do nothing &amp; came home.</p>
<p>I received these facts from both of the men -- &amp; have no doubt of the truth of their statements</p>
<p>Believing as I do that no man who thinks correctly can approve this conduct especially when horse stealing has become such a grievance that the Legislature has made it a capital offense -- I deem it proper to write to you as the Executive of the State. &amp; suggest. that you write to Gen Stoneman. &amp; have an order on Hartman to deliver up the negro -- or take such other Steps as you think best,</p>
<p>Very Respfy
<lb/>Yours -- 
<lb/>S Netherland</p>
<p>P S.
<lb/>I refer you to col W W Willis &amp; C J M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kinney<pb/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">No 151</hi> <hi rend="underline"><unclear/></hi> <date when="1865"><hi rend="underline">1865</hi></date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Rogersville -- </hi><date when="1865-11-17"><hi rend="underline">November 17</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> 1865</hi></date>.
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Netherland. S, Citizen</hi>.</p>
<p>Reports, that a horse, the property of Mr<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. <hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> J. Pearson</hi> was stolen by a negro, with the name of <hi rend="underline">Solomon,</hi> that the alleged thief was traced to Cumberland Gap and that the Officer in charge of the Military at that place, -- <hi rend="underline">Hartman</hi>, refused to give him up.</p>
<p>N. 82 Vol. 2 D K. <date when="1865">1865</date><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Respectfully referred to Maj Gen. Stoneman, who is personally acquainted with Mr Netherland</p>
<p>W G Brownlow.
<lb/>Gov &amp;c</p>
<p>H<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> -- Q<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> -- D -- of T -- 
<lb/><date when="1865-11-25">Nov 25/65</date></p>
<p>Respty. refered to Comd.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">g</hi></hi>. off<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> of Dep<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> of Ky. in whose Com<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> the Post of Cumberland Gap is located -- </p>
<p>George Stoneman
<lb/>Maj G<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> V<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">ls</hi></hi>
<lb/>Comd.g.
<lb/>Recd D. K <date when="1865-11-29">11-29 1865</date></p>
<p>Netherlands Letter</p>
<p>Head Quarters Dept of Ky.
<lb/>Louisville Ky <date when="1865-11-29">Novb<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> 29/65</date>.
<lb/>E and M 217. Vol. 3 <date when="1865"><hi rend="underline">1865</hi></date></p>
<p>Respectfully referred to His Excellency, Governor T E Bramlette</p>
<p>There is now no Military Post at Cumberland Gap and this being a civil case must be decided by the civil authorities</p>
<p>John M Palmer
<lb/>Major General Comd'g
<lb/>N. 82</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
