<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0381"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas J. Cliff to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4500</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-107</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Grant County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-12-09">9 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Gov Thos. E. Bramlett</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Thomas J Cliff of Grant County Kentucky doth hereby respectfully represent unto Your Honor that He has been Indicted for the Offense of Killing a Neighbors horse by Shooting &amp;. &amp;. He States emphatically that He is not guilty of Said Offense and that Said Indictment was procured by Malicious Persons &amp; for Malicious purposes, and that at the time of His trial for Said Offense it was impossible for him to Show His innocence by proof. He <hi rend="str">an</hi> ^had^ an only witness by which He Could have Shown His innocence Conclusively by, the man who was really guilty of the Offense, was His witness &amp; it was impossible to procure him. His Attorney advised him to go to trial &amp; he was fined $88 -- &amp; costs -- he represents that He is wholy unable to pay the fine He is a very poor man &amp; a large Family to Support by His Own labor &amp; if He is forced to pay the Same. His family must suffer. He therefore Petitions Your honor for the remission of Said fine &amp; he will ever pray &amp;. &amp;. His neighbors Jonies herewith in the above Petition &amp; asks the remission of Said fine, &amp; also State that they belive the facts Set out in Said Petition to be true.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>James Ford
<lb/>James W Ford
<lb/>G. T. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Milian
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Thomas J Ciff
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> D. Conley
<lb/>Lewis W. Foree
<lb/>M F Jones<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>John S. Mitchel
<lb/>W. W. Garrett
<lb/>W. H Hendry
<lb/>L. S. Downs
<lb/>L. F Collines
<lb/>Henry Brekley
<lb/>B. H. Calins
<lb/>T. K. Colins
<lb/>Samuel Hutton
<lb/>Polores P Craigs
<lb/>T. B. Lambert
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Ambrose Foree
<lb/>W. P Elliston
<lb/>Joel Foree
<lb/>James D. Elliston
<lb/>Thomas Crawley
<lb/>J. T. Elliston
<lb/>Pendleton Jessup
<lb/>G. M. Comely
<lb/>Henery Learcy
<lb/>J. J. Learcy
<lb/>Bivin. Webster
<lb/>Widow. B. Daneles.<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><note place="left margin">Grant County</note></p>
<p>I Simein Jackson of Grant County State of Kentucky do hereby State that I was present when the horse was Shot for which Thomas Cliff was Indicted &amp; fined in the Grant Circuit Court and I further State that I know He did not Shoot the horse nor neither is He guilty in any manner of Said charge.</p>
<p>Simeon ^his X mark^ Jackson</p>
<p>Attest W W Sipple</p>
<p>State of Kentucky Grant County</p>
<p>The above affidavit was subscribed and Sworn to before me by Simeon Jackson this <date when="1863-12-09">9 day of Dec 1863</date></p>
<p>W. W. Sipple T. P. G. C</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W. W. Sipple
<lb/>J. J. Brown
<lb/>Harrison Webster
<lb/>A M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Milian
<lb/>W N Montgomery
<lb/>N. H. Jeffers clerk Grant cir. ct.
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Spencer Berkley
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. A Franklin Clk Graves County Clerk
<lb/>John Metcalfe C. G. C
<lb/>S. T Berkley
<lb/>J. S. Oldham</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
