<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3003"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">T. P. Cardwell et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5122</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR43-103 to BR43-103A</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>We your humble memoralist would represent to your honor that one Levi C. Kask who has been indicted in the Breathitt Circuit Court, in various cases for the crime of Murder,) has put in circulation a Petitiion for a reprieve from your honor.</p>
<p>Now we would represent to your honor that he and others, (he being in command of a company of Guerillars, and Bandates) did on the <date when="1865-10-18">18" day of October 1865</date> murder John. C. Strong Citizen of Breathitt County Kentucky. by shooting him with Guns, or pistols said John C. strong was at the time a peacible quiet Citizen.</p>
<p>We would further represent that on the <date when="1865-10-18">18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of October 1865</date>. that the said Levi Kask with others did feloneousley. and with mallice -- aforethought kill and murder Washington Noble Samuel Spicer, W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Mays &amp; Benjamon Fugate, by shooting them with Guns &amp; Pistols. The said murdered men were concealing themselves as best they could for protection. And to save their lives.</p>
<p>We further represent that the said Levi ^C.^ Kask at the same time professed to act with the so called Confederacy, but, at the same time was acting and confederated with bands of Guerillas, Murders, and Bandits.</p>
<p>Wherefore we pray that your honor may dismiss said Kask petition and that he may be brought to a fair and impartial trial upon the Indictments Now against him.<pb/>
<lb/>T. P. Cardwell
<lb/>Thos. Marcum
<lb/>G W Daniel
<lb/>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> Cardwell S
<lb/>Alfred Marcum
<lb/>Edward Marcum
<lb/>John Wilson
<lb/>Alfred Little
<lb/>J. H. Hundley
<lb/>Charles J Little
<lb/>Thomas Lewell
<lb/>R. W. Smith</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
