<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0546"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. H. Lusby to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8998</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-368 to R4-369</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lexington, Fayette County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-08-29">29 August 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Lexington <date when="1863-08-29">August 29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>To his Excelency
<lb/>Govornor of Ky</p>
<p>on yesterday there was tryed in the Fayett Circuit Coart one B. F. Barns Charged with Steeling one mule from Mr Georg Brand and Convicted for four years the Jurys verdict Recomending to your Excelencys mercy the Jury Did not now Barns as Well as I Do he is one of fiv that Acted me two make there Escap and Conspierd to kill me to get Away him and one Mayloy Did make there Escape But I succeeded in Recapturing him By him Being taken again for getting money under false Pretenc I think he is a Bad man<pb/>
<lb/>you may hav seen the Dificulty I had With him and the others on the <date when="--07-17">17 of July</date> I under stand he is going to Partition your Excelency I thought I Would Put you on your Gard</p>
<p>Your Humbel Servent
<lb/>W. H. Lusby
<lb/>Jailor of F, C,<pb/></p>
<p>Remonstrance</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
