<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0500"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John C. Baker to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8952</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-295 to R4-296</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-07-27">27 July 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency James. F. Robinson governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner John. C. Baker would State that he was indicted for keeping a tipling house in the Franklin Circuit Court, and at its <date when="1863-06">June term 1863</date> was find $120.00. he states that it is true that your Petitioner had a bbl of Whisky that he had taken in the way of a Debt and did Sell by the gallon half gallon and once or twice by the Quart not to be Drank on his premises or ajacent thereto he States that he is not in the habbit of keeping whisky to Sell that he never had but one bbl on his place and that he got as above Stated he States that he is a very poor man with a large family who are dependent upon his labor for a suport that he has no means to pay said fine and that if it is corced out of him it will take his little farm to pay it and turn him and family out of Doors wherefore he prays your Excellency to remit Said fine.</p>
<p>John. C. Baker.</p>
<p>John C Baker says the statements in the above &amp;c are true</p>
<p>John C Baker</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by John C. Baker this <date when="1863-07-27">27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> July 1863</date>,</p>
<p>Lloyd Hackett J. P. F. C<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned are well acquainted with John. C. Baker and <hi rend="str">now</hi>no that he is a good citizen and believe he is entitled to the Executive Clemency wherefore we Joine with him in the prayer that you remit the fine mentioned in the within</p>
<p>J. W. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cready
<lb/>W. T. Reading
<lb/>H. B. Innes
<lb/>W Franklin
<lb/>A H Remish
<lb/>H P Miller
<lb/>Lloyd Hackett
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J. A. Crittondon</hi>
<lb/>W, H, Gray
<lb/>I,, M, Todd
<lb/>H I Todd
<lb/>R E Collins<pb/></p>
<p>Franklin Cir. Ct
<lb/>$120. } Tipling</p>
<p>The within fine remitted except Twenty dollars &amp; costs</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J F Robinson</hi>
<lb/>Jno. C Baker
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-07-28">July 28. 1863</date>.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
