<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0076"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky vs. John C. Adams, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8528</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-122</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Greenup County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-09-23">23 September 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Greenup County Court
<lb/>Special Term <date when="1862-09-23">September 23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1862</date></p>
<p>The affiant Jno. C Adams. States that Some time this afternoon a rule <hi rend="str">issued</hi> was Served on him <hi rend="str">of</hi> at his residence by the Sheriff and during the time he was at his office preparing a response to the Same the Sheriff Served another one on him both Emanating from this Court and before he had time to respond to the last rule and in a Short time after it was Served on him the Sheriff Executed an attachment on affiant requiring him to give bail in the Sum of One hundred Dollars for his appearance before the County Court at 10 Oclock A M <date when="1862-09-24">September 24<hi rend="sup">th</hi>/<hi rend="sub">62</hi></date> the rules and attachment or order of arrest were all issued from the County Court at a Called term and served on affiant during the afternoon the rules do not inform affiant upon whose motion they were made The affiant States that the Judge of the County Court. Judge John Seaton is his bitter Enemy as he really believes and is as he believes. <hi rend="str">is</hi> wholly incompetent from want of legal Knowledge as well as his prejudice lately manifested against affiant to try these rules and &amp;c against affiant he does not believe he can have a fair trial before him because of his prejudice &amp;C and he therefore prays that this cause upon the various rules and motions attachments and orders of arrest be continued until the regular term of the Greenup County Court at which time he can procure a change of venue by the Circuit Judge of this Judicial District in conformity to law. he does not make this motion for a change<pb/>
<lb/>of venue upon this affidavit for delay or vexation but Simply that he may have a fair and impartial hearing in response to the rules and attachments that have been awarded against him and unless he can procure a continueance for a change of venue he verily believes that great and manifest injustice will be done him</p>
<p>John. C. Adams</p>
<p>Affirmed to before me by John C Adams, <date when="1862-09-24">Sept. 24 1862</date></p>
<p>John S. Jones. Clk Greenup County Court</p>
<p>A copy Attest
<lb/>John S. Jones. C G.C C.</p>
<p>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs. 
<lb/>John. C. Adams<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Affidavit Deft
<lb/>Filed <date when="1862-09-24">Sept. 24 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
