<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0077"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. A. Jackson to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9545</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17A-153 to MG17A-154</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Evansville, Vanderburgh County, Indiana</placeName>
    <date when="1862-12-22">22 December 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Evansville Ind <date when="1862-12-22">Dec 22d 1862</date>
<lb/>Govenor Robison of Ky</p>
<p>Your Honor will please take into consideration the <hi rend="str">of</hi> case of a convict <hi rend="str">of</hi> now in the Frankfort Penitentiary the case I believe is about as follows Thos B Wadlington on the <date when="1850-01-17">17th Jan 1850</date> whilst in a heat of passion <hi rend="str">k</hi> killed his neighbour Milton A Cartwright it appears that there ^was^ some Dispute betwen them previous to that time and that <hi rend="str">w</hi> Wadlington his Son &amp; Negroe man was cutting Rail timber the day that cartright was killed it also appears that cartright that same day the <date when="1850-01-17">17th Jan 1850</date> came to where wadlington Son &amp; Negroe was cutting timbe brought a Pistol and forbid <hi rend="str">cartr</hi> Wadlington from cutting any timber it appears that Wadlington had just cut a tree down and proceeded to cut the tree up whence Cartright drew a pistol shot some two or three times at wadlington in the thigh Wadlington got his gun and shot cartright kiling him instantly it appears from the above that there had been<pb/>
<lb/>some Difficulty about the timber and perhaps some threats on the part of cartright it also is said by some of Wadlingtons friends that there was false testimony given in against Wadlington <hi rend="str">by</hi> But be that as it may I am not able to say as I neve saw Either of the parties or their witnesses but I have since bcome acquainted with Mrs Wadlington and her litle children and to see the distressed wife or widow and three litle children left fatherless the oldest a Boy now about ten years old and whilst his Mother ^was^ talking about his father his confinement in prison I could see the little Boy hang his head and the tear start from his Eyes I could not help but sympathise with the little Boy for I have some little Boys of my own and I thought should my little Boys be situated as that Boy what wold be the feelings between <hi rend="str">m</hi> Me and them My simpathys were aroused for the Desolate Widow and her little children and I Determined to <hi rend="str">a</hi> Appeal to you for the release of the father &amp; Husband I would say to you that it would be a great satisfaction to her relations to hear of his release as for him or his relations I never saw but I am well acquainted with the widows<pb/>
<lb/>Relations and I assure you if you need any <hi rend="str">s</hi> assurance that they and the w<hi rend="str">o</hi>idow of the said Wadlington are and ever have been true and Loyal to the Goverment of the United States of America and that some of them have suffrd as much persecution as any other people in their capacity during the war I will say to you that the murdering and trial took place in Colwell <hi rend="str">K</hi> county Ky if you can with law &amp; concience release the said Thos B Wadlington you will eve be rememberd with hearts of gratitude by the Wife and children of the said wadlington and all who simpathise with widows and &amp; Orphan Children</p>
<p>if you want any proof of wat I have stade in this address some good loyal man or Men at Maddisonville Ky or <hi rend="str">a</hi> subscriber at Ashbysburgh Ky if you see no cause why you should not release the convict aforesaid you will please address to me at Ashbysburgh Ky and reason <hi rend="str">for</hi> why you cannot</p>
<p>Your Honor will please Excuse so feeble an attempt but as I have <hi rend="str">f</hi> done the best I can you will Excuse a loyal citizen</p>
<p>Yours truly 
<lb/>J A Jackson<pb/></p>
<p>Civil
<lb/>J. A. Jackson <unclear/> for pardon of Wadlington</p>
<p>No certificate of Evidence before <unclear/></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
