<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2011"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Reuben T. Durrett to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9087</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-7 to MG24-8</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-06-15">15 June 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville, Ky
<lb/><date when="1862-06-15">June 15, 1862</date>
<lb/>Gov. Magoffin:</p>
<p>As suggested by you I have obtained the rest of signatures of the Jurymen who tried Hauserman; and your pardon of him will therefore be <unclear/> by the Jury which that convicted him. I have not seen the Commonwealth's attorney &amp; cannot see him as he is out of the county and will be gone for a long time so far as I can <unclear/> I do not think, however that you will require other support in a <unclear/> Mercifully that of the Jury.<pb/></p>
<p>I trust, my Dear Govenor that you will send Houserman home at an early day. Rest assured that you will do right -- this pardon It is but political, for aught that I know Hauserman may be the vilest abolitionist in the land. I know nothing of his political cause and don't care. I think him wrongly in prison &amp; I want him out for the cause of right and for nothing else.</p>
<p>I am sorey not to have again seen you while you were here. A sick child however kept him at home. I hope to see you again soon.<pb/></p>
<p>Dear <unclear/>, My Dear Govenor in appoint me a Notary Public. I name my Commission by Tuesday Morning next if it can possibly be had, as some <unclear/> has been put off for me to do that day.</p>
<p>Yours truly
<lb/>R. T. Durrett</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
