<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0770"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Mary S. Robertson to Landaff W. Andrews</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10238</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-199</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Morehead, Rowan County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-03-20">20 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Moorehead Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-03-20">20" March 1861</date>
<lb/>Mr L. W Andrews</p>
<p>Dr Sir while I Lived near Covington There was an Irish girle named Bridget or otherwise Biddy M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Mahan Lived with me some six months &amp; since I left there she has been sent to the state prison charged with stealing a bolt of Calico she while with me conducted herself well She had but one fault she would on some, holiday days according to Irish custom become intoxicated &amp; I Learn the facts in her case to be that she was in the City of Covington on such accasion at M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Browns her former home &amp; she became intoxicated &amp; was <unclear/> on the street in day light &amp; went to a pile of Dry goods on the side walk &amp; picked up a bolt of calico &amp; carried it off home for this she was indicted tried &amp; convicted as I am informed for two years I can not believe she took it with any intent of stoling it she had various oportunities to steal from me but never took to the <unclear/> of one cent she Lived in the family of R Patton in Covington who can certify to her good character poor unfortunate girl I pity her when She was tried M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Patton was not at home &amp; she did not have any <unclear/> or one soul to attend to her defence or she would not have been convicted as I believe she did not try to conceal the goods I got my information though Mr Patton as to the facts of the case I want you as my friend &amp; as a friend to humanity &amp; a poor unfortunate Irish girl to see the Governor &amp; get him to pardon her she has been in prison now over one year. I very much need a Servant girl &amp; notwithstanding her misfortune would rather have her Thean anyone I could get to attend to my domestick affairs See Biddy for me &amp; if she is Released tell her to come to me &amp; I will take her in She can come by the<pb/>
<lb/>way of mount sterling where she has some relations living &amp; from there you can instruct her how to come to my house It is very unusual for me to petition for any person convicted of crime indeed this is the first time in my life now would I do it now only that I have a personal knowledge of the unfortunate individual for whose benefit I write this you can show this to the Governor &amp; the same is designed as a petition to him for his clemency in Biddys behalf &amp; you can tell him who the humble write is any thing that can be done for the poor infortunate girl will be remembered by your friend &amp; treasured up in heaven</p>
<p>yrs Truly
<lb/>Mary.S. Robertson</p>
<p>L W Andrews</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
