<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1281"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Nathan Preston to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10749</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-163 to MG21-164</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excelency the Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky,</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Nathan Preston would respectfully represent that at the fall term of the Johnson Circuit Court he was indicted <hi rend="str">f</hi> in two seperate cases for keeping a tipling house &amp; for selling whiskey as a merchant without a license therefore, and at the Presant <date when="1861-05">may term 1861,</date> was found guilty on each indictment &amp; fined the sum of $120, he says the facts &amp; circumstances are these, in <date when="1859">1859,</date> he obtained a license from the county Judge to keep a tavern &amp; sell whiskey by the smalls, he was a merchant at the time &amp; had his bar-room near the store house, he continued to sell under his license untill sometime in <date when="1860">1860,</date> when it was reported that the legislature of ky. had passed an act extending the corporate limits of the the town of Paintsville, &amp; to allow the citizens included in the lines to vote, whether the county Judge should grant license for the sale or not, it was not difinetely known whether the act had passed or not as we had not received a copy, but the county Judge in anticipation of the passage went on &amp; suspended the license of this Petitioner long before the vote was taken &amp; before it was definitely known whether the act had passed or not, this petitioner not beleiving that the legislature had the consitutional Power to pass an act<pb/>
<lb/>that would Prohibit him from selling under his license untill they had expired, &amp; that the county Judge superseeded his authority by suppressing his license in anticipation of such an act &amp; was realy advised by Lawyers, that he would be perfectly safe in selling under his license untill they expired, he went on &amp; sold untill the vote was taken under said act, for which selling he was indicted for keeping a tipling house &amp; fined as above stated,</p>
<p>he further charges that after his license had Expired he went on &amp; sold whisky by the hal<hi rend="str">f</hi>f gallon not to be drank on the Premises or adjacent Premises, &amp; it was not so drunk, but that he was a merchant at the time &amp; did not Procure a license for the same, as he was entirely ignorant of the fact that the act made any difference between a merchant and other indiviuals, &amp; was informed by lawyers that he had the Perfect right to sell by the half gallon without a license so to do, &amp; went on &amp; sold out what was in his bar-room when his license was suppressed as a tavern keeper, for which he was fined as above stated for selling whisky as a merchant without a license so to do,</p>
<p>he says that he was cautious in the matter least he might violate the law and never for the first time supposed that the law did not guarantee him<pb/>
<lb/>in all that he had done, he positively avers that everything he done in the sale of the whisky was in ignorance of his real duty under the law &amp; in strict obedience as he thought of the law itself,</p>
<p>Wherefore he humbly asks your Excelency to take cognizance of his case &amp; remit all the Principle of said fines as he thinks the Payment of the costs will be a sufficient punishment for his ignorance</p>
<p>Nathan Preston</p>
<p>We the undersigned subscribers Joine in the Prayer of the Petitioner and ask that he be relieved from the Payment of the fines Except Costs, &amp;c,</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>John F. W. Sadler
<lb/>James Franklin
<lb/>J M Elliott
<lb/>Ralph Staffard
<lb/>Francis M Stafford
<lb/>T S Williams
<lb/>D. M. Hagar
<lb/>C. Comely
<lb/>H E Conley
<lb/>D W Taylor
<lb/>J W Ferguson
<lb/>Daniel Hager
<lb/>Harrison Obryon
<lb/>Jas A Ward
<lb/>Jas Stafford
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Daniel Blevins
<lb/>Wm W Conley
<lb/>E. P. Vanhoose
<lb/>Jno B Vanhoose
<lb/>John B. Williams
<lb/>John W Walker
<lb/>Winston M Conley
<lb/>James H Conley
<lb/>Andrew <unclear/>
<lb/>Rob<hi rend="sup">t</hi> J Stambaugh
<lb/>Wm L Croft
<lb/>Wm P Simer
<lb/>J. W. Howe
<lb/>Ervin Spradlin
<lb/>James A Porter
<lb/>Henry L Porter
<lb/>Crocket Murphy<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Noah Reynolds
<lb/>George G. Webb
<lb/>Wimfrey H. Walter
<lb/>Harrison literal
<lb/>J E. Burgess
<lb/>A F Dickson
<lb/>J M Porter
<lb/>Jesse Price
<lb/>Robt winn
<lb/>John Price
<lb/>Jackson ward
<lb/>V. Vanhoose
<lb/>R N Akers
<lb/>John B Aunier <unclear>its hard times</unclear>
<lb/>Robt. Alley
<lb/>Wm Castle
<lb/>Irael Castle
<lb/>John O Daniel
<lb/>Jas M Welch
<lb/>B L. Davis
<lb/>Isaac Rice
<lb/>John J Hagty
<lb/>Samuel K Rice
<lb/>Charles T fitch
<lb/>marten Rice
<lb/>Frederick Grimm
<lb/>Jno R Rice
<lb/>William N Randolph
<lb/>Noble Hair
<lb/>Anrold F Coleman
<lb/>Frank Preston
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Samuel Mury
<lb/>Jesse price
<lb/>H. R Dale
<lb/>Martin Preston
<lb/>Samuel. B. Hanna
<lb/>D. G. Denison
<lb/>Martin R Rue
<lb/>A. Preston
<lb/>Samuel J Rice
<lb/>Gor Brown
<lb/>Southrell Fayor
<lb/>J S, Mahan
<lb/>G. M. Dixon
<lb/>B. F. Price
<lb/>W Hundhan
<lb/>C Howes
<lb/>A. P. Hot
<lb/>J. N. Stambough
<lb/>H S Vaughan
<lb/>James Roberts
<lb/>D B Wells
<lb/>H S Vaughan
<lb/>Wm H C Childress
<lb/>S. P. Hagan<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p><note place="right margin">(<hi rend="underline">Nath</hi> <hi rend="underline">Preston</hi>)</note></p>
<p>Johnson Cir. Ct
<lb/>$120
<lb/>2 Judg of $60 each } Tipling
<lb/>N. Preston</p>
<p>Resp 12 Mo</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-07-18">July 18 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
