<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0703"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George Dixon to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10171</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-97 to MG19-98</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Memphis, Shelby County, Tennessee</placeName>
    <date when="1861-02-07">7 February 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Memphis Tenn; <date when="1861-02-07">Feby 7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>.
<lb/>To his Excellency Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> of Kentucky.
<lb/>Dear Sir-</p>
<p>I take the liberty of writing to you in behalf of J. H. Powell who has recently been sent to the penetentiary from M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracken Co. Ky for Stealing a carpet Bag and money in it the circumstances of the case I only learn through Mrs. Powell his wife and from whom and other sources you will no doubt get a correct Statement of the case; I have only to state that I have, J. H. Powell in this City as an honest, industrious mechanic who has worked industriously here for the support of his family, and that he is regarded by his acquaintances here, as an honest man, and I have no doubt from my knowledge of him and his general reputation, that there is some<pb/>
<lb/>mistake in the matter, and that an innocent man is condemned to confinement and disgrace. I make this statement, that he may have the benefit of it for whatever it may be worth, in deciding upon the application that may be made for his release-</p>
<p>Your Ob<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Sv<hi rend="sup">t</hi>,
<lb/>Geo. Dixon<pb/>
<lb/>To his Excellency. Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> B. Magoffin
<lb/>Frankfort
<lb/>Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
