<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0013"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. G. Gilbert et al. to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4132</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt><respStmt>
<resp n="reviewed">Fact checked by</resp>
<name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
</respStmt>
<respStmt>
<resp n="needs_review">Annotated by</resp>
<name>Jesse Nasta</name>
</respStmt>

   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-18 to BR8-20</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The undersigned citizens of <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000910">Marshall County Ky.</placeName> who are conversant with the facts in regard to the trial evidence &amp; conviction of <persName ref="cwgk:N00007932">Jas H. Marshall</persName> and the standing credibility of the witnesses, State that the evidence on trial consisted of the Statements alone of the prosecutor and of a boy fourteen years old ^&amp; <persName ref="cwgk:N00005032">Dr. Holland</persName>^. The prosecutor states that he lost ^on public road between <placeName ref="cwgk:P00007966">Briensburg</placeName> &amp; <placeName ref="cwgk:P00007967">Palma</placeName>^ a carpet sack containing coffee glass tumblers cottonade &amp; a pair of pants off of a wagon; that he lost said articles within <hi rend="sup">1</hi>/<hi rend="sub">2</hi> mile of Briensburg that distance to <placeName ref="cwgk:P00007967">Palma</placeName> is 6 miles: that he went on to <placeName ref="cwgk:P00007966">Briensburg</placeName> without delay, and discovering that Said articles were missing he immediately started back on road to Palma on horseback to hunt for said articles; that said Marshall &amp; boy 14 years viz witness <persName ref="cwgk:N00007931">Louis A. Page</persName> were the only persons that he met going the Palma road except a soldier who passed on a head of Said Marshall &amp; boy; that said Marshall was driving an ox team, and that he prosecutor road at a fast gate but ^never^ over took Marshall until he reached <placeName ref="cwgk:P00007967">Palma</placeName>, a distance of 5 <hi rend="sup">1</hi>/<hi rend="sub">2</hi> or 6 miles from where he met him: that <hi rend="str">The evidence of Said boy</hi> when he overtook Marshall he proecutor<pb/></p>
<p>asked Marshall if he had not found a carpet ^Sack^ &amp; other articles named and that Marshall said no; that prosecutor then drew &amp; cocked a pistol on Marshall &amp; told ^him^ he intended to search wagon &amp; would have Said articles, and that Marshall Said he had found some tumblers &amp; cottonade but no coffee ^pantaloons^ or carpet sacks</p>
<p>The boys evidence was that he was with Marshall driving the oxen &amp; that he first discovered some goods in road, cottonade &amp; tumblers; that he called to Marshall &amp; pointed him to same; that there was no carpet Sack coffee or other article except what was given up to prosecutor that a man ^on horseback^ in Soldiers uniform passed on same road before him &amp; Marshall about the time or a little before meeting prosecutor; that prosecutor did ask Marshall at Palma if he had found a Carpet Sack; and that Marshall said he had not found a carpet Sack but that he had found some goods in the road, in a bundle, and asked if they were prosecutors, &amp; prosecutor said they were. Marshall delivered the cottonade &amp; tumblers to prosecutor, who<pb/></p>
<p>said there was some coffee &amp; a carpet Sack &amp;c lost also by him; that Marshall &amp; witness boy went on to <placeName ref="cwgk:P00001227">Paducah</placeName> with <hi rend="str">a</hi> ^the^ load of marketing they had at the time of finding said articles; that prosecutor never drew, cocked or showed a pistol as stated by prosecutor; and that at feed time at <placeName ref="cwgk:P00001227">Paducah</placeName>, Marshall in getting out feed for his oxen found one glass tumbler &amp; a piece of cotton goods that had got separated from the bundle found &amp; had worked down under the feed &amp; was not noticed or known at time of delivering the other articles to prosecutor; Marshall as soon as he discovered same, said there was some more of the goods of prosecutor &amp; that he did not know it before, &amp; would deliver on his return home; that when they returned home Marshall Said to his wife that Said articles belonged to prosecutor, &amp; directed her to deliver ^or send^ them to prosecutor if she had a chance; that prosecutor went to Marshalls, and Marshalls wife he being absent, Said <hi rend="str">to prose-cutor</hi> before being interrogated that there was some things there belonging to him &amp; which Mr. Marshall did not see at time the other goods were<pb/></p>
<p>delivered to prosecutor, and that Mr. Marshall had directed her to give or send them to prosecutor first opportunity. Dr. Holland stated that he went with prosecutor to Marshalls &amp; that <persName ref="cwgk:N00007933">Mrs Marshall</persName> <hi rend="str">informed</hi> made the statements as above set forth and that the boy told the same tale or in other words made the same statement then as on the trial &amp; with as little difference or variation as any man ever did. We believing Marshall ^to be^ innocent &amp; that he was convicted because of the statements of a greatly prejudicial witness would ask &amp; pray your Excellency to immediately pardon him, as in justice you should do</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="3"/><cb n="1"/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007934">J. F. West</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007935">W. W. Malcone</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007936">Moses E Stone
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007938">W J Clark
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00005059">R F Gregory</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007939">Samuel Cox
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007940">James Baker
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00005046">J M Cox
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007941">A T Sims
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007942">H Washburn</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007943">E. Tatum
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007944">T. Futched
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006443">Wm Hamilton
</persName><lb/><cb n="2"/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007945">A S Brown
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007946">L. H. Sasseen</persName><lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Dason
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007948">J W Brown</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007949">L. C. Hamilton
</persName><lb/><unclear>Daneil RF</unclear>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007951">W M Mester</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007952">W. C. Fields
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007953">B F Hamilton
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007954">G Fields
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007955">W. H. Bolenroy
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007956">James J. Lindsey Jr
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007957">L. M. Fields
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006492">Jno T Stone
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007958">W H Johnson
</persName><lb/><cb n="3"/><persName ref="cwgk:N00005121">J. C. Gilbert
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00005032">B. Holland
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00005040">Cabb Lindsey
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007959">W. F. Culp
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007960">James quarles
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007961">L. F. Mecoy
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007962">James Linsey segr
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00006442">A H Lindsey
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00005042">M Lindsey</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00005106">Thomas Fields
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007963">A B Linsey</persName><lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Washburn
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00005107">J Downing
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007964">B Downing
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00007965">W Strow</persName><milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>Henry Hanson
<lb/>L. R. Finley
<lb/>John Baker
<lb/>J. W. Phillips
<lb/>Daniel Washburn
<lb/>G. W. Slaughter
<lb/>A T Cox
<lb/>Bryant Downing
<lb/>T. W. Holland
<lb/>W. W. Baker
<lb/>V L Holland
<lb/>H M Holland
<lb/>H H Downing<pb/></p>
<p>Statement of evidence and Pet for pardon of Jas H Marshall of County
<lb/>Rc<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-09-01">Sept 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/><orgName ref="cwgk:O00000428">Marshall C't C't
</orgName><lb/>vs
<lb/>J. H. Marshall</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
