<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1208"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Joseph A. Keen to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10676</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-47</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-07-20">20 July 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><date when="1861-07-23">July//20//61</date></p>
<p>To His Excellency Beriah Magofin Governor of the Commonowelth of Kentucky, Dear Governor Sir I sit Down to Write to you with the Greatest Reluctance on my Part of intruding on your Honor at this time But Dear Governor Do no censur me after Writing to you at this time For i feel that it is my Duty When Called by a Widowed Lady in good Standing in this Place But she is very Poor and in feeble Health at this time and not able to Do much work to surport herself &amp; Children</p>
<p>And Dear Governor this Poor Mother is in great Distress at this time she has a son in the Penitentiary of the Commonwealth by the name of D. M. Clark only 16 years of age But a Great help to his Afflicted Mother in these hard times to help her to Raise her Fartherless Children this young was sent up Last January to Frankfort for the term of five years and his Mother has been able to come up to see you her health is very Poor at this time on account of his Troubles concerning her son she is afraid if he Does not come home soon she never see him again in this unfriendly World of ours. O Dear Governor if you can Pardon this young Man Without Going out<pb/>
<lb/>of the Line of your Duty you will Confer a great Blessing on a Poor Aged Mother and Many good and well tried Friends of your in this Place and if you cannot be Rewarded in this unfriendly World of ours We Pray that our Divine Master will Reward you in Hevin where we shall all Meet if faithful to the grace alredy give us and Join those that gone before us Where we shall Meet at Jesus feet To Meet to Part no More is the Daily Prayer of your unworthy Constiuent</p>
<p>Joseph a Keen</p>
<p>Governor be Merciful to the Widow and the Fartherless and you will Meet Your Reward at Gods Right hand</p>
<p>J a K<hi rend="str">y</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
