<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-003-0087"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Rodrick Hamilton and Thomas Rigdon to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1604</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR5-144</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Washington County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-05-15">15 May 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Washington County Ky <date when="1866-05-15">May 15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1866</date></p>
<p>To his Excellency the Governor ^of Ky^</p>
<p>Dear Sir we received yours of the 3rd inst instructing what to do we Sent to Springfield and got a copy of the Indictment it was not the indictment we Supposed tho it was all done the Same time we was on our way to our commands and there ^was^ two Soldiers on foot and we went to John Rogers and asked him to loan us the horse which he refused then I pressed the horse and took the Soldiers to Lebanon and Sent him the horse Back the next day by my Brother who went to take Back the rest of the horses indeed the horse was not his legally for his Son took the horse from a widow of Anderson County and paid her nothing and gave the horse to his mother Mrs Rogers all Rogrses grown Son was in the rebel Service and took horses in this Neighborh^ood^ and keep them at their fathers John Rogerses we can Send you a Volume of Testimony, that I was captured on the <date when="1863-10-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of october 1863</date> out of the Eleventh Ky Cav,, and Rodrick Hamilton was then with his Reg,, in the South Dear Sir I was in the fight at Chickamauga with the fourth Ky inft., on the <date when="1863-09-19">19</date> and <date when="1863-09-20">20th of Sept. <hi rend="str">and</hi>/63</date> allso in the missionary Ridge fight on the <date when="1863-11-25">25 day of Novm,,/63</date> and had not Been at home since sixty two it was in Sixty two as we went to or commands that mason goatly told us of those pistols and threat the Said Rogers ^horse^ was in company at that time But as he got the horse the next day that ^we thought^ nothing was done in that case as allso the men got their pistols allso Brother Micajah Ridgon was with me in the Battle when I was captures went withe me to the regiment in <date when="1862">/62</date>, and had not Been in Kentucky till <date when="1864">/64</date> Sir to Show Mr John Rogers has Sworn falsly I send you a certificat from a highly Respectable<pb/>
<lb/>Gentleman as much so any man in Kentucky that I advised Tho,s Rigdon to let the horse alone But he told John Rogers he would take, the horse and send him Back as soon as he got to Lebanon which he did and here the Indictment Shows the Testimony to Be Maliciously false let me Show you what the grand Jury did, their was was man well a rebel who Stole a watch from a Union man the Jury pass By the indictment and Said it was a wild Irish Trick and of cours found him not guilty of any crime tho it was proved By good Testamony, But no Union soldier Escaped a True Bill no difference how Trivial the crime if you wish any Testamony as to our Being at our Reg,, at the time specified in the indictment that we took the hors we can send you any amount of it Except Thos, Ridgon who was prisoner from the <date when="1863-10-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of Oct. 63</date></p>
<p>Please Drop us a few lines if your clemency sees, fit to believe us as a Safe guard that if the officer Should distress us we can have your Voucher with which to defend our Selves Diret to Antioch washington <hi rend="str">Ky</hi> County Ky and we Shall Ever feel gratfull</p>
<p>Yours Obtly
<lb/>Rodrick Hamilton
<lb/>Thomas Rigdon</p>
<p>B E D Askin was ^not^ their at the time and was one of the Bigest Rebel in this county and Brother in law to John Rogers and was a commissioned Doct,, in Braxton Braggs army</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
