<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0924"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John M. Sheppard et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5043</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-421 to BR10-422</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-06-25">25 June 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To Govenor Bramlete</p>
<p>The undersigned your Petitioner states that at the last term of the Fayette Circuit Court he was fined the sum of $1000- in all for the following cases, for giving spirituous liquors to slaves $50- in 13 several cases, and $300 for disorderly house &amp; $50- for suffering unlawful assembly of slaves on his premises. He states that he <hi rend="underline">never sold or give liquor</hi> to slaves as charged unlawfully; yet the <hi rend="underline">appearances</hi> were against him. The disorderly house case &amp; suffering unlawful assembly of slaves on his premises were made out by the <hi rend="underline">same state of facts</hi>. He has his house &amp; grocery store first on the corner of <hi rend="underline">short street</hi> &amp; <hi rend="underline">Georgetown road</hi>, in Lexington &amp; the negroes from <hi rend="underline">two factorys</hi>, beyond him, passed into town by<pb/>
<lb/>the two roads meiting at his corner &amp; there they met &amp; parted on their return &amp; congregated on his pavement &amp; in the present state of that population &amp; for six months past, he could not drive them off &amp; this was the assembling that was construed to make a<hi rend="str">n</hi> disorderly house &amp; an unlawful assembly of slaves &amp; <hi rend="underline">none other</hi>. There was no evidence of <hi rend="underline">any disorder</hi> in the house &amp; now except the congregation of negroes &amp; their loud talking &amp; laughing on the corner pavements as stated. He says that he keeps a retail grocery store of as good character as <hi rend="underline">any in the city &amp;</hi> &amp; keeps a general &amp; good assortment of groceries of nearly all kinds &amp; has as good &amp; genteel a custom as any establishment in the city. He is<pb/>
<lb/>and has been striving to make by his business an honest support for his growing young family &amp; has to depend greatly upon his <hi rend="underline">credit</hi> &amp; <hi rend="underline">good name</hi> &amp; <hi rend="underline">prompt business character</hi>. He appeals confidently to his customers &amp; neighbors generaly. The indictments were produced by the unfounded prejudicial ^and malice^ of <hi rend="underline">one man</hi> against him. He asks for a remission of the fine as its payment will greatly embarass him ^&amp; is unjust^ He knows his case is a good one.</p>
<p>John M Sheppard</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by John Sheppard this <date when="1864-06-25">25 June 1864</date>.</p>
<p>Q. Gibbons
<lb/>Notary Public</p>
<p>We the neighbors of John Shepherd state that he keeps an orderly grocery store &amp; has on hands a good &amp; general assortment of such articles ^as^ are usual in that business &amp; he is industrious attentive &amp; sober &amp; has a good custom. We cheerfully recommend his case to the Governor &amp; believe his statements to be <hi rend="underline">true</hi>.</p>
<p>A T Parker
<lb/>W S M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Chesney
<lb/>Samuel M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Meekin<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>I unite in his application
<lb/>John B Payne Jr
<lb/>W F White
<lb/>Bird Taylor
<lb/>Abram Smith
<lb/>J. Dudley
<lb/>Henry Robertson
<lb/>M. C. Fowler
<lb/>H D Hulett
<lb/>Thos Shomate
<lb/>C. Shryock
<lb/>David M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Murtry
<lb/>J. T. Mayfield
<lb/>James M Bunsen
<lb/>T. Mitchell
<lb/>E D Layne
<lb/>Jno. B. Wilgers
<lb/>Robt. B. Daugherty
<lb/>J M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Michael
<lb/>R M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Michael
<lb/>Wm Robertson
<lb/>John Robertson
<lb/><cb n="2"/>We the undersigned citizens of Lexington recommend the case of Mr. Shepherd.
<lb/>Z. Gibbons
<lb/><hi rend="underline">M. Stuttots</hi>
<lb/>Geo. Lancaster
<lb/>Jno. H. Carr
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Tho. M. Bell</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J. W. Bright</hi>
<lb/>J. Harkins
<lb/>P. Harkins
<lb/>E. S. D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">e</hi></hi>Long</p>
<p>I know John Shepherd and deal with him. I was not counsel for him. I believe his <hi rend="underline">statements to be true</hi>. Those who know him best speak well of him &amp; he is <hi rend="underline">a worthy man</hi> &amp; I <hi rend="underline">earnestly</hi> recommend his case to your favor. I believe it is one deserving a <hi rend="underline">remission</hi>.</p>
<p>Yours &amp; c
<lb/>Jn B Huston</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
