<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0568"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">M. J. Cook to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4687</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-402 to BR9-403</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mount Vernon, Rockcastle County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-03-14">14 March 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Mt. Vernon Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-03-14">March the 14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>.
<lb/>Gov. T E. Bramlette</p>
<p>Dear Sir I learn that a petition has been sent to you to remit a fine against one Liberty Langford of this (Rockcastle) County.</p>
<p>To which I do most respectfully remonstrate, for the following reasons,</p>
<p>He was fined ($160) dollars for obstructing a county Road by putting a fence across it in one place and gates in other places without the proper orders to do so, it was proved before the Jury that he was told when building the fence that he would be fined that he was violating law and putting the neighborhood through which the road run to great inconveneince and leaving the road almost impassible, the grand Jury presented Langford for the obstructions, and for which he was fined from <date when="1862-08">August</date> to the <date when="1863-02">Feb Court 1863</date>. The grand Jury presented him again from <date when="1863-02">Feb<pb/>
<lb/>63</date>. to <date when="1863-08">August court 1863</date>. Langford was also presented for obstructing a county ^Road^ that led to Griffins Mill at the same time and in the same number of cases, which made four presentments for obstructing county roads, the indictments or presentments that was got against him from <date when="1862-02">Feb</date> to <date when="1863-08">August</date> was throwed out of court on some technicality; he had a fair an impartial trial before a Jury of his county, with three or four able counsel to defend him and he was fined because he was guilty knowingly and wilfully: <hi rend="str">guilty</hi> the commonwealths Atty. after being teased a great deal agreed to dismiss the second indictment if he would pay off the one found against him, under the promise that he would remove the obstructions &amp; c, Langford agreed: but since I learn that he is petitioning your Excellency to remit his fine, to which I seriously object to make him pay this fine would be of incalculable benefit to the community, from the fact that Langford is called a wealthy man for the county, and it would deter him as well<pb/>
<lb/>others from committing similar offences, with the view of getting the fine remitted if fined; his lawyers got up the petition and I dont suppose a signer ^on it^ lives in the neighborhood of the road so obstructed, it is an easy matter to get up signers at a court where people are not interested and know not the parties. This road is in my immediate neighborhood and I have heard the case in full, and for the forgoing reasons do most Respectfully remonstate against the remission of the fine.</p>
<p>M. J. Cook</p>
<p>The above is true
<lb/>W W Fish C. R. C. C
<lb/>Edwin Shivel C S C R C<pb/></p>
<p>Rockcastle Co
<lb/>Refused
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/><date when="1864">64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
