<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0195"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Pritchett, Sr. et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4314</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-305 to BR8-306</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thos E. Bramlette Esqr
<lb/>Gov. of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>Your petitioners represent that they are well acquainted with Mrs Mariah Dixon of Henderson County who is about sixty five years old, a widow, in very limited circumstances, and an illiterate woman. That she was recognized to appear in the Henderson Circuit Court at its <date when="1862-12">December Term 1862</date> to <hi rend="str">appear</hi> testify in a prosecution against one Overfield. They believe her failure to attend in obedience to the recognizance was owing to her feble health and the inclemency of the weather. At the <date when="1863-06">June term 1863</date>, judgment was rendered against her for $100, on forfeiture of the recognizance taken at the term preceding And they believe that the reason she made no defense was because she was not aware that it was necessary They respectfully ask your Excellency to remit the judgement rendered against her<pb/></p>
<p>John Pritchett Sr
<lb/>B. F. Wood
<lb/>Dluey Pritchett
<lb/>Jacob Matson
<lb/>Robert Brown
<lb/>Hiram Whitledge
<lb/>G. W. Boone
<lb/>Joseph Purnell
<lb/>W W Minton
<lb/>L. W. Powell
<lb/>L. H. Powell
<lb/>William C Gibson
<lb/>William T handley
<lb/>manuel oufet
<lb/>Charles Dixon
<lb/>Nathan Harris
<lb/>John Cook</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
