<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2028"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William A. Baxter to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9104</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-33 to MG24-34</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1862-06-20">20 June 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah Magofin Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky Your Petitioner William Baxter would most respectfully state to your Excellency that he with four others was indicted at the <date when="1861-05">May term 1861</date> of the Marion Circuit Court for the alledged misdemeanor of Shooting one Miss Sutherland in sudden heat and passion and at the same term he with four others was indicted for the alledged misdemeanor of cutting one Harison Thornton in sudden heat and passion and to the same Court was sued at Common law by both Miss Sutherland and H P Thornton and at the <date when="1862-05">May term 1862</date> of the Marion Circuit Court Your Petitioner was fined $500 for the alledged charge of Shooting Miss Sutherland and at the same term of Said Court your Petitioner acknowledged a judgment in the case of Commth agt him &amp; others under charge of cutting H. P Thornton in the sum of $100 -- </p>
<p>Now Your Petitioner would most respectfully state that himself and four others were present at the time the alledged shooting and cutting took place and were all jointly indicted and Your Petitioner as well as the others claimed a seperate trial and the Commonwealths attorney elected to try Your Petitioner first and under the rulings of the Court Your Petitioner was <unclear/> of the evidence of his codefendants in the Indictment because they were not acquitted<pb/>
<lb/>altho <unclear/> of being put on trial to show innocense Whereby Your Petitioner was at the mercy of his prosecutor and accuser and was excluded from the use of his codefendants by whom he could have manifested his innocence and the rulings of the Court he is advised are the law but it is such a case as the law is made to defeat the ends of Justice and to work oppression upon Your Petitioner -- </p>
<p>Your Petitioner would state that he is now 19 years old and was 18 years old when the difficulty is said to have occured (and would state here what he omitted to state that both the Indictments and Commonlaw suits grew out of the same affair all taking place at the same time and were all one and the same transaction and that the Commonlaw suit have not be tried) and that his father and Mother are both dead and have been dead for several years and that he is an orphan in the strictest sense of the word and has not been favored with the benfits of but little education and has but little estate that if compelled to pay the fines together with the other attendant expenses at the present prices of property it will take nearly if not quite all his little estate -- Your Petitioner says that on the day the affair occurred he fell in with his co defendants in Lebanon Ky and they drank toomuch and on their way home at the tole gate one Lamb provoked a difficulty<pb/>
<lb/>with your Petitioner and then seeing he had got himself into a difficulty he ran into the house of H. P. Thornton his brother inlaw for Safety and while in there if any injury was done to Thornton or Miss Sutherland it was accidental unintentional in any way to hurt or injure either of them As Your Petitioner &amp; his 4 codefendants were upon the most perfect terms of friendship with each of them.</p>
<p>Your Petitoner frankly confesses his guilt in drinking but denies criminalty or evil design or purpose in any thing he is alledged to have did -- </p>
<p>Under all the circumstances Your Petitioner prays that Your Excellency will exercise Your <hi rend="underline">executive</hi> <hi rend="underline">clemency</hi> and remit the fines so imposed as your Petitioner will ever pray</p>
<p>William A Baxter</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by William Baxter This <date when="1862-06-20">June 20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1862</date></p>
<p>N T Henry ck</p>
<p>We join in the prayers of the foregoing petition of William Baxter</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="3"/><cb n="1"/>D. A. Rowe
<lb/>G. W. Crum
<lb/>C. F. Bracken
<lb/>Georg Posttellwaite
<lb/>H. H. Goade J. R. C
<lb/>H H Hughes
<lb/>Harvey Savage
<lb/>W W Prather
<lb/><cb n="2"/>E.. Rick
<lb/>J B Wathen
<lb/>A Carey
<lb/>P Warren
<lb/>Edward Newton
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m..</hi></hi> Thorp
<lb/>H. W. Crowders
<lb/><cb n="3"/>J. R. Thomas
<lb/>E. A. Graves
<lb/>N. S Ray
<lb/>N. T. Bern
<lb/>G. W. Goodman
<lb/>J Phillips
<lb/>JaS S Sartin<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>Augustin Mills one of the Jury
<lb/>J.. S.. Smith one of the Jury
<lb/>Joseph H. Hinton one of the Jury
<lb/>James Bicket one of the Jury
<lb/>J P Mills one of the Jury
<lb/>James M Brown one of the Jury
<lb/>John H Clements one of Jury
<lb/>William Mudd one of the Jury
<lb/>Francis Miles one of the Jury
<lb/>Raphael Mattingly one of the Jury
<lb/>Sam Spalding
<lb/>B. Spalding
<lb/>Wilfred H Medley
<lb/>Marcus Wimsatt
<lb/>J M Cardwell
<lb/>Rh. M. Spalding</p>
<p>Respite 12 Mo
<lb/>B. M.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
