<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-009-0061"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. H. Glover to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1216</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR1-266</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Sir have no conditions or qualifications in any allegience to the union, of these States,</p>
<p>like Henry Clay I owe a paramount allegience to the national Government &amp; a Subordinate one to the States,</p>
<p>I am for the Union &amp; against every thing that shall opposes it. let it be what it may, there are many Union men to hear them talk, But it is very hard for them to Determine whether their protection llies in the negro or in their Government negro, negro, negro, Seems to be Stirrotyped on their lips, abolition, abolition, abolition &amp; negro Equality ties their toungs &amp; Racks their Brains</p>
<p>I am against negroism in all of its forms, whether Bond or free, I oppose the negro being in the army, I am opposed to the negro in all the work Shops all the grain fields, in all the labour pursuits, I am opposed to the Race Being intermixed with our anglo Saxon Race in any way Shape or form But it Seems to me, that the opposition to the negro being in the army comes with a very bad grace from those who have all their lifetime laboured &amp; Strugled, to keep the negro here. &amp; work him Beside the poor white classes of people without feeling one Single compunction about negro Equality,</p>
<p>why is labour thus Degraded why Does the lawyer or Doctor go to the Blacksmith or Shoemaker or cooper &amp; Bind his negro to him, to learn the trade if its<pb/>
<lb/>So Degrading for <hi rend="str">t</hi>him to be in the army -- </p>
<p>why not the Lawyer &amp; Doctor take their negroes in their own offices &amp; learn them their trades to be Lawyers &amp; Doctors why are the mechanics &amp; labouring class of poor people, So much meaner, &amp; of So much lower grade of the Human Spieces, that the negro, the most abject Slave. i<hi rend="str">n either</hi> that the world in either ancient or modern times ever gazed upon, Does not Dishonor him in his association, this is truly a Sad Spectable as well as a Sad Reflection for a man who loves his country &amp; his Race, let alone his god,</p>
<p>Sir at best three forths of the people of the Slave States are nonSlave holders &amp; they are very Rarely Represented, in any of the offices of the Cuntry,</p>
<p>theeforths of all most every <hi rend="str">man</hi> Representatives or governors constituents work By the Side of the negro and yet he Stands up with his official Robe on &amp; proclaims the Degradation of abolition &amp; negro Equality when there is Beyond a Doubt more negro Equality &amp; association ^with them^ than any where Else on the globe, where there are as many of Both, Races together</p>
<p>now, Sir Here is the measure of my Unionism I would not only put down the (Peculiar Institution,) But I would kill han<hi rend="str">d</hi>g or Drown every negro in America not only So But I would Spend Every other Resorce on the Continent, &amp; more than that I would Sink all affrica Europe &amp; asia &amp; Every Cuntry Beneath Sun Except my own, my own Cunty first last &amp; all the time,</p>
<p>J. H Glover</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
