<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2077"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">H. S. Withers to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6714</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-274</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Stanford, Lincoln County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-07-27">27 July 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Stanford <date when="1865-07-27">July 27. 1865</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Sir, I have been called upon by W. C. Stoughton of Detroit Michigan a Brother of Oliver Stoughton now a convict in the Kentucky Penitentiary from this County to sign a Petition to your Excellency, granting an unconditional pardon to his unfortunate Brother. The appeal has been made to me from the fact that I was one of the Jury that convicted him.</p>
<p>From motives of public policy and the <unclear/> with which criminal Law is executed it is very rare that I ever sign a petition on behalf of any of the few who are convicted of the many violators of Law, Yet I think there is mitigating circumstances in this case that calls for Executive Clemency Stroughton was not the principal, merely an accomplice, I do not think he had an idea of the magnitude of his offence, but like many other Northern Soldiers disregarded the rights of property with the people of Kentucky. He has now served seventeen months which I think is sufficient punishment and that the majesty of the Law has been fully vindicated.<pb/></p>
<p>Under all the circumstances I would be pleased your Excellency would grant the unfortunate man a pardon, I think his helpless sisters have a greater claim for his services than our state I am with great respect</p>
<p>Your Excellency's
<lb/>Obt Servant;
<lb/>H. S. Withers,</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
