<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0751"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Burnett to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10219</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-169 to MG19-169A</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Kingston, Madison County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-03-08">8 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Kingston Madison Co
<lb/>Kentucky <date when="1861-03-08">March 8" 61</date>
<lb/>To
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>Beriah Magoffin.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner would respectfully State that he has been indicted by the Grand Jury of Madison Co for carrying concealed weapons and that he is now under bonds for his appearance to stand his trial the 2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> Monday in this month &amp; that the facts of the case are these Your Petitioner lives in the neighborhood of Berea which place as your Honor is well aware is the Headquarters of a disaffected set people, some of whom had on several occasions threatened him and being true to himself and a loyal citizen to his native state He prepared himself to Repel any attack by them.</p>
<p>Happening at the House of One Todd who is the witness <hi rend="str">for</hi> agst him and who lives in that neighborhood<pb/>
<lb/>and the difficulties being mentioned by himself stating to Todd what he had been threatened believing sd Todd to be his Friend he told him he was prepared to Repel and in fact showed him his arms and also disagreeing to spend the day at his house asked s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Todd to lay them away till he went Home which he did. But the s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Todd was so much in the interest of the Abolitionists or at least so indiscreet that he told them and they had him sumoned before the Grand Jury a willing witness, and a true bill found for carrying concealed weapons. Believing that he was warranted in what he done, that a man has the Right not only but that it is his duty to defend his person or his Country at any and all times and against all foes but particularly against domestic traitors He prays Your Honor <hi rend="str">for</hi> to grant all proper Releif<pb/>
<lb/>He would Respectfully state to your Honor that He is a poor man so far as the money but is Rich in children who are dependent upon him for their living as it is by his Labor alone they have the necessaries of life and their name as well as his own He appeals to you for Relief Knowing as you must that now it is particularly hard for all who are like him to get employment. Relying upon your Justice &amp; Mercy He hopes your Relief will be speedy and He will ever pray for your Happiness &amp; prosperity and the success of those great principles of which you are the exponent I have the Honor to subscribe myself</p>
<p>Respectfully yours
<lb/><hi rend="underline">John Burnett</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Burnetts Case
<lb/>no Judgt</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
