<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1054"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">D. R. Haggard to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5691</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR[11]-125 to BR[11]-126</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-07-09">9 July 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville <date when="1864-07-09">July 9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Bramlette</p>
<p>John Welch a soldier is Condemned to be hung on the <date when="1864-07-22">22 Inst</date> I had heard so much of the poor fellow on the <date when="1864-07-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of this month</date> I went to the Jail to See him -- and have a talk with him and I confess to you Sir, That I beleave Every word he says. he has told but but one tale -- and tells it like a man telling the truth -- He Says Some few days -- before he had the difficulty -- which ended in the killing of this poor strumpet -- He Welch was in the suburbs of the city &amp; asked the man with whom -- He subsequently had the difficulty with -- If He could tell him where a soldier <hi rend="str">cant</hi> could get a drink of whiskey -- He was told he did not know of any place just there, but if He would go with him He could get him some -- and he could show him some nice women. who were all right &amp; safe -- Welch says he went<pb/>
<lb/>went with him &amp; got some whiskey -- and had an introduction to some women -- and the fellow left him alone with one of them and when He Welch went to leave He was asked to return again by the man who carried him there -- and the woman also -- after the laps of a short time Welch returned to the Same place and after being there and drinking freely he says he became verry drunk &amp; he says the man Commenced abusing him and drew an axe -- upon him and threatened to split his brains out he Welch, told ^him^ not ^to^ strike him If He did he would shoot him -- Welch backing and absolutely backed out of the enclosure -- The fellow running striking at him -- He shot at the man who was trying to kill him -- with the axe -- Missing him and the ball taking effect in the woman -- The whole thing was a plot no doubt to get the poor soldier to this den of whores get him drunk get his money -- and swear each other<pb/>
<lb/>out of any difficulty -- that might occur the whole testimony come from the lips of the dirtyest set of prostitutes -- that ever disgraced any Country I hope you will feel that this poor fellows case may come under the rule that will allow you, sir, to interpose in his case and save him from death -- Good God the Idea of having such Creatures in Court to swear away the life of an individual -- upon whose features is stamped -- the man of generous heart and noble bearing, it is the first offence of any character it is said that he ever committed -- and did not know that the woman was hurt until the next day after it occured</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/><hi rend="underline">D. R. Haggard</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
