<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1936"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Ellison to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11404</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Bradley Strait</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG23-375 to MG23-376</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Whitley County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-04-07">7 April 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To The Excelence of the govenor your petitioner wold respectifull represente to youre Excelence that at the <gap/> turme of the Whitley Circuit Courte that the Grand Jury found an inditement against one Wm Ellison for larceny and that afterwards your petitioner become the baile of the said Wm Ellison in the sum of $<gap/> and at the last <date when="--03">march turm</date> of the Whitley Curcuit Court that the courte rendered judgment against him for the sume of $250, on the forfited Reconizens he states that at the time that the offence was comited by said ^W^ Ellison that he was but a small boy and was an alphant boy his parience both being dead he states the boy had no person to protect him and it was for the simpathy that he had for <hi rend="str">the</hi> ^<unclear/>^ boys that he became the bale of said Ellison he states that in adition ^<hi rend="str">nearly</hi>^ to that your petitioner mother is blind and ^nearly^ helpless and has been for <gap/> years and that your petitioner has supported her with out compensation from the county or any other person for <hi rend="str">$</hi> <gap/> years you petitioner states that he as a large famley of his own and is <hi rend="str">very</hi> pore man and has not the meanes to pay the amount of the forfeiture or the judgment render on the forfit reconizens with out having his property sold under Executian <hi rend="str">he</hi> and wold impovish the ballance of his famley he states that he has <hi rend="str">used his exersion</hi> trid to find out whear he was to gite the said wm Ellsion to come to courte</p>
<p>The prayes of your petitioner is that the fine imposed or the judgment on the forfeited reconizens be remitted and for all proper releaf</p>
<p>John Ellison</p>
<p>John Ellison says he believes the statement in the foregoing petition to be true</p>
<p>John Ellison</p>
<p>Sworn to be fore me by John Ellsion this the <date when="1862-04-07">7th day of <hi rend="str">1862</hi> April 1862</date></p>
<p>Isaiah Bird J P W C<pb/></p>
<p>We the under signed states that it wold be an act of charity to Remit the fine imposed on said Ellison and we thare fore aske your Excelen that he remit said <hi rend="str">fine</hi> judgment on the forfited reconizens</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>John Smith 
<lb/>Isaac Osburn 
<lb/>G P Caddell 
<lb/>Isom Jones
<lb/>P M Mahan 
<lb/>William B Skeen 
<lb/>James Foley
<lb/>R Bird
<lb/>B B Bird
<lb/>Isaiah Bird
<lb/>Wm S Marct
<lb/>Jesse Bunch
<lb/>Jeremiah Jones
<lb/>Canada Goin 
<lb/>Alexr Litten
<lb/>W E Mauney
<lb/>Joseph Baker 
<lb/>S. P. Brawner 
<lb/>D. H. Laforce
<lb/>A. C. King
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J. S. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Carty S W C
<lb/>M. E. Mahan 
<lb/>Canada Dovitt 
<lb/>Enos Allen 
<lb/>Edom Lovitt Jr
<lb/>A J Skeen
<lb/>A R Barton
<lb/>Martin Bains 
<lb/>Joseph Bollin 
<lb/>A. J. Curd
<lb/>James Cutbertt
<lb/>G. W. Reeves
<lb/>James Rookard 
<lb/>E F Adkins 
<lb/>John Dury<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>London
<lb/><date when="1862-05-03">May 3rd 1862</date>
<lb/>Gov Magoffin</p>
<p>Dear Sir It would gratify me if you would remit the within fine I believe that it should be done</p>
<p>Yours respectfully
<lb/>Granville Pearl</p>
<p>Whitley Cir Ct
<lb/>John Allison
<lb/>To Petition
<lb/>$250 } Recog
<lb/>Remission Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-06-09">June 9. 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
