<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1807"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Moses Givens to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6444</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-352 to BR13-353</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thomas E. Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Moses Givens would respectfully represent that some time in the summer of <date when="1864">1864</date>, one Harrison Silva was arrested in the County of Lewis on a charge of horse stealing, and was committed to the jail of Mason county at Maysville for safe keeping, Said Silva remained in said jail for some four or five months, and his mother an extremely poor widow of Fleming, in indigent circumstances, being greatly distressed about the protracted confinement, and being very desirous to have him released from his long imprisonment, entrusted your petitioner to become his bail, and accordingly, moved by her entreaties he was induced to become said Silva's bail for his appearance at the <date when="--11">November</date> Term of the Lewis Circuit court, the said Silva protestig his innocence of the charge proferred a-<pb/>
<lb/>gainst him, and making the most positive promises to appear at said court, and make his innocence manifest, Said Silva failed to appear at said court, was indicted by the grand jury and the said bail bond, being for <hi rend="str">two</hi> five hundred dollars was forfeited, and at the present <date when="1865-05">May</date> Term of Lewis Circuit Court judgement was rendered against this petitioner upon said forfeited recognizance, which amount and costs, this petitioner will be compelled to pay unless by the interposition of executive clemency -- He would pray your Excellency for a remittance of said judgement, as your petitioner will be compelled to pay a sufficient amount in costs, &amp;c his act of kindness, and as in duty &amp;c</p>
<p>Moses Givens</p>
<p>We are acquainted with the petitioner, and the facts by him above stated, as we were employed as attorneys to procure<pb/>
<lb/>the release of said Silva, by writ of habeas corpus, to permit him to be admitted to bail; and we think the case remits an interposition of your clemency</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Stanton &amp; Throop</hi></p>
<p>I know the parties and think the judgment ought to be remitted</p>
<p>Geo M Thomas
<lb/>atto for Comth.<pb/></p>
<p>If the prayer of the petitioner is granted, please send remittance to our address Maysville, Ky &amp; we will send the secratary's fee</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Stanton &amp; Throop</hi></p>
<p>Lewis Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Moses Givens
<lb/>$500.
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1865-05-23">23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> May/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
