<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0390"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Hezekiah Alexander, Jr. (a free person of color), Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9858</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-99 to MG18-100</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Meade County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-01-29">29 January 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header"><hi rend="underline">1</hi></note>
<lb/>Meade Circuit Court
<lb/><date when="1859-11">November Term 1859</date></p>
<p><note place="left margin">Indictment as found by the Grand Jury</note>
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against
<lb/>Hezekiah Alexander Jr. (a free person of color)</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Meade County in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, accuse Hezekiah Alexander Jr, a free person of color, of the offense of burglary, committed as follows viz The said Hezekiah Alexander a free person of color, on the <date when="1859-07-20">20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of July 1859</date>, in the night time, in the County aforesaid, broke into and entered the dwelling house of John Funk with intent to commit a felony, against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Cicero Maxwell attorney for the Commonwealth</p>
<p>Information given by M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> Funk wife of John. Funk</p>
<p>Summon for Commonwealth
<lb/>George W. Noble.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><note place="left margin">Endorsement</note>
<lb/>A true Bill. Collins. Fitch Foreman of the Grand Jury.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><note place="left margin">Instructions given by the Court</note>
<lb/>Commonwealth against Alexander Jr,</p>
<p>The Court instructs the Jury that they ought to convict the Deft, if they believe from the evidence that he at night entered the house of Funk with intent to Steal or commit any other Felony -- But if the Deft, lifted the window of the house intending to Steal, but put no part of his body within the house, he was not guilty of the charge in the Indictment.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The insertion of any part of the Defts body within the house with intent of going in to Steal, or do so any other felony, was a burglary.<pb/></p>
<p><note place="header"><hi rend="underline">2</hi></note></p>
<p><note place="left margin">Instructions given by the Court Cont'd</note>
<lb/>If the Jury have a reasonable doubt whether any part of the body of the Deft. was inserted within the house, or a reasonable doubt whether he intended to committ a felony, they ought to acquit -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>If the Deft. had a Stick merely to prop the window, and inserted it within the house, that was not such an entry, as would make him guilty of burglary -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><note place="left margin">Evidence given to the Jury on trial of the prosecution</note>
<lb/>Commonwealth 
<lb/>against
<lb/>H, Alexander</p>
<p>The Commonwealth introduced Ann, Funk who stated that in <date when="1859-07">July 1859</date> after She had retired to rest, She heard some one walking upon the Porch of the house where She resided, Shortly thereafter, She heard some one trying at the door of the Shoe Shop to get in -- ^(the shoe shop was in one room of the House,)^ one roof covering the whole, She heard some one at the window of the <hi rend="str">Shoe</hi> Shop, when She got up &amp; looking out the window She saw the prisoner holding or hoisting up the Window with One hand, and in the other, in the act of putting a Stick under the window to hold it up. There were Boots, Shoes &amp; Leather in the room. She did not think he had time to get his head in the window, or that either his head or elbow was, in the window, thought both were on the outside, the prisoner had frequently been in the Shop, but never at so late an hour.</p>
<p>This prisoner had been in Town all day and her husband had <hi rend="str">been</hi> ^been^ absent for a week or more<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header"><hi rend="underline">3</hi></note>
<lb/>which was known to the prisoner, was <hi rend="underline">usual</hi> absent when he went as he had on this occasion, a longer period of time than he had been gone this time, the Moon shone brightly. She knew the prisoner and believed it to be him, She had not doubt of it, as, She could See him clearly. She hollowed at him when he let the window go &amp; fled -- </p>
<p>This occured in the town of Garnettsville Meade County Ky. A good many persons lived close around, When the prisoner run She lit a Candle &amp; it was twelve Oclock at night, The window was lying upon the Stick next morning, one end being in the inside &amp; the other outside -- </p>
<p>This being all the evidence in the cause, the counsel for the prisoner moved the Court to discharge the Jury &amp; dismiss the Indictment. The Court overruled the motion to which the defendant excepts -- </p>
<p><hi rend="underline">James Stuart</hi>.</p>
<p>A Copy 
<lb/>Of the Indictment, Evidence &amp; Instructions of the Court, given in the prosecution of the Commonwealth of Ky against Hezekiah Alexander Jr in the Meade Circuit, Court -- Upon the trial of which, the Deft was found Guilty &amp; Sentenced to three years imprisonment in the Penetentiary of Ky,</p>
<p>Brandenburg -- <date when="1861-01-29">29<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> January 1861</date>.</p>
<p>Att
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Fairleigh Clk
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Meade Circuit Court</hi>.<pb/></p>
<p>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Partial Transcript.
<lb/>Hezekiah Alexander Jr.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>A Free Man of Color.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>From Meade County.<figure type="hr"/></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
