<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2118"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Larkin Guy to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6755</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-338 to BR14-339</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Allen County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-07-05">5 July 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To Thomas E Bramlett Esqr
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Larkin Guy a citizen of Allen County Would beg leave to state that in <date when="1863-06">June 1863</date> his Son Elbridge Guy was arrested and brought before William Mansfield Judge of Said County Court charged with horse stealing and an the <date when="1863-06-29">29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of June</date> the examination was had before said Mansfield and Said Elbridge Sent on to further trial He was addmitted to give bail in the Sum of Two hundred dollars Your petitions entered into Said bond for the appearance of the said Elbridge on the first day of the first term of the Allen Equity &amp; Criminal Court Which was to have been held in Said County on the <gap/> Monday of <date when="--07">July</date> following No time of said court was held at that time The said Elbridge and Your petitioners were in attendance at the time the court was to have commenced but no Court being held your petitioner and his son supposed they had complied with the conditions of said bond &amp; that <hi rend="str">that</hi> of any thing further was done in the said Elbridge would have to be notified or be rearrested</p>
<p>On the <date when="1863-07-26">26<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of July 1863</date> the said Elbridge was recruited with Company "K" in a Tennesse Regiment the officers of which were then in this County recruiting among the refugees from Said State the commander of the Regiment was named Garnett but the number your petitioner <hi rend="str">State</hi> cannot State and his Son is now in the service in Said regiment When last heard from Stationed at Murfreesboro</p>
<p>At the <date when="1864-01">January term ^1864^</date> of said Court the Said Elbridge was indicted upon said charge At the <date when="1864-03">March<pb/>
<lb/>term 1864</date> not quite one month after said Janry term at which the indictment was found the cause was continued &amp; the bail bond continued ^without notice to your petitioner^ At the September term 1864 of said Court said bond was forfeited and a summons issued against your petitioner and at the <date when="1865-03">March term 1865</date> Judgment was rendered for $200. against your petitioner</p>
<p>He states that such was his ignorance of the forms &amp; usages of the law in such cases that he did not know that his son was required to appear under said bond except at the <date when="--07">July</date> court which should have been held soon after its execution Nor did his Son know it was his duty to do so but supposed he would have to be notified again of the proceeding Your petitioner states that he is an old man upwards of 60 years of age with a helpless wife &amp; family to support that he owns a small poor farm which serves him as a home and if this judgment is collected it will be taken to pay it as he has no other means to Satisy it He went his sons bail to Keep him out of Jail brought him up at the term he supposed he was bound to do so &amp; thought himself no further bound He prays your excellency to interpose in his behalf The history as above given of the case is true and your petition will Say nothing of the guilt of inocence of the boy as that does not come up in this case You are a father and can feel &amp; appreciate a fathers feelings for a wild &amp; wayward boy exposed to temtation as they have been in the last four years and prays that mercy may be extended to him</p>
<p>Larkin guy<pb/></p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Allen County Sct</p>
<p>This day personally appeared before the undersigned Judge of Allen County Court Larkin Guy and subscribed and made oath to the foregoing Statements this <date when="1865-07-05">5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of July 1865</date></p>
<p>William Mansfield Judge of the Allen County Court.</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Allen County Kentucky State that they have known Larkin Guy for many years and from our knowledge of his character can fully endorse him He is an honest man, old, with a helpless farmly dependant on him for support and is in every way a worthy object of executive clemency and as Such recomend him to your mercy</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>B A Young
<lb/>Malachiers Perry
<lb/>Louis Gulley
<lb/>Jakson morgan
<lb/>W H H Clark
<lb/>T S Clark
<lb/>E,, P,, M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Reynolds
<lb/>W,, L,, Wagoner
<lb/>David Millir
<lb/>John Harris
<lb/>E. Pruitt
<lb/>S. W. Pruitt
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Thomas P. Buckhanon
<lb/>M. F. Ham
<lb/>L. S Murray
<lb/>W L Alexander
<lb/>William Dearing
<lb/>Drury. W. Dearing
<lb/>F. A. Wilson
<lb/>W. R. Tapscott
<lb/>Rolly Tapscott
<lb/>Samuel McReynolds
<lb/>uriah Hinton
<lb/>Sampson Anderson
<lb/>W. A. Gardner
<lb/>John W Lyles<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>John N Briley
<lb/>S F Alexander
<lb/>Abraham Hustend
<lb/>J, M, Briley
<lb/>John <unclear/>
<lb/>Berryman Neal
<lb/>J. E. Paton
<lb/>T W Burton
<lb/>F M Burton
<lb/>M.. H.. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Elroy
<lb/>J, F, Walker
<lb/>J H Butler
<lb/>Henry F Leyles
<lb/>A S Nisbee
<lb/>J,, W,, Blankinship
<lb/>joel Blankenship
<lb/>R. M. Richards
<lb/>Wyat Saurer
<lb/>L. R haleman
<lb/>Robert Garison
<lb/>John Galvin
<lb/>James M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>farnham
<lb/>J W Foster
<lb/>B A Foster
<lb/>A. S. Foster
<lb/>J N. Tucker</p>
<p>Allen Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Larkin Guy
<lb/>$200,
<lb/><date when="1865-08-02">2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Aug 1865</date>
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1865-08-02">2 Aug /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
