<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3172"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">L. L. Parks, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5291</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-217</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Jefferson county }</p>
<p>I L. L. Parks cirtify that I was in the court room the day that William Grayham, a man of color, (Jointly indicted with another boy, whose name I dont remember) was tried and convicted. Evidence Showed that Grayham was in company with the other boy; <hi rend="str">on Sunday</hi>; that <hi rend="str">the other</hi> <hi rend="str">one</hi> ^Grayham^ went into a Shoe Shop professes to <hi rend="str">buy</hi> ^look at^ a pair of boots; the other one went in with him. Grayham Said he would get paid off next week for his work, and he would come in next Sunday and get them, and asked the Shoemaker to keep them until then. Grayham went out- the other one remained in until after he was gone- hanging around the counter- telling Grayham that he would overtake him.</p>
<p>The other boy overtook Grayham a little outside of the city; and when he did so Showed a pair of boots which he Said he had bought at the Shop where they stoped In a few days afterwards the Shop keeper accompanied by a Policeman, went out and found the boots in possession of "the <hi rend="str">one</hi> other boy"; but arrested Graham also because, he was in company with him at the Store.</p>
<p>Several members of the <hi rend="underline">bar</hi> <hi rend="underline">lawyers</hi>, expressed their surprize at the time, that graham was found guilty; and that the finding was wrong. He had no counsel<pb/>
<lb/>At least none that was any benefit to him An inexperienced young man who did him no good whatever; and had neglected to Summon his witness.</p>
<p>L L. Parks.</p>
<p>This young man Mr Parks is law-student in my office- and is a clever young man- whose statements are entitled to credit. I did not herar the trial, but others who did, gave Substantially the Same account of it He has been in the Penitentiary nerly a year, and I trust Governnor you will release him.</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>L. A. Moore</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
