<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2406"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Joseph Smythe, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7043</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-338</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-06">6 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Kentucky, Jefferson Circuit Court <date when="1865-09">Sept<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Term 1865</date>
<lb/><date when="1865-09-06">September 6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> <hi rend="underline">1865</hi></date>
<lb/>The Comth of Ky
<lb/>vs } Felony
<lb/>Joseph Smythe</p>
<p>Joseph Smythe, who has been Jointly indicted with John Hunt by the Grand Jury of this Circuit, for felony and who is now Confined in the Jail of this County on said Charge, was this day led to the Bar of this Court by and in the Custody of the Jailor attending the same and being arraigned upon said indictment plead guilty thereto and for his trial put himself upon the Country and the Attorney for the Commonwealth likewise, wherefore to try the issue joined let a jury Come and thereupon came a Jury towit: John Price, W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Hardin, W. P. Shepherd, H. H. Sale, H. W. Hawes, A. G. Woodruff, J. V. Cowling, G. W. Cochran, J. J. Hurschbuhl, John Crabb, John Dennis, and R. B. Hopkins, who being duly elected, tried and sworn well and truly to try and true deliverance make between the Commonwealth and the accused upon oath returned into Court, the following verdict "We of the Jury find the accused, Joseph Smythe, guilty as charged in the indictment and say he shall be Confined in the Penitentiary<pb/>
<lb/>for the term of two years, but on account of his youth and tender years recommend him to the Mercy of the Governor. R. B. Hopkins, foreman"</p>
<p>And thereupon the Prisoner was remanded and taken to Jail.</p>
<p>A Copy. Att <hi rend="underline">James P. Chambers Clk</hi></p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Joseph Smythe
<lb/>Comth
<lb/>vs } Copy of Trial &amp; Verdict
<lb/>Jos. Smythe,<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Pardoned <date when="1865-09-08">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sept /65</date></p>
<p>Mrs. M. A Smythe
<lb/>4<hi rend="sup">th st</hi> Between Walnut &amp; <hi rend="str">Jefferson</hi> Chesnut
<lb/>Louisville
<lb/>Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
