<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0027"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">T. J. Ewing to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14056</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1863</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Catlettsburg, Boyd County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-05-01">1 May 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Catlettsburg Ky
<lb/><date when="1863-05-01">May 1st 1863</date>
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>J. F. Robinson
<lb/>Governor of Ky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>I have a proposition to make to your honor in regard to the raising of troops for Ky service. My plan is this. As there is a probability of the conscription act being carried into effect in Ky and before I would allow myself to be drafted I would volunteer and such is the case of a large number of my fellow citizens. I want to see the mane of Kentucky come out at the end of the war without the name of one of her citizens being enrolled as a drafted man. I wish to raise a Battallion of not less than 500 men which shall be independent of all branches of the service for the purpose of ridding the North eastern portion of our state<pb/>
<lb/>of the Guerrillas and Thieves which infest it. There are a great number of men in this and adjoinging counties who would be willing to enter the service for such a purpose who would not be willing to enter the regular army. The Battallion to be mounted and to serve Twelve months. I refer you to reccommendations in my favor now in your possession from Generals Siegel Milroy &amp; Schenck concerning my ability. I shall be pleased to receive an answer at your earliest convenience.</p>
<p>I remain your most
<lb/>obedient servant
<lb/>T. J. Ewing Ex Capt
<lb/>Co. G. 5" Regt Va Vol Infantry<pb/></p>
<p>T. J. Ewing
<lb/>Capt. 5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Va I.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Cattlettsburgh Ky<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/><date when="1863-05-01">May 1"/63</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Recruiting for Ky. service</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
