<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2283"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Landon Carter, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6920</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-144 to BR15-145</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Macon, Bibb County, Georgia</placeName>
    <date when="1865-08-12">12 August 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency, Andrew Johnson,
<lb/>President of the United States. -- </p>
<p>The Petition of the undersigned, now a resident of Bibb county in the state of Georgia, respectfully sheweth, that he in <date when="1861-09">September 1861</date>, and then a citizen of Kentucky joined the Confederate amry, then at Bolling Green, in said State of Kentucky, that some afterwards he was assigned to a position in the <unclear>Medical</unclear> Department of said Army &amp; left the State of Kentucky under the orders of his superior officers; that he acted as a Surgeon of the Confederate service from the time he left Kentucky, until the order of Gen Jos. E. Johnston, disbanding his department, &amp; that he is advised that the facts as above stated, place him within the 12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Class <unclear/> <unclear/> excepted from the <unclear/> of the <unclear>Imnesty</unclear> Proclamation of your Excellency of the <date when="1865-05-29">29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of May 1865</date>.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner farther shewith unto your Excellency, that he has taken the oath presented in said Proclamation preliminary to this application for pardon, as required, <unclear/> will appear by reference to the Exhibits hereto attached; that the Government has not taken possession of any of his property, that, as far as he is advised &amp; believes, no proceedings are pending against him, in a Court of the United States, for treason or for conspirace against the Government of the United States; that he is at <unclear/> in care of a Small Pox hospital in the vicinity of<pb/>
<lb/>Macon, Bibb county Georgia, under the authority of the officers of the United States, commanding the Military District in which Bibb County is embraced &amp; that he has taken the oath hereto appended in good faith.</p>
<p>Wherefore he prays that a pardon may be extended him, as provided in said Amnesty Proclamation.</p>
<p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this <date when="1865-08-12">12 day of August 1865</date>.</p>
<p>Landon Carter
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> M Riley Ordinary for Bibb County Geo<pb/></p>
<p>UNITED STATES OF AMERICA.
<lb/>State of Georgia,
<lb/>BIBB COUNTY.</p>
<p>I, Landon Carter, of the County of Bibb, and State of Georgia, do solemnly swear or affirm, in presence of Almighty God, that I will henceforth faithfully defend the Constitution of the United States, and the Union of the States thereunder; and that I will, in like manner, abide by and faithfully support all Laws and Proclamations which have been made during the existing rebellion, with reference to the Emancipation of Slaves. So help me God.</p>
<p>Landon Carter
<lb/>Sworn to and Subscribed before me, this <date when="1865-08-12">12 day of, August, 1865</date>.</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> W Riley Ordinary.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Daily Telegraph Book and Job Office, Macon, Ga.<pb/></p>
<p>Head Quarters Department of Georgia.
<lb/><hi rend="italic">Augusta, Ga.,</hi> <date when="1866-02-06">February 6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> <hi rend="italic">186</hi><hi rend="italic"><hi rend="str">5</hi></hi>6</date>.
<lb/>Respectfully forwarded to the Attorney General U. S., at Washington City.</p>
<p>Jon Brannan
<lb/>Bvt' <hi rend="italic">Maj. Gen'l. Commd'g. Dep't. Ga.</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Refer to Gov of Ky -- </p>
<p>Landon Carter of Bibb
<lb/>12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Section<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Executive Office
<lb/>Milledgeville, Ga. <date when="1866-01-11">Jany 11/66</date></p>
<p>From all the information before me, I believe the within named applicant will be a peacable, loyal citizen, and reccommend that the application for Amnesty be granted</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Charles J. Jenkins</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
