<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3070"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. B. Champion et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5189</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR43-194</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Livingston County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Hon Thos E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioners would respectfully state that a few weeks since James J Baxter was arrested under a charge of attempting to Commit a Rape upon a young woman by the name of Johnson- If the facts were not of their character as to demand our, influence in his behalf we certainly would not have gotten up this petition But Sir the Human family are all liable to Sin, and he is only a frail son of Adam. The facts of the case are as we are informed, That he the said Baxter was heartly intoxicated which is a rare occurance, and was perfectly wild, He was at home by himself his wife being absent on a visit with her child a Baby- The lady Miss Johnson went over to said Baxters to take some meal home she had borrowed, when she went in Baxter was lying in bed, and the lady mistaking him for his wife, stepped close to the bed as she went through the Room had as she came back, to go and Baxter insulted her at least such is her<pb/>
<lb/>evidence, she then stepped out of the house and Baxter apologized. Sir Baxter is a poor man has a destitute family and is disgraced by having been a federal soldier, and his prosecuters are notorious Rebels, and bitterly his enemy Under the circumstances, that he can not have a fair trial, on account of the condition of things and the bitter political feeling of his prosecuters, and with the knowledge of the fact that he is poor and unable to give bail and will have to lay in Jail till <date when="--02">Februay</date> before trial away from a suffering family We humbly beseech you to pardon &amp; release him.</p>
<p>Resful Signed citizens
<lb/>of Livingston County -</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J. B. Champion <unclear/>
<lb/>S. M. Gray
<lb/>J W Chamption
<lb/>N. Woodford
<lb/>N. B. Brinson
<lb/>J. M. alley
<lb/>J O Duncan
<lb/>James Elison
<lb/>J. C. Wood
<lb/>J.N. Wood
<lb/>W. M. McGrury
<lb/><cb n="2"/>A. J. Fleming
<lb/>J. B Harllin
<lb/>J. P. Hueltad
<lb/>W. P. Tyner
<lb/>R. C. Champion
<lb/>Henry Mitchell
<lb/>Vinson Gady</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
