<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-021-0017"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Richard H. Stanton to J. R. Garland</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG3087</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Apprehension of Fugitives from Justice Papers, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG8-97 to MG8-98</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Maysville, Mason County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-02-22">22 February 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>R. H. STANTON. THOS. J. THROOP.
<lb/>STANTON &amp; THROOP,
<lb/>ATTORNEYS AT LAW, 
<lb/>MAYSVILLE, KY.
<lb/>Will Practice in Mason and adjoining Counties, also in District and Federal Courts and Court of Appeals.
<lb/>Collections in any part of Northern Kentucky will receive prompt attention.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Maysville, Ky,
<lb/><date when="1861-02-22">Feb 22, 1861,</date>
<lb/>My dear Judge,</p>
<p>I am very glad to perceive that M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Rice has offered a reward for the capture of Sam'l M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Roberts, who escaped from your jail a few days since. He is one of the most daring, dangerous and desperate villains in all your region, and I fear the small reward that M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Rice has offered will be insufficient to induce any one to attempt his capture, especially as it cost so much to catch and bring him back before. M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Hawkins his security, had to pay more than 70$ for the assistance required in Cincinnati.</p>
<p>He ought by all means to be had<pb/>
<lb/>and tried for he is so daring that your region and Rowan, will be in alarm all the time he remains loose and no property that ^can^ be run off will be safe,</p>
<p>.... I suggest, therefore, that you as County Judge, write to the Governor, and request that he offer a reward of $250 or $300 in addition to what M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Rice has offered, for the re-capture of M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Roberts. If you will state to him, the nature of the indictment and other charges against the felon, and the circumstances which make the case one of unusual importance, I have no doubt he will feel it his duty to offer some reward. I do not think the lives of Johnson &amp; Hawkins who took him the last time, are safe while he is loose, especially as he is supposed to have confederates in Rowan, who will secrete him any length of tiime in the hills, and afford him opportunities for any crime.</p>
<p>If you think it necessary, you may<pb/>
<lb/>enclose this letter to the Governor, to show him that I deem it necessary that a reward should be offered.</p>
<p>Your friend &amp;c
<lb/>R. H. Stanton</p>
<p>Hon J. R. Garland
<lb/>Clarksburg, Ky.<pb/></p>
<p>offer reward $200
<lb/>B. M</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
