<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2892"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">B. M. Winston to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7529</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-206 to BR17-207</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Henderson, Henderson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-31">31 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Henderson Ky
<lb/><date when="1863-12-31">Decr 31<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>To his excellency
<lb/>Thos E Bramlette
<lb/>Govn<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> of the State of Ky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>understanding that Col Hall of Union County Ky desire to be released through Executive Clemency from further trial for the killing of Dr R. W. N. Taylor in the town of Caseyville Union County Ky in the year of <date when="1857">1857</date> and for which he has already suffered extraordinary oppression hardships and expense I deem it but Justice to him and all concerned to make the following Statement in his behalf</p>
<p>I was well acquainted with both of these Gentlemen and was the warm personal friend of the Deceased -- I was also acquainted with Halls wife Mrs Josephine Hall -- whom I regarded as a young intelligent and virtuous lady. They finally separated and from common report Suspicion was thrown upon Dr Taylor as being the cause -- and ^in^ consequence of which a Serious difficulty was liable to occur between Taylor and Hall
<lb/><note place="footer">over</note><pb/>
<lb/>as a friend to the Dr. "and" in fact "of Both" I felt it my duty to interpose and if possible <hi rend="str">t</hi>prevent a difficulty and endeavor to effect a reconciliation.</p>
<p>for this purpose I visited those two gentleman and by this means learned that a difficulty of a very Serious nature -- beyond my power to remove -- really did exist between them and that the rumor as to its cause was but too well founded.</p>
<p>I witnessed a portion of the fight in which Taylor was Slain Hall was quietly attending to Some private business in the Street until menaced by Taylor when the fight Began with pistols and after the exchange of Several Shots without effect -- Hall went around Decd and entered the Store of Mess Brooks and Jennings to whence Taylor after being armed with a Spear or a Sword cane urged on by Some of the crowd -- Soon followed Swearing vengeance against Hall or any that Should oppose him -- he attacked Hall in the house and recd the fatal Stab</p>
<p>from what the Decd Said to me and form his actions at different times previous<pb/>
<lb/>to this affair -- I had good reason to believe he intended to attack or provoke a difficulty with Hall and on this day he made this intention So apparent at different parts of the town that Many were not Surprised at its Occurrance</p>
<p>and while I as the warm peronsal friend of the Deceasd and his family -- deeply regretted its fatal termination -- its but true and Just to Say that in my opinion this affair would not have Occurred had the deceased not Sought and provoked it -- and that the interposition of the executive power to the extent of his final discharge from farther prosecution would be but a Simple act of Justice to Col Hall</p>
<p>I have the honor to be
<lb/>very respectfully your obt Servant
<lb/>B. M. Winston<pb/></p>
<p>Winston</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
