<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0184"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James Carr to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4303</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-293 to BR8-294</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-08-22">22 August 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner states that something nigh two years since he was indicted in the Circuit Court of Franklin County in two cases for selling liquor to slaves and summoned to answer to the same. He attended at several terms and the last time he attended his understanding was that after the Commonwealths atty had talked with the principal witness he did not deem that he could make out the cases and that he would discuss them. This atty was P U Major who is absent from Franklin County</p>
<p>This petitioner states the facts to have been as follows. He gave his slaves leave to give a party to their negro friends during Christmas times and they invited a few negroes to attend their party. A young man by name of Tarrant had been working a short time for petitioner but had quit &amp; gone away <hi rend="str">But</hi> &amp; he returned to petitioners house on the afternoon of the day the negroes had their party. This petitioner has been advised &amp; we have the information true that Tarrant took some of the negroes &amp; went a short distance to where Tarrants father had two barrels of whiskey &amp; got two gallons and let the negroes have it whether he gave it or sold it ^He did not know of Tarrants conduct until next day.^ petitioner is not advised. Some of the negroes got drunk &amp; caused a rumpus. As soon as affiant heard of it he went to the negroe quarter and dispersed the whole of them He states most solemly that he never gave or sold or consented that any others might sell or give spritis to the said negroes or any of them</p>
<p>He did not attend court after the term he understood the case would be dismissed<pb/>
<lb/>nor engage other counsel Jno Rodman having been his counsel, as he believed said Indictments had been dismissed</p>
<p>It now seems they were not dismissed and at last court in Franklin judges were entered on each Indictment agst petitioner for $50 &amp; costs -- He declares he was innocent totally of the charges made agt him He knew nothing about the judgts until the shff came with executions</p>
<p>We pray your Excellency to relieve him of the judgts by a remission or of as much thereof as can be acquitted</p>
<p>Your petior will pray &amp;c
<lb/>James Carr</p>
<p>Ch R Smithers states that he was a witness in the cases referred to by James Carr before the Grand jury &amp; in the Circuit Court. At the <date when="1862-02">Feb Court 1862</date> he attended as a witness and P U Major examined him privately &amp; he stated what he knew, Major said witnesses evidence was not sufficient &amp; he would dismiss the Indictments witness supposing they had been dismissed attended no more until just before the last June term by Franklin Circuit Court he was served with attachments for failing to attend before &amp; was required to attend at <date when="--06">June court</date></p>
<p>At the <date when="--06">June term</date> he was examined and so was Hiram Penn Jr a boy about ten or twelve years old. Witness ^proved that he^ lived near to where the negroes had their party and his mothers having some negroes at it. Witness saw Jerry Tarrant in the early part of the evening<pb/></p>
<p>and had heard he was in the habit of selling liquor to negroes &amp; he went once to the party mainly to caution the negroes of his mother to buy no liquor of Tarrant nor to have any thing to do with him. The negroes had evidently been drinking before witness got to the place of their party &amp; were drinking while he was there Carr was not there, Tarrant was, and was puring whiskey out of a jug &amp; handing it to the negroes</p>
<p>That he was pretty certain Carr knew nothing about it until witness told him of it the next morning. He stated further to the jury being asked that the land belonged to Carrs mother &amp; Carr lived with her &amp; cultivated it. He stated further that he saw young Penn the other witness there at the party while he was there</p>
<p>What he heard of young Penns evidence his testimony was in substance the same as that of this witness</p>
<p>C. P. Smither</p>
<p>The foregoing statements were severally sworn to be James Carr &amp; Ch R Smither before the undersigned a justice of the peace for Franklin County Ky <date when="1863-08-22">Aug 22<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> 1863</date></p>
<p>Geo W Gorin J P F C</p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">
<lb/>G W G J P
<lb/><date when="1863-08-22">Agt 22/63</date></note></p>
<p>The subscribers hereto have no hestitation in saying that James Carr and Ch<pb/>
<lb/>R Smither are fully entitled to credit for the Truth of any statements made by them</p>
<p>Th N Lindsey
<lb/>G. W. Gorin</p>
<p>H. B. James</p>
<p>I write in the praying for the remission of the fines</p>
<p>John M Harlan</p>
<p>My recollection of the testimony is that the liquor was sold to the negroes by young Tarrant, at the residence or on the primises of Carr -- but the evidence did not show that Carr was <hi rend="underline">immediately</hi> present when the liquor was sold. He was about the premises somewhere, but was not in the <hi rend="underline">actual</hi> presence of Tarrant when the sale was made.</p>
<p>John L. Scott
<lb/>Com. atty.</p>
<p>I recommend that the prayer of the petitioner be granted and that the fine be remitted</p>
<p>P.U. Major Ex Comths Atty of the 8th dist -- </p>
<p>Franklin Co</p>
<p>From the statements Sworn to, I am of opinion that the Judgements was erroneous. And although it is not a safe precedent to remit upon exparte statements, when the Petitioner was so careless as not to make defense yet, in this case it is ordered that the fines be remitted except costs &amp; fees</p>
<p><date when="1863-10-05">Oct 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>Govr of Ky</p>
<p>James Carr
<lb/>$100 -- </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
