<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2702"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">S. S. Dunbar et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7339</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-344</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Columbia, Adair County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-11-18">18 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Columbia Ky. <date when="1865-11-18">N<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">ov</hi></hi> the 18<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency Thomas. E. Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of the State of Kentucky
<lb/>Dear sir</p>
<p>Some time previous to the last <date when="--05">May</date> term of our Circuit Court, one Robert. D. Campbell late of Hart County Ky. whose intellectual faculties are far below the ordinary class of young men, &amp; more particularly whn labouring under the influence of ardent spirits, to the habit of which he was very much prone; but his Paternal, &amp; Maternal relatives (to wit the Campbells, &amp; Rowes) are highly respectible citizens -- was a^c^cused of stealing of ^from^ Bell M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Beath some fifteen dollars in money, under the following circumstances, while in M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Beaths Confectionary, or drug Store, he, (Campbell) found on the floor a Pocketbook, out of which he took the money, suspition fell upon him, &amp; whn demanded gave up the money. It is in proof also that he had, had partial paroxysms of insanity for some time, supposed to be from the effects of a fall from a horse, which fall had fractured his brain He was arrested, and his trial put off from the May, to the <date when="--11">N<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">ov</hi></hi></date> term, by S. S. Dunbar going in with him, in a bond of five hundred dollars, which bond was forfeited in consequence of Campbells nonappearance.</p>
<p>Now therefore we the undersigned petitioners respectfully request your Excellency to remit said fine, as the course of Justice will not be materially arrested thereby, on the part of Campbell, but fully, &amp; meritoriously, ^<hi rend="str">(</hi>carried out)^ on the part of Dunbar. All of which we herewith submit to your Excellency -- Given under our hands this <date when="1865-11-18">18<hi rend="sup">th</hi>. day of N<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">ov</hi></hi>. 1865</date></p>
<p>S. S. Dunbar
<lb/>Tim Bradshaw
<lb/>T Q Walker
<lb/>Gaither Miller
<lb/>J. C. Winfrey
<lb/>James D Lyon
<lb/>P. C. Hardin
<lb/>R T Garnett<pb/>
<lb/>E. T Willis
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> R Ewing
<lb/>Ben. S. Coffey</p>
<p>Remit the forfeiture &amp; hand to Senator
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Ben S Coffey</hi></p>
<p>Adair Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>S. S. Dunbar
<lb/>$500
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/><date when="1865-12-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Dec/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
