<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0973"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Patrick Carroll to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5092</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-7 to BR11-8</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Fayette County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-06-21">21 June 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency the Governor of Ky.</p>
<p>Your petitioner respectfully represents that at the <date when="--02">last February Term</date> of the Fayette Circuit Court Charles Jenkins who is a worthless character, had him indicted for keeping a tippling house for three months and as he is informed and believes said indictment was procured in consequence of the refusal of petitioner to <hi rend="underline">give</hi> him the said witness, whiskey and other liquors which he was regularly licensed to sell without any compensation. Knowing the vindictive spirit actuating the said witness your petitioner by the advice of his counsel confessed Judgment for simply keeping a tippling house and now in consideration of the foregoing facts and the positive assurance of your petitioner that he is entirely innocent of the charge, and that he has not at any time violated the law in any particular, he respectfully askes that Judgment shall as far as in your power, lies be remitted. By the Judgment Your petitioner is fined sixty dollars<pb/>
<lb/>and costs, He submits his petition to your Excellency</p>
<p>Patk.. Carroll</p>
<p>Sworn to before me W. A. Stivers a Notary Public in and for Fayette County Ky this <date when="1864-06-21">21<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of June 1864</date>. Witness my hand &amp; seal the day &amp; year find above matter.</p>
<p>Will A. Stivers
<lb/>Notary Public</p>
<p><figure type="seal"><ab>NOTARY PUBLIC
<lb/>W. A. STIVERS
<lb/>FAYETTE COUNTY, K.Y.</ab></figure>
<lb/><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">W. A A.
<lb/><date when="1864-06-21">June 21
<lb/>1864</date>.</note></p>
<p>The undersigned respectfully unite in the prayer of the petitioner.</p>
<p>John O. Toole 65. Main st., Lex Ky.
<lb/>Snaren T. Dillon
<lb/><unclear/> Bookman <unclear/> #6 Ky
<lb/>W T Lee Lieut 16th Ky cal vol
<lb/>Hugh Harley
<lb/>P. W. Cannon
<lb/>P F Maguire
<lb/>G. F. Lilley
<lb/>T M Bell for G K Bell
<lb/>P. Bishop
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Hewron
<lb/>Dan Kastle
<lb/>Joseph Hoeing
<lb/>Tho. C. Oscar<pb/>
<lb/>John T. Stiller
<lb/>Geo B. Kinkead - without knowing what the evidence was
<lb/>A S. Cooper
<lb/>John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cauley
<lb/>G. S. Morgan
<lb/>John Rodger
<lb/>Richard Owens
<lb/>M. S. Keith
<lb/>Z. Gibbons
<lb/>G. Stoll Jr
<lb/>Jas C. Morris
<lb/>R. H. Prewitt
<lb/>D C Wickliffe<pb/></p>
<p>Fayette Cir Ct
<lb/>refused
<lb/><date when="1864">1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
