<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0107"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Boling to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9575</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-9 to MG17-10</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Owsley County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-11-07">7 November 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner John Boling would respectfully represent that on wednesday the <date when="1860-11-07">7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of Novr. 1860</date> he was arrested and brought before the County Judge of Owsley County charged with the offence of having carried concealed a<hi rend="str">s</hi> Pistol, to which charge your petitioner pleaded guilty and a Jury trial being waved &amp; law &amp; facts submitted to the Court, the Court assessed against your petitioers a fine of Fifty Dollars -- </p>
<p>The facts are as follows -- on tueseday <date when="1860-11-06">Novr 6<hi rend="sup">t</hi> 1860</date> (the day of the Presidential election) your petitioner apprehending a difficulty borrowed for a few minutes a pistol from a friend and shortly afterwards &amp; whilst he still had said pistol he was attacked &amp; in the difficulty exhibited the pistol -- <hi rend="str">Your</hi> <hi rend="str">petitioner</hi> <hi rend="str">all</hi> <hi rend="str">the</hi> <hi rend="str">time</hi> <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> <hi rend="str">for</hi> <hi rend="str">the</hi> <hi rend="str">rights</hi> <hi rend="str">of</hi> <hi rend="str">Mr</hi> <hi rend="str">Breckinridge &amp; Lane</hi> The Breckinridge and Lane men expecting an attack from the opposition was the Sole cause of the pistol being carried -- Your petitioner has no pistol of his own</p>
<p>Wherefore he prays a remission of said fine &amp; for all other appropriate relief</p>
<p>Owsley County</p>
<p>The petitioner John Boling says he believes the statements of the foregoing Petition are true</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by John Boling<pb/>
<lb/>this <date when="1860-11-07">7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of November 1860</date></p>
<p>The undersigned unite with the petitioner John Boling in the statement that he believes the statements Contained in his petition are and also made unite with him in his prayer for a remission of the fine therein named &amp; for all such relief as is proper under the circumstances</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>H. C. Smith
<lb/>Aly Ledford
<lb/>John Moore
<lb/>Tinsley Combs
<lb/>W S Hurst
<lb/>E B, Treadway (sheff)
<lb/>H C Moore (Jailor)
<lb/>E. Winn P. M
<lb/>T L Geer
<lb/>C. Combs
<lb/>Jno D cole
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi>. D. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Gee
<lb/>John Bowman
<lb/>Samuel A Chastain<pb/></p>
<p>B M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin Esqr</p>
<p>Sir the circumstances of M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Boling's case are about these on the morning of the day of the presidential election he had a difficulty with a M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Hampton as I understood and some <unclear/> words pased Hampton later Boling his father had sold out or something to that effect Boling told him he was a damn liar friends kept them from fighting Boling afterwards borrowed a pistol and in the evening of the same day a man by the name of Stewart Came up to where Boling was and remarked that Breckinridge was a rascal and that he could whip any Breckinridge man on the ground Boling told him he was a damn liar they came to gether but were separated Boling exhibited the pistol for which he was brought before me the County Judge and <hi rend="str">pleaded</hi> plead Guilty and was fined fifty dollars I hope the fine will be remitted by your excellency</p>
<p>W F Hensley<pb/></p>
<p>Owsley cir. ct.
<lb/>Respite 12 mo
<lb/>B, M
<lb/>Is<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1861-01-11">Jny 11. '61</date>
<lb/>$50. } Concealed Weapon</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
