<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2774"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. L. Griffith et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7411</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-36 to BR17-37</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Cynthiana, Harrison County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-16">16 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Cynthiana Ky -- <date when="1865-12-16">Decr 16<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi>/65</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E. Bramlette
<lb/>Govr of Ky -- 
<lb/>Dear Sir -- </p>
<p>We your petitioners officers of the Harrison Circuit Court &amp; Citizens of Cynthiana &amp; vicinity would most respectfully state, that at the <date when="1864-05">May term 1864</date>. of the Harrison Circuit Court, an indictment was found by the grand Jury of our county, against Kennedy Fightmaster charging him with the offence of selling liuqor to a minor, contrarly to the Statute of Ky. That W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Conner &amp; A. N. Conner were subpoenaed as witnesses on behalf of the Commonwealth for the <date when="1864-11">November term 1864</date>, that said witnesses were duly in attendance as required, but the case was continued by the Deft Fightmaster at that term. that said witnesses were again subpoened by the Commonwealth for the <date when="1865-05">May term 1865</date>, and were again duly in attendance ^in the court room^ as required by their subpoena. That the Commonwealths attorney pro tem, (in the absence of R. B Carpenter Com atty for this District) told said witnesses they might go from the<pb/>
<lb/>Court room, to their business, as the case could not be tried at that term of the Court, that after receiving said information from the Commonwealths atty pro tem they did leave the court room, and in a very short time after they left the court room as aforesaid, the case above mentioned in which they were witnesses <hi rend="str">were</hi> was called for trial, and the court ordered an attachment, to issue against both of Said witnesses, W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Conner &amp; A. N. Conner. and they were permitted to give bail in the sum of One hundred dollars each for their appearance on the <date when="1865-11-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of the Novr term <hi rend="str">of</hi>1865</date> of said Court, The order of arrest was issued by the Clerk of said Court, on the <date when="1865-03-10">10<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of March 1865</date>. &amp; the sheriff in obedience to the order of said writ arrested Said W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> &amp; A. N Conner, before the Novr term of said Court. and said W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> &amp; A. N. Conner gave bond to the sheriff in the sum of $100 -- each for <hi rend="str">the</hi> their appearance on the <date when="1865-11-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of the Novr Term 1865</date> of said Court to testify for the Commonwealth,<pb/>
<lb/>that Said witnesses were present in the Court room at the time prescribed in the Said writ, but that during the progress of the Court and a very short time before the Calling of the Case trial, Said witnesses Stepped out of the Court room but did not go farther than the Court house door, where they were when the case was called for trial, &amp; the Judge of our said Court will not permit the Sheriff or other officer to call witnesses at the door, and in consequence thereof the bonds of Said W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> &amp; A. N. Conner. were both forfeited. and now executions are in the hands of the Sheriff against each of said witnesses for $100 -- and Costs -- </p>
<p>We state that Said W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> &amp; A N. Conner are both go<hi rend="str">d</hi>od Citizens of country, and are law abiding men, that they had no intention to violate their bond, or to prevent full &amp; equal Justice being dealt out to the Deft, for his violation of the law, the violation of which has ruined so many of the youth of our state, The Mess<hi rend="str">ns</hi>rs Conner are here now, and are now as they have always been ready &amp; willing<pb/>
<lb/>to do their whole duty, &amp; abide by all orders of the Court, We state this case in our opinion is one which presents the strongest considerations for the interposition of executive Clemency We believe that your Excellency has no desire to see men punished where there is no bad intention on their part -- but on the contrary where they are go<hi rend="str">d</hi>od citizens &amp; inclined to act <hi rend="str">in good</hi> uprightly &amp; fairly. We therefore most earnestly &amp; respectfully ask your Excellency to remit said forfeiture in both Cases, except fees &amp; costs, as in in you power to do</p>
<p>Very Respectfully Yous &amp;c
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J L Griffith
<lb/>John S Day
<lb/>J M Givens
<lb/>J. W. Musselman
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John T. McClintock
<lb/>N T Lindsay S H C
<lb/>J. B. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clintock Dept Shff 
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J D Ware</hi> C H. C. C.
<lb/>C W West D C
<lb/>J S Boyd
<lb/><hi rend="underline">M, Y, Broadwell</hi> M. C
<lb/>E M Bailey
<lb/>Lewis Furnish
<lb/>Wm. N Atkins
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> T. Wilson Clk County Ct
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Nelson H. Rowland</hi></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>N. B.
<lb/>Please direct the remi<hi rend="str">ss</hi>ttance to me as atty.</p>
<p>John T. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clintock</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
