<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1378"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. Newman to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10846</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-316 to MG21-317</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mount Vernon, Rockcastle County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-09-09">9 September 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Mt Vernon Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-09-09">9<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> <hi rend="str">August</hi> Sept<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> 1861.</date>
<lb/>Dear Governor</p>
<p>While at Frankfort I expected to have talked with you in relation to the case of Jacob Scarborough who is now confined in the penatentiary upon a charge of manslaughter. but was waiting to get by mail some petitions that I had left in the hands of one of his sons to be sent me by mail. but I learn since I got home that the petitions were sent directly to you</p>
<p>I learn that all the jury that tried the case signed the petition execpt one and he has gone to camp Robinson. how many others signed I do not know but I learn a great many. I know that all the influential citizens had signed them. but if you want the number of petitioners larger I can get every man in the county to sign them, The jury had great difficulty in convicting him at all, there were five of the jury for acquiting and<pb/>
<lb/>hung on it a day and night.</p>
<p>I have known old man Scarborough all my life. I was raised right by him I know he is an honest man, and an inoffensive harmless man. he is kind hearted, and useful in a neighborhood, he helps to roll all the logs, raise all the house, waits on the sick, digs the graves and buries the dead, &amp; in fact fills all the kindly offices in the neighborhood for which there is no pay, his pardon would meet with the approbation of our entire population. The old man has one fault which every whole souled man has, which is that he some times takes too much tea when with a lot of good friends,</p>
<p>The old man has a large family of children, that are now in a destitute condition and need his assistance</p>
<p>I defended him in court and can safely say there was not a sufficient case made out against him to have convicted him. I will send you a copy of the evidence by the <hi rend="str">evidence by the next</hi><pb/>
<lb/>next mail. that is a copy of the recorded evidence before the court of enquiry which is precisely the same as before the jury</p>
<p>Yours Most Respectfully
<lb/>J. Newman</p>
<p>B. Magoffin Esqr
<lb/>Governor
<lb/>Kentucky<pb/></p>
<p>Scarborough<hi rend="sup">s</hi> case Pen 9. B M</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
