<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-031-0308"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George A. Thurston to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8048</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Appointments by the Governor, Civil Appointments, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R1-416 to R1-417</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Port Royal, Henry County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-08-15">15 August 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Port-Royal Henry Cty. Ky
<lb/><date when="1863-08-15">Aug. 15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>To his excellency the Governor of the Commonwealth of Ky.
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> F. Robinson
<lb/>Dear Sir:</p>
<p>By request of my fellow citizens of Portroyal Precinct Henry Cty, who elected me as one of their Justices of the peace at their <date when="1863-05">May</date> election, I consent to write to you to know the reason your Excellency has never forwarded a commission to me as their umble District officer. </p>
<p>My ocupation is farming in a <unclear/> way, and I am content at home, with no other incumbrance uppon me.</p>
<p>Some of my fellow citizens think you may have been informed, by some person or persons unknown to us; that I was a disloyal citizen and rendered myself so by aiding the<pb/>
<lb/>Rebelion in some way I have always avoided violating any Military law much less civil; the latter, I must confess, I esteem above any other law; the former I can, I must confess, hardly keep up with.</p>
<p>If you excellency has been informed of any disloyal acts on my part we are willing that the matter be investigated. I have not been ten miles from home since Southern Secession took place, I have advised my acquaintances, some one or two who, I supposed were going into the Rebel army, not to go, but stay at home. </p>
<p>I never fed nor harboured rebels. I have always been for the Union as it was and constitution as it is with our father's construction of it. I am opposed to the many acts, which I consider unconstitutional, of this Administration of our Government. I, with my friend Honaker, and<pb/>
<lb/>our constituents, voted the Wickliff ticket. If these acts of ours are <hi rend="str">cont</hi> rebelious, I confess guilt if not, I contend I am clear of disloyalty. I have never, in my life, had any aspirations to office without my request, my fellow citizens elected me by a large majority and if I am commissioned I will serve them to the best of my feeble ability If your excellency can not grant me a commission of course, I shall have done my duty, by applying for it.</p>
<p>Now Sir believe me your most obedient servant.
<lb/>Geo. A. Thurston</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
