<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2018"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George W. Burgess to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6655</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-178 to BR14-179</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Fleming County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-06-24">24 June 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner George W. Burgess States that he is a citizen of Fleming County a farmer residing near the Town of Sherburn, aged about 60 years and in <hi rend="str">a</hi> a feeble state of health &amp; while in such Condition on the <date when="1865-06-02">2nd day of June 1865</date> he was met in the Road by one W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Bateman and without any just Cause or provocation maliciously assaulted, beaten &amp; Bruised by said Bateman, and, in which assault Bateman was the aggressor.</p>
<p>But he went &amp; sent out a warrant upon which by <hi rend="underline">his</hi> ^false^ testimony, <hi rend="underline">he</hi> Bateman Caused your petitioner to be fined ^(as the assailant)^ the Sum <hi rend="str">Six</hi>Seven 50/100 Dollars &amp; Costs, which veredict &amp; Judgt was procured by Deft said Bateman Swearing your petitioner run upon &amp; cut him with a Knife, which was false &amp; untrue -- He, Bateman made the assault himself &amp; badly Cut your petitioner. Your petitioner has always been a peaceable &amp; law abiding Citizen -- he moved for a new trial &amp; the Justice overruled the Same -- Wherefore, he prays for the clemency of your excellency in the premises &amp; a remission of of said fine, <date when="1865-06-24">June 24, 1865</date>.</p>
<p><unclear>Go w</unclear> Burgess</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by G. W. Burgess this <date when="1865-06-24">24. June 1865</date> -- </p>
<p>David McCabe/ <hi rend="underline">Justice F.</hi> <unclear/><pb/></p>
<p>Fleming Ct Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>G. W. Burgess<pb/></p>
<p>Sherburne Fleming Co
<lb/><date when="1865-06-24">June 24, 1865</date>
<lb/>To the Governor
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>I was present to day <unclear><hi rend="str">f</hi>and</unclear> ^witnessed^ a trial between the Commonwealth and Mr. W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Bateman for the assault, &amp;c alluded to in the petition of Mr G. W Burgess herewith, and the proof in my opinion clearly exc<hi rend="str">l</hi>used Mr Burgess and sustained his petition herewith to your excellency &amp; at his instance I so write this believing he ought not to have been fined, or be Compelled to pay it, that Justice demands a remission of the fine against him as asked for in his petition</p>
<p>yours truly &amp; Respectfully
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H, Cord
<lb/><hi rend="underline">County Attorney</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
