<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1079"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William J. Cooper et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5716</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR[11]-165 to BR[11]-166</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Whitley County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-08-24">24 August 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E
<lb/>Bramblett. Governer of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>Your Petitioner W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> J Cooper would State that in the year <date when="1863">1863.</date> he rented a room from Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. Faulkner in Whitley County Ky. where or under which roof S<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Faulkner was Selling Spiritous liquors under a regular lincense that at the time he rented he Suffered &amp; believed that he had a right to Sell liquors by the Small under Faulkners license that under that belief he went on to sell liquor<pb/>
<lb/>and that at the <date when="--04">april</date> Term of the Whitley circuit court he was Indicted for Selling liquors -- by the Small in two Cases and that at the <date when="1864-08">August Term 1864.</date> a judgment was rendered against him in each for twenty Dollars he here Sends a copy of the Indictments &amp; judgment is here fw<hi rend="sup">d</hi>.</p>
<p>He States that he is a poor man haveing a wife &amp; Six Small children that he is not able to pay the fine that he did not intentionaly<pb/>
<lb/>violate the law as Soon as he was informed that he had not the right to Sell liquers he quit &amp; has sold none since nor will he sell any moore</p>
<p>He asks your Excellency in consideration of the premises his condition &amp; -- to remit the fines</p>
<p>Respy W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> J Cooper</p>
<p>Sworn to before me this <date when="1864-08-24">24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> augt 1864</date></p>
<p><unclear>C C Creekman pwc</unclear></p>
<p>we the undrsigned citizens of Whitley County State that<pb/>
<lb/>we are acquainted with W J Cooper the petitioner herein &amp; that the Statements in his Petition are true as we believe &amp; we Respectfully Solicit your Excellency to grant the pray in s<hi rend="sup">d</hi>. Petition</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W. C Gilliss
<lb/>W. H. Randall
<lb/>E. F. Adkins
<lb/>W. H. Wilson
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Isaac. Ellison
<lb/>L, P, Bird
<lb/>S Denham
<lb/>W. C. Murphy
<lb/>J L McCarty sec
<lb/>Isaiah Bird
<lb/>J C Watkins
<lb/><unclear>L J Sutton</unclear>
<lb/>John.. R.. Evans
<lb/><unclear>J C Holly</unclear></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
