<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1152"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John McDonald to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10620</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-303 to MG20-304</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-21">21 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Covington Kenton County <date when="1861-06-21">June 21, 1861</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency B Magoffin Governor of Ky.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner represents that at the present term of the Kenton Circuit Court he was fined in the sum of $50<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> for selling liquor to a minor. He represents that all the proof in the cause was that of one witness, he apparently over 21 yrs. of age, who stated that on <hi rend="underline">one</hi> occasion he had bought liquor of your petitioner but could not tell when it was. He represents that the witness age can not be <hi rend="underline">reasonably</hi> determined his own father being unable to give his age. &amp; further that the father of s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> witness had immediately after the Law went into effect authorized your petitioner to sell to the s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> witness, but could not write your Petitioner represents that he is a law abiding citizen and does not object to the law believing it to be a good one, &amp; he has been long a keeper of a tavern and has never before been called to account for his acts. He is of opinion that he sold no liquor to witness or any other minor during the time, is always careful to follow the law with strictness. He asks that the sd fine be remitted as an act of <hi rend="underline">justice</hi> and commendable<pb/>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">clemency</hi>.</p>
<p>John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Donald</p>
<p>Ben Ballen the witness in the above cause is my son. I did authorise the Petitioner to sell him liquor when required by him as he had been in the habit of drinking occasionally before the law went into effect, and have no objections to his selling it to him. His statements about his age ^as proven^ are correct.</p>
<p>Ben. ^his <hi rend="str">X</hi> mark^ Ballen
<lb/>C. Brossemer. J<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> witness..</p>
<p>We certify that we understand and believe that the statements above are correct, that we are satisfied there are ^strong^ doubts about any offence having been committed, that the witness is illiterate and as we believe not fully to be relied on in his testimony in this cause In fact he did not fix the time of the sale of liquor deformity within the time since <date when="1860-06-01">June 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1860.</date> We think this case eminently worthy of the interference of executive clemency. and hope the prayer of the Petitioner will be granted the Petitioner is &amp; has been ^for nearly 30 years^ a law abiding citisen &amp; the fine to him seems opprissive</p>
<p>C H <unclear/><pb/></p>
<p>I am well acquainted with Petitioner, and know he has kept a well regulated store in Covington for more than ten years, and I have never before known to to be charged with violating the License Laws, and do not believe he has in this case violated the law, only that he sold the boy the liquor on a verbal instead of a written permit, I think the fine ought to be remitted</p>
<p>John. F. Fisk
<lb/>J. G. Carlisle
<lb/>S. C Perrin</p>
<p>I have known the petitioner for many years -- he is a clever upright man but I know nothing of the facts on which his present application is based -- If the prosecuting Attorney thinks it a meritorious case I shall cordially join in its remission</p>
<p>J. W Heventy</p>
<p>It would be an amiable act of mercy in in Governor to grant the prayer of the petition</p>
<p>W. E. Arthur
<lb/>Atty Comth<pb/></p>
<p>I have known M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Donald for nearly twenty years, and believe he has during all of that time, been a law-abiding citizen. He has had license for many years and has always kept an orderly House. <date when="1861-06-24">June 24, 1861</date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J. W. <unclear/></hi></p>
<p>I most heartily concur in the above Statements &amp; trust that the petitioner may meet with Executive clemency. <date when="1861-06-24">June 24<hi rend="sup"> -- </hi>1861.</date></p>
<p>B W Foley</p>
<p>Kenton Cir. Ct
<lb/>Jno. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Donald
<lb/>Petition</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>$50. } Selling liquor to a minor
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-07-02">July 2. 1861</date></p>
<p>12230
<lb/><hi rend="underline">8920</hi>
<lb/>8510 -- </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
