<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-022-0005"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Isham G. Harris, Requisition</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG2903</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Requisitions for the Return of Fugitives from Justice, 1859-1861</collection>
      <idno>MG7-159 to MG7-160A</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Nashville, Davidson County, Tennessee</placeName>
    <date when="1861-03-19">19 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Tennessee,
<lb/>EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENT.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>TO HIS EXCELLENCY, THE GOVERNOR OF Kentucky</p>
<p>Sir: It has been made known to me that a certain Littlebury.B. Andrews of our County of Maury stands charged with having in the month of <gap/> <date when="1859">1859</date> &amp; <date when="1860">18<hi rend="str">5</hi>60</date> willlfully maliciously fraudulently and feloniously harbor hide, conceal, and secrete a certain slave "Friday" the property of one W<hi rend="sup">m</hi>. Biffle as will more fully appear from an authenticated <hi rend="str">copy of</hi> Affidavit herewith transmitted: And whereas, it has been made known to <unclear/> that the said Andrews has fled from justice and is now running at large in the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>Now Therefore, I. Isham G. Harris Governor of the State of Tennessee in pursuance of the Act of Congress, entitled "An Act respecting Fugitives from Justice," do hereby demand, that your Excellency will please cause the said Andrews to be arrested if to be found within the limits of the State over which you <unclear>pres</unclear>ide <unclear/> have him safely delivered to I. M. Ament who is appo<unclear>inted</unclear> <unclear>Agen</unclear>t on the part of this State to receive the said fugitive from the civil authorities of the Sta<unclear>te</unclear> of Kentucky to the end that he may be brought to the State of Tennessee <unclear/> <unclear/> with according to law.</p>
<p><figure type="seal"/></p>
<p>In Testimony Whereof, I have hereunto set my hand and caused the Great Seal of the State to be affixed at NASHVILLE, on the <date when="1861-03-19">19<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of March 18<hi rend="str">5</hi>61</date></p>
<p>BY THE GOVERNOR:
<lb/>Isham G Harris</p>
<p>I <unclear/> Ray Secretary of State.<pb/></p>
<p>State of Tennessee Maury County.</p>
<p>This day before me Stephen D Herndon an acting justice of the peace in and for said State &amp; County personally came William Biffle and made oath in due form of the law that he was the owner in his own right and property of a slave named Friday in said State &amp; County -- that said slave Friday absconded, fled and ran away from his custody and premises and possession in said State &amp; County -- that while and during the time said slave Friday was a fugitive, and runaway slave, to wit from <date when="1859-03-01">first day of March 1859</date> to the <date when="1860-03-01">first day of March 1860</date> in said State &amp; County, one Littlebury B Andrews did wilfully maliciously, fraudulently and feloniously, with force and arms in said county and state aforesaid, harbor, protect, maintain, secret, hide, and conceal said slave Friday, well knowing at the time that said slave Friday was a fugitive, and runaway slave, with the intent to deprive him the said William Biffle of said slave -- and that said Littlebury B Andrews since the commission of said crime and offence, has left and removed himself from the state of Tennesseee and is a now a resident of Graves county State of Kentucky -- </p>
<p><date when="1861-03-15">March 15th 1861.</date></p>
<p>S. D. Herndon J. P <figure type="seal"/>
<lb/>For Maury County,<pb/></p>
<p>Tennessee<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Warrant Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> for Littlebury B. Andrews
<lb/>"Harboring a Slave"
<lb/><date when="1861-03-23">Mar 23d. 1861</date><pb/></p>
<p>Governor of the State of Tennessee:<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>To all who shall see these Presents, -- Greeting:</p>
<p>It is Hereby Certified, That Stephen D. Herndon -- whose genuine signature appears to the above Certificate, is and was at the time of signing the same, and acting justice of the peace in and for said county and State duly elected and commissioned.</p>
<p>And that full faith and credit should be given to his official attestation as such.</p>
<p><figure type="seal"/></p>
<p>In Testimony Whereof I have hereunto set my hand and caused the Great Seal of the State to be affixed at NASHVILLE on this <date when="1861-03-19">19<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of March 1861</date></p>
<p>BY THE GOVERNOR:
<lb/>Isham G Harris</p>
<p>I E R Ray
<lb/>SECRETARY OF STATE.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
