<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1927"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. L. Poynter to Warren</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6564</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-42 to BR14-43</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Cave City, Barren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-05-27">27 May 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Cave City Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1865-05-27">May 27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Maj <gap/> Warren
<lb/>Dr Sir</p>
<p>I have just learned that a petition is being got up for the purpos of getting the Govenor of Ky to pardin one Pat Robinson the man who shot me some fifteen or sixteen months ago and was tried at the Barren circuit court and sentenced to the penitenary for four years I understand that the petition dose not contain one word of <hi rend="underline">truth</hi> they charge that he was tried by a secess jury and did not have a fare trial this is not so<pb/>
<lb/>they charge that the said Robinson once belonged to the southern army and deserted it and joined the union army and that I said somithing to him about it -- not one word of truth in it I did not see him for about five years and did not see him for eight months befor he shot me -- Did not know he was in the Country until the night he came to my house and shot me had no conversation with him he nocked at the door and I opened it &amp; he shot me give no reasons for it I want you to see the Gov and make a statement of the facts you have heard thim -- it was one of the<pb/>
<lb/>most darring attemps to commit murder that has ever occured in this County -- I will if necessary get up a remonstrance agst the petition and now there is not a union in this county but will assign it -- Roberson Irish friends dose not want him turned out -- his character is that of a thief and a bad man -- I do not know who is the mover of this thing but supose it is got up at horse cave Hart Co by some unprincipal vilan -- you will do me the kindness to attend to this -- I supose you are not acting for sutch a man the country is interested in the punishing all<pb/>
<lb/>men who have no use for courts if what they are to be set asid in this way -- Judge Alexander &amp; the Com<hi rend="sup">th</hi>. att<hi rend="sup">o</hi>. can give the facts to the Gov, if he diseres it -- please attend to this on receipt of it and let me hear from you</p>
<p>y
<lb/>W. L. Poynter</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
