<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0092"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Jesse Despain to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14121</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1865</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Green County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E. Bramlette
<lb/>Gov State of Kentucky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>I respectfully request of you, authority to raise an independent company to drive from Green County, (the County of which I am a resident) Ky, the guerrillas who are now infesting that part of this Commonwealth -- killing the soldiers who have served their country for three years -- and doing all manner of unspeakable depredations -- </p>
<p>I wish only to raise this independant company for service in Green County and for no definite length of time I can raise a Company of one hundred men in the county -- who will clothe and mount and subsist themselves to drive the desperate &amp; secret enemy from the borders of our county. And all we ask of you -- is the authority to do this -- You furnishing arms &amp; amunition -- all of which we will account for in proper, Army Regulations Form -- I am late 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Lt. Co. "H". 13<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky. Vols. U. S. A.</p>
<p>I refer you to Genl. E. H. Hobson, if you<pb/>
<lb/>desire any reference for my good character &amp; standing. and efficiency as a soldier</p>
<p>Hoping to receive an answer at your earliest convenience</p>
<p>I remain Govenor
<lb/>Your obedient servant
<lb/>Jesse Despain<pb/></p>
<p>Application <hi rend="underline">of Jesse Despain to raise an independant company for Green County Ky</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
