<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0065"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Edward Stevenson to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8517</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-105</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Camp Chase, Franklin County, Ohio</placeName>
    <date when="1862-08-18">18 August 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Camp Chase, O. <date when="1862-08-18">Aug<hi rend="sup">t</hi> 18<hi rend="sup">th</hi>, 1862</date>, Prison 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">x</hi></hi> Prspt.
<lb/>His Excellency James F. Robinson, Govenor of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>Dear Sir -- I take the liberty of affecting to you, as the chief majistrate of my native State, for protection, under the constitution and laws of the same. I was arrested at my own door in Russellsville, Ky, on the <date when="--06-30">30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of June</date> last, was hurried to the Depot, and there to Bowling Green, where I was informed, by the officer in command, that I was charged with having been a rabbid, or prominent Secessionist, and with have <hi rend="str">seerved</hi> ^acted as^ chairman of a "Home Committee of Safety" -- The first, I positively denied; the second, with some qualifications, I admitted. From Bowling Green -- I was sent on to Louisville, and from there to this prison. Up to this hour, I have had no opportunity of making a defense, such as I am evidently entitled to, as a citizen of Kentucky. Among my many friends, I have <hi rend="underline">some</hi> <hi rend="underline">enemies</hi> -- Hence, my present unhapy condition. There are favorable times for the development of private, personal anamosaties. No one can truthfully charge me with any want of veneration for the constitution of my country, with any lack of devotion to the Federal Union, or with having believed in, or advocated the doctrine of Secession. No one more emphatically condemned, or more deeply deplored, the rash and reckless course of South Carolina and the <unclear>Secessh</unclear> States, than I did myself. True, I was opposed to the war policy, for the preservation of the Union believing, as I did at the time, and as some of the present and best men of the country did, that there was perhaps, a "more excellent way," by which this greatest and most desirable of ^all^ earthly achievements might possible have been attained, <hi rend="underline">without</hi> <hi rend="underline">the</hi> <hi rend="underline">sheading</hi> <hi rend="underline">of</hi> <hi rend="underline">human</hi> <hi rend="underline">blood</hi>! This is the sum of my offending, as far as my sentiments are involved. I never published an article, nor made a speech on the subject of our national difficulties. I condoned but little in relation to those matters, and that, for the most part, in private, deploring the unhapy condition of the country -- If I ever cherished a disloyal sentiment, uttered a disloyal word, or performmed a disloyal act, I am not conscious of having done so. Sure I am, that I have always intended to be loyal to my State and country, whatever may have been my views in relation to the policy of the administration. Respectiing my connection with the "Home Committee," I will only remark that I concented to serve as <pb/>
<lb/>a member of that Body, hoping that I might be instrumental in presenting said and in doing some good; and especially in protecting peaceable citizens, from the violence of misguided and reckless southern citizens and soldiers -- And that this <hi rend="str">disnoble</hi> object was effected, to a greater or less extent, through the influence of the committe, all parties, <hi rend="underline">at</hi> <hi rend="underline">the</hi> <hi rend="underline">time</hi>, even free to admit and ^the fact^ can be established beyond the probability of a reasonable doubt.</p>
<p>I am ready at anytime to give such pledges of loyalty, as may be deemed right and proper; and to bind myself to there faithful performance by such obligations, as may be required. <hi rend="underline">What</hi> <hi rend="underline">more</hi> <hi rend="underline">can</hi> <hi rend="underline">be</hi> <hi rend="underline">asked</hi>?</p>
<p>I am near sixty five years of age, am greatly worn by excessive mental and physical labors. My health at best is exceedingly feeble -- And if not released from the deprivations disabilities, and manifold afflictions of my present condition, I must soon <hi rend="str">sink</hi> come down to an untimely grave. If you can do any thing for my release, as I trust you can, I beg your interfearence in my behalf.</p>
<p>Yours truly and respectfully
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Edward Stevenson</hi></p>
<p>May I hope to hear from you touching this matter?</p>
<p>E. S.</p>
<p>Ed Stevenson
<lb/>Columbus</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
