<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2049"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. C. Harris to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9125</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-66 to MG24-67</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1862-06-20">20 June 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Hon B Magoffin
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Robert C Harris would most respectfully State to your Excellency that ^at^ the <date when="1861-11">November Term 1861</date> of the Marion Circuit Court the Grand Jury empanneled at Said ^Term^ found and returned to Said Court two Indictments against John. L Ham for Selling whiskey to Soldiers. Said Ham is a youth about 18 or 19 years of age and was employed by your Petitioner to attend to his Bar Room Kept in his Hotel in Lebanon Ky. During the Sitting of the Grand Jury at Said <date when="1861-11">November</date> Term, and before Said Indictments were found and returned into Court, Thomas C Woods Esq who was then and is now County attorney for Marion County, came to your Petitioner and told him that the Grand Jury was about to Indict your Petitioner, but that he had been Sent by the Grand Jury to all<pb/>
<lb/>the men who kept bar-rooms and were Selling liquors to request them to close their houses, and if they closed in good faith that the proceedings by the Grand Jury would Stop. Your Petitioner made that agreement with Said Woods and closed his Bar-room, and the Key was delivered to Col S S Fry of the 4' Ky Regt who kept it in his possession for a considerable time Now your Petitioner would State that he entered into Said agreement with Said Woods in good faith and carried out the agreement on his part, but notwithstanding Said agreement the Indictments were returned to Court, and your Petitioner being ignorant of the fact, and having no notice as to the Indictments being found, at the <date when="1862-05">May Term 1862</date> judgement was rendered against Said Ham by default, he having been Summoned to appear, but not knowing what to do did not appear, neither did he let your Petitioner know any<pb/>
<lb/>thing about it, and your Petitioner Knew Knothing of the matter until after judgement had been rendered, believing all the time that Said agreement entered into with Said Woods had been faithfully carried out. Your Petitioner would further State that during last winter after ^all^ the Barrooms were again opened, a great many Soldiers were Stationed in the immediate vicinity of Lebanon, and other Bar Keepers Sold them whiskey in great quantities and no regard whatever was paid to the law, and at the <date when="1862-05">May Term 1862</date> of said Court the Grand Jury for Said Term returned &amp; no Indictments against any person whatever for a violation of that law Your Petitioner would further State that Said Ham is a poor Youth and totally unable to pay Said fines, he has no property of any kind, and relies Solely upon me for a Support and maintainance, he being the nephew of your Petitioner. Your Petitioner appends hereto a<pb/>
<lb/>a copy of Said judgements, and also the Statement of said Thomas C. Woods Esq County Attorney -- Now Your Petitioner would pray that in view of the above facts that you would interpose your Executive clemency and grant to Said Ham Such remission of said fines as your Excellency may deem proper just and equitable in the premises, and in duty <hi rend="str">a</hi>bound will ever pray &amp;c -- </p>
<p>R C Harris</p>
<p>Sworn to before me to R C Harris this <date when="1862-06-20">20<hi rend="sup">th </hi>day of June 1862 -- </date></p>
<p>H. H Hughes clk M C C</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M.</p>
<p>Marion Cir Ct
<lb/>$25
<lb/>$10. } Selling liquor
<lb/>Jno L Harris</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-07-22">July 22 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
