<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0332"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. E. Cooper et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4451</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-31</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1863-12-20">20 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Governor Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E Bramlett</p>
<p>Your Petitioner John Hagans Respectfully States that at the <date when="1863-09">September Term of the Magoffin Circuit Court 1863</date> that there was a Judgement rendered in Said Court in favor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky and against your Petitioner John Hagans for the sum of ($78<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi>) seventy eight dollars and cost of the proceeding in Said Court, Said fine was rendered against your Petitioner Hagans under these circumstances (viz)</p>
<p>Your Petitioner made application to the county court of Magoffin County for a change in the Public highway runing ^on the land^ <hi rend="str">near the mansion</hi> of Said Hagans, and the court awarded him an order to make Said change, He immediately proceeded to make Said change in the said road and in making the same he run his fense across the old road before the viewers of said road filed their report to the court State that after Said road was completed Said County Court refused to accept the same and the county attorney told your Petitioner that if he would make a small change at the lower end of said road that then the court would receive the same which your Petitioner immediatelty done and thought that said road was received by said Court according to the contract entered into by the attorney for the county and this Petitioner</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Hagans believed that he would have no further difficulty about Said road and he says that he was ignorant of the law in such cases and placed implicit confidence in the county attorney Statements and from the statements of the attorney for the county, he thought nomore about said road believeing that it was all fixed up according to the laws of the country, he therefore asks your Excellency to remit said fine of $78<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> and that all officers and persons be prohibited from the collection of the same</p>
<p>The under Signed Petitioners Joins in the prayer with said Hagans for the remission of said fine, and asks your Excellency to remit said fine and that all persons be prohibited and restrained from the collection of the same, they state that said Hagans, like many others is tolerably poor</p>
<p>Wherefore they pray as above &amp; will forever pray for the remision of said fine
<lb/><date when="1863-12-20">Dec 20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1863</date>.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J. E. Cooper
<lb/>Wallis Baley, Clk. M. C. C
<lb/>B F Howard Ds M. Co
<lb/>R L Cooper
<lb/>Isaac C. Howard
<lb/>Thomas B Cooper
<lb/>Stepton ^his X mark^ Arnett
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Havila Cook
<lb/>Joshua Kays
<lb/>W H Harris
<lb/>John Samuels
<lb/>James Gutter
<lb/>Isieh Salyer
<lb/>Richard Whitt
<lb/>Solomon C Bently<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>If Your Excellency has the kindness to Remit fine Send the same to MountSterling Ky care of J W Hazelrigg as there is no mails coming to my county yours very Respectfully</p>
<p>John Hagan</p>
<p>Magoffin Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John Hagans</p>
<p>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette</p>
<p><date when="1863-09">Sept Term 1863</date>
<lb/>$78.
<lb/>Obstructing Highway</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
