<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2770"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Jacob Percifull and Nancy Percifull to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7407</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-26 to BR17-27</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency, Thomas E Bramlett
<lb/>Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. -- </p>
<p>May the Lord bless and prosper you as the Ruler of this State, and grant to you and your family long life and happiness in this world, and a free and safe admission to the claims of eternal glory. Your honorable petitioner Jams A S Persifull, a native of Harlan county, a soldier, bearing the rank of 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Sergeant in the Confederate army, has been indicted by the Knox Court for treason, and has been compelled to fly from his home on account thereof. The supplicant has taken the Amnesty oath of the President of the United States, and hoped he would be permitted to return home and remain with his aged parents, where his assistance would be greatly needed. We, the undersigned, therefore respectfully beg and pray that Execcutive clemency may be extended to him, and that he may be permitted to return to the loved at home, and there remain unmolested. He has done no act that deserved censure, except being in the rebel army, and has always been a good citizen honored and respected by all who knew him. But we repeat he has erred, the Executive of the nation has forgiven him, and we think the sky of your Excellency will not be less clear, when you can look back and have the gratification to know that by your deeds you have merited the thanks and prayer of happy and united families</p>
<p>Jacob Percifull
<lb/>Nancy Percifull</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens and neighbors of the petitioner, believe the statements of the foregoing petition to be true, and pray to be heard in behalf of the petitioners.</p>
<p>A A Clewell 1
<lb/>Will Campbell 2
<lb/>R <unclear/> C<unclear/> 3<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J w Denham 4
<lb/>w m Denham 5
<lb/>ambros Miracle 6
<lb/>Thomas N Miracle 7
<lb/>James C miracle 8
<lb/>James E Boatwright 9
<lb/>Bannt S duret 10
<lb/>Elias Duret 11
<lb/>Elias S Duret 12
<lb/>Calvin Duret 13
<lb/>Barnet Arnet 14
<lb/>Bretcher hoskins 15
<lb/>Elijah Green Jr 16
<lb/>John M Green 17
<lb/>Joseph Purcifull 18
<lb/>Hiram Hoskins 19
<lb/>Woodard Lyttle 20
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Baker <hi rend="str">30</hi>21
<lb/>William Taylor <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>23
<lb/>Silas Herick <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>24
<lb/>James Johnson <hi rend="str">60</hi>25
<lb/>Daniel Johnson 26
<lb/>William Johnson 27
<lb/>Patrick Johnson 28
<lb/>Gabriel Johnson 29
<lb/>Henry Purcifull 30
<lb/>W. K. Purcifull <hi rend="str">40</hi> 31
<lb/>Zekiel Emry <hi rend="str">4</hi> 32
<lb/>Thomas Emrey 33
<lb/>James Emrey 34
<lb/>William Jenkins 35
<lb/>Charvel Jinkens 36
<lb/>Hilrey Herst 37
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Hiram Hoskins 38
<lb/>Jefferson Hoskins 39
<lb/>Carlow Britton 40
<lb/>William Turner 4<hi rend="str">0</hi>1
<lb/>George B Turner 42
<lb/>Asher Howard 43
<lb/>John Chadwell 44<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>James Percifull
<lb/>Nancy Percifull
<lb/>My post office
<lb/>address
<lb/>Cumberland Ford
<lb/>Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
