<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2010"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Peach, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9086</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-5 o MG24-6</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mercer County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-06-06">6 June 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against } Affidavit.
<lb/>James Shackelford.</p>
<p>The Affiant William Peach states, that upon the day <hi rend="str">upon the day</hi> on which George Divine was killed or said to be killed by James Shackelford, who is now in the state prison of Kentucky that this affiant had been to a Barbecue some quarter of a mile below where Divine was killed. That late on the evening he with several others Shackelford among the number got on their horses and started home -- that on their direct road home they had to pass a grocery store kept by a certain John Hale. -- they stopped at at the grocery and sitting on their horses called for something to drink and it was brought out to them in the road or to the fence -- about this time a certain John Divine a blood relation of George Devine called to Shackelford, and told him to get down, that he wanted to see him, Divine <hi rend="str">at the time</hi> had his knife open in his hand at the time and was evidently much excited. About this time the said John Divine got into a fight with a certain Robert Robertson immediately after this he heard shuffling going in the road below him &amp; he turned to see what was going on, when he saw three or four men have Shackelford by the head or the hair of his head dragging him across the road &amp; he struggling to get away first falling &amp; then getting up as best he could until he was draged or pulled by them<pb/>
<lb/>across the road where he fell they kicking him or at him all the time. How Shackelford got up this Affiant does not know. -- did not see Shackelford stab George Divine. So far as this Affiant saw or heard and he was right upon the ground. remembers nothing that Shackelford said or did to provoke a quarrel and all he saw him do was in his own defence,</p>
<p>He did not see Jacob Claunch who was the prinicpal witness in the prosectution on the ground at the time of the fight That so far as he could see the fight and fuss was commenced by the <hi rend="underline">Divines</hi>,</p>
<p>William Peach</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Mercer County To. wit.</p>
<p>This day personally appeared before the undersigned Presiding Judge of the Mercer County Court William Peach and made oath ^that^ the statements contained in the foregoing affidavit were true to the best of his knowledge and belief</p>
<p>Given under my hand this <date when="1862-06-06">6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of June 1862.</date></p>
<p>Chr Chinn P J M C C<pb/></p>
<p>Commonwealth
<lb/>against } Aff.
<lb/>Jas Shackelford.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Issue pardon
<lb/>B. M.</p>
<p>Felony
<lb/>3 ys Penty</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-06-19">June 19. 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
