<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2651"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. C. Gilliss et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7288</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-263 to BR16-264</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thomas E. Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned petitioners, would respectfuly represent to Your Excellency, That Daniel Steele a Citizen of this (Whitley County) has been Convicted and sentenced to Two years imprisonement in the State prison, charged with having committed a robbery in the adjoining County of Laurel.</p>
<p>We will not here give a synopsis of the proof, or facts of the case, understanding that the facts in proof on trial, together with the instructions of the court will herewith be by others in possession of the same fully presented to Your Excellency</p>
<p>Some of the undersigned heard the trial others saw a synopsis of the proof and instructions of the court whilst the remaining portion of those hereto subscribed have all as we are fully satisfied heard full and fair representations of the facts of the case, and we all concur in saying that we conceive that in all justice the said Daniel Steele did not at the hands of the Jury receive that Justice which the merits of his case demanded or he would immediately have been fully acquitted, Those of us who heard the trial did not believe that the Jury would hesitate a moment in agreeing on his acquittal, and we still confidently believe that it was only the deep seated prejudice which at the time pervaded the Community in which<pb/>
<lb/>was tried -- a prejudice incident to the lawless acts of the times -- which caused his conviction -- </p>
<p>Believing that Steele's Sentence and imprisonment are unjust, that he committed no felony in the case charged and on which he was tried, but that his sentence was the offspring of undue prejudice as aforesaid, We Respectfully pray your Excellency to pardon him; believing that his is an extreme case and demands the interposition of Executive Clemency</p>
<p>Signed
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W. C. Gilliss
<lb/>James Underwood
<lb/>M. J. Knight
<lb/>J W. Mitchell
<lb/>Henry. L Gilliss
<lb/>Thomas Rockhold
<lb/>A. B. King
<lb/>J B Creekmore
<lb/>H G Creekmore
<lb/>Cager. Logan
<lb/>Stephen Dorrs
<lb/>Oliver Steele
<lb/>Pleasant M. C. Farlan
<lb/>George Helton
<lb/>Peter Helton
<lb/>Hiram Childers
<lb/>F G Barton
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J, C, Watkins clk
<lb/>George Sears
<lb/>Zechariah Mitchell
<lb/>John P. Hart
<lb/>Alexander Mitchell
<lb/>John. Wilborn
<lb/>William Mitchell
<lb/>Green Elliott
<lb/>James Lee
<lb/>Andrew J. Barton
<lb/>S. L Benjey
<lb/>John Barton
<lb/>John Steele
<lb/>James W. Polly
<lb/>Matthew Snyder
<lb/>.H. B. Barton
<lb/>Joseph Hart
<lb/>Daniel Barton
<lb/>Samuel Harmon<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>M. J. Sawyers
<lb/>Anderson B. Hart
<lb/>Thomas Walters
<lb/>Jones Gaines
<lb/>A. C. King</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
