<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2452"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. E. Arthur et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7089</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-404 to BR15-405</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-16">16 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Covington, Ky. <date when="1865-10-16">Oct 16<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>To the Hon. Thomas E. Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of the Com'th of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>The Undersigned, Citizens of Covington, respectfully represent that in the Circuit Court for the County of Kenton, held in this City, at the <date when="1865-09">September Term thereof 1865</date>, Thomas Estep was tried, convicted and fined $50, on an Indictment for, with a pistol, shooting at James Westowrth with the intent to Kill or wound him. These are substantially the material facts proven in the trial: -- Wentworth without provocation struck Frank Estep, brother of Thomas, a violent blow in the face &amp; eye, causing Frank to reel and fall, whereupon Thomas instantly drew and fired, two shots -- one of these went in the ground, the other in the air, and once the pistol missed fire, Wentworth was not five feet from him when the firing occurred. One witness said the pistol was in the direction of Wentworth -- two witnesses said it was not pointed at<pb/>
<lb/>Wentworth, and one that Thomas Estep did not shoot at Wentworth, but shot in the air, and one that he knocked the pistol up and the charge went in the air.</p>
<p>The jury were of the opinion that the evidence authorized a conviction and so found. It was contended for Estep, that, for the sole purpose of protecting his brother from further injury, he fired in the air to intimidate Wentworth, and did not fire at him. This was Thomas Estep solemn assurance to his Counsel and <hi rend="str">an</hi> Estep is a truthful man. In the Mayors Court of this City Thomas Estep was fined $50 for carrying that pistol on that occasion, and he has paid that fine.</p>
<p>These fines are a grievous burden to him. Your Excellency will learn from this petition that they grew out of an unforeseen Casualty with which Thomas Estep was complicated solely by an involuntary impulse and to save his brother from grievous bodily harm. He is advised that Executive clemency may relieve him of $35 of the fine<pb/>
<lb/>in the Circuit Court, exclusive of fees and costs. To that end he respectfully invokes your clemency, and we unite with him in this his peititon, and warmly Commend him to Executive favor as a person worthy of the clemency sought.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Names</hi>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W E Arthur
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Geo T. Perkins</hi>
<lb/>A. C. Ellis
<lb/>W. H. Tebbs
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J. W. Menzies</hi>
<lb/>Levi F. Daugherty
<lb/>H S Halley
<lb/>H C. Timberlake
<lb/>Ben Moore
<lb/>David DeGarno
<lb/>Joel H Meglasson
<lb/>Ben. L. Meglasson
<lb/>Tho. L. Arnold
<lb/>Sam<hi rend="sup">l</hi> H Stout
<lb/>R Simmons
<lb/>F. Smith
<lb/>W. Smith
<lb/>W A, Kennedy
<lb/><hi rend="underline">S C Perrin</hi>
<lb/><cb n="2"/><hi rend="underline">M. J. Dudley</hi>
<lb/>R. K. Irwin
<lb/>B Young
<lb/>Charles. W. Clayton
<lb/>Jno E Hamilton
<lb/>J. E Clendening
<lb/>David M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Kay
<lb/>Jos Havlin
<lb/>J H Easton
<lb/>John B. Casey &amp; Son
<lb/>John Clayton
<lb/>J. O'Hara Jr
<lb/>F B Rust
<lb/>R. Richardson
<lb/>M. D. Moore
<lb/><hi rend="underline">John Todd</hi>
<lb/>Geo Magee
<lb/>John. C. Taylor
<lb/>Denis P. Noonan
<lb/>Chas G Wallace<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Kenton Cir Court
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Thomas Estep et, al,
<lb/>To } <hi rend="underline">Petition</hi>
<lb/>The Governer<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>$50,
<lb/><date when="1865-10-18">18 Oct /65</date>
<lb/>Remit</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
