<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1099"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Dennis C. Keley to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10567</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-204 to MG20-206</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-05-07">7 May 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellancy Governor M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin</p>
<p>Your petitioner D. C. Kelly would respectfully state that, say a Couple of terms ago of the Jefferson Circuit Court one P. E Kelly was indicted for a felony in s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Court -- that s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> P. E. Kelly has a fimily consisting of a wife &amp; <hi rend="str">several</hi> one child<hi rend="str">ren</hi> who were entirely dependant on him for a support.</p>
<p>That at the earnest solicitations of his family and purely as an act of Kindness to them, your petitioner was induced to become surety and did become surety for the accused in the final sum of six hundred dollars for, his appearance to stand his trial.</p>
<p>The accused did appear at the previous term to wit the <date when="1861-01">January term 1861</date> -- that for some cause or other the cause was Continued to the present <date when="1861-05">May</date> term thereof. Your petitioner would further state that the accused had always evinced a disposition to appear and surrender himself into the custody of the court purposely to stand his trial. That your petitioner <unclear/> within a few days last past saw him daily &amp; felt quite certain that the accused would appear and surrender himself into custody.</p>
<p>Your petitioner would further state that to his utter astonishment &amp; surprize the accused a few days since (as he learned with great regret) left the state of Kentucky, has abandoned his family, and Consequently did not appear and surrender himself in the custody of the court upon the calling of<pb/>
<lb/>docket thereof which s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> calling as had on Monday the <date when="1861-05-06">6th of May 1861.</date></p>
<p>That a forfeiture of the recognizance was had and a scire facias was ordered thereon</p>
<p>Your petitioner would respectfully state that he has a family consisting of a wife &amp; five children entirely dependant on him for a support, that he is a poor man, is dependant on his daily earnings from quite a small business to support them with. He would further state that should a judgment be had against him on the forfeited recognizance &amp; he have to pay the same it will strip him of all his hard earnings &amp; leave him &amp; his family in a destitute condition.</p>
<p>In view of the facts your petitioner has no other alternative left but to <hi rend="str">ask</hi>respectfully to ask your Excellancy to extend to him such relief as would be right &amp; proper by asking your Excellancy to remit s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> forfeiture or so much thereof as your Excellancy may think right &amp; proper in view of the premises; again respectfully reiterating that should he be obliged to pay the amount of s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> forfeited recognizance it will take all of his hard earnings to liquidate the same &amp; leave him utterly destitute of the means necessary to support his family with. Hoping that your Excellancy will favorably consider his case as in duty bound he will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Jefferson County } Sct</p>
<p>Dennis C Kelly says the<pb/>
<lb/>statements made in the foregoing petition are true as he verily believes</p>
<p>Dennis. C. Kelly</p>
<p>Subscribed &amp; sworn to before me this <date when="1861-05-07">7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of May 1861</date></p>
<p>Jo<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Clement J. P J C</p>
<p>We the undersigned state that we are acquainted with D. C. Kelly and would say that he is a worthy man and in our opinion deserving of any clemancy that his Excellancy the Governor of Kentucky may think proper to extend to him.</p>
<p>Louisville, <date when="1861-05-07">May 7th 1861.</date></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Fred Webber
<lb/>J. A. Cord
<lb/>M Mitchell
<lb/>W. H. Sparke
<lb/>Jno T. Gaughan
<lb/>W. C. Perrin
<lb/>R. C. Mathews
<lb/>A W Kayes
<lb/>John Guinan
<lb/>John. C. Gils.
<lb/>Edw A Preuss.
<lb/>John Kuhbanck
<lb/><cb n="2"/>W P Boone
<lb/>James M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Dermott
<lb/><hi rend="underline">C. Ripley</hi>
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Musselman
<lb/>Jno. S. Carpenter
<lb/>R. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee
<lb/><hi rend="underline">William</hi> <hi rend="underline">Conway</hi>
<lb/>W. H. Stokes
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W. N. Haldeman</hi>
<lb/>John Snyder
<lb/>Chas G <hi rend="underline">Smith</hi><milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Respite 12 mo
<lb/>B, M.
<lb/>Jefferson Cir. Ct
<lb/>$600 } Recog
<lb/>D. C. Kelly
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-05-13">May 13. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
