<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-019-0133"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. S. Watson and B. H. Stoval to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1439</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG5-217 to MG5-220</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Blandville, Ballard County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-08-26">26 August 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Blandville Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-08-26">Aug 26<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 61</date>
<lb/>His Excelency
<lb/>Beriah Magoffin.
<lb/>Govenor of the Comth of Ky</p>
<p>Sir in Compliance with the request of Senator Johnson we send a certificate of our arrest and detention at Cairo Illo (by the Federal troops).</p>
<p>Early in the morning of the 21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> inst. there was Considerable excitement in our village from the Heavy Canonading and incesent fireing of Musketry in the direction of Cairo Illo and Birds Point Mo. And to learn the Cause of it we Mounted our Horses and rode down to the River we had Scarcely reached the River, when Met with Some of the Citizens of our town (Blandville) riding down the river in great haste they informed us that a company of Soldiers had Just landed off the Ferry Boat from Cairo and were coming down the river. we paid no attention to them but rode on in the direction of the Soldiers. as we had Some businness in the Neighbourhood. and intending to return Via James House<pb/>
<lb/>a short distance over there was a Horseman Riding very Swift, Came in Site of Us. Halted and blew a very shrill whistle, immediately returned. Still riding very fast and then there Came about 100 or 150 Men Armed with Muskets Came running up on us they demanded of Stovall his pocket Book and papers J. Watson ^had^ none with me. he (Stovall) had a small memorandom book, A Muster Roll belonging to Jos Bishop<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Company of Home Gards and a letter from Some of the Boys at Camp Boon <unclear/> there was two negores in the Company ^with provisions^ and while the officers were consulting in regard to the disposition to be made with us. one of the Negroes Said By God if they turned all of the Prisoners loose we had as well close the war and go home. after the Examination of the papers we were Marched up the river to the ferry ordered to dismount and Sent Cairo the Head Quarters of Col Ogelsby After our arrival, the Men were asked what we were, they Said Prisoners of War this was about (Noon) Colonel Ogelsby requested us to remain until he returned as he had Some important business at Mound City and would return Soon. and have a conversation with us we hoped he would Soon return as we both had Families. Would hear of our arrest and have Some<pb/>
<lb/>Some uneasiness. Near dark the Company Crossed the River with our stores. it was Some time after dark when the Col returned to Head Quarters. he questioned us some time about Cavalry men being in our County and about Union Men being in danger of Cessesionists, to which we told him it was all false, there was no Horse Company<hi rend="sup">s</hi> at this time in the County and we knowed Union Men were perfectly safe. </p>
<p>We told him we were detained from our Businsses and wanted to be released one of us was Post Master and the other constable and belonged to no Companies Contrary to the laws of Ky or the U. S. that we were citizens of Ky and wished to abide by the laws of the Same. that if the Neutrality of Ky Could be observed and Keep out of the difficulty we would be satisfied. The Colo did not Speak well of the Neutrality of Ky. that it was all a Humbug. of Course there was no dispute on that point as we believe it nothing but a <hi rend="str">pith</hi> mith, Col Ogelsby told us if we would bring a man with whom he was acquainted to endorse for our honstey he would release us that he did not want to punish Honest Men= that there had been Men<pb/>
<lb/>Communicating with a Spie in his Camp and that he intended to have them at all Hazards. and this was why he had Sent his men to Ky -- we referd him to C, S, Marshall Judge of this County who is a Gintleman. well know in this Country we sent a telegram to Judge Marshall who went immediately to our relief The Colonel treated us like Gentlemen and Some of the officers were very polite to us= Some others treated us like felons make insulting remarks. So that we could hear them. which was there <hi rend="underline">intention</hi> (I suppose -- ) I (Stovall) asked the liberty of looking throug a Magnifying Glass at Some Men Crossing the River which was very Vulgarly refused. We were Keped in the St Charles Hotel and had the Fare that the officers had only slept on a cot. we Eat two Meals while in Custody Suppose we were there about Forty-four Hours.</p>
<p>Our Horses were badly fed and one of them Badly Abused his head is badly Bruised and one his Eyes badly<pb/>
<lb/>His Eyes badly Hurt I cant tell whether it is out or not we went back to Head Quarters to see Col Ogelsby about the damage of the Horse he was gone but am satisfied he would have given Satisfaction for the damage done him, as I think the Col is a gentleman more than worthy of the position he now fills. Although in a bad Cause he will long ^be^ Known and respected after the close of this War let it Terminate as it May. but May the curses of an avenging God fall heavily upon Some of the other officers. (Stovall)</p>
<p>This we Humbly Submit to your Honor with our warmest respects and regards</p>
<p>W. S. Watson
<lb/>B. H. Stoval</p>
<p>P. S.
<lb/>All the Company were Germans or Men of Some foreign tong, the was only one white man and that was the Horseman</p>
<p>W J S<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Blandville US
<lb/><date when="1861-08-26">Aug 26<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 61</date>
<lb/><cb n="2"/>B. H. Stovall free
<lb/>Free</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Hon. Mr Johnson
<lb/>Ky. Senator
<lb/>Paducah
<lb/>Kentucky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
