<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2260"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. H. Perkins et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9336</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-424 to MG24-425</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Kenton Circuit Court at Covington 
<lb/>To his Excellency B. Magoffin
<lb/>Governor of Ky</p>
<p>The undersigned jurors who were sworn to try and did try David Hale at the present term of the court <hi rend="underline">upon</hi> <hi rend="underline">a</hi> <hi rend="underline">charge</hi> <hi rend="underline">of</hi> <hi rend="underline">having</hi> <hi rend="underline">counterfeit</hi> money in his possession with intent to pass the same would respectfully represent that the proof tended to show that the defendent was a hard working man a blacksmith by trade, that on the day of his arrest he had been drinking frequently with two or three young men two of whom wree witnesses for the Commonwealth in this case aginst him that said two witnesses were <hi rend="underline">stool pigeons</hi> for the Marshall of the city in an attempt to catch another man The testimoney also tended to show that said Hale had never been charged with any offence or even suspicioned there with that said Hale was a Marshall who supported his family by his labour and kept them responsibly. That he has a wife and three children.</p>
<p>The undersigned jurors respectfully suggest that no beneficial result can be obtained by the confinement of the prisoner according to the verdict of the jury and that as his character has heretofore been good and as there was no attempt upon the part of the prisoner to pass the counterfeit money found in his possession they therefore warranted in asking your Excellency to interpose your perrogative in behalf of said Hale and pardon and restore him to his helpless family for whom he has heretofore provided as shown by the proof in the case</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/><cb n="2"/>C H. Railey
<lb/>F. Dresmann
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J. H. Perkins, Foreman
<lb/>S. Reynolds
<lb/>Robert Howe
<lb/>T Egelston
<lb/>John Cain
<lb/>J. W. Brooks
<lb/>A Craig
<lb/>B. Vastine
<lb/>W. H. Tebbs<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>The foregoing Eleven names are the names of Eleven of the Jurymen that tried David Hale</p>
<p>Att J. M. Blackburn D. C<pb/>
<lb/>Petitiion of Jury in Behalf of David Hale -- </p>
<p>Hale's Case Covington Pen<hi rend="sup">y</hi> -- </p>
<p>C H Railey
<lb/>C Scott
<lb/>F Dresman</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
