<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3266"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Joseph Stacy and Sampson Ingle, Affidavits</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5385</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-68 to BR42-69</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Owsley County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Ky
<lb/>Owsley County } Affidavits</p>
<p>Joseph Stacy being duly Sworn <hi rend="str">states</hi> states that on the night the Satchel was taken for which William Ingle was prosicuted and Sintanced to confinement in the Penetntuary that he was Boarding at a private house about one quarter of a mile from the Camps where the Satchel was taken and that William Single was at the Same house,, and Remained there all night and Slept in the Same Bed with me and between me and an other man and I am Sertain he was not out of the Room during the Night and from Some time in the Evening untill the next day and that William Ingle was not at nor in the Camps from two or three oclock in the Evening untill the next day.. I have been well acquainted with William Ingle for Several years he was allways Called on honest Sober discreet good citizens..<pb/>
<lb/>and a loyal man during this Rebelion and further Saith not</p>
<p>Joseph ^X his mark^ Stacy</p>
<p>Sampson Ingle ^being duly sworn^ states he was a member of the 47<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Regment and borading at the Same house at the same time the the Satchel was taken for which William Ingle was arrested and penetentured and being presant and hearing the Statements of Joseph Stacy adopts his Statements in every particular</p>
<p>Sampson ingle</p>
<p>Sworn to by Joseph Stacy and Sampson ingle before me this the <date when="1865-05-18">18" day of May 1865</date></p>
<p>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Murrell P. J. <hi rend="sup">O</hi>. <hi rend="sup">C</hi></p>
<p>I do certify that I am acquainted with Joseph Stacy and have been for sometime and know that his statements are in titled to credit</p>
<p>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Murrell P. J. <hi rend="sup">O</hi>. <hi rend="sup">C</hi><pb/>
<lb/>Owsley Ct Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W. Ingle
<lb/><date when="1865">65</date>
<lb/>Pet<pb/>
<lb/>To his excelency Thomas E. Bramlett
<lb/>Governor of the Commonwealth of Ky.</p>
<p>We your petioners would respectfully ask your Excelency to pardon William Ingle,, a young man that is confined in the penetentria charged and convicted for Stealing a Satchel,, he is a citizen of Perry County Ky and the son of William Ingle S<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> a good honest old Husband man, a citizen of owsley County Ky. We believing that the young man W<hi rend="underline">m</hi> Ingle, is Wrongfully punishing,, do ask your excelincies clemency in pardoning the young man,, W<hi rend="underline">m</hi> Ingle in evidence of which we have subscribed our names }</p>
<p>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Murrell Judge of the owsley County Court
<lb/>James M Sebastiion Dept O C C
<lb/>S. P. Hogg</p>
<p>I am not acquainted with William Ingle but learn that he was a soldier in the 47<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky. and was tried and sentenced to the Penetentiary from the Fayatte Circuit County and that the statements of Joseph Stacy and Sampson Ingle were not before the trial Jury. I feel assured that the foregoing statemts are true from the statemts of the men who have signed the above petition I would respectfully ask your Executive Clemency is Ingles behalf</p>
<p>Isaac N. Cardwell</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
