<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0600"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William H. Randall to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9052</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-446</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Laurel County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>His Excellency
<lb/>J F. Robinson.
<lb/>Frankfort Ky</p>
<p>I enclose you the petition of Wilcome Mullins for the remittance of two fines against in the Laurel Circuit Court. One of $15 the other of $50 -- Also the Petition of Wesley Mullins to be remitted of $50. and Moses Mullins of $15 -- </p>
<p>Whilst I am opposed upon all occasions to any disturbance of Religious worship, for which the fines above of $15 were assessed I have no hesitation in saying these fines ought to be remitted, I know that the leading members of the church when the supposed disturbances occurred joined in the petition for the remittance of the fines. I mean the petitions upon which the respite was granted</p>
<p>The fines of $50 ought never to have been assessed and would not have been if this case had been properly managed I respectully refer you ^to^ the original petition -- But the truth is the men are absolutely unable to pay the fines without distroying their families, it is time their crops were taken cart fall by the rebel army and their neighbors fared no better -- I do hope you will remit the fines -- </p>
<p>I am very Respetfully your
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W. H Randall</hi><pb/></p>
<p>His Excellency Gov Robinson
<lb/>Frankfort
<lb/>Ky</p>
<p>Fines Remitted</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
