<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-006-0047"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Willis M. Hughes, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1093</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Requisitions for the Return of Fugitives from Justice, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR6-53</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Charlestown, Clark County, Indiana</placeName>
    <date when="1864-10-06">6 October 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Indiana
<lb/>Couty of Clark } ss</p>
<p>Willis M. Hughes upon oath says that on the <date when="1864-08-18">18<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of August 1864</date> at Clark county state of Indiana William J. Roberts, did feloniously steal take and drive away one bay horse of the value of One hundred and thirty five dollars the property of the said Willis M. Hughes -- And affiant further says that after committing the felony above charged, to wit on the <date when="1864-08-19">19. day of August 1864</date> the said William J. Roberts fled from the state of Indiana to the county of Jefferson in the state of Kentucky where he now is, as affiant verily believes -- </p>
<p>Willis M. Hughes
<lb/><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp"><unclear/></note></p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this <date when="1864-10-06">6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of October 1864.</date></p>
<p>Joel M. Smith J. P.</p>
<p>State of Indiana
<lb/>Clark County } s. s. -- </p>
<p>I Campbell Hay Clerk of the Circuit court, in and for said county, hereby certify that Joel M. Smith Esquire, before whom the foregoing affidavit was made, was at the time of the making therof, to wit on <date when="1864-10-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of October 1864,</date> an<pb/>
<lb/>acting Justice of the Peace in and for said County duly Elected commissioned &amp; Sworn, and that full faith &amp; credit should be given to his official acts as such Justice and that the signature above purporting to be his is genuine.</p>
<p>Witness my hand and the seal of said Court, affixed at Charlestown this <date when="1864-10-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of October 1864</date></p>
<p>Campbell Hay Clk
<lb/><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp"><unclear/></note></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
