<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1597"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James Hasson to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11065</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-243</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mason County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky:</p>
<p>Your petitioner James Hasson states that at the <date when="1861-04">April Term of the Mason Circuit Court 1861</date> he was fined by said Court the sum of twenty dollars for selling liquor on the Fair Ground in said County -- </p>
<p>To the Indictment therefore, he plead guilty but at the time he committed the offense he did not know the same was forbidden by law -- He is poor, having a family to support and driving a Dray in the City of Maysville for livelihood, the payment of the fine would be a great hardship upon him and detract in these times greatly from his means of support, he most respectfully prays you to remit said fine its infliction <hi rend="str">being</hi> indeed being to him a salutary admonition for the future to beware</p>
<p>James Hasson<pb/></p>
<p>Mason Cir. Ct
<lb/>James Harson's Petition.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Respite 12 mo
<lb/>B.M</p>
<p>$20. } Selling liquor</p>
<p>Sec. State: If remitted, please hand remitter to 
<lb/>John L. Scott.</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-12-09">Dec<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. 9. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
