<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2314"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. W. Wick et al. to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9390</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG25-69</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Exelency the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your undersigned petioner would respectfully represent to your Excelency and at the same time recommend to your clemency Albert Hurt now confined in your penitentiary for passing a counterfeit bank bill. Said Albert Hurt is a young man, just entering into the years of manhood, being about 19 years of age, and the son of a widow, her father being dead some years. He was arrested in Covington Kentucky and at the June term of the court conveyed at Covington found guilty and sentenced to three years labor &amp; confinement in the Penitentiary. Your petitioners would furthermore respectfully represent, that the said Albert Hurt has learned the trade of Baker, and has of late years being a material help and support to his mother, who is sorely afflicted and bowed down with the misfortune which has befallen her eldest son, whom she has raised with good deal privation and occasioned him to learn her present trade. Of the extent of her guilt we know not, but we have known him altimes as an honest young man, but easily guided by others He left here last summer in quest of employment on some of the river towns We would therefore ernestly recommend him on account of youthfullness of the culprit and of the sorrow and grief of his old mother to extend your mercy towards him in the full belief that the punishment already suffered will be a good lesson for her future conduct, and that a long confinement will be injurious to his morals. And upon there <unclear/> and upon a certificate of citizens here, we would Recommend to your Exelency, to pardon the young man<pb/></p>
<p>W W Wick
<lb/>Fabrin M French President Judge 5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Circuit
<lb/>N B Taylor
<lb/><hi rend="underline">E, N, Shimer</hi>
<lb/>S A Johnston
<lb/>Albert Lange, Auditor of the State of Indiana
<lb/>W. A Perlle Secy of State
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Fisher Justice of the peace
<lb/>C C Campbell
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Foster Whitford</hi>
<lb/>Saml D Patterson
<lb/>L. D. Goldsberry
<lb/>C. G Werbe.</p>
<p>To his Exelency the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>We the undersigned officers of the court of <hi rend="str">Boone</hi> Kenton county and State of Kentucky and the jurors in the case of the State of Kentucky vs Albert Hurt would also recommend the young man Hurt to the mercy of your Exelency, to grant him a full pardon</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Edm<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> M. Claskey
<lb/>Daniel Savill
<lb/>H, E, Bonwell
<lb/>Henry Dresendan
<lb/>Jn<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi> Walkey
<lb/>C. B. Brasher
<lb/>Rob<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> H. Ball
<lb/><cb n="2"/>A C Ellis Depty Clk
<lb/>S. C Runn</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
