<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-006-0072"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Andrew J. Surface, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1118</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Requisitions for the Return of Fugitives from Justice, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR6-87 to BR6-88</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-08-23">23 August 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>County of Kenton } SS,</p>
<p>Before the undersigned a justice of the peace within and for the county and Commonwealth aforesaid, this day personally came Andrew J. Surface of lawful age, who being <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>by me first duly sworn according to law on oath says, That on the <date when="1864-03-19">nineteenth day of March Eighteen hundred and sixty four,</date> at the county of Kenton in the commonwealth of Kentucky Lucy Elizabeth Stover alias Elizabeth Snyder alias Elizabeth Surface late of said county, was guilty of the crime of bigamy, in this -- That the said Lucy Elizabeth Stover alias Elizabeth Snyder, alias Elizabeth Surface on the day and year aforesaid, at the county and commonwealth aforesaid was married to one Adam J. Surface, she the said Lucy Elizabeth Stover alias Elizabeth Snyder alias Elizabeth Surface then and there being a married woman, and her lawful husband <gap/> Stover being then alive, Affiant further says that he is well acquianted with the said Lucy Elizabeth Stover alias Elizabeth Snyder alias Elizabeth Surface by reputation, from which he knows that the said Lucy Elizabeth Stover alias Elizabeth Surface alias Elizabeth Snyder was lawfully married to <gap/> Stover on the <gap/> day of <gap/> and that she and her said husband had laid and cohabitated together, as such husband and wife for a number of years previous and up to the month of <date when="1864-03">March 1864</date> and reared a family of legitimate children -- That her said husband <gap/> Stover is now alive no divorce having been granted to the parties or either of them. That he has been<pb/>
<lb/>shown the record of the County Court of Kenton County Kentucky, and from said record it appears that on the <date when="1864-03-19">19th day of March 1864</date> a license was issued by the Judge of said court for the solemnization of a marriage between the said (Lucy Elizabeth Stover,<hi rend="str">)</hi> alias <hi rend="str">L</hi>Elizabeth Snyder alias Elizabeth Suface) in the name of Elizabeth Snyder, and Adam J. Surface, and affiant has also been shown said license, duly returned to said office, from which it appears that a marriage was duly solemnized by legal authority, between the said parties therein named, Affiant further says that the said Lucy Elizabeth Stover alias <hi rend="str">Lucy</hi> Elizabeth Snyder alias Elizabeth Surface, so married in said County of Kenton Kentucky is the identical Lucy Elizabeth Stover alias Elizabeth Snyder alias Elizabeth Surface whose lawful husband was then and is now living as aforesaid, and further saith not,</p>
<p>Andrew J. Surface</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed before me by Andrew J. Surface this <date when="1865-08-23">23<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> day of August A.D. 1865</date> and I further certify, that I believe the said Andrew J. Surface the affiant to be a credible person.</p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp"><unclear/></note></p>
<p>J. B. Lundrum
<lb/>J P K Co Ky
<lb/>Fee 25¢ paid by affiant
<lb/>J B L<pb/></p>
<p>Affidavits of Andrew J. Surface
<lb/>Requisition on Gov Ohio
<lb/>issued &amp; Moses Nelson
<lb/><date when="1865-08-24">24 Aug /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
