<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3457"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John B. Cassady to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5576</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-373 to BR42-374</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Metcalfe County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Hon Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. E. Bramlette
<lb/>Govenor of kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner John B. Cassady Stated that at <date when="1865-12">the ^Decr^ Term 1865</date> of the Metcalfe Circuit Court the Grand Jury of said county found an Indictment against him for Forgery a copy of Said indictment is herewith filed the receipt which <hi rend="str">is</hi> his is charged with having been changed is a receipt given by Geo. A. Clark late sheriff of Metcalfe County Said receipt was origina^lly^ given for $600.00 and after he paid Said Clark said sum of $600.00 and on the Same day, he paid Clark his Taxes and Some other debts against him and Said Clark give him a receipt for all of Said Sums they omitted to take into consideration Some countys claims &amp;c which Clark owed him he thought of Said Claims and called Clarks attention to them and Clark counted them up &amp; remarked that he would just interline the receipt he did take it and interline it and this is the <hi rend="str">a</hi>ways the receipt was interlined no one was present but Clark and him Clark returned the Execution who supposes with the proper return endorsed there on the records of the court were burned including said Execution nothing was ever Said to him about Said Execution until after Clark died Geo. R. Price file ^a^ notice to have said judgement reentered and he filed Said receipt &amp; plead it as a payment of Said Judgement which motion to reinstate Said judgement is Still pending and has never been tried Said indictment<pb/>
<lb/>was gotten up by his enemies for the purpose of annoying him and injuring his character Clark the only man ^who^ Saw this receipt &amp; who was present is dead if Clark was alive no indictment would ever have been found against ^him^ because Clark <hi rend="str">and</hi> would Explain the whole matter Said prossicution was set on foot by certain parties here maliciously He says that the charge in the indictment that the word Six had been changed from the wrod five is <hi rend="str">untrue</hi> untrue it never was five but was written first Six as it is, Several terms of the court have passed Since Said indictment was found and he has had no trial He very respectfully asks your excellency to grant him a pardon and discharge him from custody he has now for more than a year been held under heavy bond without any <hi rend="str">cause</hi> ^case^ against him &amp; for the sole purpose of annoying him &amp; destroying his character and if possible to break himself</p>
<p>John B Cassady</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Metcalfe county Say they concur in the Statement of facts made in the foregoing petition they are well acquainted with John B. Cassady he is a good citizen a <hi rend="str">h</hi>good neighbor and a man of good character and they are Satisfied that he is not guilty of the crime charged in the indictment and they earnestly ask your excellency to pardon him</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>T. G Shuffit J. P. M C
<lb/>J. M. Ralston
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John Y Wallace
<lb/>D. S. Bullington L G
<lb/>W. L. Yates
<lb/>B D Porter
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> J Whitlock M. D.<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>R. F. Browning D. P. M. C.
<lb/>G. W. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Felea
<lb/>P J Linder
<lb/>S R Young
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H London
<lb/>J E Cage
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/>W A Canyers Asst Assr
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Wallace
<lb/>J L Wilcoxson
<lb/>Joseph South
<lb/>John Scott
<lb/>W. T. Porter
<lb/>Thomas Eaton
<lb/>B A Hodges
<lb/>S R Edwards P M^C^
<lb/>J H Read Sheriff
<lb/>W O Pace
<lb/>Tho E Maury<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>Metcalfe Cir Ct
<lb/>J B Cassidy
<lb/>A Petition
<lb/>To the
<lb/>Excelency of
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. E. Bramlett
<lb/>not a case for consideration before trial</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
