<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3385"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">O. Waddell et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5504</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-255</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Webster County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency, Tho's E. Bramlette, Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned respectfully represent that at the <date when="1864-03">March Term 1864</date>, of the Webster Circuit Court, an indictment was found against W. H. Brown, for willfully and maliciously shooting one George M. Davidson, with the intent to Kill him. The facts of the case, as they are informed and believe them to be, are as follows, sometime prior to the shooting charged in the indictment, three men came by night to the house of Brown, and after treating him rudely and insultingly, took one of his horses and carried it away, Brown was satisfied that one of the three, was Davidson, who was then connected with the guerrillas infesting the county. Afterwards, Davidson came to his home, and Brown ordered him from his premises, Davidson replied in insulting and threatening language whereupon Brown went into his house, seized his shotgun and fired upon him, Davidson may have been struck in some part, by a shot, but was not seriously impaired,</p>
<p>The undersigned are well acquainted with Mr. Brown, and would state that he is a sober, quiet, orderly and peaceable citizen<pb/>
<lb/>and a worthy member of community, and they are satisfied ^he^ was impelled to the act, only by the indignant outrage which he believed Davidson had perpetrated upon him, Not knowing the companions of Davidson when the wrong was done him, he is without proof of the fact, The above is the case as stated by him, and we are satisfied fo its truthfulness. We think it a case deserving the exercise of Executive clemency, and respectfully petition your Excellency to grant him a pardon, and relief from the indictment</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>O. Waddell
<lb/>James W. Wilkins
<lb/>F. M. Nisbett
<lb/>S. B. Nisbet
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Young
<lb/>Jas G Todd
<lb/>Joseph Fuquay
<lb/>James Nisbet
<lb/>S. Rour
<lb/>S. C. Wood
<lb/>J. S. <unclear/>
<lb/>G. L. <unclear/>
<lb/>W G Nisbet
<lb/>John Ray
<lb/>J Writchett
<lb/>S W Witt
<lb/>J<hi rend="sup">no</hi>.N. Taliaferro
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Grant Green</hi><cb n="2"/>
<lb/>J L Peyton
<lb/>A K Bradley
<lb/>C. H. Young
<lb/>John T. Scott
<lb/>G H Miston
<lb/>J M Compton Depty From Marshall Hopkins county
<lb/>Wm. M. Young
<lb/>J D Browning
<lb/>John G Spardwell
<lb/>John B Frost
<lb/>W. C. Noel Col 70th Ky Regt E M
<lb/>Geo. W. Noel
<lb/>W F Nisbet
<lb/>J M Shackelford
<lb/>C. W. Cook
<lb/>Robt. B. Speed</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
