<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0119"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Marcus Endmans to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8571</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-185 to R3-186</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1862-11-03">3 November 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Marcus Endman states that he is a member of the firm of W. Levi &amp; Co Merchants Keeping a clothing &amp; furnishing store in Frankfort -- said firm commenced business, with a complete stock of foods suitable to this market, on the <date when="1862-10-16">16<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Oct 1862</date> with the bona fide intention of becoming resident merchants -- such has all the time since been their intention and such now is their bona fide intention. They in good faith complied with all the provisions of the law so far as they knew or were advised was required of them -- and they intend to so comply in future -- They occupy a store room on Main Street and have this far <hi rend="str">and</hi> conducted their business according to the usages of the market and intent to continue to do so -- Their purpose has been and now is to locate in Frankfort and establish a permanent business here, and at the time required by law to list their goods and other property for taxation -- </p>
<p>On the <date when="1862-11-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> day of Nov 1862</date> the affiant was charged with peddling and by the judgment of the County Judge of Franklin County fined <hi rend="underline">One hundred dollars</hi> -- Upon the trial, it was proven by the prosecution that affiant had sold goods in Frankfort in the said store, and that he had no license as a pedler -- For the defence it was<pb/>
<lb/>proven by the testimony of L Dudley that said firm rented the store room of him for three months at the rate of $30 per month, said firm desiring at the time to rent the room for a longer period but did not because of the too large rent charged -- It was further shown by Mr Dudley's testimony that the parties including affiant declared to him ^at the time^ that it was their intention to locate permanently in the city of Frankfort as resident merchants. It was shown by ^our^ other ^witness^ that such was their declared intention before affiant left Louisville where, as proven, he had resided for seven years -- It was further shown in evidence that said firm had paid all city dues demanded of them -- It is the intention of said firm to continue business, as resident merchants and replenish their stock from time to time as the necessity of the market may require -- </p>
<p>Affiant therefore petitions for a remission of so much of the <hi rend="str">the</hi> said judgment as is due to the Commonwealth -- </p>
<p>Marcus Endmans</p>
<p>Sworn to in due form by Marcus Erdman before the undersigned a Justice of the peace for Franklin County -- this <date when="1862-11-03">3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> day of Novr 1862</date>.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">G W Gwin J. P.</hi><pb/></p>
<p>The statement made by Mr Endman (as regards the facts proven in the trial of his case, is substantially true, the case was a similar one to that of <unclear/> both of these gentlemen had obtained a license from the city.</p>
<p>W. H. Sneed
<lb/>Co atto,<pb/></p>
<p>Franklin Co Ct.
<lb/>$100 } Peddling
<lb/>M Erdman</p>
<p>A Respite of the Judgt in this case for six months from this date <date when="1862-10-03">3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Octo 1862</date></p>
<p>J F Robinson
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-11-03">Nov. 3. 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
