<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0844"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Joseph Barkley, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4963</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-301 to BR10-302</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-05-24">24 May 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><date when="1864-03-24">May 24 1864</date></p>
<p>Doctor Jo<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Barkley stated on oath that the shot from the hand of John Cox killed David Lay &amp; Newte Johnson states on oath he saw John Cox come up to where David Lay was standing John Cocks told him he wanted a word with him Johnson said Cocks told Lay he had to quit talking about him they passed a few words and he shot him he died in about one hour</p>
<p>Ben F Wright states the same <hi rend="underline">Facts</hi></p>
<p>De B Barnhill states on oath that John Cocks came up and told Mr Lay he wanted a word with him Mr Lays reply was, well what is it, <hi rend="underline">Cocks</hi> reply was you have been me and you must quit it or I will kill you</p>
<p>Robert Barnhill states that he was with John Cox near mudyford some time in the <date when="1864">spring of 64</date> and that David Lay came where they was and in a conversation between Cox and Lay, Lay told Cox that<pb/>
<lb/>had <hi rend="str">intended</hi> altered his hog Cox told him that ^Leo^ did not matter his hog but he would tell him who did do it, Lay say Cox was a <hi rend="underline">lier</hi> Cox said I am not able to fight you, but if you will get down I try you, Lay said he was sick but if he was well that you have no character I wouldnt stoop to fight you, your mother has ruined your character that Jabe Rusk has been sleeping with her for 20 years J K Houston states that in a conversation that he had with David Lay that Lay told him that John Cox should not ride the big road by his house if he did he would kill him and he intended to drive of them Cox from their homes anyhow, this took place a short time before Lays death</p>
<p>Florance Holden, states, that she was at David Lays Some time in the <date when="1864">Spring of 64</date> and that John Cox was passing along the big road and that D Lay got down his gun and started out of the house and said he was going to shoot<pb/>
<lb/>John Cox and Lays wife and herself prevented him from going out</p>
<p>Benjamin Sharron, states that a few days before John Cox killed Lay that I <hi rend="str">J</hi> Cox requested him Sharron to go and see Lay and see if Lay was willing to settle the difficulty between them and Lay to quit talking about him. Sharron says he according to Cox request went to see Lay and told him Lay, the request Cox made of him and Lay said he would not do it that he intended to kill Cox and he wanted Sharron to tell Cox so and he might prepare for it</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
