<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1249"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Z. Wheat et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10717</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-114 to MG21-115</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency Beriah Magoffin Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Adair County and members of the ^County^ Court and bar of said County represent: that our fellow citizen R L Jones is bail for L D Jones in the Jefferson Circuit Court on an indictment for felony. that said L. D. Jones soon after his release from Jail on bail joined in the month of <date when="1861-01">Jany</date> last the army of the United States for the term of 5 years. The bail is three hundred dollars. the charge ^offering to^ pass<hi rend="str">ing</hi> Counterfeit money. the recognizance was forfeited at the <date when="1861-05">May term of the Jefferson Circuit Court in 1861.</date> R. L. Jones the bail is a worthy honest, industrious, Mechanic living in Columbia who by perseverance and economy has raised a family and has now a small property consisting ^in the main^ in a house &amp; lot in our town ^in which he resided^ said R L Jones is an incurable invalid having the use of but one leg &amp; goes on a crutch. he is in general bad health threatened with consumption we therefore represent these facts to<pb/>
<lb/>your excellency and pray you to interpose your executive clemency and save our friend and his family from incurable loss -- by the enforcement of the collection of said bail We pray that your excellency remit the bail to the Commonwealthh and as in duty bound we will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p>Z Wheat
<lb/>P, C, Hardin
<lb/>Junius Caldwell
<lb/>Sinclair Wheat
<lb/>Tho. E. Bramlette
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Garrett
<lb/>S. G. Suddarth
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> E Russell
<lb/>Nat Gaither Jr</p>
<p>I concur heartily in the Statements in the foregoing petition -- and from an intimate acquaintance with all the parties and a familiarity with the facts of the case, I do not hesitate to express the conviction that the case peculiarly requires the Executive interposition</p>
<p>Geo A Caldwell<pb/></p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Jefferson Cir. Ct
<lb/>$300 } Recog
<lb/>R. L. Jones &amp; N Gaither</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-07-18">July 18 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
