<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2842"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">O. S. Tomay et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7479</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-129 to BR17-130</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mt. Sterling, Montgomery County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-02">2 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Mt. Sterling <date when="1865-12-02">Decr 2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>The Govenor of Ky -- </p>
<p>The undersigned would respectfully state, that some few weeks ago, a youth by the name Jas. A. Landrum, of Wise County of V<hi rend="sup">a</hi> came to Ky and was in the town of Mt. Sterling without any means and to keep from starving and to supply his wants he took from ^one^ of the stores in Mt. Sterling some few Dollars in money, wi<hi rend="str">c</hi>th which he went &amp; paid his board bill &amp; started home: he is a youth of about 16 years of age he had been with the army; in fact came to Ky to show some men the way &amp; got away from home &amp; its influences, he was led to do wrong -- he is a youth of good par<hi rend="str">a</hi>entage -- his old mother has come here to look after her son, who is in much distress -- Considering the extreme youth, the first offence -- The desire of the mother to take her son back &amp; instruct him in the way he should go &amp; the necessities of the youth at the time -- we (some who<pb/>
<lb/>acquainted with the family) citzens of Montgomery County Ky. would ask that your Honer will do all for the boy for the sake of his old mother, that you feel it ^to^ be your duty, as a kind dispenser of justice There would not be any injury done to any one, but it might be the means of ^saving^ a <hi rend="underline">youth</hi> -- The youth is now in jail &amp; required to give bail in the sum of $200 -- which his mother being poor is not able to give -- Whatever you can do for the ^youth^ will meet with the approbation of this community, as they feel it is but justice, that some thing may be done for the boy -- </p>
<p>O. S. Tomay
<lb/>W Childers I have Known the boy from infancy he was always a good boy -- 
<lb/>Shelton Casssity
<lb/>M, Lacy
<lb/>L,, C,,. Kash I have Known the boy from infancy his character was good
<lb/>S. S. Combs I have known the boy from infancy his character was good
<lb/>J. G. Trumble
<lb/>Henry, R, C Greenwich
<lb/>John Stephens<pb/>
<lb/>Jas N Trumble D S
<lb/>Samuel J Adams
<lb/>N, B, Lloyd [The man who lost the ^money^
<lb/>C Sheffield
<lb/>J. B. Spratt M. D.
<lb/>N. G Haggan
<lb/>W. A Clark</p>
<p>I am not personally acquainted with the youth named in this petition. I know the family, and it is respectable as much so as any in the state.</p>
<p>This erring boy is the only that has ever caused the family any trouble. He is quite a youth, it will be a lesson to him, and I think wil be radical.</p>
<p>J M. Crawford clk.
<lb/>M Ct. Ct,
<lb/>J, W, Rose Marshal M<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Sterling</p>
<p>Montgomery
<lb/>vs Jas. A Landrum</p>
<p>Accused of larceny &amp; under arrest &amp; imprisonment upon Warrant pardon the offense &amp; remit the penalty</p>
<p><date when="1865-12-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Dec/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
