<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0129"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Elizabeth Moore to James F. Robinson </title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8581</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-199 to R3-200</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency James F. Robinson
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>The Petition of Elizabeth Moore a citizen of Louisville Kentucky, Respectfully sheweth That she was Indicted by the Grand Jury of the City Court of Louisville for Keeping a House of Prostitution in said city &amp; at the <date when="1862-10">October Term 1862</date> of said Court she was fined the sum of One Hundred dollars &amp; the costs amounting to Twenty two dollars &amp; some cents -- payment of all of which is now demanded of her. She says that she will be compelled to pay the costs &amp; attorneys portion of the fine which will amount to Fifty two dollars &amp; some cents and she Humbly begs your Excellency to remit the ballance, which is the states portion of said fine (being $70). She states that her house was situated in the Western part of the City &amp; remote from the residences of Families and that she has heretofore kept a quiet house, but since the soldiers have been in the city she has been greatly annoyed by their disorderly conduct in her house, which she could not restrain, being a woman, unmarried &amp; unprotected &amp; this disorder had Increased and until she was forced to close her house &amp; did close it &amp; leave the city for Chicago, about the time she closed her house this Indictment was returned against her solely on account of the disorder created by the soldiers &amp; the trial was had in her absence &amp; she was Inconsequence unable to be present &amp; was not represented by counsel hence the heavy fine that was assessed<pb/>
<lb/>against her. Had she been present, she could have proved that the disorderly conduct complained of was beyond her control; she has rented her House to a decent respectable family Herself occupying with her child a single room in the back part of the house where she is living quietly &amp; Intends for the future to reside &amp; not again to keep a house that can be complained of -- she states that she has no relations in Kentucky, that she has one child, whom she must support with herself, &amp; she intends to Earn that support for the future by her Honest Labor</p>
<p>She is not able to pay the fine; and asks your Excellency to remit the Commonwealths portion of the same &amp; she hopes to be able to get the portion coming to the officers stayed by their Indulgence until she can earn the money to pay it. She appeals to your Excellency to save her from the Mortification of being confined in the work House until this fine has been paid by hard Labor. She admits that her course of life has been wrong but she promises to offend no more against the Laws of the state &amp; she hopes that the appeal of an unprotected &amp; Friendless woman will not be in vain.</p>
<p>Elizabeth Moore</p>
<p>From Inquiries that I have made, I believe the statements in the foregoing Petition are True. I know the Petitioner was not present at the Trial &amp; that she was not represented by counsel.</p>
<p>Geo W. Johnston J. C. C. L
<lb/>W. G. Reasor, city atto<pb/></p>
<p>The undersigned unite with the Petitioner in asking a remission of the states Portion of the fine assessed against her. -- </p>
<p>C S Standiff, Chief Police
<lb/><hi rend="underline">G. B. Ehrich</hi> Clerk Police
<lb/>Capt W. J. Dillard
<lb/>Capt F, A, M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Harry
<lb/>Thomas G. Slaton Policeman
<lb/><unclear/> Claton " 
<lb/>Jacob Young "
<lb/>J M Vaughan<pb/></p>
<p>Fine Remitted.
<lb/>Louisvillle City Ct
<lb/>$100 } Disorderly House
<lb/>Elizabeth Moore
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1862-11-25">Nov. 25. 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
