<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1374"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Paul Garris, Judgment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10842</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-311</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Nelson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Nelson Circuit Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against
<lb/>Paul Garris</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Nelson County in the Name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky accuse Paul Garris of the offence of Attempting to entice and persuade away from the Services of her master a certain slave named Savilla the property of John Dawson while in the possession of said John Dawson against the Peace and the dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>Andy Barnett
<lb/>Atty for Comth</p>
<p>In Court <date when="1861-09-24">September 24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861 -- </date></p>
<p>"Defendant not appearing <hi rend="underline">tho</hi> called It is ordered that the bail bond be and the same is hereby declared forfeited and that process issue theron -- And on further motion It is ordered that a bench warrant issue endorsed that he be admitted to bail in the sum of $600 for his appearance -- </p>
<p>And again in Court <date when="1862-05-25">March 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1862</date> The process herein having been duly served on the Deft Jos -- Herrin and he not appearing It is <unclear>addressed</unclear> by the court that he<pb/> 
<lb/>Plff recover of said Deft the Sum of Five Hundred Dollars the amount of the Bail Bond forfeited herein and may have Execution with costs &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi></p>
<p>A Copy Attest
<lb/>Wm H Slaughter
<lb/>Clk N C C<pb/></p>
<p>Comth
<lb/>v }
<lb/>Garris -- </p>
<p>50t fee</p>
<p>1861</p>
<p>149
<lb/>1220</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
