<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0878"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">S. S. Story et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10346</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-383 to MG19-384</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-03-06">6 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excelency B. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin. Gov of The Commonwealth of Ky.</p>
<p>Your Pettitioners whose names are hereunto subscribed ask lief respectfully to show unto your Excellency that H. C. Laurence was at the <date when="1859-02">February term ^1859^</date> of the Equity &amp; Criminal Court. held at the Town of Hickman in and for the County of Fulton indited for the crime of obtaining money under false pretences and having thereafter been arrested by the Sheriff of Graves Co. was discharged upon bail, ie, -- he gave bond conditioned for the payment of five hundred dollars should he fail to appear, at the<date when="1859-06"> June</date> term of said Court to answer the inditement, found against him. Now Jasper M. Jones, Henry Ford, and J. W Laurence, were the securities in said Bail Bond. Your petitioners will further state that H. C. Laurence not being a resident of the State of Kentucky, and having been misinformed as to the time at which Court would be held in said Fulton County, failed to appear at said Court and the proepr day, and that therefore his bail bond was forfeited at the <date when="1859-06">June term 1859</date> of said Court, Your petitioners state that on the <date when="1859-06-04">4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of July 1859,</date> his securities in the above mentioned Bail Bond appeared at the <hi rend="str">County</hi> Circuit Clerks office for the County of Fulton and did actualy pay to -- Morris Clerk of said Court, who then had in his possession the aforementioned Bail Bond, the full sum of five hundred &amp; six dollars, and forty six cents being the amount of the forfeited bond and all costs thereon. Now your petitioners will state than said money ought to have been<pb/>
<lb/>paid to the Trustee of the Jury fund, and such would <hi rend="str">have</hi> probably have been done, by said Clerks to whom the money was paid but before this was done said Morris the Clerk died</p>
<p>Your petitioners will further state that at the <date when="1860-06">June term 1860.</date> the securities in the Bail Bond having been summoned to appear and show cause why judgment should not be rendered against them for the amount of said Bond, did appear in the above mentioned Court and show the above mentioned facts which were by the court held insufficient, and judgment went against them for the five hundred dollars &amp; costs.</p>
<p>Now your petitioners would respectfully pray the interposition of Executive Clemency and ask Your Excellency to interpose in behalf of said Securities, who have already paid the amount of the forfeited Bail Bond, and that they be released, from paying said Bond</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>S, S, Story
<lb/>J. C. Armstrong
<lb/>Andrew Williams
<lb/>E. Hendrick
<lb/>John A, Pullen
<lb/>Milton Summerville
<lb/>J R Coochran
<lb/>T. B. Cochran
<lb/>James M. Coulter c g c c
<lb/>Jas S Hendon
<lb/>J. B. Allcock
<lb/>John, Cunningham
<lb/>J. C. Cochran
<lb/>James. M. Smith
<lb/><cb n="2"/>A Sig: Morris
<lb/>W. B. Cook
<lb/>John M. West
<lb/>Jesse Morris
<lb/>S. M. Story
<lb/>J C.. Page
<lb/>M D Rhoades
<lb/>J. J. Tibbs
<lb/>S. A. Matheral
<lb/>Joseph Andrews
<lb/>D. Kelly
<lb/>A J Colley
<lb/>J. N. Colley<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>J W Bullock
<lb/>Eli Colley
<lb/>G L colley
<lb/>D. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>L. Johnson
<lb/>A. E. Tucker
<lb/>David Lassater
<lb/>Jemes Gerdner
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Carter
<lb/>John A Cannon
<lb/>S A Hays
<lb/>John S. Crutchfield
<lb/>Elijah Sullivan
<lb/>J. F Kelly
<lb/>H. S. Hay
<lb/>A Hamblett
<lb/>E. Carmon
<lb/>J P Hicks
<lb/>R B Watson
<lb/>I O Eaker
<lb/>Tom B Eakes
<lb/>P. J. Cochran
<lb/>R L Walkor
<lb/>H Toon
<lb/>John Wilfred
<lb/>A C Riley
<lb/>B, F, Brand
<lb/>G. Roice
<lb/>Samuel Carter
<lb/>S. H. Wilferd
<lb/>John McCartney
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J, W, Taylor
<lb/>James L Adams
<lb/>William Melvin
<lb/>I. S. Linsdsay
<lb/>B. F. Cargill
<lb/>Hugh, Hamlett
<lb/>R. U Buckner
<lb/>B. Honeycut
<lb/>I. B Ivy
<lb/>I T Lochridge
<lb/>William Duke
<lb/>John Ridgeway
<lb/>Joel Johns
<lb/>A I Pryor
<lb/>Wm C Robbins
<lb/>R A Mayes
<lb/>J,, F,, Dallam
<lb/>S. Riley
<lb/>J Weil
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Hall
<lb/>M W Galloway
<lb/>John Eaker
<lb/>W, W, Tice<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Mayfield Ky. <date when="1861-03-06">March 6<hi rend="sup">th</hi>/61</date>
<lb/>Hon B. Magoffin,
<lb/>Frankfort Ky.
<lb/>Dr Sir</p>
<p>I am informed by His Honor,- Judge Bigger that he has already written to you in reference to the objects of this petition I therefore submit it without comment, of my own, or any affidavits proving the facts stated within</p>
<p>Yours, Respectfully,
<lb/>A Petitioner</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
