<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1238"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William S. Warren and William P. Warren to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5875</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-404 to BR11-405</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-10-05">5 October 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency T E Bramlett
<lb/>Gov of Kentucky</p>
<p>your Petitioners William S Warren and William P Warren would respectfully state to your Excellency that at the fall term <date when="1862">1862</date> of the Taylor circuit court the Grand jury of said county found a true bill against your Petitioner William S Warren for an alledged Breach of the Peace committed as alledged in Said county your Petitioners state that <hi rend="str">that</hi> William S. Warren as required by law executed a bond to the Comonwealth of Kentucky in the sum of three hundred dollars with William P Warren his father as his Surety for his appearance at the next term of said Court your petitioners State that said William S Warren did attend Said Court, and said cause was continued by the Com<hi rend="underline">th</hi> and your petitioner William S Warren was permitted to stand on his bond for his appearance at the next term of said court your Petitioners State that in the fall of <date when="1862-10">1862 in Octo</date> your petitioner William S Warren who was then a soldier in the union army was attacked by a band of Guerillas under the command of Capt Edwards of Green County and was Severely wounded being Shot four times and is a cripple for life your Petitioners state that he was compelled to remain at home for Several months on account of said wounds, but that he was So far recovered as to be able to go to his command and that at the <date when="--03">March</date> term of said court he was with his command and could not attend said court as is shown by the statement of Brig. Gen. Ward herewith filed He states that said bond was forfeited and that at the <date when="1864-11">September term 1864</date> of said court that said William S Warren was required by the Court to pay fifteen dollars of said bond<pb/>
<lb/>and the balance of said bond was remitted by the court your Petitioners state that the non attendance of said William S Warren was unavoidable on his part and although the amount is Small your petitioner states that William S Warren is wholly unable to pay the same that owing to his wounds before mentioned that he is unable to support himself and that himself and family are supported by his father William P. Warren and your Petitioners state that Said William P Warren is severely afflicted and that he has been confined to his house for months past and that owing to the high price of Provisions and the great Scarcity of the Same that it is difficult for them to procure the necessaries of life &amp; that if they are compelled to pay the same it will take from them nearly all the money they have with which to buy provisions &amp; they can not get the necessaries of life without money </p>
<p>Wherefore they pray your Excellency to remit said Sum of fifteen dollars &amp; your Petitioners will as in duty bound ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p>William S ^his X mark^ Warren
<lb/>William P ^his X Mark^ Warren</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed before me this <date when="1864-10-05">5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Oct 1864</date> by William S &amp; W P Warren</p>
<p>D S Towles Clk G. C. C.</p>
<p>your Excellency will please direct your Answer to D T Towles Greensburg Ky<pb/></p>
<p>I know W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> S Warren, he was with me in <date when="1864-03">March 1864.</date> in the state of Tennessee as assistant waggon-master, &amp; remained with me as such for near three months and left me about the last of <date when="1864-04">april</date> or first of <date when="1864-05">May</date> -- had he attempted to return, to the <date when="1864-03">march</date> court of the <hi rend="str">the</hi> Taylor circuit court I would not ^have^ permitted him to have done so but would have arrested him &amp; compelled him to remain until the expiration of his term of service which expired or ended the latter part of <date when="1864-04">april 1864</date></p>
<p>W. T Ward
<lb/>Br Genl<pb/></p>
<p>Taylor Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> S &amp; W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> P Warren
<lb/>$300
<lb/>Remit
<lb/><date when="1864-10-08">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Oct/64</date></p>
<p>W P Warren</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
