<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1815"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Lewis Kring and Henry J. Savell to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11283</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Bradley Strait</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG23-188 to MG23-189</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1862-04-22">22 April 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency Gov Magoffin Governor of Ky. </p>
<p>Your Petitioners would humbly represent to your Excellency that they have been fined the sums of money to-wit: -- Lewis Kring the sum of Fifty dollars and costs; Henry I Lavell the sum of Twenty dollars and costs. The said fines were imposed by the Police Court of Frankfort Judge Graham presiding, for the offence of a breach of the Peace in Frankfort, committed <date when="1862-04-21">April 21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1862</date> by engaging in a fight -- and tried the same day before said court and fined therefor as aforesaid. </p>
<p>Your Petitioners would represent that they are poor boys in the employ of E H Steadman at his paper-mill -- this being the only means they have of support. Lewis Kring one of your Petitioners being a cripple and having a mother and two children to support out of the means he gets from his Employer E H Steadman. </p>
<p>They are unable to pay said fines. Wherefore they pray for the clemency of your Excellency in the remittal of the said fines</p>
<p>Lewis Kring
<lb/>Henry I Savell </p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Louis Kring and Henry J Savell <date when="1862-04-22">April 22<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1862</date></p>
<p>W Franklin Ex F Co<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned concur in the belief that the above fines ought to be remitted.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Jno Rodman</hi>
<lb/>Eugene P. Moore.
<lb/>W, J, Chinn
<lb/>J, W, South
<lb/>W. S. Dehony 
<lb/>W H Greenup
<lb/>J <unclear/>
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. P. O'Hara 
<lb/>James Shannon 
<lb/>Geo, W, Robb
<lb/>N, Heffner
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. J. Hutchison
<lb/>Jas W Heffner 
<lb/>Nelson Alley<pb/></p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Frankfort
<lb/>Po. Ct
<lb/>$50 } L Kring 
<lb/>$20. } H. J. Savell
<lb/>Iss <date when="1862-05-01">May 1. 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
