<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1124"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">L. P. Williams and Benjamin C. Gist to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10592</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-240 to MG20-241</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Monroe County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-05-06">6 May 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency B M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> &amp;c</p>
<p>Your petitioners B C Gist &amp; L P. Williams would respectfully state to your excellency that at the <date when="1859-04">April term 1859.</date> of the Monroe Equity and criminal court the Grand Jury found, a true Bill against them and John F Gerald for Gaming (and which they now say they were not Guilty) and at the same time an indictment was found by the same Jury against them and one Joseph Roberts and which they have submitted at the same time &amp; the commonwealths atto with the consent of the court dismissed the one against them in the case of commonwealth against them and Said Gerrlds with the understanding that the same was to be dismissed against Gerolds and the records show said fact but they are sorry to state the Clerk of the court (W A Cheatham) was a drunken inattentive man to his business and still placed the case on the docket but no summons was ever served on petitioners till Just before last <date when="1864-04">April</date> term of said court when they were not able either of them to attend to the defense of the case and sent word to W. P. Witcher their attorny to attend to it for them and not giving him the facts in the case he submitted their case and they through their inability to attend and &amp; mistake to their surprise find that they were fined $20. each &amp; the costs of suit and as they cannot now<pb/>
<lb/>obtain a new trial (see Stantons code of practice page 351 section 269) they here send their petition and a copy of the record and hope you will remit the sum and in due time they hope when they may be able to show the commonwealths attorny his Error he will release his fee</p>
<p>L. P. Williams
<lb/>Benjamin C Gist</p>
<p>Commonwealth of Ky</p>
<p>We W. P. Witchem and B Gist state that ^statements of^ the above &amp; foregoing petition are true ^as sworn all portions to it^ <date when="1861-05-06">May 6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>W P. Watchen
<lb/>Benjamin G Gist</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed by Benj G Gist &amp; W. P. Witchen this <date when="1861-05-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> May 1861</date></p>
<p>U. T. Buckner clk
<lb/>Monroe Equity &amp; Criminal Court
<lb/><date when="1859-04">April Term 1859</date>
<lb/>Commonwealth Plff
<lb/>against } Gameing
<lb/>Benjamin C Gist L P. Williams &amp; John F. Gerald Defns</p>
<p>on motion attorney for the commonwealth it is ordered that this prossecution be dismissed as to defendants gist &amp; Williams</p>
<p>Copy Test
<lb/>U. T. Buckner clk<pb/></p>
<p>I U T Buckner Clerk of the Monroe Equity &amp; Criminal Court Certify that the foregoing petition shows the facts as pertains to the Records of this court. and that it would be just &amp; right the prayer of petitioners be granted it is also. true the the said Cheathom was a very <unclear/> man to business nearly all of his time Drunk and placed the cause apon the docket which has caused the mistake as stated in the foregoing petition</p>
<p><date when="1861-05-06">May 6 1861</date></p>
<p>U. T Buckner clk
<lb/><figure type="seal"><ab>SEAL OF MONROE CIRCUIT COURT.
<lb/>KENTUCKY.</ab></figure><pb/></p>
<p>Remitted 
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Monroe Eq. Ct
<lb/>$20 each } Gaming</p>
<p>Gist and Williams</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1864-05-16">May 16. 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
