<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3292"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Jane Lasley to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5411</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-111 to BR42-112</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thos. E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Jane Lasley states that she is the mother of W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Lasley who was convicted of Larceny at the last term of the Whitley circuit court</p>
<p>She states that she is a widow. That she had two sons in the Federal army both of whom died in the service. That said W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Lasley is the only son she has living That she is old and dependent upon him for her support</p>
<p>She states that from the best information she can obtain her said son was arrested and tried <hi rend="str">and tried</hi> the same day, having no opportunity to prepare for his trial.</p>
<p>She states that he has always been an honst and upright man, and she cannot think that the charge is true.</p>
<p>She therefore asks your Excellency to pardon him and return him to his aged mother and helpless family</p>
<p>Jane ^her X mark^ Lasley<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned join in the application for the pardon of W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Lasley</p>
<p>I am not acquainted with M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Lasley and know nothing of the circumstances by which he was convicted</p>
<p>J. E. Cosson C W P C C
<lb/>E. D. Perch C W P Ci C
<lb/>M E Ingram
<lb/>Thos Z Monroe
<lb/>C B Bacheller Co Atty P C
<lb/>W. H. Pellier P. J. P. C. C.
<lb/>W A Sallee
<lb/>W P Ingram
<lb/>Late Capt
<lb/>J. C. Patton</p>
<p>Lasley has behaved himself with perfect propriety</p>
<p>H I Todd</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
