<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0281"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John F. Galbraith to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8733</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-414</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Dixon, Webster County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-03-20">20 March 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Dixon Ky <date when="1863-03-20">March 20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>Hon Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> F Robinson
<lb/>Gov, of the Comth, of Ky,
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>I have the honor herewith to transmit to you a petition signed 113 citizens of Webster county praying your excelency to remit a fine of $20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> against the <unclear/> Cobb <hi rend="str">we</hi> for sellin Liquor without licens I am happy to inform you that to my knowledge from conversing with Esqr John H. Burrgass &amp; N. N, Johnson that the statements contained in the petition are true you will perceive that Burrgass &amp; Johnson have both asigned the petition which evinces the fact that the statements there contained are true -- </p>
<p>I wish to state to you the additional fact that Cobb is a very ignorant man that he can neither read nor write &amp; that he is a quiet inofensive citizen &amp; that he is very poor -- &amp; is a weakly man -- he says that <hi rend="str">the</hi> his family were in need &amp; that he did what he did for the purpose of obtaining necessaries for them I believe the above facts are true &amp; hope that your excellency will remit the same -- </p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>John F. Galbraith<pb/></p>
<p>P, S, please take this matter under consideration &amp; write to me upon the Subject at the earliest posible convenience address</p>
<p>John F. Galbraith
<lb/>Dixon Ky.</p>
<p>Webster Cir Ct
<lb/>$20. } Selling liquor
<lb/>Micager Cobb
<lb/>Remit the fine in this case
<lb/>J F Robinson
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-04-20">Apr 20. 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
