<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2004"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Moses Baer, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6641</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-159 to BR-160</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Ohio County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Ohio Circuit Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>Against } Indictment
<lb/>Moses Baer</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Ohio County in the name of and by the Authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, accuse Moses Baer, not being a physician, of the offence of giving loaning and selling to the slave of Another, without the written order of the owner of said Slave, or of the person who, for the time being, had the legal Control of the service of said Slave. And not having at the time, said slave under his control, spirituous, Malt and vinous Liquors. Committed as follows viz</p>
<p>The said Moses Baer, not being a physician on the <gap/> day of <date when="1862-05">May 1862</date> And on divers days since in the County aforesaid, did, sell, give and loan to Anderson a slave, spiritous <hi rend="str">liquors</hi> malt and vinous liquors, said slave then and there belonged to M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Maria Ann Taylor, but was then and there under the Control of A, B, Baird, And who then and there had legal control of the services of said slave And the said Baer, did then and there, give loan and sell spiritous liquors to said slave as aforesaid, without the written order. of the said M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Maria Ann Taylor, and without the written order of the said Baird, And not himself, then and there having the said slave under his control, against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky,</p>
<p>Information given by M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Maria A. Taylor<pb/>
<lb/>A, B, Baird, Virgil Addington, John Ford, John Thomas Thomas Mosely and William Manzy,</p>
<p>A true bill
<lb/>Joseph Leach Foreman</p>
<p>A. Copy
<lb/>Attest A. L. Morton clerk
<lb/>Ohio Circuit Court<pb/></p>
<p>The Com<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of Ky
<lb/>vs } sellling Liquor to a slave
<lb/>Moses Baer<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>A. True bill
<lb/>Jo<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Leach foreman of the Grand Jury<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Filed <date when="1863-03-28">March 28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>A. L. Morton clk
<lb/>A Copy
<lb/>att A. L Morton</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
