<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-005-0005"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">S. Thomas Hauser to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG0894</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Apprehension of Fugitives from Justice Papers, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR7-6 to BR7-7</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Falmouth, Pendleton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-10-17">17 October 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><placeName ref="cwgk:P00000550">Falmouth</placeName>. <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000544">Pendleton County Ky</placeName> -- <date when="1863-10-17">Oct 17<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date></p>
<p>His Exc<hi rend="sup">ly</hi> Tho. E. Bramlett Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> of <orgName ref="cwgk:O001025">Ky</orgName></p>
<p>Sir. The murder of Maj. <persName ref="cwgk:N00001503">A. G. Wileman</persName>, of the 18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Regt Ky. Vol., on the night of <date when="1863-10-05">5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> inst</date>, in this County, -- in atrocity, cruelty and aggrivation was such, that, it seems to me, the safety of Union and law abiding citizens; and, perhaps, specially, the security of our warworn officers and soldiers, upon their returns home, from our armies, on forlough, -- sick, wounded or otherwise, to the bosom of their families, urgently and loudly, call, upon every department of the Government (to the limits of the law) for the apprehention and conviction of the heartless and marouding murderers and robbers: -- I therefore, take the privilege, under the provisions of the statute, as County Judge, to petition your excellency, to issue, as soon as convenience will permit, a proclamation with a reward, for their arrest and apprehention. -- The murderers, -- no doubt, <hi rend="underline">every one of them</hi>, are <hi rend="underline">now fleeing from justice</hi>: -- but, the events of the past, unmistakingly, proclaim, it is only, again to return, -- if unwhipped of justice, or undetered by retributive example, for full purpose of perpetrating upon others,<pb/>
<lb/>like heinous crimes, -- so soon as this community relapses, into so supposed security and heedless repose, as it unfortunately was, at the time Maj Wileman returned home, -- wounded from the field of battle, unarmed, -- confidingly relying for protection, upon the laws of his State, which he had just so nobly defended, and upon that sense of security and personal safety, inspired by his wounds -- and by these promised him, in the midst of his stricken family and a loyal and grateful <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> people</p>
<p>Respectfully Yours &amp;c
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00001515">S. Tho. Hauser</persName></p>
<p>N B At an adjourned meeting at the Court house on this day, of a small portion of the citisens of this County, sixty seven inrolled themselves as part of volunteer company under the militia law and your late proclamation; and no doubt but that in a few days, a company will be fully organized in this County -- All the people want, every where, under the present crises, is a knowledge of the <hi rend="str">law</hi> Militia Law: -- <pb/>
<lb/>and it should be distributed in a pamphlet form, the crises as a matter of necessity, it seems to me, demands such distribution, <unclear><hi rend="str">no</hi></unclear> For no man's life or property will be secure until the militia is in every County organized as required by the Gov<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> proclamation and every County has a watchfull company volunteers The arms which I understand were sent here; part for the fraction of a company under the 20,000 requisition, here guarding the rail road Bridge, and part for a volunteer company under your late proclamation, came most opportune -- Our hearty thanks for them -- &amp;c.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">S. T. H</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Pendleton Co
<lb/>Reward
<lb/>$500.
<lb/>Murderers of A G. Wileman
<lb/><date when="1863-10-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Oct /63</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
