<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-022-0015"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George W. Reardon to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG2913</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Requisitions for the Return of Fugitives from Justice, 1859-1861</collection>
      <idno>MG7-183 to MG7-184</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Cairo, Alexander County, Illinois</placeName>
    <date when="1861-08-21">21 August 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Cairo Ills <date when="1861-08-21">Augt 21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Gentlemen</p>
<p>Mr Dowdy at Columbus gave me an account of a Murder, committeed by James Gregory, Frank Gregory; and a man named Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Bosen, at Dublin, Graves County Ky. and Said that W C Wommack and Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Leopold would give 500.$ for their arrest, the parties are here acting as spies for the Federal troops. Now if you will procure a requisition from Gov of Kentucky, And have Ray Mauer inserted as Agt of the State of Kentucky to bring the prisoners, and send it to me I will beg the Gentlemen and bring them over. Now this must be done on the <hi rend="underline">Sly</hi> for if the troops find it out here I will Hardly get them. And again, they have friends in your Neighborhood. and if they found out what we are doing we may give up the chase. when you Send for the requisition try Hard to get the Governor to offer a reward for each of them Say from three to four Hundred Dollars each. So that I can if possible make<pb/>
<lb/>a little Money out of the Scoundrels. Now if you want them, please attend to this immeidately And with as little delay as possible, the Governor of this State will be bound to obey the requisition for Kentucky has not Seceded.</p>
<p>I will refer you to Mr Dowdy, city Marshall of Columbus, James Irwin, Mayor Sharp, W Wilburn Citizens of Columbus, as to who I am. An early reply will oblige</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>Yours &amp;c
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Geo W. Rearden</hi></p>
<p>I write to you <hi rend="underline">via</hi> Paducah because communication is cutoff from Columbus</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
