<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1537"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">David J. Elington, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6174</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-378 to BR12-379</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Livingston County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-03-02">2 March 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Livingston County } SS</p>
<p>David; J; Elington Says I was at Mr James Bozmans on the <date when="1861-12-25">25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of December 1861</date> and Mr W. P. Clemens &amp; W W Clemens came to Bozmans gate &amp; W. P. Clemens called Mr Bozman out Bozman went out into the Lane where the Clemens ware Pinkney said we have came up to try to setle the Dificulty Between you and William &amp; Bozman said I have no settlement to make Mr. Pinkney Clemens said to Bozman you have said thing that is too hard and you orto take them back and Bozman Said he would be Damned if he would take back anything he had said &amp; W. W. Clemens said you wont Damn you I will make you take it back &amp; Drew his pistol as he got of his horse as Bozman advanced toward, W W. Clemens around the horses head &amp; W. W. Clemens pistol fiered without effect Bozman then clinched him and ran him Backward &amp; threw him Down against a log and while they were on the ground Bozman was in the act of getting possession of W. W. Clemens pistol Pinkney Clemens then got off his horse &amp; Drew his Knife and ran up and jumped on Bozman<pb/>
<lb/>and stabed him twice Bozman then released, W. W. and started after, W. P a step or two and then turned to the wood pile and got the ax and Drew it on W. W. Clemens and then W W Clemens fired again takeing Effect in Bozmans arm then Bozman ran W. W. -- Clemens some 15 or 20 yards ^W. W^ Clemens then Stoped turned round and fired again takeing Effect in the hip Bozman fell W. W. Clemens then steped before him with his pistol cocked and presented at his Brest Pinkney called on his Brother not to shoot any more W. P. Clemens then offered to assist Bozman to the house and Seemed much Effected and Shed tears and, I, believe from the action of W. P. Clemens he came to Bozmans with his Brother to settle the Dificulty peacebly</p>
<p>this <date when="1865-03-02">March 2<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date></p>
<p>This day David J Eington personaly appeared before me J. T. Bronsten &amp; <hi rend="str">action</hi> acting Justice of the Peace for Livingston County Ky and made oath that the above statements were all true to the best ^his^ knowledge &amp; beleafe. given under my hand this <date when="1865-03-02">March the 2<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date></p>
<p>J. T. Bronsten J. P.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
