<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-002-0002"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. J. Landram to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG0867</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Jacob A Glover</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Appointments by the Governor, Military Appointments, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR5-308 to BR5-309</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Pass Cavallo, Texas</placeName>
    <date when="1864-02-01">1 February 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Head Quarters 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi>. Brig. 4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Div. 13th Army Corps
<lb/>Pass Cavallo Texas. <date when="1864-02-01">February 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1864.</date>
<lb/>Hon. Tho. E. Bramlette
<lb/>Gov. of Kentucky
<lb/>Governor:</p>
<p>I learn from the newspapers, that you have recommended to the Legislature the propriety of organizing new troops for the defence of the state, in consequence of the withdrawal of those recently raised under the Act of Congress, from the state, for the general defence elsewhere.</p>
<p>I enclose copies of papers from which it will be seen that my friends in the Army are still urging upon the President, my promotion -- but inasmuch as there is much doubt in my mind as to the certainty of any thing being done for me at Washington, I write to you, to say, that if enough troops to form a Brigade or Division shall be ordered by the Legislature for a period of not less than one year; and<pb/>
<lb/>you should think proper to tender me the position of Brig Genl., with the pay now allowed by the Army Regulations, I should feel not only complimented by such an offer, but grateful to you for the same. I have been doing the work of a Brig &amp; Major Genl for near two years &amp;receiving only the rank &amp; pay of a Col. The 4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Div of this Corps has upon three occasions ^been^ placed under my command, and the papers which I enclose will show the opinions of my brother officers as to my qualifications.</p>
<p>Of course, a command in my own state would be preferable to one elsewhere -- &amp; my knowledge of the country -- &amp; particularly of Southern &amp; Eastern Ky., acquired in actual campaigns would enable me to render more service to the state than many others who were not acquainted with the country &amp; the people. I was in command at Mill Springs, &amp; Somerset &amp; engaged in the Campaign from Cumberland Ford &amp; Gap -- through Eastern Ky to the Ohio river. I trust you will regard this communication as confidential &amp; any favors you may show <hi rend="str">you</hi> me will be properly appreciated. I refer also to Maj Genl's Grant, Sherman,<pb/>
<lb/>Granger, Baird, Logan, M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Pherson, M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clernand, Ord, Hurlbut, &amp; in fact every general officer in the Department of the Tennessee.</p>
<p>Truly
<lb/>Your friend.
<lb/>W. J. Landram Col
<lb/>19 Ky Comg Brig.</p>
<p>P. S. It is proper to add that I had one years experience in the <hi rend="underline">Cavalry</hi> service in the Mexican War -- and as you doubtless remember, was commissioned Col. of Woolfords Cavalry by Genl Nelson at the commencement of the war.</p>
<p>W. J. L.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
