<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1863"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Z. W. Bugg et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11331</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Bradley Strait</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG23-267 to MG23-268</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Blandville, Ballard County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-05-10">10 May 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Blandville Ky <date when="1862-05-10">May 10" 1862</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky 
<lb/>Respected Sir</p>
<p>We the undersinged would respectfully state to your Excellency that some time ago George Stovall was arrested for a breach of the peace, The facts as detailed before the Jury was about these -- There lived in about an half mile of the said Stovall one Elizabeth Stevenson and her mother who were notoriously known to be immoral and lude women, Elizabeth Stevenson was in the habit of getting water from Stovalls Spring. and upon severel occasions the said Elizabeth Stevenson blackguarded and abused the said Stovalls little daughters after which, The said Stovall told the said Elizabeth Stevenson that she must quit getting water off of her place or out of her springs, and she told him that she intended to get watter wherever she pleased, and would be damned if he could or would prevent her from so doing, this exasperated the old man and he struck her over the breast with a little <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> knife <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> she was the only witness that the commonwealth had to make out her case, and Stovall<pb/>
<lb/>said she Sworn to things that was untrue told her he would prosecute her for it, and she left the Country, she and the family was a character that they were not received in any society whatever, Stovall was fined Sixteen dollars upon her testimony, Stovall is a very respectable citizen <hi rend="underline">though</hi> in very limited circumstances, with a large family to support, We therefore humbly ask your Excellency to interpose and release the said Stovall of the assessed fine</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Z. W. Bugg
<lb/>J C Oneal
<lb/>W J Smith
<lb/>Henry Unsel
<lb/>P A Bondurant
<lb/>J D <unclear>White</unclear>
<lb/>D W Jackson
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Pidgoen
<lb/>Jacob Edwards
<lb/>John Flowers
<lb/>W T Watson
<lb/>J. P <unclear/>
<lb/>C. S. Marshall
<lb/>I Corbett
<lb/>G S Johnson
<lb/>G S <unclear/>
<lb/><cb n="2"/>T Violett
<lb/>Jas. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>aley 
<lb/>J A Carpenter
<lb/>James Armstrong 
<lb/>Wiley Sams 
<lb/>J M B Shelton
<lb/>W. B. Finn
<lb/>J. A. Parker
<lb/>B. A. Lane
<lb/>B. J. Couch
<lb/>Richard Todd
<lb/>D J Todd
<lb/>Isac. Edgin
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Kidd
<lb/>I F <unclear/>
<lb/>Asa Richardson 
<lb/><unclear/>. Hall
<lb/>W C Hendricks<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>James L <unclear/>
<lb/>G. W. Sullivon</p>
<p>Paducah, Ky <date when="1862-06-27">June 27/62</date></p>
<p>I know Geo Stovall to be a good citizzen &amp; very poor and that the foregoing Petitioners are respectable Gentlement &amp; that their petition is worthy of consideration -- </p>
<p>G. H. Morrow<pb/></p>
<p>G. H. Morrow
<lb/>Paducah 
<lb/>Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
