<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0439"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. R. Morrow to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9907</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-183</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Danville, Boyle County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-12-28">28 December 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Danville <date when="1860-12-28">December 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1860</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>on the <date when="1860-12-24">24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of this month</date> a young man from Tennesee Named (Joshua Flowers) was attacked by a Low character upon the Street here, and was in great danger of bodily harm when his Brother a Youth of about 15 years of age went to his rescue &amp; Struck the man with a rock for which he the Brother (Pinckney Flowers) was fined five Dollars ($5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi>) &amp; cost, which amount I write to you for the ^purpose^ of getting it remitted -- these young Men are both poor, honest &amp; industrious and are working here by the day to Earn Enough to Enable there Widow<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Mother &amp; orphan children, to get a Support they are <hi rend="str">en</hi> Strangers in this community having been here but a short while but all who know them would testify to there Soberness &amp; correctness of character hoping you will see the Justice of the request I am Yours Respectfully</p>
<p>W, R, Morrow</p>
<p>N B
<lb/>I <hi rend="str">did</hi> do not think it worth while to send you a petition with a number of Signatures which could Easily be obtained but will refer you to for the truth of any statement I might make the Sheriff of<pb/>
<lb/>Boyle County or M. J. Durham Esq<hi rend="sup">r</hi>
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> C Anderson
<lb/>J F Bell
<lb/>Clifton Rodes Sr or any prominent citizen of, Danville</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">W B Morrow</hi></p>
<p>Danvile Po. ct
<lb/>$5. } breach
<lb/>P. Flower
<lb/>Resp<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 6 mo.
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-01-14">Jany 14 1861</date></p>
<p>Flowers case
<lb/>Danville
<lb/>Respite 6 mo
<lb/>B. M,</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
