<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1343"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas J. Throop to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10811</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-259 to MG21-260</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Maysville, Mason County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-08-30">30 August 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Will Practice in Mason and adoining Counties, also in District and Federal Courts and Court of Appeals</p>
<p>Collections in any part of Northern Kentucky will receive prompt attention.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>R. H. STANTON.
<lb/><cb n="2"/>THOS. J. THROOP<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>STANTON &amp; THROOP,
<lb/>ATTORNEYS AT LAW,
<lb/>Maysville, Ky, <date when="1861-08-30">Aug 30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Dear Col.</p>
<p>A young man in our city named Benj: Clark who keeps a small grocery store in the lower end of town was fined in two cases in our Circuit Court, for selling liquor without license. He is a young man just commencing life, knows very little about the law. &amp; the fines against him in these hard times, are exceedingly onerous, &amp; will almost ruin him to pay. He will not violate the law again, as he assures me, &amp; will keep to its strict letter. He has petitioned the Governor for a remittance<pb/>
<lb/>of his fines, amounting in all to $100 -- WIll you be kind enough to speak a good word to the Governer for him, for I do think it is a case <unclear/> executive interference &amp; try <unclear/> these fines remitted. The <unclear/> will be a sufficient lesson to this young gentleman to restrain him in future. Your kindness will be duly appreciated by him, &amp; will also be considered a personal favor to me.</p>
<p>Your family are all well, Pretty <unclear/> times here, &amp; the "Union" men are many of them becoming heartily sick of their party action, in trying to <unclear/> Kentucky in civil stife. Let me hear from you soon.</p>
<p>Truly yours
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Thos. J. Throop</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Is<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-09-04">Sept 4</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
