<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1804"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Michal Mathis to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6441</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-346 to BR13-347</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-05-05">5 May 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><date when="1865-05-05">May the 5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov of Ky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Michal, would respectfully states that on the <date when="1865-05-03">3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> day of may 1865</date> being at the <date when="1865-05">May Term</date> of the City Court of Louisville he was fined fifty Dollars with costs on a charge of an Assault &amp; Battery on one Jacob Apple the facts briefly, stated are as follows one day in <gap/> <date when="1865">1865</date> the two children of your petitioner aged three &amp; 6 years were struck across the hands with a stick by a daughter of the prosecuting witnes aged fourteen years, which left a red mark on there hands, the first time your petitioner met said Apple he told him that he did not want his children whipt any more, and as the saying is one word brought on an other until said Jacob Apple threw a bucket full of wather upon your petitioner thereby commencing the assault himself afterwards several blowes passed between them, neither of them was much hurt, and one about as much as the other said Apple then had him Indided, and he was the only witness by whom any thing conserning the case was proved, now if your petitioner could have testified the case would have been the reverse from what it was, your petitioner say that he is a poor man with wife and three children<pb/>
<lb/>and a mother Eighty years old to support, in addition to which he has spent three hundred and fifty Dollars with draft Clubs, and that it would go hard now to pay this fine, and he says he is not to blame so much as said Apple commenced the assault,</p>
<p>Wherefore he prays that <hi rend="str">the</hi> your Excellency will interpose your pardning power, and relieve him from the payment of this fine, Wherefore your petitioner respectfully submits his case to you together with the following names of the officers of said Court and Citizens of Louisville Ky</p>
<p>Very Respectfully Submitted
<lb/>Michal Mathis</p>
<p>We the undersigned officers of the court and Citizens of Louisville would suggest that we think the above is a case which deserves the interposition of your Executive clemency, and therefore pray your Excellency to remit the fine against your petitioner</p>
<p>We are acquainted with the persons whose names are signed below &amp; know them to be respectable citizens of Louisville &amp; Neighbors of the Petitioners, as citizens we have no objection to the remission of the fine, but decline to act <hi rend="str">sworn</hi> as officers of the court</p>
<p>Geo. W. Johnston<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Phil Tomppert Jr
<lb/>clerk City Court of
<lb/>Louisville
<lb/>Names
<lb/>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> W. Barr
<lb/>Philip Falloran
<lb/>John Rosell
<lb/>August Ford
<lb/>Jacob Hany
<lb/>J. A. Zansinger.
<lb/>Henry Mahner
<lb/>L. W. Sheafer
<lb/>George Appler
<lb/>Jackob Eberle
<lb/><unclear>Kutner</unclear> Britel
<lb/>Henry Schafer
<lb/>J E. Elkner
<lb/>C. Kraft
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Meffert
<lb/>G. Henning
<lb/>S. E. Bauman
<lb/>Jacob. Steller Jr
<lb/>John Krebs
<lb/><unclear>Torfing Mayer</unclear>
<lb/>Jacob Miller
<lb/>Fred Schoenkert
<lb/>G E Steinkemp
<lb/>Louis Luist
<lb/>John Duffy
<lb/>John Malpin
<lb/><cb n="2"/>W G Reasor
<lb/>Will Horan
<lb/>Names
<lb/>Andrew Stickler
<lb/>Hinkeburg Jakob
<lb/>Chs Seel
<lb/>To. Wintergeisst
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H. Meffort
<lb/>Jacob. Meffert
<lb/>J. P. Kreisher
<lb/>F J Martin
<lb/>Philip Tomppert Sr. Mayor
<lb/>William Balmer
<lb/>Hy Walter
<lb/>John Hart
<lb/>Felix Gross
<lb/>Abraham Akers
<lb/>Theodor Droppelmann
<lb/>Matthaus Pracht
<lb/>Adam Geigereitz
<lb/>G Becktel
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>Ph. Breckheimer
<lb/>G. Gaffricht
<lb/>Theodore. Ahrens
<lb/>Simon Fink
<lb/><unclear>Jonah</unclear> Lauer<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Louisville City Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Michael Mathias
<lb/>$50 -- 
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1865-05-25">25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> May 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
