<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2977"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas H. Lucas et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7614</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR43-65</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Governor of the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioners would state that a young man by the name of Henry C Lucas was indicted in the Russel Circuit Court some two or three years ago for an assault with intent to Rob, said assault is said to have taken place at some time during the war.</p>
<p>Your petitioners do not profess to know the facts in the case, but are informed and believe that the charge rests on vague and unsatisfactory circumstantial evidence, the indictment was procured upon the information of Col Hoskins, The young man was a Union soldier during the war and was honerably discharge at the experation of his term of service, he has ever been loyal to the government and so was his father They are annoyed that the indictment should be kept over him, to his detriment and to the mortification of his family The premises considered we respectfully ask that he be pardoned</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Thomas H. Lucas
<lb/>W T Jackman
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J H McBath
<lb/>J. G. Stanton
<lb/>James Smith<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>R. B Thomas
<lb/>Mason Flanagin
<lb/>Griffin B Wheat
<lb/>John F Bernard
<lb/>Benjamin F. Edmonds
<lb/>A, C, Wells
<lb/>Lafayette Dunbar
<lb/>C W Harris
<lb/>Reuben Dunbar
<lb/>James Cravens
<lb/>Edmond Cook. jr
<lb/>Jacob A. Williams
<lb/>A Satterfield
<lb/>Felix. M. Harris
<lb/>I. C Winfry
<lb/>John webb
<lb/>John F Paul
<lb/>John D, Irving
<lb/>Benj M Farlan
<lb/>Aylett Buckner</p>
<p>Russell Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>H. C. Lucas</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
