<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1237"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. H. C. Sundidge to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5874</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-402 to BR11-403</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Burksville, Cumberland County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-09-10">10 September 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Burksville <date when="1864-10-09">October 9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 64</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>T. E. Bramlett
<lb/>Governor of Ky -- 
<lb/>Dear sir</p>
<p>At the <date when="1864-06">June Term</date> or at a called special Term of the Metcalf circuit court held the last week in <date when="1864-05">May 1864</date> there was a Judgment rendered against William Mann, of said County for retailing spiritous liquors. ($20.00 The accused acknowledged his guilt in open court. and seemed to be verry penitent. and pledged me his word that he would not sin in that way anymore, he is verry old and almost Blind his wife is also verry old and infirm they have but a small pittance to live upon and under all the circumstances. I think his case merits the interposition of your Executive clemency. I told him if he would pay the cost of the prosecution and agree. not to sell any more whisky I would write to you and get you to remit his fine pleas let him off,</p>
<p>Paragraph No 2.</p>
<p>At the <date when="1864-10">october Term 1864</date> of the Monroe Circuit Court There was 3<pb/>
<lb/>Judgments rendered against one Melvina E. Keys. for $20, Each making $60.00 the said Melvina E. having been Indicted in 3 cases for the small offense of Adultery, the said Judgments was rendered by Default. the said Melvina failing to appear and plead to the indictment, as a modest woman would do, One Samuel Thomas the man who committed or was engaged, in the act of adultery with the said Melvina was also <hi rend="str">engaged</hi> Indicted in three cases, and Judgment obtained against him in said 3 cases for $20 00 Each he the said Thomas pleading Guilty in all three of the cases, and immediately upon the rendition of said Judgments said Thomas came forward and Duplicated the convoy, by paying the full amount thereof including the cost. also upon the rendition of the Judgments vs said Melvina said Thomas came forward in a private <hi rend="str">and</hi> modest and penitent manner and paid me my part of said Judgments and paid the clerk &amp; sheriff their cost. and asked me if I pleased to write to you to remit the fine against the said Melvina, he says he over persuaded her to go into the said act of Adultery, and therefore doesnot feel in his concience like it would be write to let her go to Jail and he also feels like in his Pocket he had already paid pretty dear for whistling only<pb/>
<lb/>three times, and I must confess it looks a little that way to me, he says if you will let her off he will go home and sin no more Wherefore he prays your Excellency to remit said fines. and further this deponent sayeth not if you conclude to grant the pardens herein prayed for enclose them to me</p>
<p>Very Truly Yours &amp;c
<lb/>J, H, C Sundidge<pb/></p>
<p>Metcalfe Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Mann
<lb/>Tipling
<lb/>$20.
<lb/>Monroe Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Melvina E Keys
<lb/>3 cases
<lb/>Adultery
<lb/>$20, each
<lb/>all remitted
<lb/><date when="1864-10-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Oct/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
