<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-023-0001"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thornton F. Marshall and L. J. Bradford to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG2914</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG1-120 to MG1-121</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Augusta, Bracken County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-12-17">17 December 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Augusta Ky
<lb/><date when="1860-12-17">Dec. 17<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1860</date>.
<lb/>Gov. B. Magoffin
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>The clerk of our Court has received a letter from Felicity Ohio, saying some of the citizens of that place had decided upon an invasion of our County for the purpose of liberating our negroes -- The author of said letter fails to sign his name, because he states if he was known to have made such a disclosure he would be driven from his home &amp;c -- We are inclined to beleive this a hoax, <hi rend="underline">but</hi> he details &amp; refers to some circumstances which have actually transpired in our County, that convinces us of the prudence of being <hi rend="underline">prepared</hi> for any emergency -- <pb/>
<lb/>The writer states further -- that these Aboltionists have <hi rend="underline">confederates</hi> <hi rend="underline">at</hi> several points in <hi rend="underline">our own</hi> County -- We have urged the propriety of keeping this threatened invasion a secret, for if it should as we suspect be a hoax, its publicity would produce unecessary Excitement, &amp; be <hi rend="underline">gratifying</hi> to these infamous scamps in the North -- Under the circumstances we think we should be prepared for any emergency that may arise, &amp; we therefore write to ascertain from you whether we can be supplied with arms &amp;c in the Event we raise a company -- We desire to <hi rend="underline">know</hi> this <hi rend="underline">before</hi> we make any move. Write us at your Earliest convenience upon the subject. Can we also have a cannon -- Felicity you are aware is the<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">3</note>
<lb/>head quarters of John G. Fee who was driven with his associates from this County -- He doubtless Entertains towards the people of our County for that act an Especial &amp; implacable hostility, and would urge any thing which would gratify his revenge -- </p>
<p>You doubtless have good reasons for the contrary, but it strikes us in this perilous crisis that the citizens of our whole State should be armed and <hi rend="underline">ready</hi> for any state of things which may occur -- Such preparation could not we believe result in, or be productive of harm to our country -- It could be <hi rend="underline">distinctly</hi> avowed why it was done, I cant think such a course of procedure could or would add<pb/>
<lb/>anything to the Excitement of our country, or with an <hi rend="underline">avowed</hi> of the <hi rend="underline">reason</hi> for such action, mislead the Extremists of either section -- Our people have great confidence in your wisdom &amp; prudence, but can't <hi rend="underline">understand</hi> your policy upon this point -- </p>
<p>We suggest that the object of this letter, for reasons you will at once <hi rend="str">suggest</hi> perceive, be kept a <hi rend="underline">profound</hi> <hi rend="underline">secret</hi> -- </p>
<p>Let us hear from you, &amp; if you can accomodate us with arms, what sort, and send us blank bonds &amp; instructions -- </p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>Yr Friends
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Thornton F. Marsall</hi>
<lb/>L J <hi rend="underline">Bradford</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
