<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0984"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">H. T. Harris and R. M. White to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5103</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-23 to BR11-24</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Stanford, Lincoln County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-07-25">25 July 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Stanford, Ky.
<lb/><date when="1864-07-25">July 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 64</date>.
<lb/>Governor!</p>
<p>I have rec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> no answer to my letter to you, relative to remitting the fine on forfeited recognizance of two lewd women, who were bailed by myself and our Jailor, R M. White. I enclose a statement from the records of our court- also a statement of Judge Bailey, in addition to the statement of Judge Murphy sent you with my former letter. The names of the girls are <hi rend="underline">Grady</hi>, instead of <hi rend="underline">Delany</hi> as stated to you before. Col T P Hill was the Bail of the latter, and I see you have<pb/>
<lb/>remitted the forfeiture in his case. I ask this favor of you as a matter of pure Justice, under the circumstances At the solicitation of many of our good citizens Mr White &amp; myself bailed them, in order to release them, and save expense to the Commonwealth, and to do an act of charity.</p>
<p>Your favor will be graciously recv<hi rend="sup">d</hi> The amt of the forfeiture is only $50- Yours truly.</p>
<p>H. T. Harris
<lb/><hi rend="underline">R M White</hi></p>
<p>Governor Bramlette.</p>
<p>I was anxious to have Mr Harris &amp; Mr White bail those girls, as they were diseased, lewd women, and a great expense to the Commonwealth, and our citizens generally<pb/>
<lb/>desired Mr Harris to act as atty for them and obtain their release. I know that it was at our solicitation that he &amp; Mr White acted in the matter, and Should be glad to see them released from the payment of any forfeiture if consistent with your will.</p>
<p>Your Ob<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Serv<hi rend="sup">t</hi>
<lb/>W G Barleyy P. J. L. C. C.</p>
<p>Gov Bramlette</p>
<p>The abve statement of facts are true I Join in the prayer for the remission of the Judgement and hope that the sum may meet your views of Executive clemency</p>
<p>Faithfully
<lb/>T. P. Hill</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
