<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1717"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John McDermott to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6354</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-211 to BR13-212</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlette Gov of Ky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner John McDermot would respectfully represent that at the <date when="1865-06">June</date> Term of the City of court of Louisville he was fined on a charge of keeping a tipling house, the Sum of sixty Dollars, your petitioner states that he did not keep a tipling ^house^ as was charged in the Indictment. but the case was got up against him through <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> his Brotherinlaw one Patrick Ryan and his wife, he says that he had boarded said Ryan, until he owed him thirty Dollars, and that when he asked him for the money he got very angry, and paid him with abuse, and after having a smal dificulty with him, on account of the nonpayment of said, board, said Ryan (though his brotherinlaw) went before the Grand Jury and indicted him as above stated, he fother says that said Ryan and wife were the only witnesses against him, and although he did prove (by three good and lawful witnesses who were very often in his house, that he did not keep a tipling house, and that he did not sell Intoxicating Liquors<pb/>
<lb/>in his house yet the Jury desided against him, your petitioner fother says that he has a large family and that he is a poor man and that it would go hard with him to pay said fine especially when so unjust, Wherefore he prays that your excellency will interpose your pardning power and relieve him from the payment of this fine, and your petitioner respectfully submits the signatures of the following Residents of the city of Louisville</p>
<p>John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Dermott</p>
<p>We the undersigned officers of the court and Citizens of Louisville would Suggest that we believe the above is a case which deserves the interposition of your Executive Clemency and therefore pray your Excellency to remit the fine against your Petitioner</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="3"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>F G Dannecker
<lb/>G Liff
<lb/>E Gruber
<lb/>F Waugh
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/>Jno. A. Walker
<lb/>B. Murray
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> O. Haly
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi>. Conelly
<lb/>Owen Langan
<lb/>Fred'k Wobbe
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Kaye
<lb/><cb n="3"/>Names
<lb/>Cornelius Sheehan
<lb/>James Dolan
<lb/>John Kelly
<lb/>James M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Dermott
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Goeppes
<lb/>M M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Graw
<lb/>H C Russell
<lb/>John K <unclear>Egers</unclear><milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>D M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Sweeney
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="3"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/><cb n="3"/>Names<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>There certainly was much ill feeling displayed by the witness. Ryan, against the petitioner Had I been acquainted with the facts before the trial, as I have learned them since, I think I would have dismissed the Indictment. I have remitted my costs in this case,</p>
<p>W. G. Reasor
<lb/>City atto</p>
<p>Your Petitioner John McDermott I know verry well and know him to be what he represents a Poor Man and works daily to support his Family Mallice was portrayed throught the trial</p>
<p>respectfully yours &amp;c
<lb/>W R Hydes Marshal</p>
<p>I can say the same as Mr Hydes</p>
<p>Phil Tomppert Jr<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="3"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/><cb n="3"/>Names<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>Louisville City Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Dormot
<lb/>$60,</p>
<p>Remit
<lb/><date when="1865-04-26">26<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Abl/65</date></p>
<p>sen<hi rend="sup">t</hi>. for fee</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
