<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0122"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">G. T. Wood to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4241</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-181 to BR8-182</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Munfordville, Hart County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-10-28">28 October 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Munfordville. <date when="1863-10-28">Oct 28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>.
<lb/>To/
<lb/>His Excellency Thomas E Bramlett.
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky.
<lb/>My Dear Sir.</p>
<p>Mr Franklin Gorin who stands charged in the Jefferson Circuit Court for shooting and wounding W. C. Wood is personally well known to me and has been from his childhood, has never been a violater of the laws, has always been obedient to the laws of this Commenwealth; is a man of the highest honor, of pure and incorruptable integrity. Was never guilty of a mean or dishonorable act during his long and useful life, and did not commit the act of shooting Mr Wood from any malice or previous motive, the affair being one of sudden passion and impulse. I respectfully ask your Excellency to interpose and exercise the <hi rend="underline">power you</hi> alone possess, and pardon Mr Gorin immediately. I ask not this alone on account of Mr Gorins long life of usefulness and his unspotted character, but because I believe <hi rend="str">I believe</hi> the public interest would not suffer by your pardoning Mr Gorin.</p>
<p>I am very
<lb/>Respectfully.
<lb/>G. T. Wood</p>
<p>Munfordville. <date when="1863-10-28">Oct 28<hi rend="sup">th</hi>/ 1863</date></p>
<p>We are intimately and well acquainted with Mr F Gorin and believing the statements made by<pb/></p>
<p>Mr Wood to be true, we respectfully ask your Excellency to immediately extend to Mr Gorin the exercise of the pardoning power.</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>Jas A Compton Clerk 
<lb/>Hart Circuit Court
<lb/>Henry M Shuffett clerk
<lb/>Hart County Court
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Gardner Presiding Judge of the <hi rend="underline">Hart County Court</hi>
<lb/>W B Craddock
<lb/>Sheriff of Hart County
<lb/>F A Smith
<lb/>B. L. Kerr
<lb/>Atty for Hart Co
<lb/>H C Martin
<lb/>Atty at Law
<lb/>Munfordville
<lb/>Ky
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> C Rush</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
