<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1517"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. Sanderson et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6154</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-351 to BR12-352</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-12">December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><date when="1863-12">Dec term/63</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thos E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Ky,
<lb/>Dear sir</p>
<p>At the last term of the Kenton Circuit Court I was fined in the sum of $60<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> on a charge of keeping a tippling house. There was but one witness and that a bitter enemy who certainly made statements in the matter of which <hi rend="underline">I</hi> <hi rend="underline">had</hi> <hi rend="underline">no</hi> <hi rend="underline">knowledge</hi>.</p>
<p>I am a huckster in the markets in Covington and use my best endeavors to make an honest living by my toil, at my home <hi rend="str">a</hi> I keep a grocery and have license to sell liquor by the quart</p>
<p>I am a poor man and think it hard that I should be singled out, by an enemy and <unclear>mulched</unclear> in a fine which I can ill afford to pay</p>
<p>Wherefore I ask your Excellency to remit so much of the above fine as by law may be remitted and as in duty bound will ever pray</p>
<p>Respectfully</p>
<p>We know Mr Leonard the above petitioner Know him to be a poor but sober and industrious man &amp; he has the reputation of being a very correct<pb/>
<lb/>and honest man. If guilty of the offence charged certainly his conduct heretofore has not been in keeping with the presumption of guilt, for he certainly, until the indictment under which he was fined was returned had ever appeared himself a law abiding man in our community. He has lived here many years is man of family and we believe fully <hi rend="underline">entitled</hi> to the <hi rend="underline">clemency</hi> pressed for in the foregoing petition</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names- of- the Jury -- 
<lb/>J Sanderson
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Marsh
<lb/>A. J. Gray
<lb/>Robt Howe
<lb/>C Heimbrock
<lb/>Lewis Keen
<lb/>Theodor Conham
<lb/>J M Yeats
<lb/>F P Martin
<lb/>J. G. Orr
<lb/>Moses Seoim
<lb/><cb n="2"/>C. U. nooan
<lb/>A. P. Rose
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Geisbauer
<lb/>J. E Clendenning
<lb/>Ch<hi rend="sup">as</hi> F. Fichter
<lb/>H. Winkerman
<lb/>Jos Harlin
<lb/>J. Clayton
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Coulter
<lb/>Saml Bowie
<lb/>Denis P. Noonan
<lb/>Michael H Levi
<lb/>Jas. C. Gedge
<lb/>Alex Collier
<lb/>Y. Werzel
<lb/>John F. Myers
<lb/>Henry Glover<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>Thomas Booth
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> C Mahon
<lb/>James Davison
<lb/>John Stuart
<lb/>James Malony
<lb/>David M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Kay
<lb/>J. C. Taylor
<lb/>James B Casey
<lb/>John M. Casey
<lb/>L M Shoemaker
<lb/>F. W. Lessing
<lb/>Dave Cox
<lb/>R T Lumplin
<lb/>David DeGarmo
<lb/>J. Grey
<lb/>John Wolf</p>
<p>The facts in the case are these <hi rend="str">at</hi> At the <date when="1863-06">June term (I think) up the Kenton Circuit at Covington 1863</date> the petitioner was found guilty by a Jury of the offense of selling liquor to Soldiers and fined $50 At the same Term of the court the same witness upon whose testimony he was convicted went before the Grand Jury and he was indicted for keeping a tippling house and at the <date when="1863-12">December</date> Term, he not appearing, I either took a judgment by default or introduced the<pb/>
<lb/>witness I am not certain which and got a judgment for $60 In a conversation afterwards with the witness She informed me that the only time she had ever known him to sell liquor by the samall was to the soldiers on the day named in the first Indictment -- He has in fact there fore been twice fined for the same offence. I recommend the remission of the last fine</p>
<p>R B Carpenter
<lb/>Comths atty</p>
<p>Kenton County
<lb/>Petition of Michael Leonard<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Relief refused
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette</p>
<p>upon statement of Comths atty of the facts a remission is granted</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/><date when="1865-02-01">Feby 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
