<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2234"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Edward D. Scott, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6871</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-54 to BR15-55</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Mercer Circuit Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against
<lb/>Edward D. Scott</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Mercer County, in the name, and by the Authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, accuse Edward D Scott of the crime of Murder, Committed as follows: The said Edward D Scott, on the <date when="1862-04-01">1' day of April 1862</date>, in the County aforesaid, did wilfully, feloniously &amp; of his malice aforethought Kill and Murder one James Tilford by Shooting him with guns &amp; pistols, against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Andy Barnett
<lb/>Atto for the Comlth.</p>
<p>Witness before the Jury</p>
<p>Isham Vanarsdall, Tho Eadlins, A W &amp; W A Margaret &amp; Nancy Treford, Bryan Eastland, D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Eastland &amp; Jones &amp; Abell, A B Bonta Dan<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Melburn -- </p>
<p>Endorsed A true bill
<lb/>N H Burns
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Foreman of the Grand Jury</hi><pb/></p>
<p>And at a term of said Court held on the <date when="1864-08-13">13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> August 1864</date>, the following Entry appeared the Order Book of Said Court</p>
<p>The Commonwealth of Kentucky Plaintiff
<lb/>against } Indit
<lb/>Edward D Scott Defendant</p>
<p>This day came the Commonwealth by attorney and the Jury Sworn hereon on a former day of this term, and also the defendant Scott in proper person, who was again placed at the bar in custody of the Sheriff.</p>
<p>And the Jury aforesaid having heard the evidence herein, with the argument of counsel thereon, upon their oaths, returned the following Verdict towit. "We of the jury acquit the defendant on the ground of insanity.</p>
<p>Geo F See foreman of the Jury"</p>
<p>It is therefore adjuged by the court that this prosecution be dismissed -- and that said defendant be again remanded to the Jail of Boyle county, there to be Kept safely until on demand of the Sheriff of Boyle County, he Shall be delivered to<pb/>
<lb/>the said Sheriff or his deputy, to be by him Conveyed to the Lunatic Assylum at Hopkinsville, there to remain until discharged there from according to law</p>
<p>The Clerk of this Court Will copy the Indictment herein, together with the judgment, and deliver the same to the Sheriff, who will deliver the same to the Superintendent of said Assylum<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The Names of the Jurors by whom the said Case was tried and verdict found, are as follows. vz -- Anderson Rice. Geo F Lee, H M Mitchel, Merton Crow. W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> <hi rend="str">F</hi> Johnson, W F Clarkson, A M Burbank, John R Simpson, C W Metcalfe, Austin Cosby, William Figg &amp; W H Stillman.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Boyle Circuit Court Clerks Office As clerk of Boyle Circuit Court, I certify that the foregoing pages contain a true copy of the Indictment tried in Boyle circuit Court at <date when="1864-08">August Term 1864</date> against Edward D Scott, the penal Judgment rendered thereon -- and also a list of the Jury by whom the same was tried.</p>
<p>Witness My Signature this <date when="1864-11-11">11 Nov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>M T, <hi rend="underline">Chrisman clk</hi>
<lb/><stamp type="revenue"/><pb/></p>
<p>Comlth
<lb/>vs } Copy Indct, Judgt and Test of Jury
<lb/>Scott,<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>For Messrs Kyle &amp; Harden
<lb/>Attos</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
