<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1342"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. L. Bristow and Leonard Stephens to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10810</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-257 to MG21-258</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-08-26">26 August 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Kenton Co. Ky <date when="1861-08-26">August 26<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>His Excellency. :Governor Magoffin</p>
<p>The undersigned would respectfully yet earnestly represent that we would recommend to your consideration a case that we consider well worthy of Executive clemency. <gap/> Taylor who was fined at the sitting of the circuit court of (our) Kenton Cunty held at Independence <date when="1861-06">June</date> term last the sum of <gap/> dollars one of us was present and heard the testimony in the case which was to the effect that said <gap/> Taylor being a school teacher &amp; haveing occasion to correct one of the schollars who is said to be a bad boy though the correction was mild yet a Brother of said boy who is a large powerful Man became greatly insensed and threatened to be revenged on said teacher who is a small weakly man, That at the end of said school the teacher was about leaving Mr Wickliff Grub<hi rend="sup">s</hi> for the purpose of collecting his pay one of Grub<hi rend="sup">s</hi> sons handed him a pistol and said to him he had better take it with ^him^ to defend himself shoud the individual above alluded attempt an assault he took it not as we believe with the desire or expectation of shooting but mearly to frighten him and prevent an atack on him^self^<pb/>
<lb/>and it was for that purpose soley that said weapon was to be used. That said individual did make an attack as contemplated or was in a menacing attitude &amp; it was not until then that any show of arms was manifested &amp; there only as we believe to frighten as before indicated and with no intention what ever of fireing it unless compelled by dire necesity, what said pistol was the property of young Grubs and not of Taylor as before state^d^ who has not been in the habit of carrying concealed weapons. The individual on seeing said Pistol immediately desisted from show of violence but at the court before stated made or gave information to the Grand Jury who indited said teacher and upon said indition he was fined Mr Grubs with whom Taylor boarded and who was security for his appearance beged a continuance of the case until the next day being familiar with all of the circumstance appertaining to the case but it being the last case on the docket Judge Moore refused allthough willing to continue it until the next term but Taylor expecting to leave prefered a trial It is believed if all of the circumstances had have been laid before the Jury there would have been no fine imposed All of which is respectfuly submitted<pb/>
<lb/>and is believed ^to be^ substantially true</p>
<p>That said Taylor is a stranger haveing lived amongst ^us^ only about one year appears an inoffensive Intelegent <hi rend="underline">Gentleman</hi> of Good Moral habits but Poor and illy able to pay said fine</p>
<p>R. L. Bristow
<lb/>Leonard Stephens</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
