<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0987"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John D. Berry to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10455</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-46</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Owingsville, Bath County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-04-09">9 April 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Owingsville Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-04-09">April 9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Gov. Magoffin
<lb/>Der Sir</p>
<p>I have no doubt but you will think my Communications are quite frequent in one direction; however we <hi rend="underline">public</hi> men have our missions &amp; duties to perform in rendering servises to our Consittuents in various ways -- &amp; in presenting to your excellency this Communication, I do it at the earnest solicitation of one of my peculiar &amp; particular friend A. Hart -- </p>
<p>At our last term of Bath Circuit Court he was tried upon an indictment found against him at a previous term of said Court &amp; fined in the Sum of $<hi rend="underline">60</hi> "Allen says for Treating a little last fall for Breckinridge=" In no doubt but he got the money -- but there is no doubt but the fine is excessive for the amount sold.</p>
<p>I will take it as an especial favor &amp; at the same time you will but be rendering an act of Kindness &amp; Charity to him &amp; his family to remit said fine, he is very poore &amp; has a clever wife &amp; some nice children that need evry dime he can command.</p>
<p>Genl Huston made a speech here on yesterday Upon the <hi rend="underline">Union</hi> <hi rend="underline">Democr</hi>atic ticket put forth by that long life <hi rend="underline">Democrat</hi> (<hi rend="underline">G D Prentis</hi>; The General Started out for the Crittenden resolutions; but argued for the Guthrie Franklin peace Conference<pb/>
<lb/>propositions &amp; wound up for staying in the union at any &amp; all hazards. Says the only way for Kentucky to maintain her institutions of slavery is to remain in the union, &amp; that he is not, so particular about trying to bring about such a Compromise as will bring back the states now out. So Kentucky &amp; the other border slave states are satisfied it makes no material difference as to the ballance! If they Cant get no guarentees the Constitution is good enough as it is</p>
<p>That Lincoln &amp; his party have given up their Chicago platform, &amp; their purposes are peace &amp; that their whole actions indicate a conservative course. The whole tener of his speech was submission &amp; to try and array the nonslaveholders against the slave holders' -- Send us some one to Canvass this district Bob. Woolley, if he will Come,</p>
<p>Your Obt Servt
<lb/>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> D Berry</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Bath Cir. Ct
<lb/>$60 } Tipling
<lb/>A. Hart
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-04-17">Apr 17. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
