<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2396"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. S. Maxey to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7033</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-327</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Tompkinsville, Monroe County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Tompkinsville Monroe County Ky</p>
<p>Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E. Bramlette, enclosed you will find a petition asking the Executive Clemency in behalf of Jno H. Deckard of this county The petition is short, and was drawn hurriedly but it is thought it contains facts meriting ^the^ clemency of your Honor. There are many circumstances connected with the matter that would tend in favor of M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Jno H. Deckard, but it was thought ^not^ necessary to state them.</p>
<p>I hope you will release him of all the fine except the cost. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Jno H. Deckard is a feeble man, getting old and a gentleman of irreproachable character &amp; no one to help him. If I had been in Scottsville I should have got some men to sign the petition there. Please write to me on the Subject &amp; if You see proper to release ^him^ I shall be glad to receive the information and feel that You have brought M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Deckard under many obligations &amp; done in the premises the wishes of all acquainted with the facts of the case.</p>
<p>W. S. Maxey.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
