<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0457"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Richard Allen, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4576</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-218</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Clark County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-01-29">29 January 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky, Clark County Sct
<lb/>Richard Allen of said State and County being duly sworn according to law, States First,</p>
<p>That he became the surety or bail for John D. Snowden, who was indicted at the <date when="1860-07">July Term 1860</date> of the Clark Circuit Court, upon charge of suffering Gaming in his House in Clark County Kentucky. That the amount of the Bail Bond was for $500<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi></p>
<p>Second, That at the <date when="1860-11">November Term 1860</date> &amp; the <date when="1861-05">May Term 1861</date>. the said John D. Snowden appeared in Court when his case was called; and at every term since his was indicted the Commonwealth has continued the cause, and at the <date when="1863-07">July Term 1863</date> his recognizance was forfeited and that the Said Snowden is now a citizen of Harrison County Kentucky and that a Bench Warrant has been issued &amp; sent to the Sheriff of Harrison County for his arrest</p>
<p>3rd That this affiant has in no wise connived at the non-appearance of the defendant Snowden &amp; is doing all in his power to have him before the Clark Circuit Court at its next <date when="1864-05">May Term 1864</date> &amp; will not relax<pb/>
<lb/>his efforts to that end.</p>
<p>4th
<lb/>That this affiant is a poor man, with a small place, and a large family of helpless children to support, and will be nearly ruined if he has the full amount of said bond to pay, and it will cripple him to such an extent as to cause suffering to innocent, helpless children</p>
<p>Richard Allen</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Richard Allen this <date when="1864-01-29">29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of January 1864</date>.</p>
<p>E. T. Taylor P. J. C. C.</p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">E T T
<lb/><date when="1864-01-29">Jan 29 
<lb/>1864</date></note></p>
<p>Richard Allen is very poor &amp; extremely ignorant. The payment of the Judment would require a sale of his land which would render hiim &amp; his family homeless. Snowden attended at some of the terms, but the case was continued by the Commonwealth. He will have to pay the fees of the Comth Atty $150. which alone will Harrass him very much. I recommend the exercise of Executive clemency. Mr. Snowden has been arrested &amp; gave Bonds &amp; attended at the last Term ^of the Court &amp; recognized to apear next Term^</p>
<p>A. H. Buckner
<lb/><date when="1864-06-04">June 4. 1864</date></p>
<p>I concur in the above statement of M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Buckner
<lb/>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> B Huston</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
