<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2162"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">D. R. Haggard to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6799</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-395 to BR14-396</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-08-05">5 August 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville <date when="1865-08-05">Augt 5<hi rend="sup">th </hi>1865</date>
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> T. E. Bramlette
<lb/>D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Sir</p>
<p>On the <date when="1865-07-10">10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of July. 1865</date>. You remitted a judgment of Six hundred dollars -- against Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> G. Barton and W. R. Link -- Obtained against themn as the Securities of J. V. Gilbert -- because of the informations of the Service of the Notice. Gilbert nor his attorneys -- were in Court. both being ignorant. as to when the case would be Called -- His Securities on his appearance bond, was released by you. Barton &amp; Link -- during the absence of Gilbert in his sick bed -- these irregularities occurred in the notice -- and on his return from the State of Tennessee where He was Sent by a Company of Gentlemen to lease oil lands -- at my Suggestion. He was met by an officer on his way to report to me his success. in the leasing business in Tennessee. And informed that He must be in<pb/>
<lb/>default of of the payment of a judgement rendered of which he Gilbert had never heard of ^before^ And did not know that the case had been called -- and his lawyer was not presant when the case was called -- rather tha^n^ See him ^go to the city work house -- ^ (as I then and now beleave -- He was ^not^ and is not guilty -- of the Charge of faro dealing -- Since you pardoned him -- for the offence Some months Since ( -- And allow me to digress just here one moment -- the money that He deposited as collateral Security in the first Case from which penalty you released him, by a pardon -- has been Kept by the officials -- and Gilbert has said thus to recover it -- ) He was Seased upon the Streets and brought to my office -- And I replevied the debt -- The judgment thus Singularly obtained amounting to (five hundred &amp; forty four dollars &amp; 45 Cents $544.45). The whole thing is the result of malice as I beleave -- The pound of <hi rend="underline">beef</hi> must come -- I ask for the Sake of Gilbert and myself as his Security -- that you remit the judgment and -- We will try the information<pb/>
<lb/>and the <hi rend="str">Shooting</hi> Sharp Shooting of the officials for their -- proffits in this Case -- I beleave Gilberts statement to me -- and others have stated the same Bartons Statement on his petition corroborates Gilberts -- it is only the feeling of revenge and malice that is felt by those who are willng to See the poor fellow injured if they Can proffit thereby -- release him &amp; I will be responsible for his future good Conduct -- in that regard -- He is verry -- poor but honest -- He has been ruined by the rebels in Tennessee. and he is not more than able to support a large family -- Who are wholey dependant. &amp; I Could not -- bear to See him go to the work house. When his family was without any resources whatever -- He being inocent of the Charge -- </p>
<p>Yr friend
<lb/>D R Haggard</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
