<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-022-0078"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Burgess Preston to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG12003</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>37th - 76th Regiments Enrolled Militia Primary Source Documents (1861-1866)</collection>
      <idno>Box 81, Folder 65th Regiment 1864 Recruiting</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Paintsville, Johnson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-08-05">5 August 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Head Quarters 65<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Kentucky Enrold Militia
<lb/>Paintsville Johnson County Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1864-08-05">August 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>In obediance to Genral Orders No 6 ishude by the Gavoner of Kentucky on the <date when="1864-06-03">3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> of June 1864</date> I proseeded on the <date when="--07-30">30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of July</date> last <hi rend="str">to make the</hi> make the company ordrd in Said order I made an effort to make the company by Volunteers out of the men that I could git to gether &amp; failed in that effort I orderd the Reidgment to randevou again in Paintsville on Tusday the <date when="---02">2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> instant</date> about Two thirds of the Reidgment attended and I made the company on the next day by detail I detailed one hundred and one men <hi rend="str">out of</hi> by ballat out of the difrent companys in the Reidgment not having but six companeys in the Reidgment &amp; neither of the companeys having the number of men required in the order the number either too small or to larg in making the ^companey^ by ballet it fell on some men that did not randevose Same I think are Reble Simpathisers purhaps Same that will have to be brought in by the forse of armes which I will endevor to do as soon as I can git same amunition I have in camps Fifty Five men- I have put my Lt Col in Command of the Company and have appointed the first second &amp; third <hi rend="str">Lts</hi> Lieutenants and they are acting as such-</p>
<p>We are in some danger here in the<pb/>
<lb/>condition We are in I only have about 40 guns 10 enfields Some shot guns the balance old guns the Rebles left scterd about in the country &amp; I had them gethered up &amp; have got all that I can find and they are all in vary bad order have no amunition Except a few rounds I got from the united States Troops at Louisa, We are 32 miles from any Federal Force and Reble Gerrillars perty close to us but if we can git arms &amp; amunition I dont ask them any difrance my boys will make them git up &amp; dust-</p>
<p>I tharefore desire the company he armed imeadately I think the guns for this company should be a good Scouting gun of larg rang as thare is a garet deal of Brush and high mountains to scout over in thsi country -- </p>
<p>in as mutch as I have had abad chance of information as it respects my duty in my organmising this company I desire all the information that you can give as it respects the organizanation armming Equiping &amp; subsisting the company we have no regular mail nearer than Louisa which is 32 miles no order that have bin sent to me have not reached here within the time that I wase orderd to purform the duty under the order I never Revievd the order <hi rend="str">to</hi> Refered to above till about the 25 of July when you communicat with me direct to the <unclear/> <hi rend="str">of the</hi><pb/>
<lb/>of the commander at Louisa Ky and he can convey to me by Express let me heare from you imeadately</p>
<p>Burges Preston
<lb/>Col Comdg, 65, Ky, E, M<pb/></p>
<p>65
<lb/>Ky. State Militia
<lb/>Paintsville John, Co. Ky.
<lb/><date when="1864-08-05">August 5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864.</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Preston Burges<hi rend="str">s</hi> Col. Comdg.
<lb/>65<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Reg. Ky. E. M. Johnson. Co.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Made an effort to raise a company under Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> order N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 6. by volg. but failed, on the <date when="---03">3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> inst</date> he detailed 101 men from his Reg. including three Lieuts and placed the same under command of his Lieut Col. Some of these men will have to be brought in by "force of arms"; and others of them are Rebel sympathizers. Has about 40 guns of different calibres. wants to be well armed and equipped, <hi rend="underline">Asks to be informed particularly about how his company is to be subsisted</hi> All communications to him to be directed to the Post Commandant at Louisa. Lawrence County, who will forward them.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><date when="1864-08-16">Aug 16-1864.</date> Answered on letter book Page 30.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Rec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> I. G. O. <date when="1864-08-15">August 15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
