<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1579"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Herny Stern et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11047</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-218 to MG22-219</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-11-26">26 November 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Governer of the State of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your petitioner Henry Steirn, a citizen of Louisville State of Kentucky, would respectfully state that during the month of <date when="1861-05">May 1861,</date> he was indicted by a Grand Jury of the Louisville City Court, for selling liquor to a minor and at the <date when="1861-06">June Term</date> of said Court <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>viz on <date when="1861-06-05">June 5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861,</date> he was by a jury duty empannelled fined the sum of $50.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> He further says that to this indictment he plead guilty, owing to the following state of facts.</p>
<p>Having a family of six children, and being unable to carry on business in my own name from misfortunes in business my brother-in-law advanced a small stock of confectionary and toys, which were placed in a small room in the East side of Lafayette Street between corner of <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>Floyd Streets of the City of Louisville, and I left my oldest son a youth of seventeen years of age to attend to this confectionary, while I worked at my trade in the Clothing Store of Messers Isaac Straus &amp; Co in the capacity of cutter. During my absence from home in pursuance of said employment as Cutter as aforesaid, my son without my consent, concurrance or connivance, allowed one of his play-mates and acquaintances not only to frequent the confectionary but to obtain liquor from a small bottle which I had in my house for the use of my family exclusively. My family accupying the same building in which the<pb/>
<lb/>said confectionary was situated. When informed of this I was compelled to give up my situation as cutter aforesaid and have since in person attended to said confectionary, in order to prevent further infractions of the laws of the land.</p>
<p>The law holds your petitioner resonsible for the acts of his employee, and thus he had no defense, and while he regrets that the michevious conduct of a son raised amid the vices of City, have been in this petition exposed, his necesities, and the wants of a large family in this time of financial embarassment, and civil commotions, require that he should most earnestly petition your excellency to relieve him of the penalty of law, by remitting this fine. Your petitioner would further state that this infraction of the law became known to the city authorities by reason of his attempts as a father to break up the intimacy between his son and the minor who obtained this liquor, as your petitioner did wish him to frequent his house, or associate with his family.</p>
<p>Wherefore having with great difficulty discharged the costs, and <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>Atty's commissions incident to this fine, your petitioner in view of his real innocence, and family necessities now appeals to your executive clemency to relieve him from the further liability arising from this fine, and as in duty bound, this he will ever pray &amp;c.</p>
<p>Henry Stern</p>
<p>Subcribed &amp; sworn to before me by Henry Stearn this <date when="1861-11-26">26<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of november 1861.</date></p>
<p>A Maas N. P. J. C<pb/></p>
<p>The undersigned unite with Mr Stearn in his Petition &amp; respectfully ask your Excellency to remit the fine as in his said petition set forth.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> W<unclear/>
<lb/>H C Russell
<lb/>James Harris
<lb/>Jno. I. Howe D. sheriff
<lb/>A H M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kay
<lb/>Jo<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Clement
<lb/>Jno M Famar
<lb/>Joseph Odell
<lb/>Wm J. Craddock
<lb/>C. K Farrington
<lb/>Jack Fry.
<lb/><cb n="2"/>S. S. Meddis D S
<lb/>J R Green
<lb/>J M Foree<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Petition of Henry Stearn or Stirn for remission of a fine inposed in Lou. C. C. on <date when="1861-06-05">June 5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861.</date></p>
<p>Respite 12 Mo
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-12-20">Dec<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. 20. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
