<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0110"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky vs. John Cauffield, Abstract</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8562</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-170 to R3-170B</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hancock County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>We the undersigned grand Juryman for Hancock County at <date when="1862-02">Feby. term 1862</date> would respectfully represent to the Judge of the court that we have found an Indictment ^"for keeping Tippling house"^ against one John Cauffield &amp; owing to the fact of his demented mind &amp; helpless condition, &amp; the further fact that his wife is the only support for the family and being unwilling that her earnings should be taken from her family to pay any <hi rend="underline">fine</hi> that may be inflicted against sd Cuffield, would urge in view of these considerations that the court would acquit him of any penalty if consistent with duty </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>I concur in the above Petition having tried the Law &amp; facts in the case I am clear it is a matter for Executive Clemency</p>
<p>James Stuart
<lb/>Circuit Judge.
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names of Grandury
<lb/>N. C. Dawson, forman
<lb/>Jessy Rice Jr
<lb/>P H Messmure
<lb/>M H Johnston
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Carder
<lb/>Daniel Jagers
<lb/>N. B. Dupuy
<lb/>S. B. Sinder
<lb/>T. B. Moorman
<lb/>G. Lawson
<lb/>A. G. Chambers
<lb/>Sams Boling
<lb/>Jefferson Richy
<lb/>C, G, Tift
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> C. Mitchell<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Kentucky Hancock Circuit Court, Sct:
<lb/><date when="1862-08">August Term 1862</date></p>
<p>Commonwealth Plaintiff
<lb/>Against } On an Indictment for keeping a Tippleing house
<lb/>John Cauffield Defendant.</p>
<p>This day came the Attorney for the Commonwealth and the Defendant his Attorney, And by consent the law and facts submitted to the Court, and the evidence being closed and the Court duly advised, It is adjudged that the Defendant is guilty as charged, of keeping a tippling house, and that for said offense he make his fine to the Commonwealth by the payment of sixty dollars, and also that he pay the costs herein, &amp; may be taken &amp;c</p>
<p>A Copy Att:
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Eldred E Pate Clerk</hi><pb/></p>
<p>This is to certify that W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Mason who was Presiding Judge of Hancock County departed this life on the <date when="1861-12-18">18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Dec<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> 1861</date> and that his Successor Dr. T Holmes did not qualify until the <date when="1862-01-16">^16<hi rend="sup">th</hi>^ Jany 1862</date> <hi rend="str">Term</hi> of the Hancock County Court, which left a space of near one month that this county was without an acting county Judge, as appears by the records of the said Hancock County Court Clerks office</p>
<p>Witness my hand as clerk of said Court this <date when="1862-11-15">15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of November 1862</date>.</p>
<p>Eldred E Pate Clerk.
<lb/>Hancock County Court. Ky.</p>
<p>I further certify that at the called term of Said Court trial on the <date when="1862-02-03">3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> day of Feby 1862</date> a license was taken out by Patrick Murphy the owner of the house and brother of Mrs Caffield to keep a tavern in said house, as also appears by referred to said Records</p>
<p>Witness my hand as above
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Eldred E Pate Clk</hi><pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned members of the bar in attendance when the trial of Caughfield took place certify that it was proven on the trial that the said Caughfield was a poor demented person with but little of any business intelligence, indeed some of the witnesses gave it as their opinion that he had not sufficient mind at the time he was charged with the violation of the Statute to know right form wrong, whilst others thought he had sufficient mind to know a little about business matters, but very slight= </p>
<p>It was also proven that by reason of his constant inebriation and general inability of person &amp; mind, his wife was the only dependence for support of himself and family. they having some small children </p>
<p>We further certify that his condition has been and is as bad at present as it was at the time above referred to, and from all evidences is likely to continue so until <hi rend="underline">whiskey</hi> <hi rend="underline">does</hi> <hi rend="underline">its</hi> <hi rend="underline">work</hi> f<hi rend="underline">or</hi> <hi rend="underline">him</hi>= And that if the fine of $60. is collected it will be a sore infliction upon Mrs Caughfield and the little children, and take from her her hard earnings, which is scant enough indeed for a family in the situation of hers -- We would respectfully urge the Governor of Kentucky to exercise his executive clemency in this matter and respite the fine to the limit of the law. The ends of public Justice will be exemplified by so doing in our opinion</p>
<p>R. Y. Bush
<lb/>G. W. Williams
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W. P. D. Bush</hi></p>
<p>I certify that I was clerk of the Circuit Court when the above named trial was had, and I can fully endorse the statement of the members of the Bar as appears above</p>
<p>I further certify that he the said Caughfield was Indicted and found guilty for <hi rend="str">selling</hi> keeping a "tippling" house during the period between the time of the death of W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Mason former County Judge and the qualification of D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> T. Holmes his successor</p>
<p>Witness my hand
<lb/><hi rend="underline">James E. Stone</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Petition of John Cauffield
<lb/>To
<lb/>His Excellency Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Robinson<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Hancock County<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>$60 } Tipling</p>
<p>Fine in this case all remitted except the sum of Ten dollars</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J F Robinson</hi>
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-02-09">Feby 9. 1863</date>
<lb/>W P D Bush<pb/></p>
<p>Agt } Judgment
<lb/>Jno Cauffield
<lb/><date when="1862-08">August Term 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
