<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0269"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">D. A. Davis to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9737</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-246</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Pulaski County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner D. A. Davis would respectfully represent that at the <date when="1859-07">July Term 1859</date> of the Pulaski Circuit Court he was fined the sum of twenty five dollars for Gaming and that a capias for his body is now in the hands of the Sheriff. He says that the Indictment was procurred against him through malicious and revengeful feelings, He says that he Committed the offence for which he was indic<hi rend="sup">t</hi><hi rend="str">ment</hi>. but that him and a few neighbors were playing in an out of the way ^place^ for amusemsent and not for profit. That the prosecutor became angry at one of the party and indicted the whole party to gratify his malice against one, He says he is a hard working man and supports his large family by his own labor and not by Gambling. He says he is poor and that to force the collection of this fine. would materially injure him more especial during the present financial crisis. That the wealthy are scarcely able at this time to pay their debts much ^less^ a poor man who has a large family dependant upon him for Support. He there fore prays yours excellency<pb/>
<lb/>either to remit said penalty or at least to give a Stay for twelve months,</p>
<p>D. A Davis</p>
<p>We the undersgined unite in the prayer of the above petition</p>
<p>Thomas. Z. Morrison
<lb/>W D Black
<lb/><hi rend="underline">V. P. Moore</hi>
<lb/>H B Allcorn
<lb/>R Graves
<lb/>Jenkins Vickery
<lb/>Frank,, J,, White
<lb/><hi rend="underline">E Thompson</hi> -- </p>
<p>Pulaski Cir. Ct
<lb/>Respite 12 mo
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>$20 } Gaming
<lb/>D. A Daivs
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1860-12-24">Dec<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 24. 1860</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
