<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3318"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. W. Tise and C. T. Marshall to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5437</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-152</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To H. Excellency Thos E. Bramblette,
<lb/>Gov of Kentucky.
<lb/>Governor</p>
<p>Hon R. K. Williams who will hand you this note will explain it Mr Paine was at the present term of the court conficted of keeping a gaming home upon evidence of playing for treats and although the conviction was in my judgment according to law &amp; evidence yet this seems to be a hard case on Paine who is a worthy gentleman and he alone is indicted and tried when probably every saloon keeper in the county is equaly guilty, and <hi rend="underline">more worthy</hi> of punishment than Mr Paine I therefore request if it seems proper and consistent with your executive discretion that you look favorably upon Mr Paines case</p>
<p>Yours &amp;c
<lb/>W. W. Tise Comths atty
<lb/>1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> J. D.
<lb/>C. T. Marshall Judge</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
