<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0392"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George W. Johnston to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4511</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-119</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-12-04">4 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville Ky. <date when="1863-12-04">Dec<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>.
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>Thomas E. Bramlett
<lb/>Dear Sir.</p>
<p>Some months since a man by the name Marion Rowland who has for sometime been under a bad reputation was brought before me charged with having stolen a lot of coffee from a Grocer in this city which was found at the House of Michael Fahay</p>
<p>On the Examination of the case Fahay was Introduced as a witness &amp; proved that he was working on the farm of a Brother in Law of Rowland, that Rowland came to his house at night &amp; brought the coffee giving some account of haveing purchased it &amp; asked him to keep it for him till the next day &amp; he not suspecting that it was stolen, consented &amp; took charge of the coffee. The party who lost it gave Information of his loss to the police &amp; they found it at the house of Fahay, on this &amp; other Testimony as to Rowlands character. He (Rowland) was held to answer in the circuit court. When the case was taken up by the Grand Jury they returned <hi rend="str">a</hi> a Indictment against Fahay &amp; discharged Rowland Fahay was arrested &amp; committed to Jail an Mr. R. A. Hamilton who was familiar with the proof in the case &amp; being satisfied that Fahay was Innocent became his security for his appearance in the circuit court in the sum of $300. Fahay who is a verry Ignorant man became alarmed &amp; failed to appear &amp; a forfeiture of the recognizance was Entered<pb/></p>
<p>and Judgement will be entered at the next Term, unless your Excellency will remit the penalty. M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Hamilton was Induced solely by his kind feelings to become the security of Fahay &amp; not for any pecuniary consideration I would be glad to see him released from the liability. I feel well assured that Fahay was Innocent of any Intentional wrong and was Induced to runaway because of the alarm &amp; fear of a Trial opperating on a weak mind</p>
<p>I am D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Sir verry
<lb/>respectfully Yr obt servt
<lb/>Geo. W. Johnston</p>
<p>Louisville Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-04-25">April 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi>/64</date>
<lb/>Dear Governor -- </p>
<p>M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Hamilton is not able to pay more than the commissions of com<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">ths</hi></hi> atty. and other costs. I hope your Excellency will relieve ^him^ from the residue</p>
<p>Respfly y.
<lb/>P. B. Muir</p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>R A. Hamilton
<lb/>$300.
<lb/><date when="1864-04-26">26<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Apl/ 64</date>
<lb/>Remit all except 30 percent the fees of Comths atty &amp; the costs of prosecution
<lb/>Thos E Bramlette</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
