<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0465"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Claiborne Lisle et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4583</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-229 to BR9-230</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Clark County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-01-26">26 January 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>Thomas E Bramlett
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned Claiborn Lisle respectfully respectfully represents that on the <date when="1860-05-24">24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of May 1860</date> he became bound as surety in a Recognizance Bond for the appearance of Marcus Lisle at the <date when="1860-07">July Term 1860</date> of the Clark Circuit Court Ky to answer an Indictment wherein he was charged with Gaming -- $20= being said to have been won &amp; lost in 24 hours, the amount of that Bond being $100=</p>
<p>Afterwards, (during the pending of the foregoing)- to wit on the <date when="1861-05-18">18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of May 1861</date> he became further bound as the surety of said Marcus Lisle in another Recogniznace Bond, the penalty of which was $1000= for his appearance at the <date when="1861-07">July Term 1861</date> of the aforesaid Court to answer an indictment for Gaming, the charge being that $2000= were won &amp; lost in 24 hours</p>
<p>Your Petitioner further states that said Marcus Lisle appeared in said Court under the first named Indictment at the <date when="1860-07">July Term 1860</date>- <hi rend="str">and</hi> but the case was continued by the Commonwealth at the Term and also at the succeeding Terms- of <date when="1860-11">November 1860</date>= <date when="1861-05">May</date>-<date when="1861-07">July</date> &amp; <date when="1861-11">November 1861</date> = and at the <date when="1862-05">May</date> &amp; <date when="1862-07">July Terms 1862</date> = said Marcus Lisle was also present at the Apperance Term <date when="1861-07">July 1861</date>= to answer the 2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> Indictment aforesaid, but it was continued by the<pb/>
<lb/>Commonwealth, and was also continued at <date when="1861-11">November Term 1861</date> and <date when="1862-05">May</date> &amp; <date when="1862-07">July <hi rend="str">and November</hi> Terms 1862</date> - The said Lisle being present at each of the Terms of said Court subsequent to <date when="1861-05">May 1861</date>- and inclusive of <date when="1862-07">July 1862</date>, in the fall of <date when="1862">1862</date>- he went into the Confederate service <hi rend="str">and departed this life in in the fall of <date when="1862">1862</date></hi> - &amp; was not present at the <date when="1862-11">November Term 1862</date> of said Court and both of the said Bonds were declared <hi rend="str">Forfeited</hi>, and at the <date when="1863-05">May Term 1863</date> Judgments were respectively rendered against your Petitioner upon the aforesaid Bonds for $<hi rend="underline">100</hi>.= and $<hi rend="underline">1000</hi> Dollars</p>
<p>Said Marcus Lisle always asserted and your Petitioner believed he was not guilty of the Matters charged against him <hi rend="underline">he</hi> departed this life in the spring of <date when="1863">1863</date> and left no Estate, from which his surety could be indemnified in part or in whole - Your Petitioner therefore respectfully solicits your Excellency to exonerate him from the payment of the aforesaid Judgments.</p>
<p>Claiborne Lisle</p>
<p>Clark County Kentucky sworn to before me by Claiborne Lisle - <date when="1864-01-26">Jany 26 1864</date></p>
<p>A H Buckner clk</p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp"><unclear/> 
<lb/><date when="1864">1864</date></note><pb/></p>
<p>The undersigned citisens of Clark County respectfully request that the two Judgments mentioned in the foregoing Petition may be remitted &amp; Claiborne Lisle released from the payment thereof.
<lb/><date when="1864-01-27">Jany 27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date></p>
<p>Ambrose G. Bush
<lb/>A. N. Bush<pb/></p>
<p>Winchester Ky <date when="1864-07-24">July 25 1864</date></p>
<p>I was acting as Commonwealths attorney at the <date when="1863-11">November Term 1863</date> of the Clark Circuit Court, &amp; the facts set forth by Claiborne Lisle Eq. in his foregoing affidavit I believe to be true, I think that this case is a meritorious one, under all the circumstances, and under the peculiar hardship of the case I recommend it for Executive Clemency.</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>Jas Flanagan<pb/></p>
<p>I have been acting as Sheriff of said court during the <unclear>duraency</unclear> of the above named cases &amp; know that the facts are faithfully represented &amp; think it is a case that demands if any does executive clemency</p>
<p><date when="1864-07-25">July 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Sam G Stuart S.C.C
<lb/>G W Laughlin
<lb/>N. B. Gentry
<lb/>A H Sympson D S</p>
<p><date when="1864-12-26">Decr 26th 1864</date>
<lb/>I recommend this
<lb/>Jno. B Huston</p>
<p>Petition of C Lisle for Remission of Judgt in case of Marcus Lisle</p>
<p>I fully concur in and request that the prayer of the foregoing Petition be granted</p>
<p><date when="1864-12-26">Decr 26th 1864</date>
<lb/>Chas Eginton</p>
<p>Claiborne Lisles Petition</p>
<p>For Remission of Judgts rendered at <date when="1863-05">May Term 1863</date> of Clark Circuit Court on Recognizance Bonds -- the Judgts being against Claiborne Lisle for the amounts severaly of $<hi rend="underline">100</hi>=&amp;$<hi rend="underline">1000</hi></p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1865-01-04">4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Jany/ 65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
