<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3180"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Jack Shepherd, Instructions to Jury</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5299</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-228 to BR41-229</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The court instructs the jury in behalf of the Commonwealth as follows</p>
<p>1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rst</hi></hi> If the jury are satisfied from all the testimony in this case beyond a reasonable doubt that John alias Jack Shepherd on the night of the <date when="--04-02">2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> of April last</date> in this county and with malice aforethought took the life of John Collins by shooting him in the side with a gun or pistol they should find him guilty of murder as charged in the Indictment</p>
<p>2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> If the jury are satisfied (from) <hi rend="underline">in</hi> the testimony in the cause that any one or more of the witnesses have Knowingly and corruptly sworn falsely to any material fact they may entirely exclude all the statements of such witness or witnesses in their consideration of this case</p>
<p>3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> Unless the jury are satisfied from the testimony that such statement or statements are made corruptly and wilfullly false they should not exclude all such statements in their consideration of this case</p>
<p>4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> The jury are the sole judges of the credibility to be attached to the statements made by each witness in the cause and in forming their opinion as to what weight they should<pb/>
<lb/>attach to any statements made by any of the witnesses, they may consider not only the statement itself connected with other testimony in the cause they should also take into consideration the manner and conduct of the witness at the time he or she gave in their testimony in the stand</p>
<p>5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> If the jury are satisfied from all the evidence except that of the Alibi beyond a reasonable doubt of the guilt of the prisoner then the law requires that the accused who for his defence relies upon <hi rend="str">the</hi> ^an^ Alibi shall by his testimony in order to establish that alibi cover the whole time of the transaction in question so as to render it unpossible <hi rend="str">in</hi> under all the facts in the cause that the prisoner could have committed the deed and it is not enough that the statements relied on to establish such alibi render guilt impossable merely</p>
<p>Copied at Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> P Chambers for
<lb/>Hop Price<pb/>
<lb/>Comlth
<lb/>vs } Copy of Plffs Instructions
<lb/>Jack Shepherd<figure type="hr"/>for
<lb/>J. Hop Price</p>
<p>Attest copy</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
