<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2755"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Wiley P. Fowler to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7392</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-445 to BR16-446</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-11-18">18 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Steamer Charmer <date when="1865-11-18">Nov 18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Gov. Bramlett
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>I am directly from Marion Crittenden County My Court there ^ended^ unfortunately The vigalent wach and energy of Captain Jonathan Belt caused the arrest of the notorious James Guess He was brought to Marion and lodged in the jail there, and directed to be strictly guarded. After which armed men some in Federal unifrom and others dressed as Citizens, become much more numerous than before; all apparently excited and denouncing the action of the ^court^ together with the citizens of the county who seemed disposed by ther remarks and conversations to add to the discontent</p>
<p>On wednesday the number increased Secret consultations among them was noticed a man they called Captain Gibson from Hardin County Ill. made his appearance. He apparently was looked to as a leader. I was informed by letter that the jail would be broke that night, Found Capt Dowell was confined<pb/>
<lb/>at home two miles in the country sick and unable to leave his bead &amp; unable to summon his recruits. The sheriff and Jailor were directed to make the guard as strong as posible this was done</p>
<p>About 12 oclock the robbers made their appearance overpowered the guard, picketed in the citizens and with axes and sledges broke the jail and rescued Guess.</p>
<p>The grand jury next morning were called into court recharged and found bills of indictments against several among the <unclear>rest</unclear> this captain Gibson for the prison breach &amp; rescue</p>
<p>I felt and know after Guess release that the court, grand jury, and witneses were in their power. After Dark Capt. Bush made known to me that they, Guess at their head, had agreed to and arranged a plan to capture and hang me and that I had no time to spare to make my escape from them. I believed and acted upon his suggestion left town &amp; have kept out of their reach and am now on my way to the Hopkins court I am informed they did<pb/>
<lb/>not make their appearance publicly that night nor since So ended this court -- leaving the citizens of whole country especially the grand jury and witnesses in great allarm and I conceive danger</p>
<p>I recommend a reward for Guess and will forward copy of indictment against Gibson that demand may be made upon the Gov. of Ill. for his delivery. to the authority of the commonwealth so far as I can persuade citizens of Hardin county to arrest him and bring him over in advance of the requisition believe if made it would sanction the arrest</p>
<p>Capt Finnel will inform you fully as to the necessity of the organization of military companies and existance of the necessity of immediate action Would be glad you would write to Capt R A Dowell and instruct him the course to persue, and to the others you may appoint</p>
<p>I have every reason to believe the combination and its influence is more extensive than at first reported</p>
<p>Do for us all you can and with as much dispach as posible</p>
<p>I have the honor to be most respectfully
<lb/>your friend &amp; humbler servant
<lb/>W. P. Fowler<pb/></p>
<p>P S I recommend the appointment of captains in Union &amp; Webster counties also &amp; Capt Finnel have the power to designate the men</p>
<p>Crittenden</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
