<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3308"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Purdue and Joseph Owens to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5427</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-137 to BR42-138</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Wayne County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>Thos.E. Bramlette, Gov of Kentucky:</p>
<p>Your Petitioners Joseph Owens and William Perdue state that Nancy Ann Denney killed one Martin Kennedy and was arrested and tried before a court of Enquiry; sent to farther trial and admitted to bail in the sum of One thousand Dollars. Said Nancy Denney failed to appear, and the bond was forfeited and judgment rendered in the Wayne Circuit Court for One thousand Dollars and costs. The said Nancy was perfectly justifiable in law and right for said homicide. The killing was in self defence as was abundantly shown by the evidence before the Court of Enquiry -and the Justices of the Peace, contrary to their judgment of right and law sent said Nancy to further trial not because of her guilt but to save her from being mobbed and killed by certain reckless and dissolute men who were at that time returned or discharged soldiers and claimed to be friends of the deceased, and who publicly declared and threatened upon the day of the Examining trial, and afterwards that they would take her life if she was turned loose, and they were prepared to put their threats into execution, the country at that time being in such a condition that the civil law or authorities were entirely inadequate to restrain them. In consequence of these facts, the said Nancy was advised by good, prudent, and law abiding citizens to leave the country to avoid a mob which she did for that purpose, and in pursuance of that advice and <hi rend="underline">not</hi> to avoid a trial because her case was and is notoriously justifiable, for the whole<pb/>
<lb/>body of the proof showed clearly that the deceased the day he was killed went to the house in which said Nancy then lived with her Grandfather, and with a gun in his hand in the most violent and threatening manner declared that he had come there for the purpose of killing her; - and abused her Grandfather most brutally because he refused to tell him where to find her. _ And further that she is a prudent and reputable woman and had never givin him any cause whatever to wish to take her life</p>
<p>Your petitioners are both very old and poor men and one of them is the Grandfather of said Nancy and they appeal to the justice and honor of your Excellency to pardon said Judgments, and releive and release them from a burthen so grievous and severe.</p>
<p>William Purdue
<lb/>Joseph Owens</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Wayne county fully endorse the above</p>
<p>John Denney
<lb/>Charles owens
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Bartteson
<lb/>Thomas Davis
<lb/><unclear>Garrath</unclear> Hinds
<lb/>J. T. Wilhite
<lb/>Thomas Franklin
<lb/>Smith Barrers
<lb/>James.M. Daugherty
<lb/>John. M. Suttle
<lb/>John Hopper<pb/>
<lb/>J H Meadows
<lb/>C W Ard
<lb/>James Bobbett
<lb/>W A Buster
<lb/>F D Frosts
<lb/>Josiah Dodson
<lb/>Joseph Baker
<lb/>R. Burnett
<lb/>P. Miller
<lb/>J W Duncan
<lb/>William Miller
<lb/>L R Jones
<lb/>Benjamin Burk
<lb/>Samuel Walden
<lb/>John R Dick
<lb/>Peter Marshall
<lb/>Joshua Berry
<lb/>B. F. Fleming
<lb/>A. M. Saller
<lb/>E W Lee
<lb/>H Huffaker
<lb/>L. F. Tuttle
<lb/>James a Phillips
<lb/>James Jones
<lb/>James Garris J P
<lb/>E Saylor
<lb/>W D Ingram
<lb/>C. H. Buster
<lb/>H. R. Saufley
<lb/>R. C M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Beath J P before whom Nancy Denney was tried</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
