<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2215"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John P Hukill et al. to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9291</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-345</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The undersigned citizens of Clark County Kentucky, respectfully represent to your Excellency, that at the <date when="1860-05">May Term 1860</date>. of the Clark Circuit Court, George Goosey confessed judgment in the case for <hi rend="underline">Gaming</hi>, which occured three years Since, in which he played a five cent game in each instance <hi rend="underline">not for purposes</hi> of gain but simply amusement, That he is a moral good citizen, and has not since played a game of any kind, as we have been informed by his associates. The amount of the Judgment in each case was $20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> and costs, We respectfully ask that in consideration of the high character &amp; good conduct of the said Goosey ever since the indictments was found against him, that a pardon be granted by your Excellency in each case,</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>John P Hukill
<lb/>William Munday
<lb/>James Munday
<lb/><cb n="2"/>A. r. Evans
<lb/>A N Burh
<lb/>Thos Gaines
<lb/>Geo M Jackson
<lb/>S. W. J. Brock
<lb/>David Brown
<lb/>W. W. Storm
<lb/>S H Cochran</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
