<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2894"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John P. Hall to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7531</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-210 to BR17-211</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Morganfield, Union County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-15">15 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Morganfield Union County Ky <date when="1865-12-15">Decr 15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Bramlette
<lb/>Govonor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The Undersigned your petitioner does himself the honor to very respectfully present the following Statement of facts and ask your favorable consideration of the Same -- </p>
<p>during the Month of <date when="1857-11">Novr 1857</date> your petitioner had the misfortune to become engaged in a violent combat with and Slay Dr R W N Taylor in the town of Caseyville Ky -- that he immediately Surrendered himself to the legal authorities by whom he was committed to prison -- where he remained for twelve months -- " when he was arraigned in the Union circuit court and tried upon the charge of Murder" and after an investigation lasting over three weeks during the great public excitement -- the Jury disagreed and he was admitted to bail in the excessive Sum of 5000$</p>
<p>From this time (<date when="1858-11">Novr 1858</date>) until after the <date when="1861-10">October term 1861</date> your petitioner remained in the vicinity working at his trade and applying his daily earnings to the discharge of the heavy debts entailed by his misfortune -- attending each term of the court anxious to procure another trial of his cause and was Successively put off at each term (Save one) bu the prosecution In fact the whole case Seemed to have degenerated from the high purpose of legal Justice into a partisan Strife -- </p>
<p>Our late civil war had now begun the banner of Sedition was unfurled in our midst "troops" had<pb/>
<lb/>been "and' were being raised under it -- " Vindictive Scorn and threats of violence were launched at all who Should oppose; your petitioner took an active part in opposition and in attempting to enlist men for the Union Army encountered as persecution that drove him out until of the State -- " he immediately entered the Federal Service in an Ills regiment where by Legislative enactment he was allowed to remain without forfeiting his Bail Bond -- until after having Served his country faithfully near four years In the Grand old army of the Tennessee during "its' various achievements In Ternn -- "Miss" -- "Ala" Louisiana "Ark" Georgia the Carolinas and Virginia he was honorably mustered out with his command at Little Rock Ark in <date when="1865-08">August 1865</date> when he returned hom to answer the Old charge and attended the <date when="--10">October</date> term of the court and found that out of about Seventy witnesses only Six or Eight were present and that the balance were Scattered to different points Some dead and many beyond the Jurisdiction of the Court and that there was no probablity of a trial for year to come -- "</p>
<p>the Sole origin of this homicide and that trail was Simply this." the Deceased had committed a wanton act of Letchery upon the young wife of your petitioner -- which Sent her clothed with Shame to a Nunnery and to Save his own reputation essayed to run your petitioner from the Community or into a retraction and failing in this" -- Sought his life and in the attempt was Slain..<pb/></p>
<p>Your petitioner is a poor man <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>disabled for life in his countrys Service" many fo his important witnesses have died or left the County and State he is but "illy" able to provide the necessary means to Secure thier attendance at court" -- </p>
<p>he believes that if he could get a trial upon the Merits of his case he would be acquitted -- he does not believe that the case can ever be tried upon its merits "if at all"</p>
<p>he believes that his further prosectuion (except as a personal gratifcation to a few) can only result in expense to the commonwealth and annoyance and expense to himself</p>
<p>he does not believe that his immediate release by the Executive would prejudice the cause of Justice the rights of the Commonwealth or any individual</p>
<p>In addition (while deeply lamenting this Sad Misfortune) he can most truly Say that throuhgout this whole affair he has been activated by the higher attributes of our nature and Simply done what necessity and right Seemed to demand</p>
<p>In view of the facts herein and those Contained in the accompanying papers your petitioner very respectfully yet earnestly asks -- for the interposition of executive power in his behalf to the extent if his immediate release from further prosecution in this case</p>
<p>Very Respectfully your obt Serv
<lb/>John. P. Hall<pb/></p>
<p>Frankfort KY <date when="1866-01-08">Jany 8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1866</date> -- 
<lb/>John. P. Hall
<lb/>Petition</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
