<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2570"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Timothy King, Affidavits</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7207</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-108 to BR16-109</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Com'th vs Timothy King</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Coroner Gill</hi> in addition stated that the pistol shot wound was in the back of deceased -- </p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Bridget Casey</hi> also stated that she <hi rend="underline">Knew</hi> of no cause of jealousy between accused &amp; deceased, stated that she worked as a hired girl for her living<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Peter Larson</hi> did <hi rend="underline">not</hi> state that he "<hi rend="underline">did not recognise</hi> the accused as the man who shot deceased" but stated that although he saw the man who did the shooting he would now be unable to identify him</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Mrs story</hi> also stated that she would be unable to recognize or identify the man who fired the pistol &amp; could not tell whether accused was the man or not</p>
<p>Julia Brady stated that she <hi rend="underline">thought</hi> that accused did not leave the house untill <hi rend="underline">about</hi> ten minutes after the deceased and Bridget Casey left. -- he talked with me during the time pleasantly enough.<pb/></p>
<p>The affidavit made by accused for continuance states that he met Million (not a the door of Bradleys as stated in counsels notes) <hi rend="underline">after he had left Bradleys</hi> &amp; that they were on guard -- (but <hi rend="underline">not</hi> <hi rend="underline">late</hi> at night)</p>
<p>When arrested he put on a blouse (dark) &amp; a white hat of the description worn by him, was also found in the room he slept in. he was arrested in bed, about <hi rend="str">2</hi>1 o'clock at night.</p>
<p>J R Dupuy</p>
<p>not having any notes by me the above are about the only points on which I differ with counsel as to the testimony in the Case -- I think the testimony as written out by counsel with corrections by me contains as near the substance of testimony in the case as I can remember -- </p>
<p>D</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
