<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2026"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. John A. Brooks et al., Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6663</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-188 to BR14-189</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Webster County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-06-24">24 June 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Webster Circuit Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against
<lb/>John A Brooks Abner Townsend Thomas Brooks James Smith James Dockery Daniel Holeman</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Webster County in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky accuse John A Boorks Abner Townsend Thomas Brooks James Smith James Dockery and Daniel Holeman of the crime of Robbery committed as follows viz the said John A Brooks Abner Townsend Thomas Brooks James Smith James Dockery and Daniel Holeman on the <date when="1862-11-07">7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of November 1862</date>, in the County aforesaid feloniously took a double<hi rend="str">d</hi> Barreled shot gun &amp; a grey Horse the property of B S Ruby in his presence and against his will by putting him in fear of some immediate injury to his person against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>Jno Barret
<lb/>Commonwealths atty
<lb/>14 Judicial District</p>
<p>Information by
<lb/>John S Ruby
<lb/>B D Winstead
<lb/>B. S. Ruby</p>
<p><date when="1863-09">September Term 1863</date>
<lb/>Commonwealth Plff
<lb/>against } No 2
<lb/>Joh A Brooks &amp; c Defts</p>
<p>On motion of the plantiff this cause is continued, and thereupon the defendant John A Brooks together with J A. Spaulding<pb/>
<lb/>and D H Hughs &amp; S B Vance in open court acknowledged themselves indebted to the Commonwealth of Kentucky in the sum of five Hundred dollars to be void however upon the defendant John A Brooks appearing in this court on the first day of its next <date when="--03">March term</date> and answer the Indictment herein found against him for Felony and not depart without leave of the Court -- </p>
<p><date when="1865-03">March Term 1865</date>
<lb/>Comlth Plff
<lb/>agst
<lb/>John A Brooks &amp; c Defts.</p>
<p>This day came the attorny the Comlth and the defendant John A Brooks failing to appear It is adjudged that his recognizance herein be taken as forfeited and summons is awarded thereon,</p>
<p>I M C Davis Clerk of the Webster circuit Court do certify that the foregoing is a true copy of the Indictment. Recognizance and order of forfeiture in the case of the Comlth vs John A Brooks &amp; c Indictment No 2 in this court. Witness my hand this <date when="1865-06-24">24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> June 1865</date>,</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">M C Davis clerk</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
