<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3232"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Q. M. Chandler et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5351</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-18 to BR42-19</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Marion County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The undersigned citizens of Marion County Kentucky &amp; near neighbors of W<hi rend="underline">m</hi> Brown Father of Edward F Brown a miner who resides with his Father would respectfully represent to His Excellency the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>That Said Edward F Brown is Indicted in the Washington County Court with others for Robbery alleged to have been committed on a night of the Springfield Fair in <date when="--10">Oct last</date> and we can learn of no proof against him except this, that one of a party of which Brown is charged to be one, lost a hat on the occasion and that it was found at the House when one of the robberies was committed No witness so far as we can learn can Swear that Brown was seen with the party and he can prove by a reliable Lady School teacher who resides in his Fathers family that Brown went to the Springfield Fair one day &amp; one only &amp; that he returned before bedtime and could not have been present at the time and place where the robberies were said to have been committed which was some 15 miles distant He will also prove that the hat found was not the hat of one of the party alleged to have been guilty of the Robbery We have known young Brown all his life, know that he is and always has been an Industrious &amp; Steady Young man The Father William Brown is in the Bonds of his Son. He is as good a citizen &amp; has always been as resides in this County a Sober prudent discreet honest man opposed as much as any man to any violation of law<pb/>
<lb/>A few nights Since, a Mob came to Mr Browns house and attempted by force and by the desperate use of their guns and pistols to get possession of Young Brown to hang him, and were only detered by his Killing one &amp; wounding another of the party They Swear that Young Brown Shall not live in the county &amp; that they will follow him to "Hell" but what they intended have him They had a rope with Knott tied which he he was to be hung with On the next night the Mob Returned &amp; burned the dwelling &amp; all its contents and left word for the Father William Brown to leave the State in ten days which He must do, knowing as he does the immediate &amp; real danger of remaining Under the circumstances we appeal to your Excellency as an act of Justice to Pardon Young Brown &amp; remit the Penalty of his Fathers Bonds</p>
<p>Q. M. Chandler
<lb/>J. M. Robards.
<lb/>Bell Robards
<lb/>R L Chandler
<lb/>J. F. Douglass
<lb/>C. G. Chandler
<lb/>J T. Hadon
<lb/>J B. Evans M. D.
<lb/>William S Floyd J. S. M. C
<lb/>R. A. Burton
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H. Chandler
<lb/>B. R. Chandler</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
