<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-003-0059"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">T. E. Ransom to W. W. Randall</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1576</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR5-109 to BR5-110</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Matagorda Bay, Texas</placeName>
    <date when="1864-01-16">16 January 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>(A Copy)
<lb/>Head Quarters 4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Div. 13<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Army Corps
<lb/>Matagorda Bay Texas
<lb/><date when="1864-01-16">January 16<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Hon<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> W. H. Randall M. C.
<lb/>Washington D. C.
<lb/>Dear Sir:</p>
<p>I take the liberty of addressing you on behalf of Col. W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> J. Landram 19<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky Infty, who commands the 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Brigade of my Division; and to ask your influence in favor of his promotion. Col. Landram was among the first to volunteer from your state, and has commanded a Brigade or Division in the field for about two years reflecting credit upon his state and doing the country able service. He was engaged with his command at the battles of "Chickasaw Bayou," "Raymond," "Arkansas Post," "Port Gibson," "Champion Hills" "Black River Bridge" -- the seige of Vicksburg, and the battles at Jackson Miss., and in the arduous campaigns<pb/>
<lb/>in the West for two years -- distinguishing himself always for coolness and generalship where such qualities were indispensable; always popular with his troops and uniformly receiving the commendation of his superior officers.</p>
<p>After the fall of Vicksburg, General's Grant, Sherman, Logan, M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Pherson, M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Clernand, A. J. Smith, Carr, Hovey, M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Ginnis and other prominent officers united in a recommendation for his promotion to Brig. Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Vols.</p>
<p>I trust this Congress will not adjourn without showing its appreciatiion of the really meritorius services of this gallant officer; and I ask you as his Representative in Congress to press his just claims upon their attention until his promotiion is secured.</p>
<p>Maj. Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> C. C. Washburne, lately in command of this Corps -- now on leave of absence -- will visit Washington this winter. He will do all he can for Col. Landram and can throw much of the Western influence in his favor</p>
<p>I have the honor to be
<lb/>Very Respectfully Your Obedient Serv<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi>
<lb/>signed T. E. G. Ransom
<lb/>Brig. Gen. Vols_
<lb/>(A copy)</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
