<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0795"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">H. Gorrin to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10263</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-251 to MG19-252</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-03-26">26 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville
<lb/><date when="1861-03-26">March 26 1861</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Govenor of Kentucky</p>
<p>At the last Term of the Warren Criminal Court, a young man aged about 21 years old, named Rufus Young was convicted of Manslaughter and sentenced to be confined in the penetentiary for <hi rend="str">four</hi>^4^ years -- </p>
<p>I was one of the council of Mr Jones, and heard the Evidence this time, and feel warranted in saying he ought not to have been convicted, There was much conflicting and contradictory evidence, The material witnesses or most of them for the prosecution, on each trail, varied their statements Materially, to make the arguments<pb/>
<lb/>of the Comth for the Defense, I have know young Jones for some time, he is an amicable and generous Young man, of excellent family, as good as any in the county of Warren, he has an aged Grandfather, his Father died some years ago, and his Mother lately, His relatives and connections are numerous, and as I have said, very respectable and deeply sympathise with him -- </p>
<p>Mr Young and young Jenkins, whom, he unfortunatly killed, were brought up in the same neighborhood, and were like brothers, up to the evening of the unfortunate affair,</p>
<p>The proof showed that Mr Jones was drinking, and it further showed that the difficulty was brought on by another and<pb/>
<lb/>one of the most prominent witnesses against him, but, it was impossible to ascertain how or about what the quarrel arose,</p>
<p>I have no doubt Mr Jones case, demands the Clemency of your Excellency, and I should be greatly gratified, in your Excellency granting him a pardon,</p>
<p>Very respectfully
<lb/>Yours &amp;e &amp;e
<lb/>H Gorrin</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
