<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2477"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Frederick Tucker to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7114</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-441 to BR15-442</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Stanford, Lincoln County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-16">16 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Stanford Kenty <date when="1865-10-16">16" October 1865</date>
<lb/>To His Excelleny Govenor Bramlette</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Frederick Tucker would respectfully represent that in the year <date when="1858">1858</date> he was indicted by the Grand Jury of Lincoln County for Carrying Concealed deadly weapons shortly after which but before the trial he removed to the State of Missouri, and Judgment was rendered against him by default for $50 and cost, Now your Petitioner states that he is a peacable Citizen never had any dificulty in his Life with any person is poor with a Large family -- and carried said weapon to defend himself against a threatened attack by Hugh Kirkpatrick who had threatened to Shoot petitioner as he was informed by John Burnet by whom he can prove the above facts he states the fifa is now in the hands of the sheriff and the money will be coerced out of him unless your Excellency intervenes which he humbly begs you to do and remit the Commonwealths part of said fine, and he promises you in future as in past never to violate the Laws of his native State -- He hopes to hear from you Soon</p>
<p>Respectfully your obt Servt
<lb/>Frederick Tucker</p>
<p>Governor Bramlette</p>
<p>The undersigned are well acquainted with Frederick Tucker he is an honerable sober prudent Law abiding citizen and we are satisfied his petition deserves your<pb/>
<lb/>Consideration and his cause your clemency we therefore beg you will remit his fine as we know him to be Quiet and deserving -- </p>
<p>Leo Hayden
<lb/>W, T, Binley Judge
<lb/>George M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Roberts
<lb/>Peyton Embree
<lb/>H. S. Withers
<lb/>D. W. Vandivier
<lb/>S. J. Embry
<lb/>M O. Vandivier
<lb/>T. P. Hill</p>
<p>Governor inclosed find $2,00 fee of Jas R Page if my fine is remitted if you do not remit the Same, Your Excellcy will be kind enough in your litter to inclse the Same to me</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>Fred Tucker<pb/></p>
<p>Lincoln Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Fred. Tucker
<lb/>$50,
<lb/>Concealed Weapons
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-10-18">18 Oct 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
