<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0749"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. T. Goodman to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4868</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-143 to BR10-144</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-04-27">27 April 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Th<hi rend="sup">o</hi> E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>In <date when="1861-07">July 1861</date> One Wilson H Kiger stood Indicted in the Allen Equity and Criminal Court charged with the offence of "Shooting at W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> F. Austin with intent to kill" The Shff haveing process therein for the arrest of Kiger took a Bail bond from him for his appearance before said Court at the <date when="1861">fall term thereof, 1861</date> to answer the charge Joseph T. Black John W Howard &amp; your Petitioner J. T. Goodman became Security on said bond. At the next Court Kiger appeared before the court but the case was not tried Petitioner was there in town &amp; supposed he was released as he never gave any concent to be further or to continue bond for Kigers appearance again and he never did pay any further attention to it. Sometime last Winter was a year ago some officer Summoned him to attend the Allen<pb/>
<lb/>and although he did not know for what purpose yet he did in good faith leave his home when he lived in Barren County &amp; tried to get to s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> court in obedience to the Summons as he supposed. but the River &amp; water courses were so high that he could not &amp; did not get there. The next information he got upon the subject was that the shff of Barren County, has in his hands an execution in favor of the Commonwealth of Ky. for $300- and $8.95 cost The same haveing issued from the clerks office of the Allen Circuit Court upon a Judgement rendered on said Bond against Petitioner &amp; s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Black (s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Howard haveing removed to Texas &amp; s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Kiger haveing died) and now the execution is levied upon your Petitioners property</p>
<p>He states that Kiger is dead That s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Howard one of the securities has left the state of Ky. &amp; has no property in this state. said Black is also dead &amp; his estate is Insolvent &amp; will not pay exceeding 20 to 25 cents to the dollar. And your Petitioner is<pb/>
<lb/>is a poor man haveing a family and will be greatly injured if he is required to pay said Judgt. Kigers estate is also hoplelessly Insolvent</p>
<p>Wherefore He prays your Excellency to relieve him from said Judgement &amp;c &amp;c</p>
<p>J. T. Goodman</p>
<p>J. T. Goodman States that the statement &amp; allegations in the foregoing Peititoner are true</p>
<p>J. T. Goodman</p>
<p>Subscribed &amp; Sworn to by J. T. Goodman before me <date when="1864-04-27">Apl 27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date></p>
<p>W. F. Evans J. B. C. C.<pb/></p>
<p>J. T. Goodman
<lb/>Petition
<lb/>Allen Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>G. T. Goodman
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1864-06-30">30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> June/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
