<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1118"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">S. C. Perrin et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10586</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-229 to MG20-230</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-05-14">14 May 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Covington Ky <date when="1861-05-14">May 14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>To the Honourable B Magoffin Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioners would respectfully represent to your Excellency that a boy by the name of Patrick Nolan was convicted at the last Term of the Kenton Court at <date when="1861-03">March Term 1861</date> of Breaking into a house and taking there from some sigars and cinnamon for which he was sentenced to the State Penitentiary for one year Now your petitioners would respectfully represent to your honour that they are satisfied that the said Patrick Nolan who is only 14 years old was caught in bad company ^with^ some wicked young men and that the said young men whose names we will not Mention done the wicked deed and gave him the stolen property and that it was done with a design to Effect their own Escape which they did, and owing to the fact that he has a good father &amp; Mother residing here and are much afflicted on account of their boy that they have tried to raise honestly, and beleiving that he has suffered Enough for nothing they Earnestly solicit your honour to Grant him a repreive and your Petitioners will Ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names of Petitioners
<lb/>S. C Perrin
<lb/>J B S Emmerson
<lb/>J S Cott
<lb/>J. M. Casey
<lb/>B B Wallis
<lb/>C H Seymour
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Henry Maussed<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned Petitioners were on the jury that convicted Patrick Nolan and join in the foregoing Petition</p>
<p>P C Longshore
<lb/>John Hood
<lb/>R. L. Steers
<lb/>S. H. Stout sr
<lb/>Elkin Lightfoot
<lb/>E S moore
<lb/>M J Wesner
<lb/>Elisha A. Williams
<lb/>G. S. Light
<lb/>Frank Knoll</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Kenton Circuit Court Clerks office
<lb/><date when="1861-05-16">May 16<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>The above named ten persons were on the Jury That convicted Patrick Nolan, and I concur in the statements of the petition</p>
<p>N. B. Stephens clerk
<lb/>Kenton Circuit Court
<lb/>C W Blackburn
<lb/>L. F. Daughery
<lb/>Henry Lenba
<lb/>h. n. Ball
<lb/>Jo<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Zarges
<lb/>John B Casey
<lb/>J. C. Bryan
<lb/>Jo W. Kyle</p>
<p>I do not know the fact in this case yet I know the boy and think from his age that the very worst use to which his time can be put is confinement in the Penetentiary I hope the Govr will pardon him at once</p>
<p>B. W. Foley<pb/></p>
<p>H. W. Wayman
<lb/>J A Goodson<pb/></p>
<p>Nolans case
<lb/>Pen Covington</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
