<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-019-0091"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">G. W. Norton to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1397</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG5-164</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Russellville, Logan County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-15">15 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>G. W. Norton, President.
<lb/><cb n="1"/>M. B. Morton, Cashier.
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Southern Bank of Kentucky,
<lb/>Russelville, <date when="1861-06-15">15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> June 1861</date>
<lb/>To/His Excellency
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> B. Magoffin <hi rend="str">Esq.,</hi>
<lb/>Dear Sir.</p>
<p>At the request of Capt. John W. Caldwell I write to say that he has a Company of Eighty true and patriotic Young Men who are ready at once to be mustered into the State Guard, if the State will furnish 80 Rifle Muskets, Some of which we learn are in the Arsenal at Frankfort. Capt. Caldwell Succeeds Cap<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> G. R. Bibb. It is Said Cap<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Bibb's application for Arms for this Company, Called Logan Guards, was made over one year ago. The Company is not willing to take the oath and Join the State Guard unless you can assure them the Arms will be furnished -- Cap<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Caldwell has now control of about 40 Muskets mostly unfit for use, which he will have at Once forwarded to Frankfort where you can have them repaired, if you will give him assurance of 80 good Rifle Muskets on the proper application of his Company under the law establishing the State Guard. I trust you can do this, as, in my opinion, a more loyal and patriotic Company of Young men Cannot well be found and, Under Capt Caldwell I feel they will ever act will promptness and valor in defence of the Commonwealth. Please answer at Once.</p>
<p>Very Truly Yours
<lb/>G. W. Norton<pb/></p>
<p>G. W. Norton
<lb/>arms</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
