<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0278"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William B. Allen to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9746</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-262</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Greensburg, Green County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-12-31">31 December 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Greensburg Ky. <date when="1860-12-31">Decr. 31<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1860</date>
<lb/>Beriah M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin Esq
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>I have seen the petition of M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> James Jones, asking the remission of a fine against him in the Taylor Circuit Court of $200, I have also seen the affidavits accompanying it -- In addition to all this, I have heard all the testimony in the case, detailed in the Green Circuit Court on the trial of his brother Edward Jones. For the situation of the matter was about this -- some years ago James &amp; Edward Jones were indicted in the Green Circuit court jointly for permiting gambling in their grocery house; James Jones got a change of venue to Taylor County, Edward Jones was tried in Green and acquited. James Jones was afterwards tried in Taylor, and fined $200 aforesaid The same witnesses were examined in each case W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Jones, the father of James &amp; Edward testified that the grocery house was his, and that it was his liquor that was sold in it, that although not immediately attached to his dwelling house yet it was used by him as his bar room, he lived in the country some 14 miles, had license to keep tavern, and had built this room for a grocery and bar room for his tavern house these two boys lived with him, and each of them and occasionally both of them attended the house for him, that the house was under his control and supervision -- ^upon^ this evidence, together with the testimony as set forth in the affidavits Edmund Jones was acquitted -- I was not present at the trial of James Jones, but am informed<pb/>
<lb/>that the same witnesses testified on that occasion and many expressed their surprise at the result of the trial -- I regard it as a meritorious case for the interposition of executive clemency M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Jones is a very poor man, has a sickly wife and family to support, and it would these hard times be the means of breaking him up, if he had the amount to pay. I trust therefore, that your Excellency, will esteem it right to remit the fine and save him and his family almost from ruin</p>
<p>Respectfully your 
<lb/>obt. svt. -- 
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> B Allen</hi><pb/></p>
<p>His Excellency
<lb/>Beriah M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin
<lb/>Frankfort
<lb/>Kentucky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
