<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0673"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John R. Graham to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10141</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-17 to MG19-18</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-02-09">9 February 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency B Magoffin Esq Govnor of the Commonwealth of kentucky the undersigned your petitioner States that Some 3 years ago he took in poss. one Shot gun from Shingle Bower to Secure the payment of $60 that he owed him and also a dubl Bl gun from H. Buckner the Slave of John Watson and the Said guns were put into the hands of James Evins &amp; Newton Dean to Sell with directions never to Suffer Said guns to come into Said <hi rend="str">John</hi> Joshua Vinigers house or on his premises and one gun was put in my hans about 2 month ago and the other about 6 weeks without my -- knoledge or consent and I requested the men that left them there to come and take them away -- and the Said guns were taken. from my house on the <gap/> day of <date when="1861-01">January 1861</date> and he was tried and find before the police Judge on the <date when="1861-02-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of February 1861</date> five dollars for each gun ten dollars he humble askes that you would remit his fine Joshua Vinager</p>
<p>The Evidence was as follows P Meek Stated that he Borrored one gun from Joshua Viniger Sum 4 months ago and kept the gun for Same time and it got out of order ^Viniger give him 50 cts to have it repaird^ and he returned the gun to vinigers house in his absence ^about 2 month where he got it from and when he Seen viniger he requested<pb/>
<lb/>him to come and take the gun away that he did not want it an his place that it would git him in a Difficulty</p>
<p>=</p>
<p>Henry Brown State that he and W. B. Holman went to vinigers house and found <hi rend="str">got</hi> two guns ^in his possession^ that they had heard they were then and went on purpose to take them that W. B. Holman took them and handed one to Witness objected to because of intrest Stanton Statutes 368 that they took the guns Some ten days ago</p>
<p>=</p>
<p>Netwon Dean Stated that about 2 years ago he got one of the guns in Question the Single Bbl one and was directed to kepe the Same til he could Sell it and never return or Suffer it to be returned to Josh Vinigers house that about. 2. month ago Witness moved from where he was living and left this gun and his own at the house where he moved from and afterwards sent his Son after them and he left vinigers gun at his house I afterwards Saw viniger and he requested me to come. and git the gun away that he would git into a fuss about it if it Stayed there=</p>
<p>James Evins Statements admitted that the double bbl gun was left with him about 1 1/2 years ago for the owner to Redeem or Sell and pay the money to viniger for which it was parred<pb/>
<lb/>that viniger told him never to let the gun come on his premises again foregoing is the substance of all the Evidence in thie cause given under my hand this <date when="1861-02-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of February 1861</date></p>
<p>John R Graham P. J. C. F.</p>
<p>The Judgment of the Court in the above case forfeited the 2 guns in qustion to W. B. Holeman. the officer capturing them</p>
<p>J. R. Graham P J C F<pb/></p>
<p>Frankfort Po. Ct
<lb/>Jashua Viniger
<lb/>vs } Pet.
<lb/>Commonwealth<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>$10. }
<lb/>Respite 12 mo
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-02-12">Feby 12. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
