<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2277"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Delaney Sanders to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6914</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-124</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hancock County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Delaney Sanders States that he was indicted and at the present <date when="1865-08">August term 1865</date> of the Hancock Circuit Court found Guilty of erecting a fence in the Public road from Haydens Well to Cloverport and fined $120 &amp; costs a copy of the Judgment is filed herewith -- He says that a great number of witnesses were Examined some testifying that the fence was not in the road &amp; that the road was frequently removed in consequence of obstruction thereabouts -- others testifying that the ^outer corner of the^ fence was in the road at certain points from 2 to 4 feet, but the Jury being satisfied that it was then partially in the road found him guillty, though they regretted the necessity of so finding -- He says that he is in Humble circumstances and illy able to pay the fine that he did not intentionally put the fence in the road nor does he believe it was in the public road -- He asks a remission of the fine</p>
<p>Delany Sanders</p>
<p>The undresigned Jurors <hi rend="str">tr</hi> ^who^ tried the Indictment above referred to felt them selves bound under the law and facts proven to find the petitioner Guilty -- <hi rend="str">they</hi> <hi rend="str">concur</hi> but Concur in the above statements and recommend his case to executive clemency</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>James Mason
<lb/>John C Thomas
<lb/>C B Duncan
<lb/>N. C, Davison
<lb/>A Lewis
<lb/>Davis, Richey
<lb/><cb n="2"/>D S Thomas
<lb/>W M Estes
<lb/>Peter Brunner
<lb/>David Alsop
<lb/>J. G. Bozoritz
<lb/>Jesse Gallagher<pb/></p>
<p>I concur in the petition for the remission of the fine</p>
<p>Jesse W, Kincheloe
<lb/>Special Judge who tried tried the case</p>
<p>I am a neighbor to the petitioner, Delaney Sanders, &amp; fully concur in the statements in the petition for the remission of the fine,</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Minor, E, Pate</hi></p>
<p>Hancock Cir Ct
<lb/>Delaney Sanders
<lb/>To } Petition
<lb/>$120,
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi>
<lb/>Erectr<hi rend="str">t</hi>ing on road,
<lb/><date when="1865-08-28">28 Aug/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
