<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0776"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">L. M. Eckert et al. to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4895</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-194 to BR10-195</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1862-12-10">10 December 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency James F. Robinson
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky,</p>
<p>We the Undersigned the Jurors who found the verdict in the case of the Comth of Kentucky against Philip Kenedy and Patrick White charged and convicted at the <date when="1862-02">February term 1862</date> of The Campbell Circuit Court of committing a rape on the body of one Elizabeth Franklin, would respectfully state that since the trial of said cause we have learned the character of the prosecuting witnesses Elizabeth Franklin and her sister on whose testimony we mainly relied in forming our verdict as to the guilt or innocence of the accused, and are now satisfied that they were women of lewd character and that their statements were not entitled to credit, that there reputation for truth and veracity <hi rend="str">is</hi> notoriously bad, in the community where they lived, that they were Entire strangers in this County and State having resided here but a short time previous to the trial, and left this State, a very short time thereafter for fear of being prosecuted for keeping a House of Ill fame. Their statements of material facts on the trial were contradictory, but not Knowing their previous character we looked over it, but had we then known their character as we now do, their statements would have little or no weight in making up our verdict, and the prisoners might have received at our hands the benefit of a reasonable doubt. We are satisfied that there exists great reason to beleive that the offense charged against them and of which they stand now convict may not be true. They have already<pb/>
<lb/>suffered nearly a year's confinement in the penitentiary besides some two or three months incarceration in our County jail, they are both respectfully connected, and previous to the time and up to the trial of this cause, sustained a good reputation for Honesty, sobriety and industry, and were looked upon and recognized as respectable promising young Mechanics In view of all the facts in the case, we pray your Excellency to give their case your favourable consideration, and trust that you may deem it one worthy of the Executive clemency, as we are of opinion that the cause of Justice and the public interest would not suffer by restoring them to their friends, and their liberty.</p>
<p><date when="1862-12-10">Dec<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>L M Eckert Foreman Jury
<lb/>J. K. Stone, Juror
<lb/>Martin Johrall Jurors
<lb/>Tho W M.. gider Juror
<lb/>Samuel Tiberghien Juror
<lb/>John F Herbert Juror
<lb/>C. C. Harris Juror
<lb/>James Lainer Jurer<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Newport Campbell County Kentucky, join in the foregoing petition, of the Jurors in the suit of The Com<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of Ky. vs. Philip Kenedy &amp; Patrick White, and pray your Excellency to restore them to their liberty.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>H Sine
<lb/>Robt B MCrackin
<lb/>J Horsfall Jailor
<lb/>Thomas Fowler
<lb/>J. T. Masshat
<lb/>F Stagaman
<lb/>C. P. Buchanan
<lb/>Sidney B. Jones
<lb/>Geo W Searons
<lb/><cb n="2"/>I was present and heard the trial of the above two young men on the charge of Rape. From the Evidence in the case &amp; the character of it I had strong doubts of the guilt of either of the parties.
<lb/>F. M. Webster Attoy<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>I know Mrs Clayton She so far as I know is a lady of good character and veracity I would accompany her but am a yet confined to my room</p>
<p>R. T. Baker</p>
<p>I beleave the petition States the case fairly<pb/></p>
<p>Kennedy &amp; White
<lb/>Petion</p>
<p>The evidence upon the Jury was very strong, several witnesses corroborating main witness I do not think <unclear/> for <unclear/> <unclear/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J F Robinson</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
