<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1576"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Timoleon Cravens to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11044</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-213 to MG22-214</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Columbia, Adair County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-10-06">6 October 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Columbia Ky <date when="1860-10-06">October 6. 1860</date>
<lb/>Gov. B. MaGoffin
<lb/>Franfort Ky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>Enclosed you will find a petition of John Webb endorsed by a number of the most respctable citizens of Russell County praying to be released from <hi rend="str">of</hi> a fine of $300 imposed by the Russell Circuit Court &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi>. You will also find a statment of E. L. Vanwinkle on the subject &amp; a copy of the judgment. I believe the facts stated to be correct. There has been some delay on my part in sending on the papers. It was my judgement not t<hi rend="str">b</hi>o be in a hurry.</p>
<p>I believe that the remission of this heavy fine against an ignorant man who is scarcely able to live &amp; who has had and now has many troubles to encounter would be right and would meet with the general approbation of the commu-<pb/>
<lb/>nity.</p>
<p>I hope you will take a like view of the subject &amp; will transmit to me here a remission of the fine</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>Yours
<lb/>Timolen Cravens</p>
<p>This is the case to which I referred when I last saw you.</p>
<p>T. C.<pb/></p>
<p><hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>I reached home last night &amp; leave tomorrow. My appointments extend from ^Monday^ until the election. I think we are improving -- but we need workers</p>
<p>Talbot has been compelled to abandon his appointments on account of his wifes illness. Gaither is entirely unable to ride or speak. Durham is sick. I can hear nothing from Hill. Chrisman &amp; myself have been together for a few days &amp; think we have done good. I have undertaken for four weeks to bring up as many homecomers as possible &amp; have done all I can do here. I hope some good speaker or speakers will be sent to Taylor; Green, Cumberland -- Clinton &amp; ^Russell^ Casey Counties -- two speeches to the County. say at</p>
<p>Mannsville &amp; Saloma Taylor Co
<lb/>George Elmores &amp; Brewersburgh Green Co
<lb/>Burksville Cumberland Co
<lb/>Illwill precinct &amp; Seventy six Clinton Co
<lb/>Creelsboro &amp; Webb X roads Russell Co
<lb/>Miltonvile &amp; Liberty Casey Co.</p>
<p>T. C.<pb/></p>
<p>Russell Cir. Ct</p>
<p>Respite 12 Mo
<lb/>BM</p>
<p>$300 } Breach Tavern Bond
<lb/>John Webb
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1860-10-16">Octo 16. 1860</date></p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Issd <date when="1861-12-19">Decr. 19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
