<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1609"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John G. Carlisle to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11077</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Andrew P Patrick</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-256 to MG22-257</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-01-08">8 January 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Covngtion Ky
<lb/><date when="1862-01-08">Jan. 8 1862</date>
<lb/>Dear Governor:</p>
<p>I did not hear the testimony in the case against young Timberlake, but I know his father and at his request I cheerfully unite with his other friends in asking you to interpose in behalf of the young man. He is a wild boy and it may be that he is clearly guilty of the crime with which he is charged; but he certainly has the capacity to become a useful member of society, and no harm can be done by giving him an opportunity to reform.<pb/>
<lb/>His confinement in the Penitentery for the period of 18 months, might, and doubtless would, do both him and the community more harm than his release. He will in all human probability be ruined forever if the sentence is carried out, and I hope that you will give him one more chance to redeem himself. </p>
<p>Yours Truly
<lb/>J G Carlisle</p>
<p>Hon B Magoffin
<lb/>Gov of Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
