<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0827"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. F. Black to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10295</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-301 to MG19-302</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Greensburg, Green County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-03">March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Greensburg Ky <date when="1861-03">March <gap/> 1861</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency, B Magoffin Govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky,</p>
<p>Your Petitioner William F Black would most respectfully state, that at the <date when="1861-02">February term of the Green Circuit Court 1861,</date> a Judgment was rendered against him for the sum of $100.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> upon a Charge of gambling. No defense was made to said Charge by your Petitioner and and Judgment was rendered against him by default He says he is not guilty of said Charge, and had, the evidence to establish his innocence, but was prevented from so doing under the following Circumstances towit, the Judge of said Court called a special term, which commenced one week sooner than the regular term, Your Petitioner, made preparations to meet his trial, at the regular term, having had no notice of said Special term, and in this way was mislead and prevented, from making any defense, As soon as Your Petitioner learned that Judgment had gone against him he went to see a Lawyer, in order to apply for a new trial, but was informed that, it was to late to make the application, for a new trial, the law requiring the motion to be made within, three days after the rendition of the Judgment, and at the term in which the Judgment was rendered, In this way, your Petitioner, without any fault or delay of his own was cut ^off^ from all remedy, and, forced to appeal to your Clemency. Your Petitioner is a poor boy, not of age Just, starting out into the world, depending upon<pb/>
<lb/>himself <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> for a living, He has no way to pay, said Judgment, except by going to Jail, and this he would not, mind so much if he was guilty of the charge, but to have his character injured ^which is all his fortune^ for nothing, fills him with profound mortification, He says, he has, by the kindness of his friends managed to pay the ^commonwealth's^ attorney's fee in the case, and will make out to pay the cost, &amp; keep from going to Jail, if your Excellency will favor him, by remitting the balance Govenor Please interpose and be charitable to a poor orphan boy</p>
<p>Yours Respectfully,
<lb/>W F Black<pb/></p>
<p>To his Excellency, Govenor of Kentucky</p>
<p>We the undesigned, Citizens of Green County do certify that W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> F Black is an honest, upright boy, and entitled to Executive Clemency, and that any statement made by him can safely be relied upon, and we think your, Excellency would perform an act of charity by remitting the Judgment against him mentioned in the petition annexed, to this certificate,</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J. W Lewis
<lb/>Wm sisson
<lb/>R M toun
<lb/>R. y. Graham
<lb/>B F Whitlow
<lb/>John Akin
<lb/>M J Lewis
<lb/>Alfred L. Kiser
<lb/>John H Elmore
<lb/>W M Whitlow
<lb/>James A Noe
<lb/>Jessey Bolles
<lb/>W W M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cubbin
<lb/>Stephen Corum
<lb/>E. L. Cantrell
<lb/>Samuel Akridge
<lb/>J A Lewis
<lb/>Pleasant bylee
<lb/>C,, <hi rend="str">G</hi> G,, Close J p G C
<lb/>thomas Beances
<lb/>John D Spain
<lb/>John M Despain
<lb/>feilden Spain
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Joseph Warren
<lb/>Dewitt C Akin
<lb/>William Akin
<lb/>C C Morris
<lb/>H Jones
<lb/>S F Graham
<lb/>Jas, S, Hudgins
<lb/>C G Hudgins
<lb/>John vistor
<lb/>John W Whitlaw
<lb/>Wallace Victor
<lb/>Hafett Victor
<lb/>W H H M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Lane
<lb/>E J Graham
<lb/>Robt.. Graham
<lb/>E. M. Angel
<lb/>David Walker
<lb/>F T Sidebottom
<lb/>H Sidebottom
<lb/>John B. Perkins
<lb/>E W Graham
<lb/>I. P. Brewer
<lb/>L. W. Elmore
<lb/>A P Johnson<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>Isaac Hartfield
<lb/>F B Beauchamp
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. M. Buckner
<lb/>Wm. S. Peace
<lb/>Danl Peace
<lb/>H. T. Smith
<lb/>Jas.. M.. Johnston
<lb/>I. H. Skaggs
<lb/>E A Jones
<lb/>E B Skaggs
<lb/>Fields Skaggs
<lb/>Berry Reed
<lb/>Mathew Skaggs
<lb/>P. C. Warren
<lb/>Jas Perkin
<lb/>Joseph Peace
<lb/>Jas,, F, Thompson
<lb/>Henry Childress
<lb/>Stephen Skaggs
<lb/>W M Skaggs
<lb/>Clay Elmore</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
