<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1313"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John W. Boyd et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10781</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-204 to MG21-205</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned would respectfully represent to Your Excellancy that at the <date when="1860-09">September Term 1860</date> of the Christian Circuit Court J C Bentley Was Indicted by the Grand Jury of Christian County for Shooting a Slave of Dr E R Cook of Said County of Which said Slave died the Undersigned Would further State that Said Bently was the Overseer, of Said Cook and in attempting to Chastise the Slave (Garland) Said Slave resisted and Said Bentley shot him inflicting a Mortal Wound and at the <date when="1860-09">September term 1860</date> of Said Court the undersigned entered into reocgnizace With Said Bently in the sum of Five Hundred dollars for his appearance at the <date when="1861-03">March term 1861</date> of Said Court and Said Bently failed to appear his recognizance was forfeited &amp; a Summons awarded agaisnt the undersigned as his Sureties returnable to the <date when="1861-09">September Term 1861</date> of Said Court</p>
<p>The undersigned are Satisfied that the Said Bently if he had appeared could not have been convicted for Said Offence but being a poor Young Man to Save the Expense of the prosecution left the County &amp; has not Returned Your Petitioner Would further State that they Went the bail of Said Bently in good faith did not<pb/>
<lb/>Procure Or adive Him to leave the State to avoid Prosecution &amp; Would not have gone his Surety if they had believed he Would have failed to appear in discharge of his Obligations</p>
<p>Your Petitioners are fully Satisfied of Said Bently had appeared and been tried for said Offence he Would have been acquitted and left only to Save the Expense of defending the prosecution being quite a Young Man &amp; Very Poor</p>
<p>Wherefore Your Petitioners Would most Respectfully request Your excellancy to remit &amp; release Your Petitioners from any liability as Sureties of Said Bently in Said Recognizance</p>
<p>John. W. Boyd
<lb/>George L Elliot.
<lb/>M,, D,, Brown
<lb/>V T Vaughan
<lb/>R A Elgin<pb/></p>
<p>The undersigned would respectfully commend the foregoing petition to the <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> favorable consideration of Governor Magoffin and ask that the prayer of the petitioners be granted</p>
<p>Jno. B. Knight
<lb/>John C Latham
<lb/>W. H. Scott
<lb/>James A Brewer
<lb/>Joseph Clark
<lb/>John. M. Long
<lb/>S. A. Boyce
<lb/>W. M. Shipp
<lb/>Tho S. Bryan<pb/></p>
<p>Christian Cir Ct
<lb/>Brown &amp; others
<lb/>Recognizance
<lb/>no Judgt -- </p>
<p>Remitted as to all but one Hundred &amp; fifty Dollars -- </p>
<p>B. M</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1861-08-22">Aug 22 61</date>
<lb/>TBM</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
