<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0915"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Claiborne Lisle to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5034</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-405 to BR10-407</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Clark County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-01-27">27 January 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>Thomas E Bramlett
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned Claiborne Lisle respectfully represents that on the <gap/> of <date when="1861-05">May 1861</date> he became bound in a Recognisance Bond <hi rend="str">for</hi> as the surety of Wm W Baldwin for said Baldwin's <unclear/> appearance in the Clark Circuit Court to answer an Indictment pending in said Court whereon he was charged with Gaming, the charge being that $2000, dollars were won and lost withing 24 hours- the Penalty of the Bond being for $1000= and for his appearance at the <date when="1861-07">July Term 1861</date>= of said Court, he did appear at that Term_ but case was continued for Commonwealth <hi rend="str">at the term</hi> and also at the succeeding term_ of <hi rend="str">May</hi> ^<date when="1861-11">November^ 1861</date>_ <date when="1862-05">May 1862</date>- &amp; <date when="1862-07">July 1862</date>= until finaly at the <date when="1862-11">November Term 1862</date>= the said Baldwin not being present <hi rend="str">was</hi> the Bond was declared forfeited_ and at the <date when="1863-05">May Term 1863</date> Judgment rendered on the Bond against the undersigned for the sum of one thousand Dollars.</p>
<p>Said Baldwin had always operated <hi rend="str">and</hi> <hi rend="str">that</hi> he was innocent of the change against him &amp; <hi rend="str">which</hi> Petitioner beleived his assertions.</p>
<p>In the fall of <date when="1862">1862</date>_ Baldwin went into the Confederate service, and was not in Clark County at the <date when="1862-11">November ^term^ 1862</date>, he was killed in <date when="1863-07">July 1863</date>, leaving a small Estate in Clark County and also a wife<pb/>
<lb/>and six Infant children_ it is not certain that the Estate left by him <hi rend="str">would be</hi> ^is^ sufficient to indemnify this Petitioner but if it is, or to the extent that it may afford indemnity would affect said wife &amp; childred. To the end therefore that they may be saved from that loss and your Petitioner releaved from the aforesaid Judgment he prays for the interpostition of your Excellency_ and the remission of the aforesaid Judgment</p>
<p><date when="1864-01-27">Jany 27 1864</date>.
<lb/>Clairborne Lisle</p>
<p>Clark County Ky</p>
<p>Sworn to before me this <date when="1864-01-27">27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of January 1864</date> by Claiborne Lisle-</p>
<p>A H Buckner ck</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Clark County Kentucky respectfully request that Claiborne Lisle may be released from the payment of the Judgment referred to in the foregoing Petition - <date when="1864-01-27">Jany 27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date></p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">A H B
<lb/><date when="1864-07-27">July 27
<lb/>1864</date></note></p>
<p>John W. Laughlin
<lb/>E T Woodward
<lb/>Ambrose G Bush
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. Chase
<lb/>Chas Poston
<lb/>John Clinhinheard
<lb/>Robt. Barker
<lb/>William Garner
<lb/>Benjamin Turner
<lb/>Wm F Pool
<lb/>John Williams
<lb/>W C Sumper<pb/>
<lb/>N B Gentry
<lb/>R. S. <unclear/>
<lb/>J H Ogden
<lb/>E S Jonett
<lb/>John E Gordon
<lb/>Ge<hi rend="sup">o</hi> E Gordon</p>
<p>I was engaged by Baldwin to defend him in the case named above &amp; in a <unclear/> <unclear/> about it which was settled- I believe the facts are correctly stated in the Petition. Mrs. Baldwin &amp; her children are clever &amp; it will press them sorely to pay the full judgement For that sake I recommend a remission as far as you can- ^I believe the gameing charged was a frolick &amp; show^</p>
<p>Jno. B. Huston</p>
<p>I am acquainted with M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Baldwin and family and am of opinion that it would operate very sorely upon them to collect the forfeiture as stated by the Petitioner W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Lisle I know nothing of the maters of the Petition farther but am well satisfied, that if your Excellency will interpose clemency in a case <hi rend="str">of the merit</hi> of this character, that this case is one that should be remitted</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Ja</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> H G Bush</hi><pb/></p>
<p>I consider this case viewed in all its aspects, as one that is entitled to executive clemency, as the enforcement of the penalty of the Bond would operate as a punishment of an innocent widow and her children, who have but a small estate, and who by the enforcement of the penalty would be rendered nearly if not wholly destitute</p>
<p>James Simpson</p>
<p>I concur with Judge Simpson in the above statement</p>
<p>B F Buckner</p>
<p>I am well acquainted with M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Baldwin &amp; family &amp; I fully concur with Judge Simpson in opinion as above stated</p>
<p>Sam G Stuart</p>
<p>I understand that the estate of W. Baldwin dec. in not likely to be sufficient to pay all the legal claims against it and if the Bond on which C. Lisle is security be enforced_ creditors will lose, and the widow &amp; children be in very destitute circumstances_ I think that it will be well for Your Excellency to give due consideration, in the manifestation of clemency not to <hi rend="underline">Lisle</hi> but to the benefit of Mrs. Baldwin, her children &amp; the creditors of his estate</p>
<p>respectfully J. M. Ogden</p>
<p>Petition of C Lisle for Remission of Judgt in W W Baldwins case<pb/>
<lb/>Genl Huston, Judge Simpson, Judge Bush ^J M Ogden, S G Stuart Sheriff^ &amp; Mr Buckner are too well known to require any commendation</p>
<p>The signers to the general Petition are all Union Men of the very best character and standing, and from the interest &amp; feeling evinced almost every clever man in the county would readily sign it if necessary</p>
<p>I know the application to be meritorious- and desire that the prayer of the Petition be granted</p>
<p><date when="1864-05-12">May the 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi> <hi rend="underline">Eginton</hi></p>
<p>W T Downey Atty for Commonwealth authorise me to say that he recommends the case of Mrs Baldwin for favorable consideration</p>
<p>Jno B. Huston<pb/></p>
<p>Clark Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>C Lisle
<lb/>$1000-
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/><date when="1864-05-25">25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> May/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
