<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-028-0061"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Silas F. Barrall et al. to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7716</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Appointments by the Governor, Military Appointments, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R2-198 to R2-199</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>West Point, Hardin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-10-07">7 October 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Fort Blair West Point Ky,
<lb/><date when="1862-10-07">October 7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>Honorable James F. Robinson</p>
<p>Govenor of Kentucky We the undersigned members of Company C 28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky volunteers wish to state a Case to you for your consideration which we Sincerely hope you Will Take Favorable notice of The case in point is the office of fifth Seargeant was and has been vacant for some Time When very much to our surprise on yester^day^ He the Captain Promoted a private to fifth seargant only serving in our company for six weeks</p>
<p>He also at the same time Had three corporals to appoint Which was men that had Served in the company sinc it was organized But we appeal to you To Have Wm H Horine Promoted to fifth Seargeant as He has been In the company eleven months and was appointed Corporal at the time the officers of the company was Elcted He Has been first corporal for many months We ask that his claims may not be overlooked It may ^be^ Propper to state that captain Barth Made the appointment Without consuting the other officers or privates Major Gault of the 16<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky approved the appoint of first seargeant We will state also that you are the only one To Look at this time As Col Boone &amp;c Johnson Was Taken Prisoners and are Prisoners yet<pb/>
<lb/>We to be more plain would ^state^ that the appointment of the fifth Seargeant given to a New Recruit</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Silas. F. Barrall 3 Sgt
<lb/>M: L: Goldsmith
<lb/>Thomas.. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Nutt
<lb/>John T. Monroe
<lb/>R M Thompson
<lb/>Geo Seibert
<lb/>S. S. Smith
<lb/>B. F. King
<lb/>Fred Kohler
<lb/>Martin J Miller
<lb/>Joseph. A. Barrall
<lb/>John J Samuels
<lb/>James foster
<lb/>William. F. Miles
<lb/>John Siebert
<lb/>James. Marshall
<lb/>L. Batchelor
<lb/>M. B. Stinson,
<lb/>Wellington, Critchlow
<lb/>J. S. Earickson
<lb/>Patric Gilsbury
<lb/>James S Norman
<lb/>John Horine
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Eli Williams 
<lb/>Alexander Elliott
<lb/>Peter Nalon
<lb/>John Gunner
<lb/>James M Nelson
<lb/>A C Ewing
<lb/>Henry Deal
<lb/>Steven Cook
<lb/>Christopher Fridenburger
<lb/>William Davis
<lb/><hi rend="str">Chas G Miller</hi><milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>We would also state that there is only about Forty men in this company Reported for duty. Would you allow us the Privilege of Electing Fifth seargeant would Be all that we would Ask</p>
<p>Should you take Notice of this Write to William H. Horine Fort Blair West Point Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
