<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0623"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">T. B. Cochran to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10091</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-454 to MG18-455</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Shlebyville, Shelby County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-02-01">1 February 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Shelbyville <date when="1861-02-01">Feby. 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Dear Esq.</p>
<p>I wish you to do me a favor -- and will first give you the facts on which I wish you to operate. <hi rend="str">In the</hi> At the <date when="1859-03">March Term 1859</date> a boy about 17 or 18 years old David Brown by name was indicted for Stealing a heart pin and watch. He was the son of a widow very poor in fact without any property of any kind, he had always borne a good character and we did not believe him guilty of the charge and myself. Henry Vannatter, and J. D. Montgomery went on his bond to appear at the next term of the Court. The penalty was $200 -- Well he did not appear and we believe at least I have been so informed that he was persuaded to run by those who got up the charge agt him -- Consequently at the <date when="1859-09">Sept. Term 1859</date> of the Shelby Circuit Court<pb/>
<lb/>the bond was forfeited and Judgment went agt us for the $200 &amp; costs.</p>
<p>I want you to <hi rend="str">use</hi> see the Governor and if he will get thim to remit the judgment except the costs and attorneys part. I think it <hi rend="str">was</hi> is a good case for clemency -- We had no security from Brown whatever, and we only went on his bond from motives of charity -- His mother was ill at the time and if he had gone to jail it would have killed her -- </p>
<p>Your truly</p>
<p>T. B. Cochran</p>
<p>You may show this letter to the governor if you wish -- He respited the judgment once for a year -- We do not wish any respite -- If we have it to pay we had as soon pay one time as another</p>
<p>T. B. Cochran<pb/></p>
<p>Shelby Cir Ct
<lb/>$200 } For Recog</p>
<p>T. B. Cochran &amp; others
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-02-05">Feby 5. 1861</date><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>There is no one; not even those who had him indicted but would be willing to have the judgment remitted. There is no feeling agt Brown whatever</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">T. B. C.</hi></p>
<p>Remitted B. M</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
