<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1674"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Michael Dailey to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11142</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Andrew P Patrick</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-347 to MG22-349</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-01-30">30 January 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>County of Kenton</p>
<p>To His Excellency Governor Beriah Magoffin. Your Petitioner Michael Dailey represents that at the late <date when="1861-12">December Term (1861)</date> of the Kenton Circuit Court, on the <date when="1861-12-30">30<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of December</date> he was found guilty on two Indictments, and fined respectively Ten Dollars, and Fifty Dollars; both of which judgments he replevied on the same day with John Simmons as his security. He prays for a remission of the said two sums, so far as your Excellency has the power so to do;</p>
<p>The facts as penned, were substantially as follows. Mrs. Fogerty -- a connection of his family by marriage -- took tea at his house, from which he accompanied her home. Her husband brought in some Brandy and treated him A short time thereafter two Irishmen from Cincinnati, came in and Fogerty brought in some Beer and treated the Company. Petitioner thinking it was his treat, invited them all over the way to drink, one of the men, Brazelle refused, and when interrogated gave as a reason that Dailey had on some occasion down the river called him names and taken the part of another against<pb/>
<lb/>him. Dailey denied, Brazell reiterated calling Dailey and a son of a b -- h -- Dailey went away and after a while came back and enquired for Mr Fogerty, and said something about going over to Cincinnati the following day. Brazelle again joined in the conversation and his friend Honan took some part, and Fogerty protested that there must be no difficulty in his house, Dailey said he wanted none -- Henan said he wanted none -- and stepped up to Dailey a gently put his hand on Dailey while he and Brazelle ever bandying epithets, Brazelle also advanced towards Dailey, who told him to stand off or he would shoot, Brazelle replied you are too damned a coward to shoot, I am not afraid of your pistol, and advanced to the open door, out of which Dailey had backed, pistol in hand, just then Dailey put the pistol almost against Brazelle and shot, making no wound, no breach in his clothing, and leaving no evidence of the pistol's having been loaded. The next day Mrs Fogerty found a bullet rolling on her floor, which bullet did not fit Dailey's pistol. </p>
<p>When the pistol went off Dailey kept<pb/>
<lb/>going from the door. Brazelle cried I am <hi rend="underline">not</hi> shot, says the rascal, Fogerty and Henan caught Dailey, and threw him upon the paved street, Fogerty caught up his feet, while Henan ^and Brazelle^ fell to beating and kicking Dailey about the head and chest, at which time while down he drew a large Bowie Knife and slightly cut Hanan. They beat Dailey, till he was almost dead, in the meantime a man by the name of Biggs, hearing Dailey's cry of Murder and help came, and hit Fogerty over the head with a big stick and the other two fled. Daily was taken home and put under the care of the Dr where he remained for many days. He <hi rend="str">h</hi>is forehead was cut to the bone in two places, and three other places on his head cut to the bone. They left him as bloody as a hog, with several great holes cut in his coat. While under the care of the Dr. these parties had him arrested and as soon as he could get out, had him bound over to Court, where they appeared before the Grand Jury and had him indicited, and then against him on the trial, for <hi rend="underline">shooting</hi> at Brazelle for which he was fined $10. In this case the costs are $13.10, The other Indictment<pb/>
<lb/>was for carrying concealed weapons, and the fine was $50. and the costs were $15.80 Taking the Dr's Bills -- the great loss of time -- the pain and suffering -- the horrid scars on his forehead, which he must carry till death -- taking all these things into consideration Petitioner, thinks he will have been more than sufficiently punished, when he shall have paid the costs and that portion of the fine going to the Atty for the Commonwealth for whatever wrong he may have committed. He therefore prays that <hi rend="underline">all</hi> the $10, fine may be remitted, and all the other except that portion going to the Atty for the State, and as in duty bound he will ever pray.</p>
<p>Michael ^his X mark^ Dailey
<lb/>Attest
<lb/>John F. Fisk</p>
<p>This affiant the Petitioner Michael Dailey says he believes the preceding statements are truely made and set out as they were given in testimony on the trial</p>
<p>Michael ^his X mark^ Dailey
<lb/>Attest } John F. Fisk</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me by Michal Daily this <date when="1862-01-30">30<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of January 1862</date>,</p>
<p>J C Howard J P K C<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Covington join with the Petitoner, and ask that the fines be remitted as prayed by him</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J C Howard J, P, K, O
<lb/>H. Drexelius
<lb/>C. B. Sandford
<lb/>Jas, M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Laughlin
<lb/>B. H. Elliston
<lb/>Jos Mansaur
<lb/>T, F, West
<lb/>James Martin
<lb/>M Rilly 
<lb/>Benj Egelston
<lb/>John Murphy 
<lb/>John Sommer 
<lb/>John Masters
<lb/>H. W. Thomas
<lb/>R. Richardson
<lb/>H. Stacey
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> D,, Davis
<lb/>G W Crist
<lb/>S, F, Roberts
<lb/>D Griffin
<lb/>N Pratt
<lb/>G Clay
<lb/>G Wl M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Donald
<lb/>Chas M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Curdy</p>
<p><cb n="2"/>I know nothing of the facts -- nor the parties but of true, it is a case for clemency</p>
<p>J. W Stevenson
<lb/>J. G. Carlisle
<lb/>R A Athey.
<lb/>C H <unclear/>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Henry C Harris</hi>
<lb/>W R Thomas
<lb/>John C. Picker
<lb/>John Pye
<lb/>S. C Perrin<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>I was the atty that prosecuted Michael Daily before the examining Court, and heard the proof upon the final trial <hi rend="str"><unclear/> <unclear/> the <unclear/> is <unclear/> <unclear/> <unclear/> <unclear/> in the within petition I think</hi> I became very well acquainted with all the particulars of the case, and see no reason why Executive Clemency should not be exercised in favor of Mr Daley. He suffered greatly from his wounds received in the difficulty &amp; has been at great expense. I respectfully Join in the Petition for a remission of his fines.</p>
<p>J, P, Harrison</p>
<p>I am of opinion that the Petitioner is worthy of Executive clemency -- the above statement correctly presents the testimony </p>
<p>W. E. Arthur
<lb/>Atty Commth</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>Kenton Cir. Ct
<lb/>Michael Dailey
<lb/>to } Petition for remission of Fine
<lb/>Govr Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Iss <date when="1862-02-05">Feby 5. 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
