<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2133"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas M. Hicks to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9209</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-208 to MG24-209</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-06-16">16 June 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville <date when="1862-06-16">16th June 1862</date></p>
<p>My Dear Governor -- A Letter from judge Riker -- will introduce to you one of the best and purest men in character, and all the walks of life known to Mo Rev<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> G. S. Rogers of Bullett Co. Ky -- I do most cordially Sympathise with this good man who is now in his 70th year of his most worthy family -- and I can do this from feelings of gratitude to you in your most Humane Leaneancy to my once Prodigal<hi rend="str">e</hi> Son Louis B Hicks who is now a prisner at Camp Morton but who has reformed &amp; gives assurances of future good conduct &amp; a Total abandonment of all dis^s^ipated Habits To your Kindesss I owe the Larger part of his reformation &amp; he and his humble father will never forget you for it. -- you will pardon me under these circumstances to ask your interpossition. in behalf of<pb/>
<lb/>our venerable friend who in his old age, is, bowd down in grief and sorrow -- will you please examine the papers M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Rogers will exhibit to your Excellency and if in your better judgment you can order his release from prisson &amp; remit the fine to do it. I have no acquaintance with the accused (Jeff Rogers) know nothing of him personally and would not ask a favour knowing it to be wrong -- But your decisssion in his case will no doubt Satisfy all parties &amp; Believe me your friend</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Tho</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi><hi rend="underline">. M Hicks</hi></p>
<p>Hon. B. Magoffin
<lb/>Frankfort Kentucky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
