<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0481"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. H. Price to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4600</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-263</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Governor Bramlette
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>Mrs Banks has procured the signatures of a majority of the Jury who tried her husband &amp; M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clure, this you will see from the petition &amp; the certificate of the clerk of the Jeff. Circuit Court. C. Henry Finck the owner of the tobacco &amp; Baumberger the man who bought the tobacco unite in the prayer for a pardon. You will discover many good names signed to the petition.</p>
<p>Mrs banks takes with her a letter from the officer of Banks' Reg in which they "say he is a man of good character: they would have written the same for M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clure had they be applied too for that purpose. I learn from the officers that they are both good men &amp; have been good soldiers. I do hope &amp; pray you will grant them a full pardon.</p>
<p>Those of the Jury would have signed the petition but are absent from the city</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>J. H. Price<pb/></p>
<p>Louisville <date when="1864-02-09">Feby 9th 1864</date>
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>T. E. Bramlette
<lb/>D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Sir.</p>
<p>The two men Banks &amp; M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Clure who were sometime since brought before me charged with Larceny, I understand belong to the army or have served a Tour of duty Each &amp; have been regarded as good Soldiers &amp; faithful to their country. The Two men Fincks &amp; Baumberger who alone suffered by their acts have signed their Petition for a Pardon. Indeed their seems to be a general wish with those acquainted with the circumstances &amp; the history of the two men for the past two or three years, that they should be Pardoned &amp; I admit that I feel the same wish that they should be released</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>Your obt Servt
<lb/>Geo. W. Johnston.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
