<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1676"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">L. C. Winfrey et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6313</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-154 to BR13-155</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jamestown, Russell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-04-24">24 April 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Jamestown Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-04-24">April ^24<hi rend="sup">th</hi>^ 1865</date>
<lb/>Your Excellency Gov Bramlette
<lb/>Sir -- :</p>
<p>on the <gap/> day of <date when="1864-02">Feb 1864</date> Licens was granted Green. B. Warren to keep Tavern in Jamestown Russell County Ky and retail spiritous liquors and about <hi rend="str">8</hi> 4 or <hi rend="str">9</hi> 5 month of the time for which said licens was granted the said G. B. Warren died leaving his wife Rebecca Warren &amp; 10 children the most of whom were infants and from the best information that the said Rebecca Warren could obtain from her friends and persons whom ought to have known better she was advised that she had a right to sell and retail spiritous liquors under the licens afore said that was procured by her husband in his lifetime for which offence she was indicted at the <date when="1864-10">last october</date> term of this Court for keeping a tipling house for three months in consequence of which circumstances forced her this to confess a Judgement in this Court for the sum of $100) &amp; costs and We the undersigned most respectfully represent to your honor that the said Rebecca Warren is not able to pay the said fine on account of her extreme poverty and do Justice to her little orphan children who look entirely to her for support and that the said offence was committid by her believing that she had a right to do so -- under the said licens till the time for which they were granted to her husband expired and that the said offence was ignorately and not willfully committed Therefore We ask your Excellency to remit the portion of said fine due the commonwealth as We believe the circumstances under which M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Warren acted will Justify the same</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>L. C Winfrey
<lb/>Jas. L. Willoughby
<lb/>P. C. Hardin
<lb/>Joseph Ballenger
<lb/><cb n="2"/>George Bryan
<lb/>W T Jackman S R C
<lb/>John Johnson DS for RC
<lb/>S P Collins<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>I do not know the facts in the case but think it a case admitting executive clemency</p>
<p>T T Alexander</p>
<p>Rebecca ^Warren^ states that the facts stated in this Petition are true <hi rend="str">to the best of her knowledge</hi></p>
<p>Rebecca ^her X mark^ Warrin</p>
<p>sworn to and subscribed before me <date when="1865-04-25">April 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date></p>
<p>Jo Ballenger J P. R. C</p>
<p>I regard the petitioner as a fit subject for executive clemency</p>
<p>Jno S VanWinkle
<lb/>Joseph E Hays
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Garrett
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> E Russell
<lb/>Simoleon Cravens.</p>
<p>I respectfully solicit. the Governor of Ky to grant the prayer of the within Petition</p>
<p>Fon T Fox Judge
<lb/>6 Judicial Circuit of Ky
<lb/>M H Owsley
<lb/>J. A. Williams<pb/></p>
<p>Russell Co
<lb/>$100
<lb/>vs
<lb/>R Warren</p>
<p>remitted
<lb/><date when="1865-05-03">3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> May 1865</date></p>
<p>Fine Released
<lb/>Richard T. Jacob
<lb/>Lt. &amp; act. Governor</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
