<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-027-0064"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Unknown to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1297</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R2-98 to R2-100</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-10-13">13 October 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">No 1</note>
<lb/>Frankfort <date when="1862-10-13">Oct 13<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> /62</date>
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>I do not intend to obtrude my opinions upon you, but feel it to be my duty to give you a few military facts.</p>
<p>Chapter 1st</p>
<p>1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> I arrived here at one O'clock P. M. on thursday &amp; found Gen Dumont encamped, with a large force, of Infantry, with several batteries &amp; some 1.000 or 1500 Cavalry on both sides of the river, -- his advance having aided in driving out Scotts cavalry -- (a few hundred) the night before &amp; prevent<hi rend="str">ed</hi>ing them from burning the bridge. -- (2<hi rend="sup">d</hi>) On friday morning I received the following information from M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Scarce (a true Union man) from Versailles -- (see paper N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 1.) and went with him -- first to Genl Grainger -- 2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> in Command, located with his troops, on the Dudley farm, who replied that he could not move without orders -- I then took M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Scarce to Genl Dumont &amp; urged him, <hi rend="underline">at once</hi>, to send Genl Graingers division -- Say 1000 Cavalry one or two<pb/>
<lb/>Batteries of some 4 or 5 Regiments of Infantry in pursuit, via Versailles to Nicholasville &amp; as far as the bridge, at the mouth of Hickman, -- hoping thereby to overtake the enemy -- cut off his heavy trains -- <hi rend="underline">in part</hi> -- &amp; save the bridge.</p>
<p>3rd On Saturday, Col Miller was sent to Versailles with several thousand Infantry -- some Cavalry &amp; artillery -- reaching there that evening &amp; capturing some 150 Rebels; -- I presume the Sick in the hospitals. He remained there till 12 or 1 oclock yesterday &amp; <hi rend="underline">then</hi> started in pursuit. After marching a few miles towards Nicholasville &amp; finding no enemy, he <hi rend="underline">faced about</hi> &amp; camped, last Night 3 Miles on this side of Versailles. What he will do next God knows, I have no idea.</p>
<p>4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Genl <hi rend="underline">Granger</hi> marched also on Saturday with a large force of Cavalry &amp; Infantry with one or two Batteries towards <hi rend="str">Lousville</hi> Lawrenceburg,, which he reached about dark, drove out the enemy in considerable force &amp; <hi rend="str">afterwards</hi> captured some prisoners. -- <pb/></p>
<p>What he has since done, I have not heard. So much for Genl Dumont &amp; his army.</p>
<p>Chapter 2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi></p>
<p>A gentleman well known to you M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. D. E. Harcourt arrived here last Night from Georgetown, who walked up from here on Saturday &amp; gives me the following information -- </p>
<p>1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> At Elkhorn bridge he was stoped by Capt White, at the head of about <hi rend="underline">eight</hi> Rebel Cavalry, <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>who cautioned him not to tell he had seen them, as they were looking out for Federal Pickets.</p>
<p>2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> Genl <hi rend="underline">Pratt</hi> reached Georgetown yesterday at 3 oclock P. M. and gave M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Harcourt the following information, which he hastened to communicate to Genl Dumond last Night &amp; to me this morning Viz That he had left Genl Burbridge with a large column of Infantry, Artillery &amp; cavalry at Williamstown (Say 9000) &amp; understood that Genl Green Clay Smith was at the head of a similar Column on the great State dirt road to Cynthaiana -- all waiting<pb/>
<lb/>for orders &amp; to hear from Genl <hi rend="underline">Dumont</hi>; Reminding me, very much, of the remarkable pursuit of Morgan, on his late raid -- when two columns -- each large enough to whip him, (if well commanded) after coming up with him at Paris, <hi rend="underline">rested</hi> <hi rend="underline">a</hi> <hi rend="underline">day</hi> <hi rend="underline">&amp; night</hi> &amp; then pursued him in double-<hi rend="underline">Slow</hi>-time.</p>
<p>Remarks</p>
<p>1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> I would stake my life, &amp; so told Genl. Dumont, that there is not, at this time, &amp; was not on yesterday, 1000 armed Rebels -- all told -- North of the Kentucky River &amp; yet these large Columns, instead of moving ahead rapidly on Braggs rear &amp; supporting Genl Buell, will wait on each other till they can do no good &amp; then march into our rich counties &amp; consume or destroy all that the Rebels have left us.</p>
<p>Respectfully Yours
<lb/>Most Ob't Sv't.</p>
<p>His Excel. Gov Robinson<pb/></p>
<p>Paper No 1</p>
<p>M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Scarce informed me &amp; I wrote to Genl Dumont &amp; told him that a Column of Rebel Infantry (say 5000 or 6000) left Versailles on the Nicholasville Turnpike Wednesday Evening -- leaving only some 150 sick in the hospitals -- that Genl <hi rend="underline">Scott</hi> left these with all his cavalry, except Col Stearns Regiment, which was encamped at Harts farm, on this side of Versailles -- about 2 oclock thursday afternoon &amp; was followed by Col Stearnes at 7 oclock the same Evening -- towards Nicholasville -- That a large train of Waggons which had started towards Harrodsburg, was brought back &amp; sent off also on the turnpike road to Nicholasville &amp;c &amp; c. He had also received reliable information that with the exception of a small cavalry force, all the Rebels left Lexington Wednesday-Evening in haste and confusion.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
