<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1347"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. John W. Morgan, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10815</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-266 to 273</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Marion County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-02-07">7 February 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">Page 1</note>
<lb/>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Marion Circuit Court } Sct</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Caption</note>
<lb/>Pleas before Hon George W Kavanaugh Judge of the Marion Circuit Court at the courthouse in Lebanon on the <date when="1861-11-29">29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Day of November 1861.</date></p>
<p><note place="left margin">Style of action</note>
<lb/>Commonwealth Plff
<lb/>vs } On forfeited bail bond. N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 2.
<lb/>John W Morgan Deft</p>
<p>Be it remembered that at a regular term of the Marion Circuit court towit <date when="1859-05-26">May the 26<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1859.</date> The Grand Jury empannelled and Sworn in and for Marion County at Said term among other Indictments returned into court One against J Smith alias J Brower and W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Daniel for Setting up and exhibiting and keeping a Faro bank (N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 2.) endorsed by M J Cecil the foreman thereof a true Bill. And is as follows towit:</p>
<p>Marion Circuit Court
<lb/><note place="left margin">Indictment</note>
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against
<lb/>J Smith alias J Brower &amp; W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Daniel<pb/></p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Marion County in the name and by the authority of the commonwealth of Kentucky accuse J Smith (alias J Brower) &amp; W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Daniel of the offence of Setting up exhibiting &amp; Keeping a Faro bank committted as follows. The Said J Smith alias J Brower On the <date when="1859-04-18">18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Day of April 1859.</date> in the county aforesaid did unlawfully Set up exhibit &amp; Keep a Faro bank a contrivance whereby money or other thing was &amp; might have been bet lost or won against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Andy Barnett
<lb/>attorney for Commonwealth</p>
<p>witness before jury
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Chandler
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> S Robinson
<lb/>Benj Simms</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Endorsement of foreman on Indictment</note>
<lb/>And upon the back of the above indictment is the following endorsement of the foreman</p>
<p>True Bill
<lb/>M J Cecil foreman of Grand Jury</p>
<p><note place="left margin">clerks endorsement filing indict</note>
<lb/>And upon the back of the above indictment is the following clerks endorsement of filing the Same<pb/></p>
<p><note place="header">3</note>
<lb/>Filed <date when="1859-05-26">May 26/59</date>
<lb/>N T Berry ck</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Order for bench not to issue</note>
<lb/>And on the Same day of Said Term on motion of the attorney for the commonwealth there was an order made awarding a bench warrant on the above and other Indictments admitting the defendants to bail in the Sum of Six hundred dollars each</p>
<p>And on the <date when="1859-09-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Day of Sept 1859</date> there was issued by the clerk of Said court the following Bench warrant towit:</p>
<p>Marion Circuit Court</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Bench warrant</note>
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>To any Sheriff Constable Corner Marsahl or Policeman in this State You are hereby commanded forthwith to arrest J Smith alias J Brower &amp; William Daniels and bring them before the Marion Circuit court to answer an indictment in that court against them for misdemeanor; or if the court be adjourned for the term, that you deliver them to the Jailer of Marion County Given under my hand as clerk of said court this <date when="1859-09-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Day of Sept 1859.</date></p>
<p>N T Berry C M C C.<pb/></p>
<p><note place="header">4
<lb/>Upon the back of the above bench warrant is the following endorsement. towit:</note></p>
<p><note place="left margin">Endorsement of bail on bench wt.</note>
<lb/>The defendants may give bail in the Sum of Six hundred dollars each and if they desire to give Such bail it may be taken by the Sheriff of the county in which they are arrested or by the Sheriff of Marion County</p>
<p>N T Berry C M C C</p>
<p>And upon Said bench warrant is the following Sheriffs return towit:</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Sheriffs endorsement &amp; return on bench wt</note>
<lb/>Executed on W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H Daniel <date when="1860-03-22">22<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> March 1860.</date> See bond returned herewith the other defendant not found.</p>
<p>J C Vanansdall D. S.
<lb/>For G W Tompkins S M C</p>
<p>The bond refered to in the above return is a follows towit:</p>
<p><note place="left margin">bond of J W Morgan</note></p>
<p>Wiliam H Daniel being in custody charged with the offence of dealing Faro and being admitted to bail in the Sum of Six hundred dollars now I John W Morgan of the county of Mercer and State of Kentucky hereby undertake that the above bound W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H.<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">5</note>
<lb/>hereby undertake that the above bound W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H Daniel will appear in the Marion circuit court on the first day of its next <date when="1860-05">May</date> Term to answer Said charge and will at all times render himself amenable to the order &amp; process of Said Court. in the prossecution of Said charge and if convicted will render himself in execution thereof or if he Shall fail to perform either of these conditions that I will pay to the commonwealth of Ky the Sum of Six Hundred dollars witness our hands this <date when="1860-03-22">22<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> Day of March 1860.</date></p>
<p>J. W. Morgan</p>
<p>Taken and Subscribed to before me as Deputy for Geo W Tompkins Sheriff of Mercer county this <date when="1860-03-22">22<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> Day of March 1860.</date></p>
<p>J C Vanansdall D S
<lb/>For Geo W Tompkins S M C</p>
<p>And at a regular term of the Marion Circuit Court towit: <date when="1860-05-29">May 29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1860</date> there was made the following order.</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Judgment confessed by W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Daniels</note>
<lb/>Commonwealth Plff
<lb/>vs } Faro Bank <unclear/>
<lb/>J Smith alias J Brower and William Daniel } Defts<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">6</note></p>
<p>This day the defendant William Daniel came in upon Court and by consent of the attorney for the Commonwealth confessed judgment in the Sum of five hundred dollars It is therefore adjudged that Said defendant make his fine to the commonwealth of Ky by the payment of five hundred dollars the amount confessed as aforesaid and also the costs herein expended. and this came in continued as to defendant Brower and an alias is awarded against him.</p>
<p>And on the <date when="1860-06-28">28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of June 1860</date> there was issued upon the above judgment the following capias towit:</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Capias upon the Judgment</note>
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>To the Sheriff of Marion County Greeting. we command you to take the body of William Daniels late of Said county if he be found within the Same and him Safely keep until he Shall Satisfy us $500. dollars which we late in our circuit court recovered against him for keeping a faro bank against our peace and dignity also the Sum of Seven dollars and 20 cents which to us in the Same court was<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">7</note>
<lb/>adjudged for our costs in that behalf whereof the Said Deft is convicted as appears to us of record: And how you Shall have executed this writ make known to our judge of our Said Court at the courthouse thereof in the Town of Lebanon On the 2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> Monday in <date when="181860-08">August next.</date> And have then there this writ. witness N T Berry clerk of our Said court at the courthouse aforesaid the <date when="1860-06-28">28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Day of June 1860.</date></p>
<p>N T Berry C. M. C. C.</p>
<p>And upon Said Capias is the following Sheriffs return towit:</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Shffs return on capias</note>
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Daniels not found this the <date when="1860-08-13">13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of August 1860</date></p>
<p>E. Kimberlin D S for G W Goodman S M C</p>
<p>And at a further term of Said Court towit: <date when="1861-06-05">June the 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861.</date> There was make the following order:</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Order forfeiting bond</note>
<lb/>Commonwealth Plff
<lb/>vs } Indict for Faro bank No 1
<lb/>J Smith alias J Brower. and William Daniel } Defts</p>
<p>It appearing to the Satisfaction<pb/>
<lb/><note place="left margin">8</note>
<lb/>of the Court that at the <date when="1860-05">May term 1860</date> Judgment was rendered herein against defendant William Daniels for the Sum of five hundred dollars upon which judgment there was an Execution issued against Said Daniels which was duly returned by E Kimberlin Deputy Shff of Marion County (William Daniel not found.) and it further appearing that John W Morgan executed a bond to the Commonwealth of Kentucky in the Sum of Six hundred dollars conditioned among other things that the Said Morgan would at all times render himself amenable to the orders and process of this court and the Said Morgan failing to render himself amenable to the orders and process of Said Court Said bond is declared forfeited. It is therefore ordered that a Summons issue on Said forfeiture against Said John W Morgan returnable to the next term of this court.</p>
<p>And on the <date when="1861-07-22">22<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> Day of July 1861.</date> There was issued the following Summons towit:</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Summons on forfeiture</note>
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>To the Sheriff of Mercer County<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">9</note>
<lb/>Greeting. You are commanded to summon John W Morgan to appear in the Marion Circuit Court on the first day of its <date when="1861-08">next August</date> term to Show cause why Judgment Should not be rendered against him for Six hundred dollars on account of the forfeiture of the bail bond executed by him for the appearance &amp;c of William Daniels in said Court at its <date when="1860-05">May term 1860</date> and have then and there this writ with due return how you have executed it Given under my hand as clerk of Said court this <date when="1861-07-22">22<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> day of Juy 1861.</date></p>
<p>N T Berry ck M C C</p>
<p>And upon Said Summons is the following Sheriff return towit:</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Shffs return on Sums</note>
<lb/>Executed <date when="1861-07-25">July 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861.</date> On John W Morgan by delivering him a true copy of the within Summary</p>
<p>S S M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Fatrige S M C</p>
<p>And at a further term of Said court towit <date when="1861-08-21">August 21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1861.</date> there was made the following order.<pb/></p>
<p><note place="header">10</note>
<lb/><note place="left margin">Order filing ans &amp; demr of Deft</note>
<lb/>The Commonwealth Plff
<lb/>vs } On foreiture N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 1.
<lb/>John W Morgan Deft</p>
<p>This day came the defendant by his attorney and filed his answer and demurer. herein and the court not being advised take time &amp;c</p>
<p>The answer filed as above is as follws towit:</p>
<p>Marion Circuit Court
<lb/><note place="left margin">Answer of Deft</note>
<lb/>Commonwealth of Kentucky Plff
<lb/>against } On Recognizance No 1
<lb/>John W Morgan Deft</p>
<p>The defendant John W Morgan for answer to the Plffs Summons herein Says that the Said William H Daniels did appear in the Marion circuit court on the first day of its <date when="1860-05">May term 1860.</date> and continued in Said Court till the <date when="1860-05-29">29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of May 1860.</date> On which Said last named day he confessed Judgment in open court for $500. &amp; costs which Judgment was accepted by th Commonwealth by her attorney in open court and the Said William H Daniels was then and there ready to Surrender himself in execution of Said Judgment<pb/>
<lb/><note place="left margin">11</note>
<lb/>And the Commonwealth failed and neglected to ask the court to commit him to Jail or to ask or receive his commitment. whereupon the Said Daniel returned to the county of Mercer his place of residence where he has continued to be &amp; reside ever Since &amp; his place of residence has been all that time well known to A Barnett Esqr attorney for the Commonwealth and no Capias or Execution has been issued or Sent to that county to arrest Said Daniel nor has his body been at any time demanded in execution of Said Judgment whereupon he prays that Said Summons be dismissed</p>
<p>J W Morgan</p>
<p>J W Morgan Says he believes the Statements made in the foregoing answer are true </p>
<p>Jno W Morgan</p>
<p>Sworn to by J W Morgan before me this <date when="1861-08-19">19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Aug 1861.</date></p>
<p>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> C Woods
<lb/>Chm of Leb.</p>
<p>The Demurer filed by Defendant is as follows towit:<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">12</note>
<lb/>Marion Circuit Court
<lb/><note place="left margin">Demurer of Deft</note>
<lb/>Commonwealth Plff
<lb/>vs } On Recognizance N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 1. Demurer.
<lb/>John W Morgan Deft</p>
<p>The Defendant John W Morgan demurs to the Summons and proceedings herein. because the court has no jurisdiction of the Subject of the action -- Wherefore he prays the Same be dismissed &amp;c</p>
<p>Shuch &amp; Woods
<lb/>attys for Deft</p>
<p>And at a further day of Said term towit: <date when="1861-08-23">August 23<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> 1861.</date> there was made the following order.</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Order overruling demr of deft &amp; Plff filed demur to Defts ans &amp; demr Sust. <unclear/> &amp; time given deft to ans <unclear/></note>
<lb/>Commonwealth Plff
<lb/>vs } On forfeiture No 1
<lb/>John W Morgan Deft</p>
<p>The court being advised as to the demurer filed by the defendant overrules Said demurer. to which defendant excepts and Plff filed demurer to the answer of defendant and the Court being advised Sustains Said dermurer to which defendant execpts and time until the next term of this court is given defendant to answer further.<pb/></p>
<p><note place="header">13</note>
<lb/>The demurer filed by Plaintiff is as follows towit:
<lb/><note place="left margin">Demurer filed by Plff</note>
<lb/>Marion Circuit Court
<lb/>Comth Plff
<lb/>vs } On forf Recognizance Demurer to Defts ansr
<lb/>John Morgan Deft</p>
<p>The Plff demurers to defts answer because he Says it Sets up no valid defence to this action &amp; is otherwise informal &amp; defective</p>
<p>Andy Barnett atty for Comth</p>
<p>And at a further term of Said court towit: <date when="1861-11-29">November 29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861.</date> there was made the following order towit:</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Judgment</note>
<lb/>Commonwealth Plff
<lb/>vs } On forfeited Recognzance N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 1
<lb/>John W Morgan Deft </p>
<p>This day came the attorney for the commonwealth and the defendant failing further to plead herein It is adjudged that he pay to the Commonwealth the Sum of five hundred dollars the amt of the forfeiture herein and also the costs herein<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">14</note>
<lb/>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Marion Circuit Court } Sct</p>
<p>I N T Berry clerk of the Marion Circuit Court certify that the thirteen foregoing pages contain a full true and complete transcript of the record and proceedings had therein in said court in the case of the Commonwealth against J Smith alias J Brower &amp; W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Daniels for Faro bank No 1. Als a true copy of the record and proceedings had on the bond of John W Morgan executed in Said case Given under my hand as clerk aforesaid this <date when="1862-02-07">7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Day of February 1862.</date></p>
<p>N T Berry ck</p>
<p>Index</p>
<p><table rend="rules">
<row>
	<cell>Caption</cell>
	<cell>1</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Style of action</cell>
	<cell>1</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Indictment</cell>
	<cell>1</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Endorsement of foreman on Indictment</cell>
	<cell>2</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Endorsement of clerk filing indictment</cell>
	<cell>2</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Order for bench warrant to issue</cell>
	<cell>3</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Bench warrant</cell>
	<cell>3</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Endorsement for bail on bench warrant</cell>
	<cell>4</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Sheriffs return on bench warrant</cell>
	<cell>4</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Bond of John W Morgan taken by Shff</cell>
	<cell>4</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Judgment confessed by W Daniels</cell>
	<cell>5</cell>
</row>
</table>
<lb/><pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">15</note>
<lb/><table rend="rules">
<row>
	<cell>Capias on Judgment</cell>
	<cell>6</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Sheriffs return on capias</cell>
	<cell><hi rend="str">6</hi>7</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Order of court forfeiting bond of Morgan and directing a Summons to issue</cell>
	<cell>7</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Summons On forfeiture</cell>
	<cell>8</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Sheriffs return On Summons</cell>
	<cell>9</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Order filing answer &amp; demurer of Defendant J W Morgan</cell>
	<cell>10</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Answer of Defendant Morgan</cell>
	<cell>10</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Demurer of Defendant Morgan</cell>
	<cell>12</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Order overruling defts demurer and Plff filed demurer to defts ansr. &amp; demurer Sustained &amp; time given deft to answer anew.</cell>
	<cell>12</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Plaintiffs Demurer</cell>
	<cell>13</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Judgment on forfeiture</cell>
	<cell>13</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>cks certificate to record.</cell>
	<cell>14</cell>
</row>
</table>
<lb/><pb/></p>
<p>Commonwealth Plff 
<lb/>vs } On forfeited Bail Bond } N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 1
<lb/>John W Morgan Deft</p>
<p>Defandant John W Morgan lives in Mercer county Ky</p>
<p>Fee for this Transcript $3.00</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
