<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1219"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Joseph A. Keen to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10687</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-66 to MG21-67</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-07-21">21 July 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Covington
<lb/><date when="1861-07-21">July 21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 61</date>
<lb/>Gov B Magofin</p>
<p>Sir I wish to Adress your Honor in behalf of one Hiram Alexander now confined in the Penitentiary House of this Commonwealth for and Assault with intent to kill, The facts of this case are as follows on Cristmas Eve Hiram Alexand and H Slaughter had been at the Drover in and Drink together in the evening and Started to go <hi rend="str">to go</hi> to their Homes on Banklick Street after going up the street about a square the young Men Parted at the Corner of Bacherton Street and Slaughter Proceded up Banklick Street not more then fifty yards when he met 4 or 5 Duchman when they Pushed H Slaughter of the side Walk into the street and H. Alexander heareing <hi rend="str">the</hi> Slaughter called for him H. Alexander to come Back well H Alexander Run Back as quick as Possible and When in about 50 or 60 feet when 2 of the Duchman met him and Struck him and knock him Down and he Land on the side Walk untill he was helped up <unclear>sowrn</unclear> to by a Lady on trial of H Slaughter But this witness could not be Had on the trial of Alexander for she Had Left the Place the Duchman that was injured was confined to the House tow or three Days and now is in Lincoln Army to fight against Southern Confederacy in an unjust <unclear/> May the Lord grant that these Duch and all the Duch in Lincoln Army May be Put in front of Batle for they are all Aboliost and Will if an opportunity afords them will fight against Kentucky if she seceds and this she is bound to Do to sustain her Honor as a soverign State<pb/></p>
<p>These Duch that swore Aginst H Alexander are all Catholics and where <unclear/> or the Bible and I know from experience that they will not tell the truth unless sworn on the Cross Governor this is a Hard Case for those young Men that has been forced into the Dredful <unclear/> for on Account of their Poor Parents M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Alexander is very old &amp; Feble at this ^time^ a man of Good Standing and M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> Alexander is a fine Lady and a Hard Working Woman Now Governor if you can in any way without going out of the Line of your Duty we Do hope &amp; Pray that you would Relese the young ^Men^ from confinement for their Parents need their Assistance in these hard time to help them to Make Living They are Both industrous well behaved and steady at their work that I know from <unclear>experins</unclear> for they have Work for me at the Brick yard which is very hard Work they are as good Hands as I ever hard and I have had Many Hundreds of hand</p>
<p>O Dear Governer Try and Do all you can for the sake of their Aged and Afflicted Parents and by so Doing you will Release them a Great trouble at this time and if you Do not Meet your Reward in this unfriendly World of ours we pray you will be Reward in<pb/>
<lb/>Heven whire we shall all Meet if we are all faithful to the Grace alredy Givens and have a seat at Gods Right Thare where Parting will be no More Where you and Family and I will Meet your Departed son for we have no Doubt in our Minds but that he as a seat at this time ^at Gods Right Hand^ we have no Doubt I Must quit writing unless I very your Patience of Reading such a Long Letter Now May the Blessings of ^God^ Rest and abide with you &amp; Family is the Daily Prayer of your <unclear/> <unclear/> <unclear/></p>
<p>Joseph a Keen</p>
<p>Governor Magoffin</p>
<p>M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Keen<hi rend="sup">s</hi> statements may be relied upon He is a clever man and I hope you may be able to grant his request</p>
<p>Yrs
<lb/>Jno. W. Finnell<pb/></p>
<p>Kenton Cir Ct
<lb/>H. Alexander
<lb/>2 <hi rend="sup">1</hi>/<hi rend="sub">2</hi> yrs Penty
<lb/>"Cutting with the intent to kill"</p>
<p>Pardon Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-07-03">July 3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
