<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-023-0075"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas B. Monroe, Jr. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG2988</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG1-275 to MG1-276</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-08-07">7 August 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Frankfort. <date when="1861-08-07">Aug 7. 1861</date>
<lb/>Dear Governor.</p>
<p>I enclose an important letter from Gov Harris, which may require an answer if not other attention.</p>
<p>We are probably defeated in the state, but from local indications I feel more hopeful of the state than at any time since the Legislature adjourned. There are unmistakable signs of a revolution in popular feeling which might to be at once seized upon -- In this District (except Franklin Co, in which you know local exertion will account for the exception) not only have the Union majorities been largely reduced but the Union candidates were liberally forced upon our platform. Ward in Woodford, Buckner in Fayette, Clay in Bourboun, Burnam in Madison, all repudiated their M. Cs. opposed <unclear/>, pledged themselves not to vote <unclear/> and denounced the war while old Robinson moderated, dodged, squirmed and retracted. All these would have been certainly <unclear/> had they stood out fair upon the "men &amp; many propositions" -- I tell you sir the demand of the Fed. Govrm<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> upon Ky. for taxes will revolutionize Kentucky -- This is most disgraceful to our people their avarice should drive them to a position which<pb/> 
<lb/>honor demanded they should have first <unclear>answered</unclear>. But the fact is so and the right to push our cause now. Now my object in all this is to make this suggestion, our friends right to regard the canvass as not just commenced The right to hold public meetings in all the counties, our speaker ought to go upon the stump and our newpapers redouble their exertion -- I begged Beck (when defeat is a real victory) to let me publish in yesterday a list of appointments for him -- He feared that such a movement by him would be ascribed to soreness on his defeat, that some others ought to lead off and he would join in and speak whenever &amp; wherever he was wanted. He concurred with me that we ought to continue the canvass of the state and work like <unclear/>. Can't we initiate a simultaneous movement throughout the state, call our speakers out, hold county meetings, instruct the Legislature &amp;c. I tell you good speeches will play the devil with Union cause. Beck and Clay literally tore the party open. I never saw such effect attending political speeches -- If we can get the facts well presented to the people we will revolutionize the sentiments of the State -- If we could get up a concerted movement strengthen the state, get all our<pb/>
<lb/>friends enlisted and at work the result will be glorious. I believe if Beck could be heard over Kentucky we would effect an enormous change. Our cause in the hands of an able &amp; decent speaker is absolutely <unclear/>. Our friends so far from being dispirited are encouraged -- For Gods sake let us all try once more to rescue old Ky from the abyss of dishonor &amp; degradation into which she is about to be plunged.</p>
<p>These suggestions are based upon local indications. I am of course without returned from the state and may be mistaken We have no news here. All you are well in the office.</p>
<p>Very Truly Yr
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Tho B. Monroe Jr.</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
