<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0240"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Paterick Casey to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8692</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-360 to R3-361</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> F. Robinson -- Govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner, Paterick Casey would respectfully represent to your Excellency, that he was fined at the <date when="--10">October</date> Term of the city court of Louisville under an indictment from the Grand Jury of said Court, the sum of fifty dollars charged with having committed an assault and battery on one <gap/> Kenedy.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner would state that there were circumstances connected with the case that could not be properly brought before the Jury that would cirtainly go in a mittigation of damages that the party he is charged of assaulting was a bitter enemy of his at the time of the alleged assault. that they were both in the employ of the United States government. They were detailed at the time gauding the Louisville &amp; Nashville R. R. Depot The Petitioner left his post for<pb/>
<lb/>for a few moments to get a drink of water and the party charged to have been assaulted pick up my gun, which I had laid down for a moment to get the drink, and hid it from me. The intension of the party was so apparent, that is, to injure me and have me turned out of my employment, that I became enraged and assaulted him not doing him any great damage however</p>
<p>The Petitioner would further state that he is a very poor man and dependent upon his daily labor for a support for himself and large family of wife and helpless children that he has paid the cost and city attory's part of the fine and that deprived his family of the actual necessaries of lilfe and if he is compelled to pay the commonwealth's portion his family will be brought to suffering.</p>
<p>For the above reasons the petitioner humbly prays that you may remit the balance of his fine</p>
<p>Paterick Casey<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens and officers of the City Court of Louisville would state that the petitioner is known to us and we believe that it is a case for Executive clemency</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>C K. Fairfax
<lb/>Geo. Jonas Interpreter C. C.
<lb/>H C Russell D M
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>I respectfully unite with the petitioner &amp; ask that twenty five dollars of the fine be remitted. I feel confident that Justice will have been done by the Exercise of Executive Clemency thus far</p>
<p>W, G, Reasor
<lb/>City Atto
<lb/>W R Hydes Marshal
<lb/>Phil Tompfert Jr C C C L</p>
<p>I concur with M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Reasor in what he has stated</p>
<p>Geo W Johnston J. C C L<pb/></p>
<p>Louisville City Ct.
<lb/>P Casey Pettn is remit fine Louisville<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>$25.00 Twenty five dollars of fine remitted
<lb/>J F Robinson
<lb/>$50 } Assault
<lb/>Iss <date when="1863-02-09">Feby 9. 1863</date>
<lb/></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
