<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-033-0038"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James R. Dupuy to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1501</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Apprehension of Fugitives from Justice Papers, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-67 to R3-68</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-03-27">27 March 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville Ky <date when="1863-03-27">March 27th 1863</date>
<lb/>Gov Robinson</p>
<p>Sir, the bearer of this Mr Ray is a policeman of this city. He assisted in the arrest of the parties charged in the indictment enclosed &amp; is well posted in regard to the whole of the matters with which they are charged. Guinnip &amp; Bradsaw were <hi rend="underline">indicted</hi> in two cases for <hi rend="underline">enticing</hi> <hi rend="underline">slaves</hi> <hi rend="underline">from</hi> <hi rend="underline">their</hi> <hi rend="underline">masters</hi> they gave bail &amp; forfeited their bond In asking for a requisition upon the Governor of Illinois I have deemd it prudent not to charge them with negro stealing &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi> &amp; prefer keeping those charges in the background &amp; hope we may be able to get them here to answer the third charge against them &amp; when <hi rend="underline">once</hi> here I sincerely hope they may meet the punishment they so richly merit.</p>
<p>Mr Ray has visited the residence of Guinnip, in connection with another &amp; 4th charge against these parties but which we were unable sufficiently to substantiate &amp; of which I am quite conviced they are guilty and since there has been corresponding with parties in Illinois<pb/>
<lb/>who will give him every assistance he may need &amp; if we can only find out some way by which Mr Ray can be remunerated for his time &amp; labor I am sure these scoundrels will serve a good term in the state prison, where they ought to be. Would it be foreign to the intention of the Legislature to appropriate something in this direction out of the <hi rend="underline">secret service</hi> <hi rend="underline">fund</hi>? -- Mr Ray will himself give you all the information you may desire in regard to Guinipp &amp; Bradshaw -- I hope your excellency will take this matter <hi rend="str">under</hi> into favorable consideration </p>
<p>Though a stranger to your excellency allow me to express my very great regret that you did not permit your name to be used in the nominating convention for Governor recently held in this city</p>
<p>Very Resptly
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J R Dupuy</hi>
<lb/>Com atty 7th judicial District</p>
<p>The amt of money deposited in court on the three charges was $3600, all of which was forfeited, the state receiving $2580 --, the balance $1080 was the 30 pr ct allowed me as com atty -- <pb/></p>
<p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Governor Robinson</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
