<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0442"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. M. Doty to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4561</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-197 to BR9-198</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Barren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-01-16">16 January 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thomas E Bramlett.
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your petitioner J M Doty of Barren County would represent to Your Excellency, that he stands indicted by the Grand Jury of said county for an offence known in our statutes as usurpation of office.</p>
<p>Now your petitioner asks the indulgence of your Excellency while he makes a candid statement of facts in regard to the whole affair.</p>
<p>On or about the <date when="1862-01-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of Jan 1862</date> Your petitioner (who lived 7 miles in the country) was in Glasgow and while there, received a note addressed to W R M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Ferran Judge of the Barren County Court and signed by one Clark commissioner of a so-called provisional government of Kentucky <hi rend="underline">temporarially</hi> holden at Bolwinggreen, informing him that his office aforesaid was vacated and that your petitioner was his successor by order or decree of the said Government</p>
<p>Your petitioner never saw said Clark nor were his wishes on the subject of said office ever consulted by the authorities at Bowling green or esewhere.</p>
<p>At the time above mentioned the town of Glasgow as well as the county was occupied and held by rebels under the notorious Hindman and others exercising great power and control in carying out the decrees of the so styled government<pb/></p>
<p>Your petitioner did not wish or intend to have anything to do with the said office of Judge nor did he feel that he could <unclear>percinposily</unclear> decline it with safety to his person or property. He had seen the light from burning buildings from his door, had heard threats from the lips of semisavages from Arkansas till he realized that he was in the midst of a reign of terror. After keeping said note some week or two an officer showoed to your petitioner a process issued by said M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Ferran in the capacity of judge of the Barren Co Court and as he said in contempt of the Provisional authorities at Bowling green. And stating that he would arrest M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Ferran and send him to Richmond Your petitioner protested against the arrest of McFerran on the ground that he was not aware of the action of the provisional government, whereupon your petitioner was ordered to deliver to him immediately said note which he did on the evening of the same day.</p>
<p>Your petitioner states that he never attempted to exercise any of the duties of said office or had he at any time the Keys records or anything there unto belonging nor would he have taken the place except by commission Your petitioner will not attempt to disguise the fact that he was identified with the Southern rights party as they are styled; but he does not believe he was admitted to their secrets, knows he never sympathysed with their plans, their follies and their crimes, whatever erroes he may have been led into by being so identified he trusts they<pb/></p>
<p>are few and under the cirumstances, hopes to be forgiven. He feels that he is now loyal to his Government both state and National and intends so to remain Your Petitioner is in limited circumstances. He has a family dependant upon him for support, and apart from the disgrace of being tried for an offence of this kind, the costs of defending himself would be heavy and burdernsome to him. Your petitioner therefore apeals to your excellency for clemency to the end of granting to him a pardon for the <hi rend="underline">offence</hi> aforesaid</p>
<p>J M Doty</p>
<p>J. M. Doty states, that the statements made in the foregoing petition are true</p>
<p>J M Doty</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Barren County</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me by James M Doty this day. And I further certify that I am well acquainted with said Doty and from a full investigation of the charge against him, I think he has fully and truthfully Set out the facts. I regard him a loyal man and have no hesitancy in saying that he ought to be pardoned as prayed for in his petition</p>
<p><date when="1864-01-16">Jany 16<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>W. F Evans J. B. C. C.<pb/></p>
<p>Barren Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>J. M. Doty</p>
<p>Pardon the offence &amp; remit the penalty
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/><date when="1864-07-30">30th July/ 64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
