<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-023-0083"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Nathaniel L. Berry, A Proclamation for a Day of Public Thanksgiving and Praise</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG2996</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG1-294 to MG1-295</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Concord, Merrimack County, New Hampshire</placeName>
    <date when="1861-10-22">22 October 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Proclamation/Legislation</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The State of New-hampshire.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>A PROCLAMATION
<lb/>For a Day of Public Thanksgiving and Praise.
<lb/>BY THE GOVERNOR.</p>
<p>In accordance with a most worthy custom, it becomes my duty to set apart a day of Public Thanksgiving and Praise to Almighty God, the ruler of men and of nations. In conformity to this custom, honored by time and sanctioned by religion, we cherish the memories of our noble ancestors, and offer to him upon whom we are dependent for all good, a grateful tribute of praise. Notwithstanding the cloud of war hangs sullenly in our sky, and the danger of arms echoes along our hillsides and through our valleys, and many of our brave sons have gone forth to meet danger and death in defence of equal rights, and of the Union, the Constitution and the Laws, we still have reason to feel grateful to our God for manifold blessings. Our fields have yielded bountifully; our domestic industry has been protected; labor, in all its departments, has been amply required; health has prevailed; justice has been impartially dispensed; religion and education have shed abroad their benign influences, and the loyalty of the people to their country, in this hour of peril, has been nobly manifested to the rejoicing of every patriotic heart, and every friend of a free and Republican Government.</p>
<p>I therefore, by advice of Council, do appoint Thursday, the <date when="1861-11-28">28th day of November</date> next, to be observed as a day of Thanksgiving, Prayer and Praise to him who is the Author of all Good, and on whom we, as individuals, and as a State and Nation, are dependent for every blessing. I do earnestly invite the people of this State to suspend on that day their usual secular avocations, to assemble in their accustomed places of worship, and heartily and devoutly render thanks to the Giver of all Good, for the multiplied favors he has graciously shown us; to acknowledge our dependence upon him, and to invoke his continued favor and blessing upon our Nation, our State, our Communities, our Families, and ourselves.</p>
<p>Given at the Council Chamber, in Concord, this <date when="1861-10-22">twenty-second day of October, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and sixty-one</date>, and of the Independence of the United States the eighty-fifth.</p>
<p>Nathaniel L. Berry. -- </p>
<p>By His Excellency, the Governor,
<lb/>With advice of Council,
<lb/>Allen Tenny, Secretary of State. -- <pb/></p>
<p>New Hampshire<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Proclamation
<lb/><date when="1861-11-26">Nov. 26. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
