<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-017-0419"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Ezkiel P. Hobbs et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG2767</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Civil Appointments, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG4-412</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Wolfe County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-04-19">19 April 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky Wolfe Co. <date when="1862-04-19">Apr 19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1862</date></p>
<p>to his Excellency Beriah Magoffin Governor of Ky, we as citizens of sd County think it our duty to state to you the condition of our county so far as officers is concerned we have not had any courts held in our county Since <date when="1861-09">sept 1861</date> up to <date when="1862-04-14">April 14<hi rend="sup">th</hi></date> there was an attempt made By the County Judge to hold County Court on the Regular court day in <date when="1862-04">Apr 1862</date> and was prevented by force of arms as he were acused of Being a disloyal citizen of Ky, then on the same day and at the same place Bowen -- D. Rose Justice of the peace for sd, Co occupied the Judges seat and held county court and appointed a Sheriff<hi rend="str">s</hi> constable and other officer to fill vacancies of officers which have Resigned or are considered Disloyal Now we wish to Know whether the court were held legal or not the county Judge is accused of aiding the Southern confederacy but have had no trial Several of the Justices are in the same fix the old sheriff is in the Southrn army and we as citizen of sd County want the Regular courts held and the proper officers appointed to do Business and if we are not on the Right track if your honor pleas give us Some instructions there have Been But very little tax collected in this county neither can be until we have a proper Sheriff the constable of District No 3 is also in the southern army Larken Drake were appointed Sheriff John B. Horton appointed constable in district No 3: C. B. Needham were appointed to fill the vacancy of A. P. Lacey ^esqr in dis No. 2^ and James F. Halsey were appointed to fill the vacancy of Andrew Swango ^esqr^ Resigned in district No 1 and George W. Kincaid and W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Booth were appointed to fill the vacancy of John g Spencer &amp; W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> S. Spencer ^esqrs,^ accused of Disloyalty in District No 4, Now we have give you the facts of the case So near as we know<pb/></p>
<p>Now we as citizens of sd county Request you in Behalf of sd county to give us all the information you can so as to enable us to transact and have the Business of the county transacted occording to Law pleas write to us By Return mail yours. Truly</p>
<p>Ezkiel P Hobbs
<lb/>Larken Drake
<lb/>G: Evans
<lb/>S. A. Duff
<lb/>S. T. Jones
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W. F. Hanks</hi></p>
<p>We The above Named citizens are Resident Freeholders of the county of wolfe &amp; ste of Kentucky and are Loyal citizens</p>
<p>Sworn to before me the undersigned this <date when="1862-04-19">19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Apr 1862</date></p>
<p>W. F. Hanks Clerk of the Wolfe County Court</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
