<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1527"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Dohn et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10995</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-125 to MG22-126</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-10-26">26 October 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Beriah Magoffin Governer of the State of Kentucky. </p>
<p>Your Petitioner John Dohn, a citizen of the City of Louisville, will respectfully state that on the <date when="1860-09-06">6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of September 1860,</date> upon the trial of an Indictment for a misdemeanor, in the City Court of Louisville, he was fined by the verdict of a jury the sum of One Hundred Dollars; and the circumstances under which the alledged Assault &amp; Battery was committed are as follows, viz.</p>
<p>Petitioner, and one <hi rend="str">John Probts</hi> Peter Hurbts, the person upon whom the Assault was alledged to have committed, occupied, ^parts of^ the same house, and used the cellar in commen, that prior to the findings of said Indictment, the said <hi rend="str">John Probts</hi> Peter Hurbts at a late hour of the night. accused Petitioner of permitting the workmen employed in his Bakery to steal his Beer, and upon your Petitioners denial of said accusation made a violent assault upon Petitioner, and at an early hour of the morning between 4 &amp; 5 o'clock as Petitioner was opening the front door of his Bakery, he renewed<pb/>
<lb/>his attack upon Petitioner. No Persons were at the time passing upon the street and the only persons in sight, were at a <unclear/> more than half a square distant who upon examination under said Indictment, mistook your Petitioner defense of his person for an Assault upon said <hi rend="str">Pro</hi>Hurbst, and thus your Petitioner was unable to present the facts to the jury by whom he was as aforesaid tried. </p>
<p>Your petitioner would state that no real injury was sustained by said <hi rend="str">Pro</hi>Hurbst, no blood shed, and that by circumstances beyond his control he has been made the real sufferer.</p>
<p>He would state that in <date when="1860-12">December last</date> a petition numerously signed, by citizens, by the Judge &amp; officers of the City Court of Louisville, &amp; ^recommended^ by the City Atty was forwarded to your Honor, praying for a remission of said fine.</p>
<p>He further states that he has paid all fees and costs arising from said fine and would again most earnestly ask your Honor to remit said fine.<pb/></p>
<p>He would state that he has but little means, is doing business ^as a Baker^ in a portion of the city inhabited by persons of limited means, that the complete prostration of business, the want of employment in those who are his customers, it is with great difficulty he can sustain and support a wife and <gap/> children by the most untiring industry.</p>
<p>Wherefore as in duty bound, he will ever pray &amp;c.</p>
<p>John Dohn</p>
<p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed by John Dohn this <date when="1861-10-26">26<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of October 1861.</date></p>
<p>A Maas N. P. J. C.</p>
<p>The undersigned unite with Mr Dohn in his Petition &amp; would respectfully ask your Excellency to grant to him the remission as prayed.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/><hi rend="underline">A. M. Gazlay</hi></p>
<p>I remember a Petition was prepared in this case on which I made a statement -- to the effect that Petitioner is a clever man</p>
<p>Geo W. Johnston
<lb/><cb n="2"/>T. <hi rend="underline">Jack</hi> <hi rend="underline">Conn</hi>
<lb/>Jeff Brown
<lb/><hi rend="underline">John F Simpson</hi>
<lb/>Joseph Odell.
<lb/>C. K. Fairfax<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Louisville City Court
<lb/>$100. } Misdemeanor
<lb/>John Dohn
<lb/>Remission Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-11-07">Nov. 7. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
