<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0310"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky vs. John a Slave of C. S. Parrott Elijah &amp; James Slaves of Q. Beckwith, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8762</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-5 to R4-8</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hickman County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-04-11">11 April 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>Hickman Circuit Court Sct.</p>
<p>Pleas before the Hon C. S. Marshall, Judge of the Hickman Circuit Court, at the Court House in the town of Clinton on Saturday the <date when="1863-04-11">11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of April 1863</date></p>
<p>The Comth of Ky "Pltf."
<lb/>against } upon an indictment for arson.
<lb/>John a Slave of C. S. Parrott Elijah &amp; James Slaves of Q Beckwith } Defts</p>
<p>Be it remembered that heretofore to wit. at a Called Circuit Court for the trial of Criminal and penal Causes continued and held for the County of Hickman at the Court house in the town of Clinton on Wednesday the <date when="1863-04-08">8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of April 1863</date>. "This day Came the Same Grand Jury empanelled Sworn and charged on a former day of this term to enquire in and for the body of Hickman County, to wit: Lewis Powell Foreman. David Allison Alfred Travis. N G Henderson. L B Bruce. C H Ricke Saul Phasis. Charles Allison Jno C Allison H W Rouse. Prior Owens. B. C. Bugg. Ellison Nall. E. W. Allison. Lewis Courtney. and Richard Woolley. and returned into open Court the following indictment to wit:</p>
<p>Hickman Circuit court
<lb/>The Comth of Ky
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John (A Slave man) of C S Parrott. Peter (Alias Mose) a slave man of W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Parrot John (no name) &amp; W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> (no name) slave men whose owners are unknown to the Grand Jury.<pb/></p>
<p>"The Grand Jury of Hickman County in the name and by the authority of the Commwealth of Kentucky accuse "John (a slave man of C S Parrott) "Peter alias Mose" (a slave Man of W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Poore) and the two men Slaves John no Name and W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> No Name whose owners are unknown to the Grand Jury, of the crime of arson committed as follows viz. The Said John. Peter. John No Name and W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> No Name did on the <date when="1863-04-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> day of April 1863</date> in the county aforesaid, Maliciously wilfully and feloniously, set fire to and burn the dwelling house of W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Poore, the Said Slaves having conspired to-gether and with one <gap/> Wheeler (a white man) for that purpose and the Said purpose was actually carried into effect in manner and form as above Stated against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky."</p>
<p>P. D. Yeiser
<lb/>Commonwealths attorney for 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Judicial District.</p>
<p>Endorsed on the back of Said indictment "a true bill" "L. Jewell foreman"</p>
<p>Filed in open Court <date when="1863-04-08">April 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date></p>
<p>Attest Thos G Poore C. H. C. C.</p>
<p>And afterwards to wit: at a Called Circuit Court continued and held for the County of Hickman at the Court house in the town of Clinton on Friday the <date when="1863-04-10">10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of April 1863</date>, this day came as well the attorney for<pb/>
<lb/>the Commonwealth as the defendants John (a slave of C. S. Parrott) John (No Name) and W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> (No Name) in the custody of the Sheriff and it appearing to the Satisfaction of the Court that the defendants have failed to procure Counsel for their defense, it is ordered that E. J. Bullock Esq and Col Woodyard be appointed attorneys to defend Said defendants. Whereupon Said attorneys appeared for Said purpose. And it appearing to the Satisfaction of the Court that the names of the defendants "John No Name" and "W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> No Name" are Elijah and James the Slave of Quirus P. Beckwith of Mississippi County Missouri, it is ordered that the further proceedings in this Case shall be in the defendants true names of Elijah and James indicted in the names of John No Name and W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> No Name. Whereupon Said prisoners John Elijah and James were arraigned and upon their arraignment, Severally plead "Not Guilty" to the charge Contained in the indictment. The defendants then moved the Court to rule the plaintiff which offense, charged in the indictment, the charge of Conspiracy or the charge of arson, she will proceed upon. And Said Motion being fully heard and understood is by the Court overuled to the overuling of which the defendants by their counsel except and thereupon cause a jury to wit: Joel Hinfry. Harvey Hughes. W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Haydon. Turner Evans. Saml J. Moore. D M Neely. J. C. Stevens. Matthew Riley B T Hale. John Rushing W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Bayles. Geo Evans who being elected tried and sworn well and<pb/>
<lb/>truly to try the issue found and a true deliverance make between the Commonwealth of Kentucky and the defendants John Elijah and James and a true verdict give according to the evidence and having fully heard the evidence and argument of Counsel returned into open Court the following verdict to wit: "We of the Jury find the within named defendant (Except Peter who is not on trial) guilty as charged and Say by reason thereof they shall Suffer death, but we recommend that the Governor modify the Same to punishment in the penitentiary for life</p>
<p>B T Haile foreman.</p>
<p>Whereupon Said prisoners were remanded to the Custody of the Sheriff to await the sentence of the Court.</p>
<p>And afterwards to wit at a Called Circuit court continued and held for the County of Hickman at the Court house in the town of Clinton on Saturday the <date when="1863-04-11">11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of April 1863</date>. The defendants were this day brought into Court and being Severally informed of the Nature of the indictment, plea and verdict, were asked if they had any legal Cause to show, why Judgement Should not be pronounced against them and none being Shown it is adjudged by the Court that the defendants "John (a slave of C S Parrott) &amp; Elijah and James (Slaves of Quirus Beckwith) be taken by the Sheriff of Hickman County"<pb/>
<lb/>to the Jail of Graves County (the Jail of this County having been heretofore condemned by an order of this Court) and there Safely kept until the <date when="1863-01-15">15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of May 1863</date> on which day between Sunrise and Sunset the Sheriff of Hickman County shall hang each one of them by the neck until they are dead.</p>
<p>Whereupon the Court proceeded to Value Said Slaves, according to law and having Sworn and heard the evidence of H. O. Earl, Geo B. Moss and C T Seay persons acquainted with the Value of Slaves, do Value Said Slaves as follows to wit (viz) John (the slave of C S Parrott) at One thousand &amp; Sixty Dollars. James (the Slave of Quirus Beckwith) at One thousand one hundred &amp; forty Dollars and Elijah (the slave of Quirus Beckwith) at Eight hundred dollars.</p>
<p>It is admitted on record that the Slaves James and Elijah belong to Quirus Beckwith of Mississippi County Missouri and that they are here as runaways without the Consent of Said Beckwith and against his will.</p>
<p>I, Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> G. Poore clerk of the Hickman Circuit Court in the State of Kentucky do certify that the foregoing and annexed five pages contain a true and Complete transcript of the record of the prosecution therein set forth as is on file in my office.</p>
<p>Witness my hand this <date when="1863-04-11">11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of April 1863</date></p>
<p>Attest Thomas G Poore
<lb/>Clk H C C.<pb/></p>
<p>Record of Conviction of Negroes</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
