<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0970"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Nathan W. Hill to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10438</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-17 to MG20-18</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Boyd County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-04-25">25 April 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Govenor Ky</p>
<p>To his excellency Beriah Magoffin; your petitioner <hi rend="str">H</hi> Nathan W Hill states that at the <date when="1861-04">april Term 1861</date> of the Boyd circuit court he was fined the sum of $50 -- and imprisoned the space of five days for an assault on one Winfield strait -- he says that he was surprised at the evidence introduced upon the trial that he could have proved the bad character of the principal witness if he had known that he would have sworn any thing against <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>him -- he says that he had a Little difficulty but no injury was really given that he was forced to do what he did to drive him from his House ^&amp; protect, himself from the insults^ that strait had come to his House and charged him with various crimes also his wife charging her with being a bad woman ^&amp; whore &amp; other names^ he says he done nothing more than to drive him from his premises -- he says he is very poor unable to pay the fine -- that he is in prison <hi rend="str">for</hi> now and will have to remain the five days and will also if not relieved by your excellency have to <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>be put thare <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi><unclear/> the fine -- which he is informed will not pay the same -- he prays a remission of so much of the fine as your excellency is authorised to do</p>
<p>Nathan W Hill</p>
<p>state of Kentucky Boyd county sct -- Nathan W Hill personally appeared before the undersign and made oath to the ^truth of the^ facts in the foregoing petition -- <date when="1861-04-25">april 25th 1861</date></p>
<p>L. J. Hampton J. P. B. C<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersign petitioners your excellency to remit the fine against Nathan W. Hill. he is poor with a family and in times like the presant he is certainly, unable to pay the same -- he is imprisoned five days for the offinse besides the fine of $50 -- which imprisonment we think is fully sufficient for the offense said Hill is worthy of credit</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>John Faulconer
<lb/><unclear/> Wiley
<lb/>William Lamb
<lb/>Wm fergusan
<lb/>Hirbert Sibley
<lb/>E K Gaviet
<lb/>H. W. Noris
<lb/>Thomas Potiot
<lb/><unclear/> Vaughan
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> T Hood
<lb/>C. S. Guilkey
<lb/>B. Frasher
<lb/>A. C. Haily
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>G. W. Chappell
<lb/>John Alley
<lb/>J C Cooe
<lb/>Adam M Coun
<lb/>Richard Scott S<hi rend="sup">r</hi>
<lb/>Henry Batsen
<lb/>Peter Hudson
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John Kirkpatrick
<lb/>Richard Scott jr
<lb/>Jeremiah Wilburn
<lb/>J F Medley
<lb/>B Burk
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Kelsey</hi> <hi rend="underline">N</hi> <hi rend="underline">Harris</hi>
<lb/>Morris Wellman
<lb/>S S M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Crayer
<lb/>A. Sanich
<lb/>W. O. Hampton
<lb/>John Clark
<lb/>J. A. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Elrath
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Ely
<lb/>O W Martin
<lb/>C, L, M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Connell
<lb/>G W Andrews
<lb/>H. I. Witman
<lb/>F,, H,, Bruning
<lb/>William Tilsbey
<lb/>Daniel Davis
<lb/>A W Johnson<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Catlettsburg Ky -- <date when="1861-04-27">april 27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>Dear Governor -- The signers to this petition many of them are the neighbours of Hill who are well acquainted with the parties and <hi rend="str">cas</hi> facts which Hills was fined for. the character of the witnesses could have been readily impeached introduced by comth &amp; no other was introduced ^&amp; defense had been prepared^ -- others who have signed this petition are among the best citizens of the county &amp; some of the jury who found the <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> verdict they are satisfied <hi rend="str">they</hi> since they have conversed with those who know the parties -- that Hill is much more reliable than strait -- The court after hearing strait on oath to bind Hill to be of good behavior growing out of this difficulty Hill was tried for Bound strait to his good behavior in the same penalty that he did Hill -- I have no doubt it would be right to remit Hills fine the cost can probably be made he is very poor &amp; without a good states right man -- </p>
<p>yours truly
<lb/>George N Brown<pb/></p>
<p>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi>, E, Henderson
<lb/>L Stephenson
<lb/>R. Omstead
<lb/>Jep A Akins jr
<lb/>Wm T Potat
<lb/>G Gibbs
<lb/>Peter Smith
<lb/>John. F. Friend
<lb/>J. D. Kincaid
<lb/>James Gilkison
<lb/>John Wilson
<lb/>J. Williamson
<lb/>John Brown
<lb/><unclear/> Ridel
<lb/>Jonathan Charmi^chel^
<lb/>L L Burditt
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Williams
<lb/>M. L. Williams</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M -- 
<lb/>Boyd Cir. Ct
<lb/>$50. &amp; 5 day Imp<hi rend="sup">t</hi>
<lb/>W. W Hill
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-05-03">May 3. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
