<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0368"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Charles Catlett and J. H. Vanderipe to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4487</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-84 to BR9-85</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1863-12-28">28 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Charles Catlett &amp; J H Vanderipe state that at the <date when="1861-04">April Term 1861</date> of the Mercer Circuit Court that they entered into recognizance before said Court for the appearance of Charles Westerfield who was ordered for misdemeaner and Trespass therein is the penalty of Three Hundred ^Dollars^ for his appearance on the Second day of <date when="1861-07">July Court to be held for the said Mercer Circuit Court in the year 1861</date>. That said Westerfield left and went into the southern army and had returned to his Brother in laws in Mercer county early in <date when="1861-07">July 1861</date> and these petitioners being his bail captured and delivered him to the Jailor of Mercer county on the <date when="1861-07-03">3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> Day of July 1861</date> in discharge of their recognizance</p>
<p>That said Westerfield was afterwards on the <date when="1861-07-05">5 July 1861</date> bailed out again before Judge C Gheni Judge of the Mercer county Court having been brought before said county Judge by and of Habeus corpis and gave recognizance for his appearance in the Mercer Circuit Court on the second day of the next term thereof with Dudley Barnett David A Davis and Thomas Huston in the penalty of three Hundred Dollars Which bond <hi rend="str">is</hi> for the said purpose executed in the penalty of 300$ and now a file in the Mercer Circuit Court.<pb/></p>
<p>Your petitioners suffered and believed that they were finally and fully discharged by the surrender of said Charles Westerfield and that they were no longer responsible for his appearance</p>
<p>They understand that on a <unclear>challine</unclear> to wit on the <gap/> day of <gap/> 18<gap/> said <hi rend="str">bond or</hi> recognizance <unclear/> wholy then as afore and was forfeited and that summons issued against them to their cause &amp; his judt should not be rendered against them returnable to bet Term <date when="1863">1863</date> or said recognizance</p>
<p>They employed Mayor W A Hove to attend to said case and who told Petitioners that he would attend to it and have it dismissed, but neglected to do so and Judgement was rendered against your petitioners for the sum of 300$ with costs <unclear/> the penalty of C Westerfield forfeited recognizance to or on the <date when="1863-10-15">15 Oct 1863</date>. that Petitioners were not aware of the fadq Judgement being rendered agt them <unclear/> <unclear/> the last week when the sheriff Thones then the exectuive &amp;c.</p>
<p>They state that said recognizance should not have been forfeited as against them but against his subsequent sureties towit Barnett Davis &amp; Huston. That in Case equity and Justice they are not responsible and should not pay one cent of said Judgement<pb/></p>
<p>Your petitioners state that they are poor men and cannot pay the said Judgement and unless relieved by your Excellency will be incarcerated in Jail for said debt</p>
<p>They therefore pray that you will remit said Judgement &amp; costs &amp;c</p>
<p>Charles ^his X mark^ Callett
<lb/>J. H. Vandaripe</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Charles Catlett this <date when="1863-12-28">28 Decr 1863</date></p>
<p>O S Pston N P
<lb/>Mercer County <unclear/></p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">O S P
<lb/><date when="1863-12-28">28 Decr 
<lb/>63</date></note></p>
<p>Mercer County</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by J H Vanderipe this <date when="1863-12-28">28 day of Decr 1863</date></p>
<p>David J. Jackson J. P. M. C</p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">D. J. J.
<lb/><date when="1863-12-28">28 Decr 
<lb/>63</date></note></p>
<p><hi rend="str">Richard Board C.M.C.C</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Mer County Sct</p>
<p>Elisha Lowe states that he was Jailer of Mercer County in <date when="1861">1861</date> and that Charles Catlett &amp; J H Vanderipe the <unclear/> of C Westerfield in the Mercer Circuit Court on recognizance therein on the <date when="1861-07-03">3 July 1861</date> delivered said Charles Westerfield ^onto Court and he was^ <hi rend="str">to be</hi> held by me as Jailor of said County to answer said indictment and I held him as a prisoner in Jail till the <date when="1861-07-05">5 day of July 1861</date> where under a Habeas Corpus issued by Judge C Ghent he was brought out and baled by Barnett Davis &amp; Hudson as statedin the petition prefixed hereto</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">E. Lowe</hi></p>
<p>Sworn to before me by E Lowe this <date when="1863-12-28">28 Decr 1863</date></p>
<p>O S Poston NP
<lb/>MC County</p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">O S P
<lb/><date when="1863-12-28">28 Decr 
<lb/>63</date></note></p>
<p>The undersigned request the Governor to remit this Judgt in the above petition
<lb/>O S Poston</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J. L. Smedley
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Richard Board C. M. C. C
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Ben C Allen</hi>
<lb/>John G. Kyle D. J. H.
<lb/>C Gabbert</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
