<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1871"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">G. W. Barnett et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11339</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Bradley Strait</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG23-278 to MG23-279</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency B Magoffiin, Governor of Ky, </p>
<p>The undersigned would respectfully represent that at the late Mch, Term of the Kenton Circuit court in Covington <hi rend="underline">Mortimer</hi> <hi rend="underline">Peck</hi> was sentenced to pay a fine of $200<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> and to be imprisoned seven months in the County jail upon a charge of assault with the intent to commit a rape. The said Peck is a youth of about 18 years, in feeble health and evidently at the time of the alleged offence was partially demented. His friends are very poor and all of them of good character and conduct as he had been before the unfortunate occurance which has consigned him to the quarters of the felon, and the abandoned of both sexes. He is now a mere shadow and needs the medical treatment and care which in the jail he can not receive. He also needs the benefit of a wholesome moral atmosphere in order even to render medical treatment of any avail. A mere youth necessarily depressed by a consciousness of the degraded position which the insane folly of an unguarded moment <hi rend="str">have</hi> has rendered him to, he is in danger of drinking in the dangerous poison which inevitably infests the very atmosphere of a common jail. It is hoped that a removal <hi rend="str">of</hi> <hi rend="str">him</hi> to the home of a friend remote from the <hi rend="str">same</hi> place of his single disgrace, may make him yet what he ought to be, and what nature &amp; the care and prayes of his mother intended him to be, an ornament to society and a useful citizen. We desire to remind your<pb/>
<lb/>Excellency of the fact that <hi rend="str">that</hi> the object of punishment is just to reform, and in this case we believe longer confinement in jail will have a tendency to make reformation more difficult. </p>
<p><hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> He was accused of attempting to commit a rape on the person of a girl by the name of Clark, who as the proof showed conclusively sustained no injury. We therefore heartily recommend him to the clemency of your Excellency, believing that a pardon of the fine (not on cent of which is he or his mother able to pay) and imprisonment,</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>G. W. Barnett Juror
<lb/>William Lang
<lb/><unclear/> Mason
<lb/>G W Crest
<lb/>W E Ashbook 
<lb/>N. W. Ingersoll
<lb/>R <unclear/>
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/><cb n="2"/>A. W. Herod
<lb/>J A Goodson<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>The offence committed by the young man (an assault with intent to commit a rape on a child of very tender years) was a revolting one= I am led to believe, however from the statements of Mr W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> White his step-Father, who I believe to be a very excellent man, that the young mans mind at the time of the commission of the offence had been already greatly impaired by self-abuse. tere is palliation in at is circumstance. Moreover the salutary effect of <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> a public conviction, sentence and punishment has been effectuated, though the prescribed duration of his imprisonment has not been fulfilled. In view of these and other considerations arising out of the merit &amp; respectability of that young mans Family and the hope of his redemption by being sent to ^a^ friendly asylum in that family of a kinsman in one of the north western states, I think he is a fitting subject for the clemency of the Executive and I sincerely join in the prayer of the petitioner</p>
<p>W. E. Arthur
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Atty. Com'th</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Kenton Cir Ct
<lb/>Mortimer Peck 
<lb/>Petition 
<lb/>$200. &amp; 7 mos impt
<lb/>Remitted as to Imprisonment &amp; Respite fine for 12 mos. 
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-05-13">May 13. 1862</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Kenton County</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
