<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2096"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Susan Wilson to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9172</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-144</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Beriah Magoffin the Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>Your Petitioner Susan Wilson Most respectfully represents that she was indicted &amp; tried in the City Court of Louisville on a charge of Keeping a disorderly house and fined on the <date when="1862-03-03">3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> day of March 1862</date> in the sum of twenty five dollars -- </p>
<p>Also on the <date when="1862-06-03">3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> of June</date> in the sum of fifty dollars -- </p>
<p>She states that it is true she had in her house certain inmates, young women, about four in number, who paid their board to her, and who in all probability, from time to time were of bad behavior -- The Indictments were preferred on this account -- </p>
<p>She states that as soon as she could move she left that neighborhood and the alleged nuisance was <hi rend="underline">abated</hi> -- She now lives in <hi rend="underline">another</hi> <hi rend="underline">vicinity</hi> and has no boarders, and no complaint exists against her -- </p>
<p>She states to your Excellency that her health is bad, that she is very poor, that the times are hard that she has no property except her household furniture, <hi rend="underline">no</hi> <hi rend="underline">money</hi>, and to pay these fines would render her a pauper and a burthen to the City. </p>
<p>She has no way of satisfying them except by confinement at hard labor in the workhouse at 75 cents a day -- </p>
<p>She is too infirm by reason of bad health for that sort of treatment.<pb/>
<lb/>She therefore, in view of the premises prays your Excellency to <hi rend="underline">remit</hi> <hi rend="underline">these</hi> <hi rend="underline">two</hi> <hi rend="underline">fines</hi>, And promises that she will not in future give cause of complaint &amp; she will every &amp;c -- </p>
<p>Susan Wilson</p>
<p>Address
<lb/>Clerk of City Court
<lb/>Louisville Ky</p>
<p>We do not ask for a remission -- but think that a reasonable <hi rend="underline">Respite</hi> should be granted</p>
<p>W. G. Reasor
<lb/>Geo W Johnston</p>
<p>Louisville City Ct
<lb/>$25.
<lb/>$50 } Disorderly House
<lb/>Susan Wilson
<lb/>Resp<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 9 Mo
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-08-12">Aug 12 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
