<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2163"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">E. H. Wilham and J. E. Russell to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6800</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-397 to BR14-398</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-08-12">12 August 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thomas E. Bramlette Governor of the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioners the undersigned would respectfully represent that they are now and have been for some time doing business as Partners on market street two doors above 3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Street as Wholesal &amp; Retail dealers in Watches and Jewelry &amp;c: and that they have a repairing Shop in which the same is repaired; That at the present Term of the City Court of Louisville they were indicted jointly for setting up and managing a Lottery, under the Statute forbidding it: They plead not guilty to the Indictment, but they were fined the sum of One hundred dollars each, before the said Court: they state that they never did set up or manage a Lottery or any thing like it but having incurred the especial displeasure of two of the public officers they were presented by them on the above ^accusation^ their names are to the first of the accusation a copy of which is appended hereto: They state, that they never set up or managed a Lottery in the City of Louisville or elsewhere: Ben Ewing (a policement) being introduced as a Witness testified that the Defts in thier store Kept in a glass-case set upon their count a number of paper boxes, and that a purchaser paid one dollar for a paper-box, with the privilege of contents: that he bought a box and obtained in it a set of Jewelry worth more than a dollar, that he selected the box for a dollar, and the Merchant<pb/>
<lb/>delivered it to him having received the dollar he said he thought it was a sort of Lottery: Pat Dillon said He had information that the Defendants had set up a Lottery He knew nothing personally about it: He never had bought any thing from them: and this was all that the state proved.: Your petitioners then introduced Mr J W. Surrey who stated that he had bought a box for one dollar: and upon opening it, It contained a watch worth $25.00 $30.00 He stated that He Knew the Machining of a Lottery, and was well acquainted with Lottery-schemes, and that the business done by the Defts was not a Lottery He was often in thier place of business: and that they had not ^managed^ or set up any Lottery. Mr Richard <gap/> stated that he was a watch repairer and that his shop was at the window in the house occupied by Defts; and was acquainted with their business, and that they were engaged as wholsal &amp; Retail Watch &amp; Jewelry; that He was there night and day, and that Defendants had never set a Lottery or managed a Lottery or dispersal of Money or prospects by way of Lottery:</p>
<p>Your Petitioners stated this <unclear/> all, in Consideration of the above they pray your Excellency to remit to them, the fine save fees &amp; costs. they are poor having lost all by the troubles of the Country with large families, and to pay an unjust fine would be hard indeed<pb/>
<lb/>and further impoverish them; the are very respectfully you humble petitioners</p>
<p>E H Wilham &amp; J E Russell</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Jefferson County</p>
<p>J E Russell states that the above is true in substance</p>
<p>J E Russell</p>
<p>Sworn to by J E. Russell beform me this <date when="1865-08-12">12th day of August 1865</date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Sam</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> Matlock</hi> J. P. J. C
<lb/><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">SM
<lb/><date when="1865-08-19">Aug 19
<lb/>1865</date></note></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
