<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2055"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Alexander Hudson to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6692</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-240 to BR14-241</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Rockcastle County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-07-18">18 July 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Rockcastle County Sct
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>Govinor Bramlett</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Alexander Hudson of the county of Estill State of Kentucky would respectfully represent to your Honor That At the <date when="1864-08">August Term of the Rockcastle Circuit court 1864</date> a Judgment for a fine was rendered against him for the sum of four hundred dollars together with cost in favorer of the Commonwealth of Kentucky under the following Circumstances first that your petitioner was the Security in a Recognizance Bond. On an Inditment against one Jefferson Vaughan -- found in the Rockcastle Circuit court. who was charged with horse stealing. The said Vaughan failed to appear. and Judgment was renedered against Your Petitioner with notice being Served. said Judgment was also rendered whilst your petitioner was a Soldier in the 47<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Regiment of Kentucky Infantry. Now your petitioner would respectfully ask your honor as the fine is oppressive and the Judgment unjustly rendered<pb/>
<lb/>against him. that he is only the Security for Vaughan his fellow comrad in arms who was in the Service of the united states at the Same time your petitioner was and believed him not Guilty he entered his security he further states that he is a poor man with a Family looking to him for support. If has a fine to pay will Injure himself and Family verry much. The Execution is or has been pressing him and unless an interposition of Your Excellency he will be bound to pay the debt at a Sacrifice of property your petitioner therefore would respectfullly pray your Honor to interpose and remit the fine. or so much thereof as you may think Just and right and as in Duty bound will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p>Alexander ^his X mark^ Hudson</p>
<p>Alexander Hudson States his foregoing Statements are true.
<lb/>Alexander ^his X mark^ Hudson</p>
<p>The foregoing Petition was Sworn to before me by Alexander Hudson on the <date when="1865-07-18">18<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">"</hi></hi> day of July 1865</date></p>
<p>W. W. Fish Clerk of the Rockcastle County Court<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned Citizens of Mt Vernon Rockcastle County would respectfully state that we believ it Just and right the foregoing fine should be remitted and respectfully ask Your Excellency to interpose ain favour of the Petitioner. -- </p>
<p>This <date when="1865-07-01">July 1<unclear><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi></unclear> 1865</date></p>
<p>E T. Fish
<lb/>G. W. Roberts
<lb/>W, A, Brooks
<lb/>Alfred Smith clk
<lb/>Rockcastle Circuit court<pb/></p>
<p>Rockcastle Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Alex Hudson
<lb/>$400,
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/>Respited 12 months
<lb/><date when="1865-09-09">9 Sept/65</date></p>
<p>His Excellency
<lb/>Governor Bramlet
<lb/>Frankfort Ky</p>
<p>Please address to the clerk of the Rockcastle Circuit court</p>
<p>Alexander ^his X mark^ Hudson</p>
<p>Attest
<lb/>E. T. Fish</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
