<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0938"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William B. Jones to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10406</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-487</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Munfordville, Hart County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-04-13">13 April 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Munfordville Ky <date when="1861-04-13">13 April 1861</date>
<lb/>To the Governor of Ky</p>
<p>At the present term of the Hart Equity and Criminal Court a Judgt, was rendered in favor of the Comth against Thos Hardy and J T Martin, on a forfieted bail bond as the bail of one John Root who was Indicted for an assault &amp; Battery, The Amount of Said Bond and of Said Judgt being one hundred Dollars. They became the Sureties or bail of said Root on principles of pure Sympathy, and to prevent his lodgement in Jail, and the failure on the part of Root to attend, or be at Court at the Calling of the Cause, was a matter wholly unexpected to his bail as he had been attending the court during the earlier part of the term, Although the amount of the Judgt is not large, it is nevertheless, oppressive on the defts, and from the facts and circumstances attending to the case, I am fully Satisfied and so state, that, it would be not only liberal, but Just, that, so far as the executive has the power, he should remit Said Judgt, And I cordially unite with the petitioners in any petition which may be Sent you asking Such remission,</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> B Jones Atty for the Comth,</p>
<p>I unite with Mr Jones in the above statement of facts &amp; request to remit so much of the above judgment as you are authorized to remit -- </p>
<p><hi rend="underline">G. T. Wood</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
