<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-027-0011"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Madison C. Johnson to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1244</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R2-15</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lexington, Fayette County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-08-21">21 August 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Northern Bank of Kentucky,
<lb/>Lexington, <date when="1862-08-21">Augt 21. 1862.</date>
<lb/>Gov J F Robinson
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>The City Council &amp; Military Authorities here ordered the Citizens to enrol themselves and drill every day from 4 to 6 ock P M, during which time all business is suspended.</p>
<p>We have been obeying this order and regularly drilling. But we have no guns except some shot guns and but few of them. The Company to which I belong is well officered and the men good &amp; true. I was told the only way to procure arms was to write to you or Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Finnell.</p>
<p>There some guns here in the hands of the quartermaster but he says he can only issue them upon the order of Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Boyle.</p>
<p>We have drilled thru evenings without Guns, and I promised our officers, Capt Williams &amp;c I would write to know if arms could be procured.</p>
<p>Fifty guns, with those we have belonging to us individually would do for our Company.</p>
<p>Yours truly
<lb/>M C Johnson</p>
<p>N B. W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Fleming writes you about arming a Home Guard company in Fleming County, which deserves attention.<pb/></p>
<p>M. C. Johnson
<lb/>arms for Home guards</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
