<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0535"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. George Rennicker, William Rennicker, and J. D. Rennicker, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4654</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-312 to BR9-313</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Grant County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Kentucky Grant County S.S -- </p>
<p>The Grand Jurors chosen &amp; swown for Grant County in the name and behalf of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, on their oath present that George Rennickar, <gap/> late of said County, on the <date when="1854-04-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of April A D. 1854</date> in the County of Grant aforesaid, did make an assault upon one Elisha Isaacs and with a gun which he the said Renicker in both his hands then and there held, loaded with a leaden ball, did shoot at and wound with intent, him the said Isaacs then and there feloniously wil<hi rend="str">l</hi>fully &amp; with malice aforethougth to kill and murder; and other wrongs to him the said Isaacs then and there did, contrary to the form of the statute in such case made and pro<hi rend="str">d</hi>vided, and against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>And the Jurors aforesaid upon their oath aforesaid do further present that the aforesaid Rennicker, on the <date when="1854-03-02">2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> day of March ^A.D.^ 1854</date> in the county of Grant aforesaid with a certain gun, loaded with a hard ball, which he the said Renicker then and there <hi rend="str">held</hi> in both his hands held, did make an assault upon one Elisha Isaacs and him the said Isaacs did with said gun shoot at and wound, with intent, him the said Isaacs then and there feloniously, wilfully and of his malice aforethought to kill and murder, contrary to the form of the statute in such case made and provided and against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>And the Jurors aforesaid upon their oath aforesaid<pb/>
<lb/>do further present that the aforesaid Renicker, on the <date when="1864-03-01">first day of March ^A.D.^ 1854</date> in the county of Grant aforesaid, with a gun loaded with a hard ball, which he the said Renicker then and there in both his hands held did make an assault in and upon one Elisha Isaacs, and did then and there with said gun shoot at and wound him the said Isaacs with intent him the said Isaacs feloniously, wilfully and with malice aforethought to kill and murder, but reason of which said wounding and shooting he the said Isaacs did not then and there die, nor has since died contrary to the form of the statute in such case made and provided and against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Jno. Hutchinson
<lb/>Atto. for. Comlth</p>
<p>Witnesses
<lb/>James A. Johnson
<lb/>Berry Smith, John Hicks
<lb/>Henry Templeton
<lb/>John Daugherty</p>
<p>Endorsed "Filed <date when="1854-04-19">19<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> April 1854</date> W. Smith clk</p>
<p>A Copy att.
<lb/>N. H. Jeffers clk. Grant Cir Court.</p>
<p>State of Kentucky.
<lb/>Grant Circuit Court.
<lb/>September Term. <date when="1855-09-13">13 Sept. 1855</date>.
<lb/>The Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Scirefacias
<lb/>G. W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> &amp; J D. Rennecker</p>
<p>The defendants W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Rennicker and J. D. Rennicker craves <unclear/> of the recognizance &amp; demurred to Scirafacias, demurrrer overruled and they failing further to answer. It is adjudged by the<pb/>
<lb/>Court that the plaintiff have execution against the said W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Rennecker for the sum of Two hundred and fifty dollars and against the said John D. Rennecker for the sum of Two hundred &amp; fifty dollars the amount of their recognizance and the costs herein expended. and the Scirefacias as to Geo. Rennicker continued.</p>
<p>And afterwards at a circuit court held for the county of Grant at the Court house in Williamstown on the <date when="1856-11-28">28<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of October 1856</date>.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth Pltff.
<lb/>against } Indictment
<lb/>George Rennicker Deft.</p>
<p>George Rennicker the defendant and W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Rennicker and John Rennicker securities appeared personally in court and acknowledged themselves jointly indebted to the Commonwealth of Kentucky in the sum of One thousand dollars, to be void however if Geo. Rennicker shall appear in the Grant Circuit Court on the first day of the next <date when="--05">May term</date> of this court to answer the Indictment for felony found in said court against him and shall not depart without leave of the court.</p>
<p>And afterwards at a circuit court held for the county of Grant at the Courthouse in Williamstown on the <date when="1857-05-26">26<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of May 1857</date>.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth Pltff.
<lb/>vs } Indictment
<lb/>George Rennicker Deft.</p>
<p>The defendant appeared in discharge of his recognizance <pb/>
<lb/>and plead not guilty to the Indictment thereupon Ben. Northcutt, James Scroggin, Haydon Northcutt, G. W. Grant, S. Osborne, Ely Clark, J. W. Williams, C. Sipple, G. Bobbett, Henry Northcutt, Jacob Ashcroft &amp; Tully Sweards who being elected, tried and sworn well &amp; truly to try the issue joined after hearing the evidence &amp; arguments of counsel retired to their room to consider of their verdict, and in a Short time returned "We of the Jury find the defendant guilty as charged and assess a fine against him of fifty dollars G. W. Grant." It is therefore adjudgedly the court that the defendant make good his fine to the Commonwealth by the payment of fifty dollars in manner &amp; form by the Jurors aforesaid assessed and also her costs herein expended and that execution issue</p>
<p>A Copy Att.
<lb/>N. H. Jeffers Clerk, Grant Cir. Ct.</p>
<p>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } copy of Judgement &amp;c
<lb/>Geo Rennicker W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> &amp; J. D. Rennicker</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
