<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0311"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Aylett H. Buckner to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4430</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-488</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Winchester, Clark County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-11-03">3 November 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Winchester Ky <date when="1863-11-03">Novr 3rd 1863</date>
<lb/>Thos E Bramlette Esq
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>On yesterday <date when="1863-11-02">2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Novr 1863</date> being the first day of the <date when="1863-11">Novr Term</date> of the Clark Circuit Court a Judgment was rendered in favor of the Commonwealth against Ovadick Curry on forfeited Recognizance for $500. as the surety of Geo W Hensley who was indicted as a person of Bad fame. Hensley failed to appear having joined the Rebel Army. About <date when="1863-07-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> July 1863</date> Hensley was killed at Buffington; he being in Morgans Command.</p>
<p>I respectfully ask for, Mr Curry or remission of the Judgment.</p>
<p>Curry is a Southern sympathizer but as many of great personal cleverness, kind &amp; obeying. To John B Huston &amp; myself he has repeatedly shown acts of kindness by warning us of danger from Rebels &amp; aiding us to escape -- has protected our property in our home from violation -- for two months while the Rebels, were here allowed no one to enter our rooms at his hotel.</p>
<p>When Clarke drove us all from home the Rebels stole a valuable horse belonging to my son who was about in the Federal Army, Curry claimed the horse as <hi rend="underline">his</hi> <hi rend="underline">own</hi>, dismounted the Rebel &amp; locked up the horse with his own horse, and the Rebels having seized two valuable horses of Thos H Moore Provost Marshall 7 Congl District, Curry went to release them and did save them, and while so employed the Rebels broke open his stable &amp; took his horse as well as my sons &amp; they were both lost. I mention these things to show the kindness of the man &amp; his devotion to<pb/>
<lb/>his friends -- I might fill pages with incidents showing his great cleverness as a man. Hensley is dead leaving no estate &amp; Curry will have to pay the Atty for Comth his 30 percent which will be a pretty good lesson to him, if any were needed.</p>
<p>I hope that you may feel sufficiently justified to exercise executive Clemency &amp; remit his fine -- </p>
<p>If remitted let the Secretary send it to me so that I may not have to tax Curry further with Sheriff's <unclear/> in our Fi Fa.</p>
<p>Yours Truly
<lb/>A. H. Buckner Clk
<lb/>Clark Cir Court</p>
<p>Clark Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>C. Curry
<lb/>$500.
<lb/>Forfeiture</p>
<p>Remit all except fees &amp; costs
<lb/><date when="1863-11-04">Nov 4th 1863</date>
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>Govr of Ky</p>
<p>enclose to
<lb/>A. H. Buckner
<lb/>Clk Cir. Court
<lb/>Winchester Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
