<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1884"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Richard H. Botts to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6521</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-457</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Boone County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-05-08">8 May 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Boone County Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-05-08">May 8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Govenor Bramlet</p>
<p>Dear Sir I take the liberty <hi rend="str">for</hi> of adressing a few lines to you for the purpose of Getting information upon an official Subject "Is a man who says he will swear to any thing for the purpose of Getting to vote qualified to hold office" The circumstances are these Some time since our troubles commenced M. B. Green with others were required to take an oath that the legeslature of Ky imposed upon voters before they were permited to vote "refused to take s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> oath and w<hi rend="str">ere</hi>as not suffered to vote" Some time afterwards he said in the presence of two or three persons he would not be cheated out of his vote any more for he would swear to any thing upon the face of Gods earth if it was necesary to Get a vote" And at another time he the s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> M B Green with others made a rush on the Poles for the purpose of voting, (but did not succeed)</p>
<p>The s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> M B Greens backers elected him a few days since as one of ^the^ Justices of ^the^ Peace in this destrict and it is with you to say whether he shall be commissioned</p>
<p>If you require the testimony as above stated please drop me a line and it will be furnished you</p>
<p>Yours with respect
<lb/>Richard, H, Botts</p>
<p>P O address Risingsun I<hi rend="underline">a</hi><pb/></p>
<p>If you want references I can Give any man in Boone but you can refer to John L. Scott or Co<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Hoges</p>
<p>R, H, Botts</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
