<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2707"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">H. I. Duderrar to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7344</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-352 to BR16-353</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lincoln County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-11-01">1 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Governor T. E Bramlette</p>
<p>Your petitioner would respectfully represent that during the Month of <date when="--01">Jany</date> or <date when="--02">February</date> of the present year he rented a part of his residence in Lincoln County to William Scein, at which time petitioner was absent from home in the Federal Army, Whilst said Scien occupied Said rooms at the foot of Halls Gap he sold Some whiskey by retail how much petitioner knows not being absent from home at the time but is informed he sold but Little, for which Offence the Grand Jury of this County presented petitioner at the <date when="1865-03">March Term of the Lincoln Circuit Court 1865</date> and at the Last September Term the Cause went against petitioner, there being no defence, because petitioner did not suppose he could be fined for the acts of another and for that reason employed no atto. and made no defence, Judgement for $60.<hi rend="underline">00</hi> -- I sold no whiskey to any person have committed no offence Except it may be in reting a part of my house to Scien without having any idea that he would thus bring me in to trouble for which reason petitioner prays your Excellency will remit the Commonwealths part of said fine; having been no violator of the Law in past; never having been even charged with any Offence, he promises your Excellency strict obedience to the Law in future</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>H, I, Duderrar</p>
<p>Hiram I. Duderar states that the statements of the foregoing petition are true <date when="1865-11-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> November 1865</date></p>
<p>H I Duderrar</p>
<p>Sworn to before m by H I Duderrar this <date when="1865-11-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day November 1865</date></p>
<p>B W Dunn Notary Public Lincoln County Ky.<pb/></p>
<p>The Affiants Harrison Graham and Isaak Graham state that they are and have been for years past Neighbors of H I Duderrar that the facts stated in his petition are true that they know Scein rented and was owner at the time by renting of the rooms in which the whiskey was sold that petitioner was not partner of Scien and had nothing to do with the same was in the Army at the time as Harrison Graham the undersigned lived with Scien at the time of the Selling of the whiskey aforesaid further that H I Duderrar is innocent of the charge in the indictment, and should not have been fined for the same this <date when="1865-11-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Nov 1865</date></p>
<p>I. Graham
<lb/>Harrison Graham</p>
<p>This day being <date when="1865-11-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Novmber 1865</date> personally appeared before the undersigned Notary public I Graham and Harrison. and were by me sworn, to the statements of the foregoing affidavit this the day &amp; date above</p>
<p>B. W. Dunn Notary Public Lincoln County Ky.<pb/></p>
<p>Governor I send $200 for Mr J S Page assistant secrety of state if my fine is not remitted please enclose the same to me, if remitted he will get it</p>
<p>Respectfully -- 
<lb/>H I Duderrar</p>
<p>Lincoln Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>H. I. Duderrar
<lb/>$60,
<lb/>Tipling
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-11-03">3 Nov/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
