<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1829"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Sheppard to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11297</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Bradley Strait</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG23-213 to MG23-214</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1862-04-01">1 April 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency the Governor of Kentucky </p>
<p>Your petitioner would respectfully represent that at the August term of the Fayette Circuit Court two indictments were found against him, one for Keeping a disorderly house, the other for selling liquor to a slave without the <hi rend="underline">written</hi> order of his master. </p>
<p>Your petitioner states that he keeps a large and general assortment of groceries, in a part of the City of Lexingtion where from the great number of families such an establishment is much needed. That he sells annually about Twenty thousand dollars worth of groceries, that his Store-house and his dwelling thereto attached is of the value of six thousand dollars, that he keeps an orderly well governed house and has not knowingly and wilfully violated the law in said establishment at any time. </p>
<p>At the last term of the Circuit Court held for this County your petitioner being satisfied that the jury would if possible inflict a heavy penalty upon him and also being fully satisfied that the prosecution would prove that more than five negroes had congregated on his Corner on Sunday when your petitioner was really absent and knew nothing about it, and at a time when your petitioners gro-<pb/>
<lb/>cery was not open at all, and being possitve that no other infraction of the law could be proven under that indictment, with all there facts staring him in the face your petitioner confessed judgment for One hundred dollars being satisfied that a Fayette Jury with this slight proof would inflict a severe and unjust penalty upon him. </p>
<p>The other indictment against him was for selling liquor to the slave of Isaac W Scott without the masters permission, Now the fact in this case is that Berry Dixon <gap/> the overseer of said Scott, who had the controll of said negro boy, told your petitioner that he might sell liquor to said slave whenever he called for it and your petitioner believing that he had a right to sell the liquor upon the <hi rend="underline">verbal</hi> order of the said overseer did so sell it to said slave &amp; being informed by his attorney that with that evidence before them the hury would certainly find your petitioner guilty he Confessed judgement on said indictment in the sum of Twenty dollars. </p>
<p>Your petitioner states that he has not wilfully violated the law at any time, that he has a license to sell liquor by the quart. and prays that your Excellency will remit all of the foregoing fines in your<pb/>
<lb/>power to remit. All which is respectfully submitted</p>
<p>John Sheppard</p>
<p>John Sheppard says the statements contain-ed in the foregoing petition are true</p>
<p>John. Sheppard</p>
<p>Sworn to before me this <date when="1862-04-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day April 1862</date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Z.</hi> <hi rend="underline">Gibbons</hi> Ex F. C. </p>
<p>We the undersigned unite in the prayer of the petitioner </p>
<p>Z. Gibbons
<lb/>B H Allin 
<lb/>Speed S. Goodloe
<lb/>B H Graves
<lb/>J W Patterson 
<lb/>S. N. Drake 
<lb/>James F. Drake 
<lb/>A. Robertson 
<lb/>John Carly 
<lb/>Dr J M Bruce
<lb/>J L Frazer
<lb/>Thos Bradley 
<lb/>Jno R <unclear/>
<lb/>H. F. Jones 
<lb/><hi rend="underline">James B. Woodruff</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Remitted 
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Fayette Cir Ct
<lb/>$100 
<lb/>$20
<lb/>John Sheppard
<lb/><date when="1862-04-04">Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> April. 1862</date><pb/></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
