<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0874"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. P. H. Campbell, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4993</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-342 to BR10-343</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Owen County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-06-23">23 June 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Owen Circuit Court</p>
<p>Pleas before E. F. Nuttall Judge of the Owen Circuit Court at the Court House <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> in Owenton on <date when="1859-05-02">May 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1859</date>.</p>
<p>The Commonwealth of Kentucky Plff
<lb/>agst } Indictment for Felony
<lb/>P. H. Campbell Deft</p>
<p>Be it remembered that heretofore to wit on the <date when="1856-05-08">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day May 1856</date>. at a circuit Court began and held for Owen County at the Court House in Owenton</p>
<p>Came the grand Jury for Owen County and filed in said court an Indictment agst the Deft which Indictment is in the words and figures following (viz)</p>
<p>"Owen Circuit Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth of kentucky
<lb/>against
<lb/>Preston. H. Campbell</p>
<p>"The grand Jury of Owen County in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky accuse Preston H. Campbell of the crime of Shooting at H. R. Abbott with intent to Kill committed as follow<hi rend="sup">s</hi>(viz)</p>
<p>'The Said Preston H. Campbell on the <unclear/> day of <date when="1855-12">December 1855</date> in the County of Owen did unlawfully and with intent to kill or<pb/>
<lb/>Wound Shoot at One H. R. Abbott three times with a pistol Commonly called a revolver against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>R. W. Masterson attorney
<lb/>for Commonewealth <hi rend="underline">Protem</hi></p>
<p>upon the foregoing Indictment is the following indorsement (To Wit)</p>
<p>"A True bill"
<lb/>R. H. Alexander <hi rend="underline">foreman</hi></p>
<p>At A Circuit Court began and held for the county of Owen at the Court house in Owenton On Monday <date when="1859-05-02">May 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1859</date>. the following Order was made in this cause (viz)</p>
<p>The Commonwealth of Kentucky Plff
<lb/>agst } On Indictment
<lb/>P. H. Campbell Deft</p>
<p>Came parties by their attorney and by consent of parties Deft confessed Judgment for Eighty six dollars &amp; costs" It is therefore adjudged by the court that the Deft do make his fine to the Commonwealth of Kentucky by the payment of Eighty six dollars together with the costs of this prosecution and that he be taken &amp;c.<pb/>
<lb/>State of Kentucky } Sct
<lb/>Owen Circuit Court</p>
<p>I W. H. Sandford Clerk of the Circuit Court in and for the County and State aforesaid do certify that the foregoing two pages contain<hi rend="sup">s</hi> a true copy of the Indictment and Judgment therein mentioned..</p>
<p>Given under my hand this <date when="1864-06-23">23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> day of June 1864</date>.</p>
<p>W. H. Sandford clk
<lb/>By Lawrence Sandford D C</p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">L. S.D C
<lb/><date when="1864-06-23">June
<lb/>23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1864</date></note><pb/></p>
<p><date when="--06-25">June 25</date> recommended by J S Scott Comths Atty in person
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette</p>
<p>Owen Cir Ct
<lb/>The Comth of Ky
<lb/>To } Copy Indictment &amp; Judgment
<lb/>P. H. Campbell<figure type="hr"/>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>Govr
<lb/><date when="1864-06-25">25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> June/64</date>
<lb/>$86.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
