<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1179"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William R. Buford et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10647</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-4 to MG21-5</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Danville, Boyle County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-05">5 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Danville <date when="1861-06-05">June 5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th </hi></hi>1861.</date>
<lb/>Gov. Magoffin:
<lb/>Dear Sir -- </p>
<p>A few days ago I was arraigned before the Police Court of this place on two indictments -- one for "<hi rend="underline">drunkeness</hi>" -- the other for "hooping and hollowing." On the first of which I was fined ($2.00) two dollars -- On the second ($5.00) five dollars -- the costs and fines in both together amounting to ($13.40) thirteen dollars and forty cents. As to the first charge, namely -- "<hi rend="underline">drunkeness</hi>" -- I proved by four gentlemen who were with me during the <hi rend="underline">entire</hi> evening, that I was not drunk. These witnesses stated they were with me hours before and after the time I was charged with being drunk, and in fact had not been separated from<pb/>
<lb/>me during the night, and that they saw no signs of intoxication. The witnesses in behalf of the Commonwealth stated that they did not see me drink any thing, but judged much from my conversation. This decision was given against me on the circumstantial evidence of two witnesses in opposition to the testimony of four in my behalf.</p>
<p>To the second indictment I responded by bringing forward the same number as in the former, who testified <hi rend="underline">positively</hi> that I was innocent of the charges of the indictment. One the contrary when the witnesses in favor of the Commonwealth came forward they were unable to say that I had been guilty of those things for which I was on trial. Being called upon to state whether they knew that I whooped or hollowed, the only one who <hi rend="underline">attempted</hi><pb/>
<lb/>to state any thing positivley. refused to answer the question. Being pressed by my Attorney, and under the compulsion of the Judge he said that he was unable to state certainly that I had whooped &amp;, and that "he did not know" This is the statement of the proof in the cases certified to by witnesses in the trial, and by other gentlemen who were present -- whose names are given below. Believing that a decision has been given against me without evidence to sustain it, and very unjustly. I petition your Honor to remit the fines. Hoping to hear from you at your earliest convenience. I remain,</p>
<p>Very respectfully
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> R. Buford<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned certify that we were present at the trial of Mr Buford and that the statement of the evidence as given above is correct.</p>
<p>H. C. Baker.
<lb/>J. W. Jacobs.
<lb/>S. K. Montgomery
<lb/>D M. Rodman
<lb/>F. B. Crutcher,</p>
<p>I was with Mr Buford all the time and agree to the above </p>
<p>F. D. Denton</p>
<p>I was present at trial &amp; agree herewith</p>
<p>R. M. Griffin
<lb/>J. W. Lewis
<lb/>Amos Graves</p>
<p>Respite 
<lb/>B.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
