<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0072"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">G. W. Barbour to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9540</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17A-146 to MG17A-147</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Princeton, Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-02-21">21 February 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Princeton Ky. <date when="1861-02-21">Feb. 21, 1861</date>.
<lb/>Gov. Magoffin,</p>
<p>Dear Sir: I was one of the Counsel, who defended Thomas B Wadlington and his son, William, charged with the murder of M. A Cartwright in this, Caldwell County. And I have no hesitation in saying that a more <unclear>unrichous</unclear> verdict was never rendered than in each of those cases, yet I can not blame the Jurors, who rendered those verdict, as the material witnesses, Prince and Blalock, for they swore positive fact, that placed W. and Son in the wrong. That their statements were <hi rend="underline">false</hi>, I have not the <hi rend="underline">slightest</hi> doubt.</p>
<p>I have in the course of my professional life had much to do with criminal trials, and I can in truth say, that I have never seen witnesses when on the stand display more evidences of untruth and bad faith than thoes two young men, Prince and Blaylock. They were both obscure, that little known at the time they gave their testimony, and whoes characters were unknown, indeed they were without character good or bad. So much so, that on the part of W. and Son, we were unable to attact their character succsessfully by witness and did not attempt it on the trial of Thomas B Wadlington. Your Excelency knows how dificult it is to get Jourors to discrimate from department and manner alone of the witness as to his being the witness of truth or falsehood.</p>
<p>The Prosecution was carried on by the Relatives of Decd. by great energy and vindictivenes. -- every thing that welth and influcence could command was brought<pb/>
<lb/>to bear against the Accused. Judges Hise and Bradley were employed and assisted the Commonwealth Attorney at each trial. Publick sentiment was misdirected by false and unfair reports as to the killing. Since the Trial of Thomas B Wadlington publick sentiment has changed and I learn the character of the witnesses or at least one of them is by his conduct being developed, showing very clearly, that he is a man destitute of moral principal and wholy without integrity.</p>
<p>I have known Thomas B Wadlington for more than twenty years and his son William from his early boyhood, and will state with all truth and candor that better Citizens than they can not be found in this or any other County in the Sate, So far as peacfulness, industry, honesty and integrity are conserned. Thy were always kind, liberil and generous. As Father and Son they discharged all thoes duties enjoined by the principals of morality social and domestic duty. As neighbors, they were kind, generous and charitable.</p>
<p>Under all the circumstances I do most sincerely hope and entreat your Exelency to grant a full pardon to both Father and Son, knowing as I do that with few exceptions such an act would be grattifying to the People of this County and indeed to this whole Section of Country.</p>
<p>I am not in the habit of addressing the Executive for the exercize of his clemency, but in this cases I consciencious beleave it to be a duty I owe to Justice and Humanity ^to aske for^ a full pardon to the unhappy father and Son, and in making this<pb/>
<lb/>request, let me assure your Excellency, that I am ^not^ influence <hi rend="str">of</hi>by me at <hi rend="str">by</hi> the relations I boure the Parties as one of the Counsel.</p>
<p>With the sentiment of respect
<lb/>I am your Excelency's 
<lb/>most obedent Servant,
<lb/>G. W. Barbour</p>
<p>George W Barbour States that the Statements contained in the foregoing letter are true.</p>
<p>G, W. Barbour</p>
<p>Sworn to before me this <date when="1861-02-21">21<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of Feby 1861</date>.</p>
<p>D C Mitchersson J<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> D. C.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
