<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0297"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Henry J. Stites to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9765</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-293 to MG17-294</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><hi rend="underline">Private</hi>
<lb/>D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Gov.</p>
<p>I enclose you the duplicate of a respite sent to our friend S. M. Bernard Esqr. In June last a petition was handed you by me in Taylors behalf for a remission of the forfeited Recognisance against him, and I understood from you that you had acted upon it and favorably to the petitioner; and further that it would be sent down by the Sec^t^'y.</p>
<p>It may be that it has been overlooked, if so, will you please consider the matter, if you have not already done so, and if possible let the remission<pb/>
<lb/>come. The papers M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> B. tells me were forwarded to M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Tate. I handed <hi rend="underline">you</hi> the petition in June.</p>
<p>The election here has resulted most disastsrously to M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clarty -- I fear Combs has a plurality of from three to four hundred in the County. The squatters are very numerous in this Co. as they are all over the 2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> Con. Dis.</p>
<p>Very truly
<lb/>Yr friend
<lb/>H. J. Stites</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
