<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0488"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. P. Clayton to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8940</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-281</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mason County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-07-16">16 July 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>I would most respectfully ask Gov Robinson to remit two fines of $200 each imposed upon me by the Mason Circuit Court for permitting unlawful gaming in my house. I do not ask this clemency upon the ground that the fines were illegally or improperly imposed; but I do entreat your Excellency to forgive as much of them as you can, upoon the ground of mercy to myself and family.</p>
<p>I am now in jail; put there to force me to pay these fines -- I would most assuredly pay them, if I was able, rather than remain one moment in confinement under the circumstances. But I aver that I am utterly unable to pay them, without stripping my family, of what little property I have for their comfort and support. I have no friends who are willing to pay these sums to relieve and, and I am left with no other alternative but to appeal to the clemency of your Excellency.</p>
<p><date when="1863-07-16">July 16<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1863</date> -- 
<lb/>W. P. Clayton<pb/></p>
<p>Mason Cir. Ct
<lb/>$200 2 cases. } Gaming</p>
<p>The fines in these cases remitted except Ten dollars &amp; costs in each case</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J F Robinson</hi>
<lb/>W. P. Clayton
<lb/>Iss <date when="1863-07-17">July 17. 1863</date>.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
