<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1942"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Edwin Terrell to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6579</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-68 to BR14-69</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Shelbyville, Shelby County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-06-17">17 June 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Shelbyville Ky <date when="1865-06-17">June 17<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 65</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>Gov. Bramlette
<lb/>Frankfort Ky.</p>
<p>I have the honor to make the following statement as regards my past conduct, since I have commanded a Company of Independent Scouts, in the Service of the State. On the <date when="1863-10-24">24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Oct 1863</date> I entered the Federal Service as a Private of the 37<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky Infty, and was discharged on the <date when="1864-12-29">29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Dec 1864.</date> by reason of expiration of term of service. I went home with the intention of staying on my Grandfathers Farm but my life was in danger as the numerous bands of Guerrillas that were roaming through the neighborhood were Killing all Federal Soldiers that fell into their hands. There were some 7 or 8 discharged soldiers in my neighborhood (hiding from the Guerrillas) These I formed into a Company for our mutual defence and proceeded to Louisville and purchased arms paying for them out of my own private means At the same time I applied and rec'd permission from the General Com'd'g the Dep't of Ky to operate against these Guerrillas, as an Independent Company. I afterwards increased my force to 20 men, and with them operated against bands of Guerrillas that outnumbered me two to one and in nearly all my engagements have contended against superior numbers As a proof of the service, my Command<pb/>
<lb/>has done, I would respectfully refer Your Excellency to the fact that in the country in which I have operated only five Guerrillas remain who have already acceeded to my demand for their surrender as soon as they are assured that they will be treated as prisoners of war. My command has Killed, and captured more Guerrillas than any organization in the state, I do not state this in a spirit of braggadocio or to boast of my deeds. But to the point, Some weeks ago I rec'd from General Palmer verbal orders to arrest one Herc. Walker (I suppose your Excellency has heard of him by reputation) who had been furnishing Guerrillas with Arms ammunition and information. I went to his place and found him in the field plowing, told him that I had orders from Gen'l Palmer to arrest him, and to go to the house and get ready. On the way to the house Walker made an attempt to escape, was halted and on refusing to comply with my demand was shot at the shot proving fatal.</p>
<p>Your Excellency I Know is conversant enough with military regulations, that in making an arrest where a man refused to halt he is shot at.</p>
<p>At Taylorsville Ky. while on the chase of One-armed Berry I rested my horses, Some of them needed shoeing one horse belonging to a man by the name of Weathers in particular I sent Weathers to the shop of Enos Woo<hi rend="str">d</hi>ten but Wooden on our arrival in town had<pb/>
<lb/>ordered his negro to secrete the iron and refused to shoe Weathers horse called him a d -- d son of a b -- h -- used insulting language to him, and finally became so exasperated that he knocked Weathers down was beating him on the head with a rock. I happened to come along and ordered Woo<hi rend="str">d</hi>ten to desist as he was beating the man to death. Woo<hi rend="str">d</hi>ten paid no attention to my request and in orer to <hi rend="underline">save the life</hi> <hi rend="underline">of my man</hi> I drew my pistol and fired killing Woo<hi rend="str">d</hi>ten on the spot.</p>
<p>Mr Woo<hi rend="str">d</hi>ten has during this war been an active rebel. harbored and assisted Guerrillas in every manner in his power. I Know that a great deal of money belonging to Guerrillas is now secreted in his house. There are now plenty of men in Taylorsville who would be willing to swear away my life if had to be done by perjury. if ever I should be brought before a Court. It is for these two acts that I humbly ask your Excellency's clemency and pardon as I have already sacrificed everything I possessed for I have spent over $1,000 out of my own pocket &amp; have been wounded 8 times in the service of Kentucky. and all I ask in return is that this application may meet <hi rend="str">the</hi>your immediate attention and approbation, Hoping you will grant it</p>
<p>I remain Sir
<lb/>most Respectfully
<lb/>Your Ob'd't Serv't
<lb/>Edwin Terrell
<lb/>Late Com'd't Scouts</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
