<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2308"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Henry Wenzel to Beriah Maoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9384</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG25-61</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency B. Magoffin Governor of Ky,</p>
<p>The undersigned Henry Wenzel states that he has for several years been engaged in the business of a tavern keeper in the city of Covington. He states that at the present term of the Kenton Circuit Court in Covington he was fined in the sum of $50<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> on the change of selling liquor to a minor,</p>
<p>The proof was as follows, one Emanuel Wilson stated that he had on one occasion visited s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Wenzel's house and drank and treated two other persons, getting the liquor from the barkeeper, this was the only proof.</p>
<p>He states that the said Wilson has the appearance of being at least 25 years of age, and has been the sole witness in several trials against other parties, seems to have made it a part of his business, to go into houses and get a drink and go immediatey before the grand jury and inform on the vender.</p>
<p>S<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Wilson is doing business as a man of full age hiring out and collecting his wages and paying his own board as a stranger although he is boarding with his father.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner states that he keeps &amp; ever has an orderly house, pays his license and aims to comply fully with every requisition of the Law. He states that he can illy afford to pay the said fine and yet would not ask<pb/>
<lb/>Your Excellency to interfere did he not believe Clemency is really his due. He therefore prays your Excellency to remit by pardon so much of the s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> fine as is coming to the State of Ky, and as in duty bound will ever pray.</p>
<p>Henry Wenzel</p>
<p>We the undersigned recommend the granting of the above petition. We know the Petitioner well and can fully endorse the statements made in the foregoing Petition</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J P Mosewell Juror
<lb/>J. Dresmann Juror
<lb/>N. W. Ingersoll Juror
<lb/>J H Condell Juror
<lb/>H Drexelius Juror
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Hopkins Juror
<lb/>H F Bowen Juror
<lb/>F. Herrmann Juror
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Maxwell D. S.
<lb/>W E Ashhook Juror
<lb/><cb n="2"/><hi rend="underline">C. H. <unclear>Mooar</unclear></hi>
<lb/>R Simmons
<lb/>A, H, Hood
<lb/>S F Roberts Shff
<lb/>S C Perrin
<lb/>J A Goodson
<lb/>W. E. Arthur, Atty Com'th
<lb/>A H Bowen
<lb/>S H <unclear>Cauher</unclear>
<lb/>John R. Ricke
<lb/>S Mourer
<lb/>H. Hafsen<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>The above recommendation is signed by 9 of the jurors who tried the cause the Atto for Comth &amp;co</p>
<p>C. H. <unclear>Mooar</unclear></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
