<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-022-0106"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Sebastian Vick to Thomas E. Bramlette and John F. Boyle</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG12029</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>37th - 76th Regiments Enrolled Militia Primary Source Documents (1861-1866)</collection>
      <idno>Box 81, Folder 71st Regiemnt 1863-1865 Col. Vick's Correspondences</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Greenville, Muhlenberg County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-12-04">4 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><date when="1863-12-04">Decem the 4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>Greeneville, Ky.
<lb/>to his Excelency Thos E Bramlett
<lb/>and John. F. Boyle
<lb/>Adjut. gen. of. Ky.</p>
<p>Sir, I have the honor to report to you that Last night myselfe and a few of the 35 ky mounted Infantry and my little, com.d, of State guards attacted the Infamous, Lutenant, Col, Robt, M. Martin guirillar that has Bin infestin Southern Ky, Ever since the Rebellion We over, took, them in greeneville about 9 oclock and drove them from the town it. Being dark we got mixt on the Streets and was unable to distinguish our own men<pb/>
<lb/>from the guirilas we capturd Several guns and coats I capturd one of his officials which I Enclose to you that you may know how this Region is Empossd. upon By a Set of murdurous Robers tohoo would disgrace the Most Savage myscreants hells own dominon they have Rob,d. murder,d, and done all the out Rages to civilization that the fiends of hell, could Invent</p>
<p>Sir I am working to organize the State guard acording to your orders well Report to you Soon</p>
<p>Sir I will try to capture those guirilas Before. I they Escape from the county had I forty men I would drive them from the State or capture them<pb/>
<lb/>I will soon Be able to Report you a full company In a few days Ready for their arms &amp;= <unclear/>=</p>
<p>Sir in my Report to you on the Reception of my comission as colonel of the 71<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi>. Regt. Ky., <unclear/> jointed Saying to you that I presented M. Leff. Roark <hi rend="str">per</hi> comission to him as lutenant, Col he cant accept of his comission from the fact that he is comissioned to fill an office in the government of the U. S. etc Sir I take greate pleasure in Recomending. T. S. lewis as a Suitable apointment to that office &amp;. <unclear/>.=</p>
<p>Your Respectfully
<lb/>Sebastian.C. Vicks
<lb/>Colonel, com.
<lb/>the 71<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Regt
<lb/>ky. mia.<pb/></p>
<p>Ky State Militia<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Muhlenberg Co<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>S C Vick
<lb/>Col 71<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Regt<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Date <date when="--12-02">2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> Dec</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Rec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> I G O
<lb/><date when="1863-12-07">7 Dec 63</date></p>
<p>Sir I hope that I will Be able to Send you a look of Rebell Boob marting hair By next mail</p>
<p>Your, Respectfuly
<lb/>S. C. Vick</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
