<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-009-0036"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">A. C. Schlenker to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1191</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR1-66 to BR1-67</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Metcalfe County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-04-24">24 April 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Metcalfe County Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-04-24">April 24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency Thomas E Bramlette Governor of the State of Kentucky I hereby respectfully beg leave to inform you that I attempted to arrest Richard Williams, the man that killed Neal on the <date when="1865-02-04">4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of F<hi rend="underline">eb</hi> 1865</date> and failed from the following reasons I went to Indianapolis I<hi rend="underline">nd</hi> and found that he had Substituted,, giving his proper name place of Residence &amp;c has since as you will find been transfered from the 6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Con<hi rend="underline">g</hi> Dis<hi rend="underline">t</hi> I<hi rend="underline">nd</hi> and assigned to the 33 Re<hi rend="underline">g</hi> In<hi rend="underline">d</hi> Vo<hi rend="underline">ls</hi> after learning this I was reccommended to Governor Morton he being absent I saw his S<hi rend="underline">ect</hi> and his advise was for you to make a recquisitiion for his delivery to our State and as your humble Servant beg you as our chief magistrate to promptly attend to it N, B. the 33 In<hi rend="underline">d</hi> vols. are at<pb/>
<lb/>Wilmington, N, C, please do us the honor and favor to inform us what action has been taken upon the part of your excellency and what will be my further duty to have him delivered to our civil authorities as I have undertaken the matter</p>
<p>Permit us to Remain Respectfuly
<lb/>Your most obedient Servt
<lb/>A. C. Schlenker<pb/></p>
<p>Edmonton <date when="1865-04-25">Aprl the 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi>
<lb/>1865</date></p>
<p>To his his Excellency Thomas E Bramblet Governor of Ky I would say to you that I am well acquainted with Mr Shinker &amp; that he is all wright &amp; a gentleman &amp; I would be glad that you would do some^thing^ in this case if you can</p>
<p>John Y Wallace
<lb/>Judge of the Metcalfe County Court
<lb/>County Cort
<lb/><unclear/><pb/></p>
<p><date when="1865">1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
