<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-022-0102"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John T. Smith to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG12026</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>37th - 76th Regiments Enrolled Militia Primary Source Documents (1861-1866)</collection>
      <idno>Box 81, Folder 69th Regiment 1864-1864 Recruiting</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Gordonsville, Logan County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-06-14">14 June 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Gordonsville <date when="1864-06-14">June 14<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Hon Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E Bramlette
<lb/>Dr Sir</p>
<p>I was selected by the County Court of Logan County Ky as a messenger to confer with you in person for the purpose of explaining more in detail the object of their communication herewith enclsoed to you; and to carry out their wishes I started a few days ago. to see you. I proceeded as far as Bowlinggreen where I met with Col. C. Maxwell the Commandant of this District with whom I am well accquanted. I intended going to see Gen. S. G. Burbridge also an old friend and acquaintance whose assistance I expected to get I was told by Col. Maxwell that the General was off on some expedition and was not at Lexington and being a stranger to you I conluded to defer my trip to a future and more convenient time but ^as^ the circumstances transpiring are such as to render a trip to upper Kentucky rather unpleasant I thought I would drop you a few lines.</p>
<p>Our object is to fall upon some plan so as to have a company organized to act against Guerillas in the part of the Country, having authority from those in power, other Civil or Military<pb/>
<lb/>or both. We wish to have a sort of independent company to act immediately in the vicinity with your sanction or approval provided you can consistently with your position, grant it.</p>
<p>The condition of the most of us is such that we can not be spared long at a time from our familes and therefore can not with propriety volunteer regularly and devote our whole <hi rend="str">to</hi> time to the Service but we can raise a sufficient number to keep off guerillas &amp; robbers by taking turn about with each others. We are compelled to spend a porition of our time in cultivating our crops or we will raise no provisions for our families. Most of our slave laborers have left us and there are none to be hired.</p>
<p>It is also thought by some of us that a sufficient company could be raised by volunteering for six months provided that you could arrange it so that they would have assurance that they would not be taken from their own part of the country. We have soldiers near by us, but they are unacquainted with the country and its citizens and can do but little in catching <hi rend="underline">guerrilas</hi> who are well acquainted with both people and country.</p>
<p>It may be that your Excellency can suggest some plan better adapted to carry out the purpose than any named or suggested by us. We would be glad to accept any relief that may be offered. Our country is becoming more and more infested by<pb/>
<lb/>thieves and robbers. We hear of ^them^ in every part of the country, at Princeton, and Hopkinsville, and many other parts of the Country. A band of some 15 came to a little village last night (Volney) about 5 miles from us and about 8 miles from Russellville and robbed a merchant of all his goods, with impunity.</p>
<p>Col Maxwell gave us much encouragement and told us that he would give us all the assistancein his power, in furnishing us with arms &amp;c, but we wish to act with proper authority and organized by your approval.</p>
<p>We would refer you to Col. Maxwell or Gen S. G. Burbridge who are acquainted both with us and the Country. If you can give us any relief it will be thankfully received. Please let us hear from you at your earliest convenience.</p>
<p>Yours with the
<lb/>Highest Regard
<lb/>Jno. T Smith</p>
<p>P.S. We are troubled by all sorts of Guerillas. Since writing the above, I learn that a squad of federal guerillas or negro Soldiers from Clarksville Tenn. came into the neighborhood of Voleny last night (the place visited by rebel guerillas two nights before) and stripped the citizens of their negroes and horses.<pb/>
<lb/>It is a perfect outrage upon our country. The Federal Soldiers at Clarksville are so busy recruiting negroes that they pay no more attention to guerillas and robbers than if they belonged to the same class of individuals. If we are permitted to raise our company give us instruction what is to be done with negro guerillas. I think we can raise from 150 to 200 men a portion of whom can always be in motion and when necessary all can act. </p>
<p>J. T. S.</p>
<p>Logan
<lb/>Ky. State Militia
<lb/>Gordonsvile Logan Co Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-06-14">June the 14 -- 1864</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Smith J. T. -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Enclosing a petition from the County officers of Logan County to the Gov. and by him referred. requesting that the county court of Logan County be permitted to organize a com and that the influence of the Gov. be used to get the Legislature to defray expenses &amp;c<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Ans. <date when="1864-06-18">June 18, 1864</date> on letter book Page 413 in a co<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m,n</hi></hi> to A. D. Kennedey Pre. judge of Logan Co. Ct.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Rec. I. G. O. <date when="1864-06-18">June 18. 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
