<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0294"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">F. M. Bristow et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4413</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-466 to BR8-467</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Greenville, Muhlenberg County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-11-18">18 November 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Greenville Ky
<lb/><date when="1863-11-18">Novr 18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>To His Excelency 
<lb/>Gov Bramlett</p>
<p>Whereas a Judgement was rendered against Thomas P Boggess in favor of the The Commonwealth of Kentucky ^at <date when="1863-11">Novr term 1863</date>^ The fact are about these at the <date when="1861-11">Novr term 186<hi rend="str">2</hi>1</date> Boggess was recognized as a witness for the Defendants on an indictment against J W &amp; M L Simpson charged with aiding in the escapes of a prisoner from Jail Boggess was at no time ever recognized on behalf of the Commonwealth at the <date when="1863-05">May Term 1863</date> the action of the Commonwlth vs Simpson was continued and on the recognizance of Boggess was forfeited on motion of the Attorney for the Commonwealth at this time Boggess was in the hands of the Military authorities under arrest. So soon as the summons on the forfeited recognizance <hi rend="str">issued on</hi> was served Boggess spoke to one of the counsel for Deft Simpson to know why the forfeiture was taken when the counsel replied that it must be through mistake and he would have the matter corrected, upon these facts Boggess did not attend for the purpose of<pb/>
<lb/>of making defense and Judgment entered. After this a motion for new trial or to set aside the Judgment was made but overuled. We therefor request your excelency to remit said Judgement.</p>
<p>The facts in the foregoing petition, I can say are ^true^ of my own person knowledge. So far as they refer to matters of record, but what he was advised by one of the counsel for the Deft I can only speak from the affidavits filed for new trial from those facts I think his cause meritorious and calls for Executive clemency</p>
<p>J. H. Lowry</p>
<p>I cheerfully join in the petition of Thomas P Boggess for the remission of the Judgement refered to above.</p>
<p>F. M. Bristow
<lb/>R. T. Petree Cir. Judge
<lb/>Jesse N Reno Clk M.C.Ct
<lb/>Thos. J. Jones Clk Co Ct.
<lb/>Jas P M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Intire S M C
<lb/>C. Eaves
<lb/>B E Pullman
<lb/>Jno E Reno
<lb/>E. W. Martin
<lb/>M. D. Hay
<lb/>W B Harrison
<lb/>Alvey McClean
<lb/>T. E. Mann<pb/></p>
<p>Muhlenburg Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Remit forfeiture except costs &amp; fees
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi></p>
<p>Thos P. Boggess
<lb/><date when="1863-12-03">3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Dec 1863</date>
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/>$50 -- 
<lb/>wrote for the amt &amp; Court <date when="1863-11-23">23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Nov/ 63</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
