<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0715"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Hunt &amp; Beck to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4834</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-94 to BR10-95</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lexington, Fayette County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-04">April 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Lexington Ky <date when="1864-04">April 1864</date>
<lb/>Hon: Thomas E. Bramlette Governor of Ky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>We desire to apply to Your Excellency for the release of a judgment against W. C. P. Breckinridge upon a forfeited recognizance of bail. The amount of the bail was $500., for which judgment was rendered at the <date when="--08">last August Term</date> of the Fayette Circuit Court. The circumstances are these: Braxton, a slave of D<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. R. J. Breckinridge -- father of W. C. P. Breckinridge, was indicted at the <date when="1861-02">February Term 1861</date> for the murder of another slave, and was tried at that term. The jury failed to agree, and he was bailed by his master. At the <date when="1861-06">June Term 1861</date>, the cause was continued, &amp; D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Breckinridge recorded his recognisance of bail. At the next <date when="--02">February Term</date>, the cause was again continued; and Dr Breckinridge being absent, his son William became bail for Braxton in the sum of $500. This was done for his father's accomodation &amp; at his request, simply because he was not here himself to Enter into the recognizance. Subtantially, &amp; we think legally too, W. C. P. Breackinridge was but the surety of his father, who (we understand) feels himself bound in morals (as he probably is in law) to make up, in some form, to his son or his son's<pb/>
<lb/>family for any loss that may result from it.</p>
<p>Braxton continued to appear for trial till the <date when="1862-08">August Term 1862</date>, at which time (we think) he made default, though no forfeiture was entered till <date when="1863-02">Feburary 1863</date>. The Commonwealth was at no time preparing for trial; indeed was at no time ready for ^a^ trial after the first took place. In fact, the Attorney for the Commonwealth felt that there was no likelihood of procuring a conviction. Hence the cause was suffered to drift along.</p>
<p>It is certain that Braxtons failure to appear was not from fear of the result; for (as we have said) he was in attendance for four terms after his trial, &amp; in the meanwhile some important witnesses against him had gone off. His disappearance no doubt, resulted from the same general causes which have induced so many slaves to run away in the past two years, &amp; have rendered that class of property so insecure.</p>
<p>We know that D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Breckinridge has all the while intended that his slave should be forthcoming &amp; amenable to the law. He has expressed, <hi rend="str">the desire</hi> from the first, a ^desire^ that he should be promptly tried for the offence with which he is charged; &amp; whilst wishing to give him the protection due from a considerate &amp; humane master,<pb/>
<lb/>he had distinctly directed that no shifts or delays should be resorted to for the purpose of postponing or evading a fair trial. And we are informed that he has made every effort in his power to recapture Braxton that he had offered a reward, at one time of $50., at another of $100., for his apprehension.</p>
<p>It cannot be doubted that he is sincerely desirous of bringing this about, and that he will continue his efforts to that end.</p>
<p>His son William made an assignment of his property for the benefit of his creditors. The assignee, D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Desha, has <hi rend="str">paid</hi> ^made arrangements to pay^ $150.- the Commonwealth's Attorney's part of the forfeiture. We think the residue ought to be remitted, &amp; respectfully make that request of Your Excellency. Though nominally the debt of the son; it is (as we have said) really &amp; ultimately the debt of the father.</p>
<p>D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Breckinridge wishes this remission, &amp; has expressed a desire that this application should be made: but he naturally feels a delicacy about making a personal application to Your Excellency in his own behalf. We were his counsel in the defense of the slave; &amp; knowing all the circumstances, we feel that it presents a strong case for the Executive interposition, &amp; on his behalf appeal to Your Excellency for it. We think his character &amp; public services, the loss which will in any event result to him, &amp; the whole circumstances of the<pb/>
<lb/>case as we have detailed them, will incline Your Excellency to remit the liability, as they will surely justify your doing so.</p>
<p>If it were a debt that would ultimately fall on W. C. P. Breckinridge, we would still think it ought, under the circumstances, to be remitted, as it is a charge on the fund assigned to pay his debts. But (as we have said) it is not ultimately his, but his father's liability.</p>
<p>We beg to invoke Your Excellency's favorable consideration of this application.</p>
<p>If you should determine to interpose, the document may be enclosed to us.</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>Hunt &amp; Beck</p>
<p>In hope your Excellency may grant the prayer of the foregoing Petition</p>
<p>W L Downey
<lb/>CW atty.
<lb/>W C Goodloe</p>
<p>Fayette Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>W. C. P. Breckinridge
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/><date when="1864-04-13">13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Apl/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
