<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0595"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Charles Maleroy et al. to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9047</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-438 to R4-439</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency James F. Robinson Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Ballard ^M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracken^ &amp; Graves Counties Kentucky would respectfully represent unto your Excellency that Eli Smith a citizen of Graves County was arrested by N. S. Ca<hi rend="str">l</hi>valry from Columbus Ky on the <gap/> day of <date when="1862-08">August 1862</date>, and sent as we are informed to Alton Illinois, where he still remains a prisoner -- M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Smith is a respectable citizen of said county about sixty years of age, and in bad health being crippled with rheumatism; like most of the citizens of this part of the state M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Smith has been and is a Southern Rights man, and sympathizes with the Southern people in this war. But we believe like most of the citizens ^now remaining in^ <hi rend="str">of</hi> this region he has taken no active part in the rebellion and was a quiet law abiding man -- </p>
<p>What the particular charge against M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Smith is for which he is imprisoned we his neighbors and ^his^ family have not been able to ascertain farther than this, that his son in law who had been in the Rebel army on the night of his return to Graves County was caught at M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Smiths house -- Without trial, without any sort of investigation a quiet citizen of Kentucky has been taken from his family &amp; home and immersed within the walls of a prison in a distant state -- This we believe is an outrage, that there is nothing in the history of the times to justify it, and we appeal to you<pb/>
<lb/>as our Governor as Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky to demand of the U. S. Government Justice and right for the citizens of Kentucky. If M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Smith is guilty let him be punished according to law, let him be punished after a trial and conviction and not before. Feeling confidant that M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Smith has been guilty of no violation of law, We respectfully ask your Excellency to interfere and have him released from prison</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Charles Maleroy
<lb/>W. A. Lintz
<lb/>G, G, Barriger
<lb/>T. B. Thomas
<lb/>L M Barriger
<lb/>Thomas W Barriger
<lb/>H Fulgham
<lb/>W. D. Lenten
<lb/>J. McMahan
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> J. Fulgham
<lb/>Samuel Mahon
<lb/>J. <unclear/> Lowe
<lb/>Wilis Saler
<lb/>S. R. Whitlow
<lb/>B F Gruse
<lb/>E. Z. Whitlow
<lb/>J R Lowe
<lb/>W F Lowe
<lb/><cb n="2"/>M. D. Chenault
<lb/>C, H, Fuller
<lb/>A Fuller
<lb/>A. A. Flint
<lb/>W, harper
<lb/>Rodam Barrot
<lb/>John A. Lamm
<lb/>Joseph Lamm
<lb/>L,, L,, Williams
<lb/>James B Lecey
<lb/>J, P, Marrill
<lb/>Thomas Goins
<lb/>James Ziggs
<lb/>J,, Richardson
<lb/>Henry Kirtle
<lb/>G F Ott
<lb/>J B Stevenson
<lb/>G,, W,, Famm<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>John Hatcher
<lb/>R M Clayton
<lb/>Wm. W. Barrett
<lb/>C C Richardson
<lb/>R Hubblefield
<lb/>J Lamm
<lb/>E. T. Chenault
<lb/>R S Graham</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
