<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3274"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">V. H. Jones to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5393</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-82 to BR42-83</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Barren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>His Excellency Thomas E Bramlette Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Thomas Purcell who is now in the Penitentiary of this state, was sent from this (Barren) county some two years since, convicted of Horse stealing and sentenced for Four years.</p>
<p>I think under all the circumstances that his a proper case for the exercise of Executive clemency, &amp; to pardon him &amp; release him from the residue of his term would be right. He was in the rebel service (said he went against his will) attracted to desert the first opportunity he had, was pursued, captured, &amp; kept under guard for sometime, &amp; placed again on duty, and immediately deserted, went to Metcalfe county, where remained until arrested &amp; brought to Glasgow by Federal soldier.</p>
<p>He proved before the military authority by M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Drake of Tompkinsville, who ^was^ arrested by the rebels for being a union man, &amp; who was in the guard home with Purcell, the Purcell told<pb/>
<lb/>him that he was in the service against his will that he had attempted to escape from them &amp; that he would escape the first opportunity that presented itself, which he did very soon after</p>
<p>The military authorities released him, &amp; turned him over to the civil, by which which he was tried and convicted</p>
<p>The charge upon which he was convicted was stealing two Horses the property of J. Buckingham The facts as shown by the proof was <hi rend="str">the</hi> that Purcell went with a number of others, some 20 perhaps all being rebel soldiers, &amp; in the service &amp; took Two horses from Esq Buckingham took them to the command, (Purcell says they were ordered to take the horses by the co<hi rend="sup">l</hi>. commanding) &amp; Purcell being the only person among them known or recognized, was the only one indicted</p>
<p>Purcell did not take the horses for his own use, did not attempt to apply to them his own use, or<pb/>
<lb/>make money, out of them, but was <unclear/> acting under orders &amp; however wrong his being there may have been, I think it is <unclear/> by his leaving, &amp; quitting as soon as he could</p>
<p>The proof also showed that he saw Mr<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. Buckingham, as he was on his way from the army, told her that he and others took the Esq<hi rend="sup">s</hi> horses, that they were then with Helms Regiment, &amp; that he thought that perhaps if she would <unclear/> some friend, he might be able to get the horses.</p>
<p>He has a wife &amp; two children destitute of any means of support was confined in Jail one year before he was tried has been some Two years in the penitentiary</p>
<p>I hope you will take the same view of it, that I do, &amp; release the residue of his time &amp; let return to &amp; support his helpless wife &amp; children &amp; as in duty will ever pray</p>
<p>Respectfully Yours
<lb/>V. H. Jones</p>
<p>P. S. M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Drake of Tompkinsville is well known to M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> W Sampson &amp; Mr. Hagan of Monroe-</p>
<p>V H J<pb/>
<lb/>Barren Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Purcell</p>
<p>Refused</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
