<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3271"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Robert Richardson to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5390</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-77</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><hi rend="underline">To His Excellency Gov</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">n</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> Thos. E. Bramlette</hi>
<lb/>Dear Sir,</p>
<p>I would make this statement in behalf of <hi rend="underline">Capt. Crout</hi>, the petitioner, herein.</p>
<p>He was indicted in the Kenton Circuit, on three several indictments, charged with having sold liquor to <hi rend="underline">3 minors</hi>. One of the regular pannell tried <hi rend="underline">2</hi>; the other <hi rend="underline">one</hi> of them.</p>
<p>The principal witness against him was one <hi rend="underline">John Beasely</hi>, by whom (as Beasely himself testified) the boys- Merriman, Moran, and Peter- <gap/>, were invited to go into Mr. Crouts saloon and drink wine &amp;c. One of those boys lacked only a few months of 21 years; and they all had the appearance of men. Mr. Crout was fully deceived by their appearance- deeming them of age. The jury were constrained to find him guilty on the three Indictments <hi rend="underline">Nos 782,</hi> <hi rend="underline">783</hi> &amp; <hi rend="underline">785</hi> and a fine of $<hi rend="underline">150</hi> ^<hi rend="underline">or $50 in each case</hi>^ was assessed against him, for selling to each of the 3 minors. These young men all worked, contracted, and did business in their own names.</p>
<p>I shall always believe our late Commonwealth's atty- ^R.B. Carpenter^ who has left these<pb/>
<lb/>parts- and against whom are now pending two indictments- one for "<hi rend="underline">malfeasance in office</hi>", and one "<hi rend="underline">for obtaining money under false pretences</hi>"- took unwarrantable steps in the proceedings against Capt. Crout.</p>
<p>Hon John F. Fisk prepared the petition to your Excellency; and I afterwards procured the affidavit of <hi rend="underline">Mr. Pack</hi>, on file with the papers, and the signatures and <hi rend="str">written statements</hi> of some of the jurors. All of the jurors, I doubt not could have been obtained to join in the petition; but many of them live in the country.</p>
<p>The written statements of Mess<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> <hi rend="underline">Lowry</hi>, <hi rend="underline">Robeson</hi> &amp; <hi rend="underline">Spilman</hi>, jurors, are also filed=</p>
<p>Capt. Crout is a man who bears a very exemplary character for honesty and probity; I believe he would never willingly violate any penal law.</p>
<p>The witness, <hi rend="underline">Beasely</hi>, is shown to be a a person utterly disreputable &amp; untrustworthy.</p>
<p>I am constrained to think the matter is one of such a character as makes it a fit subject for Executive Clemency.</p>
<p>Very Truly Your Excelleny's Obt. Servt.
<lb/>Robt. Richardson
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">n</hi></hi> Bramlette=</p>
<p>accompany the petition is also a certificate signed by some of our best citizens.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
