<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0508"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Mountraville G. Wilson to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8960</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-310 to R4-311</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Fulton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency, James F Robinson, Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky:
<lb/>The Petition of Montraville G Wilson, of the City of Hickman, Fulton County, Kentucky,
<lb/>Respectfully represents:</p>
<p>That at the <date when="1861-05">May Term 1861</date> ^of the Fulton Equity &amp; Criminal Court,^ in company with John W Cole, and Thomas Wallace, he was indicted, tried and convicted for Gambling, contrary to the act of Assembly in such cases made and provided. That being so as aforesaid convicted, he in company with the said Cole &amp; Wallace was sentenced to pay a fine of $20.00; but so it was, that through the interposition of the then Commonwealth's atty. the fine as against said Cole &amp; Wallace was remitted, but still remains as against your petitioner. Now your petitioner would respectfully further represent -- That the said prosecution was the result of anything but justice sought on the part of the prosecutor -- inasmuch as your petitioner is a hard working and as he conceives and believes in law abiding citizen, but upon the occasion referred to, being in company with the parties named, they entered into a game and for mere interest to the game, the stakes were made at five cents nor was there from the commencement to the end as much as five dollars in issue. Wherefore your petitioner humbly prays your Excellency to be pleased to remit said fine And as in duty bound he will ever pray &amp;c.</p>
<p>Mountraville G Wilson<pb/></p>
<p>To His Excellency. Jas F Robinson
<lb/>Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>We, the undersigned most respectfully recommend to your Excellency, that the fine imposed on M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Montraville. G. Wilson be remitted. From our knowledge of the party, M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Wilson, we are satisfied that his is a proper subject for the exercise of Executive Clemency.</p>
<p>Geo C Hallet
<lb/>County Atty.
<lb/>John H Davis
<lb/>Post Master
<lb/>J M Gest
<lb/>Special aid Revinu
<lb/>W A Brevard Clk, C, C
<lb/>W Morrow S f c<pb/></p>
<p>Fulton Eq. Ct
<lb/>$20. } Gaming
<lb/>Fine in this case remitted
<lb/>J F Robinson
<lb/>M. G. Wilson
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1863-08-21">Aug 21. 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
