<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1456"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Eliza Moore et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10924</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-24 to MG22-25</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mercer County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-10-01">1 October 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency B. Magoffin Govenor of the State of Kentucky,</p>
<p>Your petitioners Eliza Moore F. B. Everslain, W. T. Cooke, M. B. Pulliam, Samuel Ruply and James Burke, citizens of Mercer County, very respectfully represent to your Excellency, that a Judgment has been entered against them in the Washington circuit Court in the sum of $400 on a forfeited recognizance of W. H. Moore &amp; $6,50<hi rend="sup">cts</hi>. costs in <date when="1862-03">March 1862,</date> and upon which a capais has issued and is now in the hands of the sheriff of Mercer County -- </p>
<p>They state that the said W. H. Moore was a youth, &amp; the son of the Petitioner, Eliza Moore, and was charged with larceny, and that your petitioners became bail for his appearance at the request of and in conjunction with his ^s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi>^ mother, she havig indemified the other of your petitioners by all she owns or possesses &amp; which is not more than sufficent to pay the said Judgment, &amp; that if executed by the commonwealth will take it all from her &amp; leave her pennyless -- she is a woman of age &amp; has no other property &amp; has no one to take care of her &amp; is dependant upon the little property on which the other of your petitioners hold said lein for a partial support -- The boy, her<pb/>
<lb/>said son W. H. Moore was young and inexperienced, and believed to be innocent and in fright left his home &amp; his mother and has gone to the wars, -- she is in a helpless condition, and will be the whole sufferer, if not relieved by Executive clemency, -- she will be compelled to pay the Commonwealths attrnys fees, &amp; the cost which is more than she can pay without suffering to her, wherefore we ask that your Excellency will remit said Judgment, and give her relief which the circumstances, &amp; her condition implore -- </p>
<p>Eliza Moore
<lb/>W. T. Cooke
<lb/>Sam<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Ruply
<lb/>Jas Burke
<lb/>M. B. Pulliam
<lb/>B. F. Everslain</p>
<p>Mercer County, Ky</p>
<p>This day came before me Eliza Moore &amp; M. B. Pulliam and made oath that they believe the statements of the forgoing Petition are true </p>
<p>Giving now my hand this <date when="1861-10-01">1 day of October 1861. -- </date></p>
<p>John Slavens Jr J. P. C. H.<pb/></p>
<p> -- The undersigned citizens of Mercer County respectfully requests the Hon B. Magoffin Govener of Ky to remit the fine referred to in the forgoing Petition &amp; unite in the prayer thereof -- <date when="1861-10-01">Oct 1 -- 1861</date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">W. A. Hooe</hi>
<lb/>John Slavens Jr
<lb/>Chr Chinn
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Tho</hi> <hi rend="underline">Allin</hi>
<lb/>N H Burrus
<lb/>Ben C Allin
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> B Allin
<lb/>B W Allin
<lb/>F. W. Currey
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H Buckner
<lb/>R N Scott
<lb/>A. F. Cochran
<lb/>S W Jones
<lb/>John Kane Jr
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> C Clark
<lb/>John Kane
<lb/>A, Portwood<pb/></p>
<p>Return Remittance to W. A. Hooe if remitted -- </p>
<p>Washington Cir Ct
<lb/>Remitted 
<lb/>B. M. </p>
<p>$400 } Recog
<lb/>Eliza Moore &amp; otherz
<lb/>Iss <date when="1861-10-10">Oct 10 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
