<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2338"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Simpson Adams to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6975</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-234 to BR15-235</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Rockcastle County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-26">26 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Rockcastle Circuit court.
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>Governor Bramlett
<lb/>Frankfort.</p>
<p>Your petitioner Simpson Adams of the county of Pulaski state of Kentucky, would respectfully represent. That he was fined by a Judgment of the Rockcastle Circuit court at its <date when="1861-02">Febry Term 1861</date>, the sum of twenty dollars, upon a charge of tipling. That by the same court at its <date when="1864-08">august Term 1864</date>, he was find by a Judgment of said court $20 -- upon a charge of Tipling. ^and that the C P F. is now presssing him.^ he would further represent that in bothe cases he attended at an an election precinct and sold some whisky, at the same time was not apprised of a violation of law -- supposing an election was a free day in such business=he further states that he is and always have been a law abiding citizen. That he served a term in the armey of the united States in the war of 1861, and whilst in the service was wounded. and that he is now a pensioner of the united States at $96 per annum. he further states that he is a cripple and unable to labor, and has a family ^with Eight children^ dependent upon him for support and the pittance he is drawing is almost insufficient for there support and if he is compeled to pay the two fines; him and his Family is bound to suffer. and is a verry poor man, he therefore humbly asks Your Excellency to interpose and remit the fine. and as in duty bound will ever pray &amp;c -- </p>
<p>Simpson ^his X mark^ Adams<pb/></p>
<p>The foregoing petition was sworn to and subscribed before me by Simpson Adams by making his mark the <date when="1865-09-26">26<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of Sept 1865</date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">A, Smith</hi> C R C C</p>
<p>we the undersigned Citizens of Rockcastle county would respectfully <hi rend="str">ask</hi> state that the two fines against the petitiner: Simpson Adams. deserves the interposition of Your Excellency and think it Just and right the two fines should be remitted.</p>
<p>G W Roberts
<lb/>James G Carter
<lb/>B K Betherum J R C C
<lb/>J D Cook S, R, C</p>
<p>I Think Justice demands these two fines should be remitted and hope your Excellency will interpose in the matter. C. P. F. is now pressing him &amp; will be out in a few days</p>
<p>Verry Respectfully
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Alfred Smith C R C C</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Rockcastle Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Simpson Adams
<lb/>2 judgts $20. each
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-09-28">28 Sept/65</date>.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
