<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1939"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Perry McNeely to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11407</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Bradley Strait</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG23-381 to MG23-382</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Petersburg, Boone County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-05-22">22 May 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Peterburg Boone County Ky <date when="1862-05-22">May 22d 1862</date>
<lb/>Hon- Beriah M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">a</hi></hi>Goffin
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>I Received your note, Informing me of the Receipt <hi rend="str">of</hi> of my Letter With the Petition Accompannying the Same. I Spoke to Mr- George. W. Terrill (as he was travelling in the portion of the County where the Ballance of the Jury Resided, who tried James Sebree) To Request Mr- Patmore, Mr- Stephenson, and Gaines to Sign a certificate for the Release of James Sebree Mr Terrill Spoke to Patmore &amp; Stephenson who Gave Terrill the Enclosed certificates. Mr Terrill did not see Mr-Gaines in his travels but Believes Gaines would Sign The Petition on Sight, but I cannot git to this house Short of fifty miles of a Ride, (hors Back as there is no other way to git to this house). Now I have Procured all of the Jury that is in the County, Exept Mr<hi rend="underline">-</hi> Gaines and have not seen him as above Stated. Mr<hi rend="underline">-</hi> M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Manama is in Henderson County in this State, (so I am toled). Mr- Vest has left the County, I do not Know Where he is. So you will Purceive that we have nine of the Jury Signed to the Petition, with the two certificates, and also the Judges name attached, and I Suppose the Prossecuting Attorney (Mr- P U. Major) has Signed it before this, But if he has not Signed it, the Petition is verry Strong, and I Suppose Satisfactory to you, So that you will have no hesitation in Granting Sebrees Pardon. I Enclose you the above two <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>Certificates, With a List of the whole Jury who tried Sebree, which, I Procured from our circuit<pb/>
<lb/>Clirk. (Milton Hamilton.) In <hi rend="str">C<unclear/></hi> Conclusion, I would be verry Mutch Obliged if you Could Spare time, and drop me a note on Sebree; Release and Let me Know if my friend ^<unclear/> Mayor^ has Singed the Petition. Please tell Sebree to Call at my house at fiirst arival in this place, as I want to Start him out of the County as Soon as he Can Bundle up his little affects and go, with his Wife.
<lb/> 
<lb/>Yours Respectfully
<lb/>Perry M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Neely</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
