<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2103"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James H. Berry, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9179</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-155 to MG24-156</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mason County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-08-13">13 August 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>I James H Berry Clerk of the Mason Circuit Court do hereby certify that the following named persons sat as a jury upon the trial of William Calvin who was fined at the last <date when="1862-07">July Term 1862</date> term Benedict Kirk Peter L Parker Ha M Boyd F W Long W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> H. Pollett Peter S Anderson John Rockey Charles Anderson <unclear/> S Walker Alexander F Power Robert F Means and Thomas Suit, none of whose names are signed to the foregoing petition.</p>
<p><date when="1862-08-13">August 13 1862</date></p>
<p>James H Berry Clk M Ct ct<pb/></p>
<p>Mason County Ky</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Colvin states that he has just been fined $50 for carrying concealed a pistol by a jury of Mason County He states that this pistol he borrowed of M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Ralls at Maysville a few days before the witness saw him with it, for the purpose of defending himself against Allen Brownfield a desperate man who had threatened to shoot him before 10' o'clk next day He states that W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Masterson told him that Brownfield has made such a threat against him, &amp; this affiant believe it &amp; obtained the pistol for the sole purpose of defending himself against Brownfield The Indictment was found <date when="1859-10">Oct<hi rend="sup">o</hi> Term 1859,</date> &amp; affiant was down the <unclear/> for several terms afterwards working at his trade &amp; knew nothing about it till he got back At that time both Ralls &amp; Masterson were gone away Masterson joined the U S Army &amp; Ralls went off to Florida, as he affiant learned &amp; he could not get them to Court These facts he swore to this day &amp; moved the Court for a Continuance, but the Court said they might never come back, and affiant must try &amp; appeal to the Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> to remit the fine He had therefore to try without his witnesses He swears these facts are true</p>
<p>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Colvin</p>
<p>To His Excellency Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Magoffin</p>
<p>We the Jury, who found the verdict against M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Colvin, respectfully petition the Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> to remit M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Colvins fine We heard him swear<pb/>
<lb/>to the foregoing facts &amp; believe him He is a poor young laboring man, &amp; the fine will fall heavily upon him, for doing perhaps only a lawful act.</p>
<p><date when="1862-07-29">July 29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1962.</date></p>
<p>Peter S Anderson
<lb/>John B Ky
<lb/>L Anderson
<lb/>P L. Parker
<lb/>L. S. Water
<lb/>W H Powell
<lb/><unclear/> Layer
<lb/>R F Means
<lb/>A T <hi rend="underline">Power</hi></p>
<p>We concur in the above petition most heartily</p>
<p>W. H. Watsworth
<lb/>Emery Whitaker
<lb/>Will P. Coons
<lb/>Jno R. Clarke
<lb/>F H Bierbower
<lb/>F B Trussell.<pb/></p>
<p>
<lb/>Mason Cir Ct
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Remitted</hi>
<lb/>JFR.
<lb/>Issued <date when="1862-08-20">August 20 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
