<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2275"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John M. Clayton et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6912</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-120</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Exellency Thomas E Bramlett Governer of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioners citizens of Lawrence County would represent to your Exellency that on the <date when="1865-07-12">12" day of July 1865</date> before his Hon Jno M Clayton Judge of the Lowrence Quorterly Court Washington Word was upon plea of "Guilty" fined Sixty dollars for the offense of keeping a <hi rend="underline">tipling</hi> <hi rend="underline">house</hi>.</p>
<p>Your petitioners would further represent that this is the first conviction against said Word for such an offense that a military camp has been for a long period kept at the place when the offense was charged to have been Committed, and that tipling and such like offenses have been to a very great extent countenanced by the officers of Said camp, that such irregularities have now ceased and the regular process of law enforced, and apprehensions of further disorder have been dissipated. Your petitioners would respectfully <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>ask that the said fine of Sixty dollars against the said Washington Word, be remitted except for so much as Thirty percent thereof</p>
<p>And as in duty bound your petitioners will every pray &amp;c</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Petitioners Names
<lb/>Jno M Clayton Judge S L C C
<lb/>Martin H Johns
<lb/>George. W. Kirk
<lb/>William Indicott
<lb/>Henderson Bernheim
<lb/><unclear/> Salmans
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>Jasper Williamson
<lb/>Julius <unclear/>
<lb/>Levi Muncy
<lb/>J. Spaulding
<lb/>J K Allison S L C
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Petitioners Names
<lb/>William P. Johnson
<lb/>John T. Travis
<lb/>John. T. Stafford
<lb/>John D. <unclear/>
<lb/>Edward Dixon
<lb/>William Carel
<lb/>Benjamin S. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Whorter
<lb/>William F minix
<lb/>John W Kines
<lb/>amos Wilkerson
<lb/>B Fitzpatrick
<lb/>Bennet Cox<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>The facts set forth in the foregoing Petition are substantially true I would further add that Washington Word is a soldier in the U. S. Service and the opinion has prevailed among soldiers that they were not liable to be fined for selling Ardent Under all the circumstances I respectfully recommend that the fine be remitted</p>
<p>R F Prichard
<lb/>County Attony
<lb/>J. H Allison S L C
<lb/>Jas <unclear/></p>
<p>R. L Vinson</p>
<p>Petition of Citizens of Lawrence County
<lb/>To Release $60 fine
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Washington Word
<lb/>for <hi rend="underline">Keeping</hi> <hi rend="underline">a</hi> <hi rend="underline">Tipling</hi> <hi rend="underline">house</hi>
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-08-19">19 Aug/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
