<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0561"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George C. Drane and John L. Scott, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9013</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-391 to R4-392</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Henry County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>In the case of the Commonwealth against Edward Hayden for Stukey Ransdale. Hayden not appearing The testimony in substance was that Hayden &amp; Ransdale were both old men. near neighbors. members of the same church and on friendly terms &amp; had been so for years. That they were walking home together from church on Sunday &amp; were in friendly conversation when Hayden asked Ransdale if he did not think it a sin to own slaves. Ransdale replyed that he did not when Hayden became furiously mad &amp; struck Ransdale when they fought. Neither being much injured. Hayden introduced no no testimony &amp; did not attend the trial. Hayden was find one Hundred &amp; fifty Dollars &amp; costs for which Execution issued &amp; is now in the sheriffs hands This judgment was rendered at the <date when="1862-09">Septr term of the Hrny Circut Court 1862</date>. -- </p>
<p>Geo. C. Drane
<lb/>Ct Judge.
<lb/>John L. Scott
<lb/>Com. atty.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
