<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2777"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William J. Owens to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7414</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-40</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency, Governor Bramlette,</p>
<p>Your Petitioner W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> J. Owens, would respectfully request the remission of the enclosed judgment of Commonwealth vs him, for Dealing Faro -- The facts are simply these Genl Brisbin sent an officer with a <unclear/> guard into a room where your petitioner and others were, Seized over three thousand Dollars the private money of George Ashlock &amp; over five Hundred belonging chiefly to petitioner, without rightful authority. In order to recover the money thus illegally and unjustly seized this Petitioner caused an <hi rend="str">I</hi> indictment, to be returned against himself &amp; confessed judgment upon the Same -- He does not think that he ought to pay said judgment &amp; appeals to you to relieve him from his trouble. The room in which the money was seized was not the room of the petitioner. He merely happened there that moment. You having heard of the facts heretofore and having assisted George Ashlock Esq. in recovering his own money, your petitioner <unclear/> the hope that you will promptly relieve him from his trouble</p>
<p>Wm. J Owens</p>
<p><note place="left margin">The statements of this Petition so far as my information extends are true, and that information was derived from Brisbin himself The facts were presented to the Grand Jury in some way, They directed an indictment upon which a Judgt was obtained
<lb/>W L. Downey</note><pb/></p>
<p>Fayette Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> J Owens
<lb/>$500,
<lb/>Faro
<lb/><hi rend="str">Gaming</hi> Remitted <date when="1865-12-21">21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Dec/65</date>
<lb/>Remit</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
