<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0430"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William &amp; Holloway and William M. Stone to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8882</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-189 to R4-190</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Madison County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-07-21">21 July 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To the Hon James. F. Robinson
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky,</p>
<p>Your petitioners W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Holloway &amp; Richard G. Burton ^W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> M Stone^ respectfully state, That they are and have long been merchants residing in the town of Richmond Ky. In the month of <date when="1862-01">January 1862</date> they established a branch of their store at London Ky. They expected to get a suitable house in which to transact business but were disappointed in getting said house after the arrival of their goods at London, and were compelled to open their stock in a very indifferent room. They offered enormous prices for a house, but could not rent one. They proposed to buy a house, but failed. They were therefore compelled either to continue business in the rooms they had or to go elsewhere. After remaining in London near three months they found they could rent a good house in Barbourville Ky. And finding they could not do business in the room they had in London, they removed the London branch of their house to Barbourville Ky -- And at the first term of the Circuit Court of Laurel County thereafter, they were<pb/>
<lb/>upon the exparte testimony of certain malicious persons <hi rend="underline">indicted</hi> for Peddling without license, They state that they did not design to evade any law, but had they been able to get a house, should have established a branch of their store at London permanently. This Indictment has never been tried, They pray your excellency to grant them a pardon of said offense and a dismissal of said procedure, &amp; they will ever pray -- </p>
<p>Holloway &amp; Burton
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> M Stone</p>
<p>Sworn to before me a Judge of the Madison County Court by R. G. Burton this <date when="1863-07-21">21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> July 1863</date>.</p>
<p>J W Bournee P J M C C</p>
<p>The undersigned citisens of Madison County concur in the prayer of the foregoing petition. Messrs H.&amp; B are gentlemen with the highesst character for integrity and respectability in our midst, and we<pb/>
<lb/>are satisfied they acted in good faith as stated in their petition.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">C. F. Burnam</hi>
<lb/>W M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clanahan
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> J. Gordon
<lb/><hi rend="underline">David Irvine</hi>
<lb/>W M Irvine
<lb/>W. W. Embry
<lb/>E S Shackelford
<lb/>Will.<unclear/>. Walker
<lb/>J. W. Crooke
<lb/>R. Russell
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J. W. Caperton</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Richd. White</hi>
<lb/>E B Jurman
<lb/>Thomps. Burnam Jr
<lb/>James H. Embry
<lb/>C. J. Walker
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J. D. Smith</hi>
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> L. Neale
<lb/>Willard Davis
<lb/>Collector 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Dis. Ky.
<lb/>G. E Billingsley
<lb/>R H Johnson W. S. Apr.
<lb/>J. W. Gilbert
<lb/>P. P. Ballard
<lb/>J W Bowman
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J M Shackelford</hi><pb/></p>
<p>I think the pardoning power was never given ^but^ with the intent that cases should be rested from trial by the Constituted judicial tribunals. But upon <unclear/> of justice of his trial that those might be an ultimate result. I think it against the policy and intention of the Constitution to interfere before trial</p>
<p><date when="1863-06-22">June 22 1863</date>
<lb/>J F Robinson</p>
<p>Laurel</p>
<p>Laurel Cir. Ct.
<lb/>Indictment for Pedling
<lb/>Holloway &amp; Burton</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
