<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2994"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Nelson Stephens to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7631</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR43-91 to BR43-92</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To the Governor of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>The undersigned would respectfully show that he became surety for John D Snowden, in bail bond for the appearanc of the latter in the circuit court of Clark county Which bond was forfeited at the last may term of said court &amp; summons has been served on yr petitioner a short time since</p>
<p>The bond was executed in <date when="1864">1864</date>, and at the time at which Snowden should have appeared the undersigned gave Snowden money to pay his expenses to Winchester -- so that he might enter in his appearance</p>
<p>Snowden left Danville where <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> he was engaged at work for the undersigned with the view &amp; under the promise to enter his appearance according to his bond.</p>
<p>After an absence of ten days or two weeks Snowden returned to the employment of the undersigned assuring that he had attended to the matter &amp; had entered his appearance &amp; all was right -- The undersigned knew no better until sum<pb/>
<lb/>mons. but fully confided in the statement of Snowden -- After remaining some time in Danville Snowden left &amp; the undersigned does not know where he is -- </p>
<p>If the undersigned had known the falsity of Snowdens statements -- he would have had him arrested But I had implicit confidence in his statements -- as he had been recommended to me as a strictly honorable &amp; pious member of the church.</p>
<p>The undersigned is in limited circumstances &amp; beginning a new business -- carding and weaving, and all his little means are necessary to succeed -- If he should have the amount of the bail bond is $500 ^to pay^ it would result in great disaster to him &amp; a large family dependent on his exertions He respectfully prays for a remission of the said bond</p>
<p>Nelson Stephens</p>
<p>Sworn to before me
<lb/>J P Mitchell P J B C</p>
<p>The undersigned Know M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Stephens &amp; believe him to be a truthful and reliable man -- &amp; concur in his petition</p>
<p>Joshua F Bell<pb/>
<lb/>J. P Mitchell
<lb/>Fon. T. Fox
<lb/>M T Chrisman
<lb/>M J, Durham
<lb/>Jon<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">a</hi></hi>. B. Nichols<pb/></p>
<p>Clark Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Nelson Stephens</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
