<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3100"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">A. M. Ferguson and W. B. Galloway to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5219</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-258 to BR41-259</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To Thos. E. Bramlette
<lb/>Govr of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned most respectfully represents that heretofore on the <date when="1864-09-26">26 day of Sept 1864</date> Thereupon a recognizance became the surety of George a man of Color then the property of Thomas Blackburn for the appearance of said George at the next term of the Scott Circuit Court to answer &amp;c an indictment therein against him for Felony a Copy of said Recognizance is herewith exhibited- That immediately after said George was Released upon the bail afs<hi rend="sup">d</hi> he volunteered and enlisted in the service of the United States Army for three years and whilst so under service failed to appear according to the condition of his bond and the same was declared and adjudged forfeited and judgement rendered therein against your Petitioners copies of which orders of forfeiture and judgement are here exhibited -- That the said George served out his term has been regularly discharged and returned home and since his return upon a Bench warrant issued upon the indictment afs<hi rend="sup">d</hi> from the Scott Circuit Court has been arrested and is now in custody of said Court in the jail of Scott County- Your Petitioners are informed that the<pb/>
<lb/>proof will render it very doubtful whether said George was ever guilty of the charge alledged against him</p>
<p>And inasmuch as said George incurred the forfeiture of his bond afs<hi rend="sup">d</hi> by his absence in the Service of his country and is now in Custody to answer said charge the Commonwealth has not been injured but benefitted it seems but reasonable and just that said forfeiture and judgement should not be enforced against your Petitioners therefore they pray,, that the same be remitted</p>
<p>A. M. Ferguson
<lb/>W B Galloway<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned Citizens of Scott County believe the statements of the foregoing Petition to be substantially true. The patriotic Justice requires Executive interference and earnestly unite in the prayer of the Petition</p>
<p>J. F. Robinson
<lb/>A, M, Brady
<lb/>S. F Gaut
<lb/>H. Rankins
<lb/>G. W. Riley
<lb/>E H Parrish
<lb/>Saml. W, Long
<lb/>J. T. Pratt
<lb/>Q. S. Sinclair</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
