<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3393"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. W. Haws et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5512</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-265</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thomas E Bramlett Govenor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned petitioners would respectfully represent that on the <date when="1864-05-03">3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> day of May <gap/> 1864</date> a judgment was rendered against J P Israel and Nathan Adams before Samuel Short Eqr. then Judge of the County Court of Lawrence County for Sixty <gap/> dollars Each that at the time of its rendition Smiley Stewart went there Security in a bond for the payment of the same and at that time he could have indemnified himself out of the property of the parties but Govenor Magoffin respited the fine for one year and before that year had elapsed the property of the principals had been wasted or removed from the State and one of the parties had also left the Judgment was left to sleep untill lately and now the Security will be compelled to pay the whole amount and will not be able to get the Least indemnity as one of the parties has<pb/>
<lb/>left the county the other is in the United States army and there is no property with which he can be indemnified the security is a poor man in straightened circumstances and if compell to pay this judgment it will be ruinious to him in tender consideration of the premises we pray your excellency to remit the fine</p>
<p>J. W. Haws P. L. C. C
<lb/>John N Allison S S C
<lb/>Henry Meek Dep L. L. C.
<lb/>Thomas Wallace.
<lb/>S Short</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
