<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0198"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas J. Throop to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9666</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-147 to MG17-148</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Maysville, Mason County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-11-28">28 November 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Maysville
<lb/><date when="1860-11-28">Nov 28<hi rend="sup">t</hi> 1860</date>,
<lb/>Dear Governor,</p>
<p>I sent you a petition to remit a fine of $50 -- imposed at <date when="1860-10">oct Term</date> by court upon a poor devil named W. H. Ingram, Jr. carrying concealed a deadly weapon, &amp; when I was in Frankfort, Mr Tate told me he thought the fine had been remitted by you, but if it has, the remittision has never been received, The fine has been replevied by his wife, that is, it will have to be paid by her, as she only has a hundred &amp; ten dollars, left of all her estate, &amp; her husband is wholly insolvent<pb/>
<lb/>The poor fellow is trying to quit drink, the source of all his misfortunes, and it would be a meritorious act on your part to remit this fine. so as to encourage his reformation, &amp; to enable him to get bread for his children,</p>
<p>Your letter on the state of public affairs, receives almost universal commendation, &amp; it is viewed as eminently patriotic, sacred &amp; conservative by all parties, Your positions are undoubtedly correct, &amp; if our union as states is preserved, the movement must come from the north, They must abolish all these nullifying laws, carry out the provisions of the constitution, as to the comity between the states, carry out the provisions of the<pb/>
<lb/>fugitive slave act, respect their so called personal liberty bills, allow the free transit of persons from the south with their families, &amp; property through their territories; acknowledge by their acts, not words onely, that we as states have an equality of rights, with them: unless this is done, our union is a farce, it is <hi rend="underline">effete</hi>, a humbug &amp; a cheat,</p>
<p>You ^have^ taken broad, reactional ground as to these questions, &amp; the people will sustain you -- </p>
<p>In the midst of all these troubles which now distract the country, and under the press of cares of your official business, have you fixed any time to review your former opinion in regard to this poor fellow, Brookover -- <pb/>
<lb/>I wish you could find it in your heart, to pardon him; you would do no one any wrong, the interests of the commonwealth &amp; of society would not suffer you would do a personal favor to some of your best friends and bring happiness &amp; peace to a miserable &amp; divided family -- What say you to it? Pardon my importunity for I think I am right, &amp; I would not, if I could, persuade you to do, what I believe to be wrong -- Let me hear from you, fully, about all these matters at your first leisure</p>
<p>Most truly yours
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Tho</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> J. Throop</hi></p>
<p><note place="left margin">Refer to Sec state</note></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
