<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-024-0130"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Cowan to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG12180</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Mitchell A Krock</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>1st - 20th Regiments Kentucky Infantry Primary Source Documents</collection>
      <idno>Box 8, Folder 19th Ky. Inf. - Misc</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lexington, Fayette County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-10-29">29 October 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">X</note>
<lb/>Lexington Ky
<lb/><date when="1862-10-29">Oct 29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>Gov Jas. F. Robinson
<lb/>D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Sir</p>
<p>The Col of our the 19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Regt. having been assigned the command of the 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Brigade 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Div. Army of Ky under Gen A J. Smith. it devolves upon me (its Lt Col) to address you. Suggesting some important wants of the regiment as I conceive them -- </p>
<p>Four of our companies are armed with the Springfield &amp; Enfield Rifles. which are of the same calibre &amp; a good gun -- The remaining Six are armed with Belgian muskets. which are of a different calibre from the rifles. This produces great inconvenience in the regiment &amp; the having ammunition of different calibres in an engagement might result in great confusion and serious &amp; inrepairable disaster<pb/>
<lb/>Besides the <unclear>injury</unclear> from having different calibres the Belgian Musket is an exceedingly inferior weapon. is very heavy &amp; clumsy &amp; with its ammunition makes too great a burden upon the march &amp; won't of all from the inferior construction of its Tube misses fire <hi rend="underline">very</hi> <hi rend="underline">often</hi>.</p>
<p>I feel that it is almost indespensable to the efficiency of our regiment that its remaining Six col should be armed with Springfield on Enfield rifles.</p>
<p>They have been promised us time &amp; again until we almost feel discouraged at the prospect of getting them &amp; we make this the first appeal to our state authorities for assistance in procuring them. with a feeling that you will do all in your power for us -- </p>
<p>We were hurried off mainly a year ago into the service with muskets gathered in from home guards &amp; have managed to gather up the rifles for 4 <unclear/> We need to complete the<pb/>
<lb/>matter <unclear/> Springfield on Enfield rifles. I made appreciative &amp; engaging at the ordinances office at Cin as we came through <unclear/> poor encouragement &amp; without the interposition of some of our state authorities I think we will not receive them until the new Free State regts are first Supplied with them to drill &amp; stand guard with -- </p>
<p>Ours is the most indifferently armed regt I have ever seen -- </p>
<p>Another matter I conceive to be of high importance to the usefulnesss of our regt is that it should be thrown into a field of service sufficienctly remote from the homes of our men to prevent that restlessness to get home &amp; consequent dissatisfaction in camp &amp; frequent desertion which in such situations always render a regt. a source of great trouble &amp; of discredit to its state. We had a great deal of this sort of trouble for 3 or 4 months<pb/>
<lb/>&amp; I am exceedingly anxious to avoid it in the future.</p>
<p>These two matters I feel are <hi rend="underline">very</hi> <hi rend="underline">worthy</hi> of the attention &amp; interposition of our State authorities. Our regt comes from the counties of Mercer. Washington. Boyle Garrard. Lincoln. Pulaski. Perry &amp; Letcher &amp; to avoid the trouble I speak of I would suggest<hi rend="str">ion</hi> sending it on the Nashville. on Miss route -- I am aware you have no control in the latter matter but your suggestions to the proper persons might be of great service= We have been cut down in our allowance of tents. one bell tent being isssued to 18 men. (which (should they all be in camp) it is simply a cruelty &amp; outrage to require them to occupy --  -- The act of Congress gives over such tent to 15 men &amp; then they are crowded -- </p>
<p>We have about 800 men &amp; 48 tents were isssued to them. but on account of inequality in the size of our companies, there will<pb/>
<lb/>be in some cos. a fraction of men over 18. when they are all in without a tent -- the tents having been isssued dividing the whole no of men by 18 -- instead of calculating the wants of each company. To meet the probably wants of our regt. we ought to have <hi rend="str">about</hi>at least 15 more tents -- Gen Finnell promised us we should have 22. Mon -- No tin cups plates knives or spoons were isssued to our men. They had to destroy nearly every thing in leaving the gap -- About 500. of each of the above articles would supply our wants -- </p>
<p>Them with two coppee mills to each company when first equipped by the State -- If they could be supplied again. they would be of great service to our men. They are generally quite poor men &amp; the State could well afford them small matters to them -- <pb/>
<lb/>There is nearly Six months pay due us &amp; this should be attended to very speedily -- I know many of our regts have wives &amp; children at home almost destitute -- </p>
<p>I hope you will pardon me for setting out such an array of wants -- &amp; proposing so much trouble to you. but I feel I owe it to the men &amp; that they need badly what I have started -- &amp; that we may expect more assistance &amp; sympathy from our own state than elsewhere -- </p>
<p>If you have the time to reply &amp; say what you think can be done for us. I will feel greatly obliged to you.</p>
<p>In Very Resply &amp;c
<lb/>John. Cowan</p>
<p>We were not furnished flies for any of our 30 Wall Tents -- &amp; would like very much to <unclear>ban them</unclear><pb/></p>
<p><date when="--10-30">30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Oct</date> -- We are past starting to Camp Dick Robinson Please write me there<pb/></p>
<p><note place="header">19</note>
<lb/><hi rend="str">Lt Col A. J. Cowan<figure type="hr"/></hi>
<lb/>Lexington Ky
<lb/><date when="1862-10-29">Oct 29/62</date><figure type="hr"/><hi rend="underline">
<lb/></hi>Cowan John
<lb/>Lt. Col. 19<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Infty (Ky.)<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Regt<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> affairs.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
