<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0187"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">F. G. Anthony to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8639</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-282 to R3-283</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Fayette County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-01-06">6 January 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>James F Robinson Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner F G Anthony states that at the <date when="1862-08">August Term of the Fayette Circuit Court 1862</date> -- Judgement was rendered against him for the sum of Six Hundred Dollars. the Judgement was ordered on the forfeiture of Two Bonds one of Five Hundred Dollars the other One Hundred Dollars Executed to the Commonwealth of Ky by Jno B Watts of Fayette Co and your petitioner as Surety -- The complaint of the State against said Jno B Watts was for Persons going into his stable &amp; playing cards, which was an every day occurrence in this place in peoples stables They could get into Jno B Watts went south on legitimate business previous to the breaking out of the Rebellion -- (The Bonds were given early in the winter of <date when="1861">1861</date>.) And the civil law has been so paralized by the Military law it has been impossible to exercise justice in civil cases.. And he prays that you will remit the amount due to the Commonwealth as he is not able to stand the loss and begs your Executive clemency in the case.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">F G Anthony</hi>.</p>
<p>We the undersigned are Union men &amp; know that what your petitioner has stated to be so, and further pray that you release him of as much of the above amount as lays in your power -- </p>
<p>Fayette Co Ky. <date when="1863-01-06">January 6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1863</date>.
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>S S Grimes
<lb/>Garrett Watts
<lb/>Geo. T. Fishback
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi> S Bodley
<lb/>Sheriff Fayett Co.
<lb/>Jno B Norton C F C C
<lb/>Thos D Carr D S of F C</p>
<p>I fully concur in the prayer of the foregoing</p>
<p>W. L. Downing
<lb/>Co'm atty<pb/></p>
<p>Fayette Cir Ct
<lb/>$600 } Recog
<lb/>F. G. Anthony
<lb/>Iss <date when="1863-02-18">Feby 18. 1863</date></p>
<p>Fine remitted in this case
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J F Robinson</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
