<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0554"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Cocke et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10022</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-360 to MG18-361</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Commonwealth of Ky.
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Christian Shroeder </p>
<p>The undersigned, members of the petit Jury who tried and rendered the verdict in the above case as follows "we of the Jury find the defendant guilty in the within indictment and say he shall be confined in the Jail and Penetentiary House of this commonwealth for the term of two years, and recommend him to Executive clemency." beg leave further to say -- The indictment was for uttering a forged check in the name of Bills &amp; Co on Quigley Lyons &amp; Co. The defendant pleaded guilty to the charge of presenting the check and receiving the money thereon. He accompanied his plea of guilty with the statement that the check was placed in his hands with a request to present it for payment, by a man by the name of Hudson who was the general agent of Bills &amp; Co and their clerk. He knew but little of Hudson -- after presenting the check &amp; receiving the money he handed over the money to Hudson and asked and received no part of the same. Hudson immediately absconded and has not since been heared from.</p>
<p>The Jury does not doubt, and in that opinion M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Bills fully concurs, that Hudson in fact committed the forgery and received the money. He, no doubt imposed upon the defendant and<pb/>
<lb/>procured his services, and has left him to bear the consequences of the act. The Jury felt constrained to find the verdict notwithstanding their beleif in the facts aforesaid, but they believe that it is a strong case for the exercise of Executive pardon. The defendant is a youth of prepossessing manners and appearance and evidently of fair capacity. The manner and facts of his statements made a strong impression upon the Jury favorable to the accused.</p>
<p>We earnestly entreat the Executive to extend to him a pardon. He ought not in our judgment to be sentenced to the Penetentiary.</p>
<p>Respectfully.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Thos Cocke</hi>
<lb/>M G Lowry
<lb/>J. M. Shindler
<lb/>J. J. Gilmore
<lb/>C. A. Sale
<lb/>J. M. Wills
<lb/>Jas. H Grove
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> J Cornell
<lb/>A P Oldham
<lb/>Isaac Ryans
<lb/>Geo. Daugherty
<lb/>Hiram M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Gehee</p>
<p>The undersigned officers of the Jefferson Circuit Court, having heard the trial of the case of the case of Commonwealth vs Shroder above mentioned heartily<pb/>
<lb/>concur in the petition for a pardon for the unfortunate accused.</p>
<p>E. S. Craig Com Atty
<lb/>J. W. Davis Shff
<lb/>Lee Chambers D Clk</p>
<p>Under all the circumstances a pardon would be best for the com<hi rend="sup">th</hi> &amp; the accused. P B Muir<pb/></p>
<p>Jefferson Cir. Ct
<lb/>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Christian Shroeder.
<lb/>Felony
<lb/>Petition to the Governor of Ky.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>$ Penty 2 years
<lb/>Pardon Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi>
<lb/><date when="1861-01-19">Jany 19. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
