<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2836"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. H. Harrison et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7473</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-125 to BR17-126A</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thos: E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioners respectfully represent unto your Excellency that Archibald Alexander, a young man about nineteen years of age was recruited into and joined what he believed a portion of the late rebel army at that time (in the month of <date when="1863-08">Aug 1863</date>) situated in the county of Trimble and state of Kentucky, and that after he was so enlisted and sworn into the regular service of the south, in obedience to the command of those controlling the squad with which he was associated he went one night and aided in the robbery of the Branch Bank of the southern Bank of Kentucky at Carrollton, from which they took many thousand dollars -- that were divided among the men who took it in various sums. Your petitioners state that all who were engaged in the robbery, or nearly all have been indicted for the robbery in the Carroll Circuit court, where many of the indictments are now pending: Your petitioners state that they are entirely convinced <pb/>
<lb/>and verily believe that young Arch: Alexander when he robbed the Bank aforesaid beleived that he was in the performance of a military act and acted under the orders of his superior officers. They state the fact to be that so soon as he was informd of the character and nature of the act in which he had been engaged that he immediately, returned to the Bank officers every dollar that had fallen to his share, thereby designating the integrity of his purposes although he made good his escape into the Confederate lines and has never been under arrest by the civil or military authorities for or on account of said crime, Now in as much as we verily believe all these statements to be true, and have heard that the Bank itself does not desire the conviction and punishment of the said Alexander, and the conviction would be a wanton cruelty, and useless punishment of an otherwise estimable young man; we pray your Excellency to pardon the civil offense committed by him in the robbery of the Bank, and restore him to his aged parents who are poor and need his aid and protection in their<pb/>
<lb/>declining years -- (no indictment) has as yet been found against him for the above offense, yet fearing one is unwilling to return without a pardon his conviction therewith is well known by the Bank officers</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>W. H. Harrison
<lb/>M, D, Abbott
<lb/>George Abbott
<lb/>J, H, Gassom
<lb/>W. T. Humphrey
<lb/>Daniel B Johnson
<lb/>Barnett Johnson
<lb/>F Crafton
<lb/>James Crafton
<lb/>Elige Crafton
<lb/>W F Hall
<lb/>Greenup Nicholson
<lb/>Joseph Miller
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> W Callis
<lb/>H Mosely
<lb/>W H Mosely
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi>, Purgeron
<lb/>Andy, Brandon
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi>, Jessup
<lb/>V. S. Barriger
<lb/>John Edwards
<lb/>William Austin
<lb/>T. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>mahon
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names -- 
<lb/>M B Mosely
<lb/>B. P. Cornell
<lb/>W, H, Calvert
<lb/>Dabney Coleman
<lb/>R E Humphrey
<lb/>J. S. Stubbins
<lb/>T. B. Connell
<lb/>D. M. Shelton
<lb/>S W Fallis
<lb/>T H Brady
<lb/>W. M. Kegle
<lb/>James G. Ginn
<lb/>F. C. Fallis
<lb/>Robert, Gunn
<lb/>Jo W Cull
<lb/>D N Cull
<lb/>T Wood
<lb/>Will Wise
<lb/>J W Hunter
<lb/>L. Milner
<lb/>F Farley
<lb/>Robert Tollever
<lb/>H. T Coffin
<lb/>Madison Mosely
<lb/>Oliver C <unclear/><pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>T M M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Carty
<lb/>J. B. Pierce
<lb/>W. Phelps
<lb/>B B Button
<lb/>J H Lane
<lb/>D R Lane
<lb/>C. C. Holmes
<lb/>W P Adcock
<lb/>J S Greenwood
<lb/>W M Callis
<lb/>Mirron horton
<lb/>E M Garriott
<lb/>Geo W Pryor
<lb/>T W Yeager
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> O. Callis
<lb/>Jas, B, Cook
<lb/>F. E. Skidmore
<lb/><cb n="2"/><unclear/>. B. Hunt
<lb/>S Gatewood
<lb/>John W. Stewart
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> C. King
<lb/>S. D M<hi rend="sup">c</hi><unclear/>
<lb/>James H Cornell
<lb/>Thomas Jones
<lb/>D. J. Vawter
<lb/>J. E. Underwood
<lb/>Richard C Yeager
<lb/>Jas Chowning</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
