<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3103"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">M. Y. Tadisman et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5222</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-263</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Union County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. E. Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Union county Ky will represent to your Excellency that Mathew Spalding (of color) was fined fifty dollars by the Police Court of the town of Morganfield in said county for carrying concealed a deadly weapon. Said fine was imposed on the <date when="1865-08-27">27 day of August 1865</date>.</p>
<p>They respectfully recommend said boy and his case to the Executive clemency upon these grounds, towit Mathew whilst a Slave and since his liberation has always been a first rate character for honesty and good demeanor. He is and has been all the year faithfully at work trying to support himself and his family,- consisting of a wife and two small children.</p>
<p>He was in the U. S army and, like nearly all the negro soldiers, was induced to buy a pistol when discharged.</p>
<p>The subscribers are credibly informed that at<pb/>
<lb/>the time the offence was committed he has the pistol on his person with the sole view of selling it.</p>
<p>Upon these considerations the undersigned request and hope that Your Excellency will remit his fine.</p>
<p>M. Y. Tadisman
<lb/>Police Judge of Morganfield
<lb/>Ken Chasseze
<lb/>Dan Hughes
<lb/>D. C. James Clk <unclear/>
<lb/>J. H. Wall Clk Cty Co
<lb/>R. Street US Asst Assr
<lb/>J M. Waggoner D C U Co Ct
<lb/>H. W Waggoner <unclear/>
<lb/>J M Houckman
<lb/>J. W. Dupin
<lb/>M. R. Waller
<lb/>R. A. Wallard
<lb/>Geo Huston
<lb/>Comt Adair Co atty</p>
<p>Mathew formerly belonged to me. He was a first rate boy. Refused to leave me to join the army or for any purpose. He was forcibly carried off by negro soldiers, and when discharged came immediatly back to me; and is now in my employ doing exceedingly well.</p>
<p>J. A. Spalding</p>
<p>Police Judge
<lb/>Morganfield
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Mathew Spalding
<lb/>$50
<lb/>Concealed Weapons</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
