<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0541"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Banks and John McClure to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4660</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-354 to BR9-355</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thomas. E. Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioners William Banks &amp; John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clure would respectfully state, that they were Tried upon an Indictment for Larceny &amp; Receiving Stolen Property knowing it to be stolen. &amp; convicted by the Jury for three years. The conviction was had upon the receiving &amp; not upon the Larceny.</p>
<p>Your petitioners further state that they make no denial now, nor never did, that they received the property alledged in the indictment, but they do deny that they knew it was stolen, but upon the contrary they state that they purchased it honestly believing at the time that they did no wrong.</p>
<p>Your Excellency will be furnished with a substantial statement of the testimony properly certified, which statement may in some manner <hi rend="str">may</hi> go to show our guilt, but with the following honest explirations<pb/></p>
<p>We hope to convince your Excellency that no fellonious intention existed. In the first place M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Fink, lost two packages of Tobacco both packages weighing 37<hi rend="sup">lbs</hi> This Tobacco was bought by petitioner Banks of some Boys aged from 15 to 18, representing themselves as boys working at the Tobacco business. Said Tobacco was proven to have been sold originally at 85<hi rend="sup">cts</hi> per pound, but your petitioners sold it for 40<hi rend="sup">cts</hi> per pound, &amp; at the time of selling requested the purchaser not to mention anything about it.</p>
<p>The request of Secresey was not made for the reason that the Jury must have infered it was made, it was simply made because petitioners had no <hi rend="underline">Licens To Sell in the City Limits</hi>, &amp; were Liable to <hi rend="underline">fine</hi> for so doing.</p>
<p>Your Excellency will find from the proof that petitioners were members of the 64<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ohio Infantry, serving as privates at 13 dollars per month, &amp; have been in the service since the <date when="1861-10-10">10th of October 1861</date>, &amp; were located at Barracks no 1 in the city of Louisville.</p>
<p>Your Excellency will readily grant<pb/>
<lb/>that $13 per month would furnish but meager surport to any family however small, &amp; if your petitioners did resort to this trafic to make a better surport for their families, who on the broad earth can blame them, "He that does not provide for his own household, is worse than an Infidel." Your petitioners are only guilty of violating on ordinance for Selling without Licens. The marks upon the packages were not obliterated, but were plain &amp; had not been altered, &amp; were in the packages whole &amp; entire.</p>
<p>Your petitioners have served in the National army for nearly three years, a service willingly rendered, for they were fighting for their country. But how different the three years service now allotted them, constant hard labour during the day time, &amp; a little cell at night. no more to hear the ear piercing fife or spirit stiring drum, never again to hear the battle shout, &amp; see victory perch upon their countrys banner. Your petitioners must wash out the stain that this conviction<pb/>
<lb/>has placed upon them, &amp; that this oportunity may be furnished they pray your Excellency to grant them a pardon that they may reenlist for three years more &amp; that the time fixed for their service in the Penitentiary, may heartily be given to their country</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Banks
<lb/>John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Lure</p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John Banks
<lb/>&amp;
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> McClure
<lb/>Pardoned
<lb/><date when="1864-02-10">10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Feby 1864</date></p>
<p>Issue Pardon for Wm Banks &amp; John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clure.</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
