<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2897"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William A. Pollock et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7534</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-215 to BR17-216</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Stanford, Lincoln County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-15">15 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Stanford, Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1865-12-15">15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> December 1865</date>
<lb/>Governor T, E, Bramlett,
<lb/>My Dear Sir</p>
<p>About Twelve months Since a Young Man in his Eighteenth year from Texas and formerly a Confederate Soldier -- stole from my Lot in stanford a sorrel mare, saddle &amp; bridal, rode her about one mile and was met by one of my sons &amp; brothersinlaw who arrested him brought back the prisonr tried him before Court of Inquiry, by which he was sent to further trial, and at the <date when="--03">March</date> Term of our court, he was indicted by the Grand Jury for horse stealing the cause continued and the boy still remains in prison -- He is young and been well raised and is of good appearance and well Educated has been in confinement in our county Jail<pb/> 
<lb/>for about one year, is entirely destitute of clothes and is in miserable condition to pass the coming winter in our prison house of stone and iron; after considering the matter maturely, Looking at the Extreme Youth of the prisoner, his Long confinement in our County Jail which of itself has been a great punishment, to the fact that this is a time of almost universal pardon, at the miserable condition of this poor boy I have felt it my duty to ask your Excellecy to pardon said boy -- I feel that he has been sufficiently punished, that he may suffer greatly in prison this winter, that humanity, the youth and good appearance of said boy requires his pardon -- I feel confident that under the circumstances the enlightened public sentiment of the County will sustain you in granting the pardon I ask for said boy -- I therefore pray your Excellcy will speedily pardon said prisoner whose name is George<pb/>
<lb/>Adams -- Hoping to hear speedily from your Excellecy favourably I remaine</p>
<p>Your Obdent Servant
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> A. Pollock</p>
<p>Governor T, E, Bramlette
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>The undersigned Citizens of Stanford and viciinty Know the facts stated by our neighbor W A Pollock true we therefore concur in the pryer of his petition for the parden of George Adams</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>W. S. <unclear/>
<lb/>Saml H Shanks
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> H Shanks
<lb/>Ed. Davidson
<lb/>J, R, Alford
<lb/>W,, R,, Carson J P L C
<lb/>M. V. Smith
<lb/>W. R. Warren
<lb/>A. J. C. Robbins<pb/></p>
<p>Lincoln Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Geo Adams
<lb/>Indicted for Horse Stealing
<lb/>Pardoned
<lb/><date when="1866-02-10">10 Feby/66</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
