<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0856"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">E. P. Davis et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10324</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-345</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Carter County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Carter county Sct
<lb/>To his Excellency B Magoffin Governor</p>
<p>we the under signed petitioners would represent to your Excellency that James Jennings find by the Carter Circuit Court the sum of $20. for Illegal Gameing Now we think Mr Jennings case Kneeds Your clemency for these reasons that <hi rend="str">that</hi> the fine was for Shooting for a beef with others and declares that when the matter took place that he did not Know it was wrong to shoot for beef as it had been done so offten before but says she will not do so any more since <hi rend="str">it has</hi> he Knows that it is wrong or a violation <hi rend="str">to shoot for beef</hi> of the Law Now Mr Jennings is a poor man with a family to rase and Educate and he abandoned all such conduct and he is for ever done with such things; and that times are too hard for a poor man to raise money; and for such releif we shall ever pray</p>
<p>E P Davis
<lb/>George Nethercutt
<lb/>Allen Duncan
<lb/>Jas W Thompson
<lb/>B F Crawford
<lb/>J B Ward
<lb/>C N. Swis
<lb/>A F Goble
<lb/>B S Shepherd<pb/></p>
<p>Carter Cir Ct
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>$20. } Gaming
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. Jennings
<lb/>Iss <date when="1861-03-26">Mar 26. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
