<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2752"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">E. P. Campbell to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7389</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-441</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Eddyville, Lyon County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-15">15 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Eddyville Kentucky <date when="1865-12-15">December 15" 1865</date>
<lb/>Governor Bramlette
<lb/>Dr Sir</p>
<p>At the <date when="1865-11">November Term 1865</date> of the Caldwell Circuit Court a judgment was rendered in favor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky against A,, W,, M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Chesney for ($1500) as bail for W,, R,,. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Chesney indicted for <hi rend="underline">Murder</hi> and also a judgment rendered in favor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky against Alfred Beckner as bail for said W,, R,, M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Chesney ^for $300=^ indicted for <hi rend="underline">robbery</hi>,, the <hi rend="underline">answers</hi> of said A,, W,, M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Chesney and Beckner to Summons alledged that said W,, R,, M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Chesney was <hi rend="underline">conscripted</hi> by one Captain Webster into the <hi rend="underline">Rebel</hi> Army in Caldwell Co in <date when="1864-08">august 1864</date> and carried to <hi rend="underline">Alabama</hi> against his will and consent (<hi rend="underline">see</hi> <hi rend="underline">answer</hi>) A,, W,, M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Chesney and Alfred Beckner are good citizens and law abiding <hi rend="underline">men</hi> Beckner is a poor man and M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Chesney is a man in Moderate <hi rend="underline">circumstances</hi> and in the spring of <date when="1865">1865</date> was <hi rend="underline">robbed</hi> of about ($1500) by a band of <hi rend="underline">desperados</hi> at night at home and badly treated and abused by <hi rend="underline">them</hi> and I have no idea it was by their consent that W,, R,, M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Chesney failed to appear and answer said indictments against him If said parties are forced to pay the full amount of said judgments to the Commonwealth it will be oppressive on them and<pb/>
<lb/>and as said A,, W,, M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Chesney and Alfred are each of them moral men and good citizens and have <hi rend="underline">violated</hi> no law and are law abiding citizens,, I recommend to your excellency to examine into their applications and if consistent with the public good that you extend to them such executive clemency as their cases and circumstances seem to demand under all facts in their case</p>
<p>I am Verry Truly
<lb/>Your Obdt Servt
<lb/>E P,, Campbell
<lb/>atty for <hi rend="underline">Commonwealth</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
