<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2282"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">H. R. Powell to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9358</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG25-28</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency B Magoffin
<lb/>Govr Ky.</p>
<p>The undersigned H. R. Powell would respectfully represent that at the <date when="--02">last Feby Term</date> of the Franklin Circuit Court Judgment was given against Me in two cases for a Misdemeanor for $50 each &amp; Costs. No defence was Made. It is proper to state that I Keep a Restaurant &amp; Coffee House in Frankfort Ky for the accommodation of the Citizens &amp; transient persons and therefore it is Almost impossible for me to know all &amp; every person that are entertained at My House. The Judgments were obtained upon the evidence of two or three young gentlemen (Minors as it turns out) who were accommodated With Food &amp; Liquors. the Liquor being sent from the Bar to the eating room probably without Knowing who they were. It is expressly against My Order<hi rend="sup">s</hi> to permit youths to loiter about my house, And especially ever furnishing them with any liquor_ If I am guilty I am So unconsciously. and would respectfully<pb/>
<lb/>Ask your Excellency to remit such part of said fine as Justice in the premises Warrant</p>
<p>Resply
<lb/>H, R, Powell</p>
<p>Believing that Mr Powell Keeps an orderly House and at all times endeavors to do what is right. and especially in keeping the Youths of the City from his House We Would respectfully ask the Executive for its interferance on his behalf</p>
<p>Jno A Crittenden D. Sheriff
<lb/>L. Tobin
<lb/>John J Johnston
<lb/>T. W. C. Blackburn
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Ja</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> P. O'Hara</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">G. W. Triplett</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W. V. Williams</hi>
<lb/>W. P. Watson
<lb/>D, H, Johnson
<lb/>S. S. Ellis
<lb/>L. Lamm</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
