<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0077"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">G. C. Alfred to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14106</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1865</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Duncansville, Mercer County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-04-06">6 April 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Duncansville Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-04-06">April 6th 1865</date>
<lb/>Gov. Bramblet Esq<hi rend="sup">r</hi></p>
<p>I write a few lines to inform you what is going on in my neighborhood. a company of some 80 men pass down the road in the direction of Bloomfield on saturday <date when="1865-03-25">25th of march</date> It is said this Capt is by the name of Akin lives about Mundyville the commd about 6 miles from Harrodsburg to take Horses from the farm out of the plow and at my house I was not at home the went and took my Horse out of the plow and carried Him off<pb/>
<lb/>and the have not returd them they pass back about a week after leading several Horses some men has got their horses and other has not I am afraid that there business is more after horses than to rid the country of Gurillers. I write more on account of my neighbours than myself for since the war I have been robbed so often and lost so much that I have long since ceased to complain. I must say that if this man &amp; Bridgwater &amp; some other company are commissioned by the state and an independent company you will<pb/>
<lb/>Know what to do. Citizens should be protected from <unclear>such</unclear> my negohood has furnished more soldiers than any other in the war and soon <unclear>them</unclear> returned to their homes, to be treated in the way this indepdent company in acting is too bad and they say they will not stand if after serving three <unclear/> to have their neighbors &amp; friends so treated that had helped to sustain their family while they were in the army independent company will <unclear/> do no good unless you can <unclear/> proper men for such company for the purpose of good and to <unclear/><pb/>
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/> <unclear/> And in that way the peaceable citizens life is in danger from Some men that had stolen his property or wronged him in horses pass and that he had to appeal against us a witness and it is in this way things is going on I would say for god sake if in you power for we have had enough of Home Guard or independant company and Gurrillas to be at least satisfied that it will not do for we will never get clear of the Guerillas by such <unclear>men</unclear> -- please to keep this letter secret for if it was Know<pb/>
<lb/>that I had written to you and give information of what their company are doing. the would Kill me the first chance. if I had not been deprived of my Horses I would have come to Frankfort myself please read said letter and <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> and Keep my name secret as it would bring on me the vengence of those -- person that I have names and I have suffered enough already by them -- </p>
<p>Respectfully yours
<lb/>&amp;c G C Alfred<pb/></p>
<p>Duncansville Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-04-05">April 5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Alfred G. C.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>To the Gov.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>says Capt Aikins Co. passed down the road in direction of Bloomfield on saturday <date when="1865-03-25">25<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Mar.</date> taking horses, in many cases taking them out of plows -- can not a stop be put to such acts? -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>If Aikins has been behaving as
<lb/>L B N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 11 -- <date when="1865">1865</date> P 348<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Rec<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> A. G. O. Ky <date when="1865-04-06">6 April 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
