<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1065"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. M. Fulkerson et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10533</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-161 to MG20-162</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To the Governer of the Commonwealth of Kentucky. your petitioners would most respectfully represent, That Simpson Tredaway was fined in this term of the owsly circuit court. <date when="1861-05">(May term 1861)</date> the sum of $100 -- Dollars for betting on the Presidential election of <date when="1856">1856,</date> Buchananan &amp; Filmore, that no one in this region of country understood that betting on Porsidential election was a violation of law at all and they say that it was not so understood in Kentucky but that it was a new doctrine of law that has been adjudecated, and settled on since the election as above refered to we pray to this end, that the fine so far as the Governer can remit that it be done as we believe it just and right, that pretty generally <hi rend="str">your</hi> His Excellency has remitted all such fines that went up from this county, and well in duty bound we pray</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W M Fulkerson
<lb/>S, Isaacs J P
<lb/>J. M. Johnson
<lb/>D Bleakly
<lb/>U F Hensley
<lb/>W. Williams
<lb/>I H Gabbard
<lb/>A. B. Gilbert H M
<lb/>J C Minter
<lb/>Sam Hundley Juror
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John Farmer
<lb/>W, H, Glass
<lb/>A Carmack
<lb/>D. D. Spicy
<lb/>Jacob Gabbard
<lb/>H C Hargis
<lb/>Hiram M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Geer
<lb/>John C. Cote
<lb/>J. M. Beatty
<lb/>I F Blount<pb/>
<lb/>Jas. E, Gibson<pb/></p>
<p>Governor Magoffin</p>
<p>This young man was fined for Bitting on the Pres Election of <date when="1856">1856</date> he is a Clever Boy -- not a Gambler you certainly will Remit his fine</p>
<p>J, E Gibson</p>
<p>Booneville Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-05-28">May 28<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Dear Gov.</p>
<p>Mr. Treadaway was fined at this court $100. for betting on an Election, He was indited several years since, He purchased or sold a pr of <hi rend="str">Boots</hi> Boots worth $4.00 the people severally did not know that purchasing property was a violation of the act. a great number were find at the time and all were remitted -- His case stands in the same condition. I hope you will remit the fine</p>
<p>Your obet servt
<lb/>John Dishman<pb/></p>
<p><hi rend="str">L</hi> L. J. Peters C, o, C
<lb/>James Hampton
<lb/>Connelious Thomas
<lb/>T. Horton
<lb/>Aly Leaford
<lb/>John Peters
<lb/>John Mare</p>
<p>Boonville <date when="1861-05-28">May 28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> ^1861^</date>
<lb/>Gov Magoffin</p>
<p>I hope that you will remit this fine I believe that it aught to be remited yours respectfully</p>
<p>Granville Pearl</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1861-06-24">June 24</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
