<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1547"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">E. K. Seele to Nathaniel Wolfe</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11015</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-162</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-11-12">12 November 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville <date when="1861-11-12">Nov 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Dr Sir</p>
<p>I received your note to day and ^am^ very willing to state that I have not only examined Angelo Devoto, but that, I have been frequently called upon to prescribe for him since his confinement in Jail. His health is injured by confinement <unclear/> in Jail. he is suffering from disease of the chest and genenal Constitutional neuralgia, to recover from which release from confinement is necessay, and I do not think he would stand confinement in the Penitentiary, I also know that he has a family of small children, who are entirely destitute of the necessaries of life, and depend wholy upon charity for subsistance</p>
<p>E. K. Seele
<lb/>Physician Louisville Jail</p>
<p>To N. Wolf Esqr</p>
<p>P.S. I have known his for some Years and have never heard his character impeached before.</p>
<p>E K, Seele</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
