<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-027-0019"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John H. M. Brayer to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1252</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R2-30 to R2-31</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lawrenceburg, Anderson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-08-23">23 August 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Lawrenceburg Ky <date when="1862-08-23">August 23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>Gov Jas F. Robinson
<lb/>Dear Sir,</p>
<p>From the, favor, I have of your, right of "justice and Law," I am induced to write you -- Though a stranger to you, Dr Jas R. Chambers, a Brother in law to me was -- arrested by the military about 4 weeks since sent to Louisville Ky -- and, was parolled to Gallatin County Ky= I have heard the charges that are preferred against him are these 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> that he is a member of the Golden Circle a secret-Political organisation, 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> that he is a man of much influence. The 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Charge is untrue as he will make oath if allowed, and he is an honorable man, &amp; will not state a falshood -- 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> he is a man of much, influence professionally and may exert some Politically -- But still he is an Honoralble man -- and whose statements can be relied ^on^ for any thing he will state, I thinke he <hi rend="underline">ought</hi> to be allowed to return to his County &amp; persue th<hi rend="str">is</hi>e practice of medicine as his service<hi rend="sup">s</hi> are much needed, he is willing to give Bond that he will not in any way aid or assist the rebellion -- I will refer you to Adgt Gen Finell<pb/>
<lb/>of your City also Thos Lindzey -- I could get the names of nineteen twentieth of union men of this County -- &amp; Town to affirm all that I state in his behalf Justi<hi rend="str">s</hi>ce Humanity &amp;c<hi rend="str">o</hi> demands that he should be on a footing with other Freeman, He will satisfy you If you will extend his Parole to Frankfort-Ky. that he is a true Gentleman= and sir, this I ask at your hands, believing that ^you^ are the man, for the <hi rend="underline">times</hi> and (not for the place) -- </p>
<p>I rest satisfied without having to adduce proof of any thing personal= I am generally known in Frankfort-Ky -- </p>
<p>Yours Most Respect
<lb/>Jno H. M. Brayer,</p>
<p>To
<lb/>Gov. Robinson
<lb/>Frankfort Ky</p>
<p>P. S.
<lb/>Dr Chambers is a Brother to A. B. Chamber<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> -- who, you may be acquainted with,<pb/></p>
<p>J. H. M. Brayer
<lb/>Lawrenceburg
<lb/>about arrests</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
