<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2981"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Benjamin P. Cissell et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7618</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR43-71 to BR43-72</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thos. E. Bramlette</p>
<p>We, the undersigned Citizens of Livingston County, would respectfully represent, that one J J Baxter was indicted at the last term of this Court for detaining one Penelope Johnson, a white woman about Eighteen years of age against her will with intent to Carnally knew her and tried and Convicted &amp; senteneced to the Penetentiary for the term of two years, Miss Johnson is a Lady of good standing and entire respectality in the County, a woman of sense honor, virtue and integrity and the fullest Credit can be given to any and all statements made by her on or off oath, Besides she was fully Corroborated by all the evidence in the Cause This offense we believe to have been a deliberate &amp; premeditated attempt to rape by the accused and thus believing We protest and remonstrate against his pardon.</p>
<p>Ben. P. Cissell atty for Comtlth 14 District<pb/></p>
<p>J D Morisson
<lb/>H. B. Edwards
<lb/>James Pringle
<lb/>James M Donakey
<lb/>J. W. Clark
<lb/>J. H. Merry
<lb/>A. J. Donakey
<lb/>R. C. Loyd.
<lb/>J. L garman
<lb/>J. W. Bice
<lb/>G. W. Phillips
<lb/>T C Furnish
<lb/>C. C. D<unclear/>
<lb/>W G ^his X mark^ Scyster</p>
<p>Witness
<lb/>B. P. Cissell</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
