<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3365"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Joseph B. Hartley to Hunt and Beck</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5484</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-221 to BR42-222</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Messrs Hunt and Beck,
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Attornies at Law.</hi>
<lb/>Gentleman,</p>
<p>I am extremely thankful, to you, more so than words can express, for your great kindness to me, in attending to my case. I find impossible to give my bail, for reason, I have no outside friend to assist me, or see parties for me. I, recognise what will be the Jury's just award, but even that cannot alleviate the intense suffering of my mind, attendant upon my probable conviction. There is no choice left to me, but to proceed to Trial and plead "Guilty" and then Dare I venture - Gentleman, to pray you, to implore you, with an overfull heart - to present a Petition to His Excellency the Governor on my behalf. Surely, the fact of my six long months incarceration; the smallness of the sum; the credentials I am able to produce; and my pledge to leave the State, forever, would induce His Excellency to look favorably, at my case = the very<pb/>
<lb/>first charge I was ever under, and incline him to remove this stigma from me, and by a reprieve give me another opportunity for the furture.</p>
<p>A superfluity of words are unnecessary - you can understand all I would say - Do not look on my words, as the mere inklings of the moment but as the sincere dictates of a Lesson, I have learned by a most bitter experience.</p>
<p>Have not my sufferings both mentally and physically during my confinement in this Jail satisfied the dignity of the Commonwealth for the wrong I committed.</p>
<p>I have nothing to offer to Enlist sympathy, save my isolated friendlessness I am truly a stranger among strangers and at their mercy. I can prove to you that I have first class positions open to me, in the South, were I at liberty.</p>
<p>Gentlemen, Please Do all you can for me, and accept the assurance, "from a Heart which could not be, to one who would prove<pb/>
<lb/>his Saviour from such disgrace," of a full and adequate return for all your favors to me.</p>
<p>I cannot creak confidence, but I do ask you, as Heaven is my Witness, to believe, that for all you have done and may do for me - I will pay you satisfactorily</p>
<p>Apologising for the length of my note, yet hoping for your valuable influence Permit me to subscribe myself</p>
<p>Gentlemen,
<lb/>Most Respectfully and Humbly
<lb/>Your obed<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Serv<hi rend="sup">t</hi>
<lb/>Joseph B Hartley</p>
<p>P. S. Gents, If you could only have me taken out of here, On the word and honor of a man I would give you my services in any shape till I paid you thrice the bail. As a Clerk I can write 14 folios per hour, but I would do anything whatever, to save myself this disgrace I am a Witness on the case - Curley vs Smih &amp; Rose<pb/>
<lb/>Smith is trying to go my bail but his brothers are away and until their return. He can do little. Gen Huston can inform you of particulars.</p>
<p>-<hi rend="underline">Special</hi>-
<lb/>Messrs Hunt and Beck
<lb/>Attornies at Law
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Lex</hi> <hi rend="underline">Ky</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
