<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1167"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Rodman and Thomas N. Lindsey, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10635</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-326 to MG20-327</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-06-13">13 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>We are asked to give our recollection of the Substance of the Testimony in the case of the Commonwealth against Washington <hi rend="str">Wiegert</hi> Eblin now confined in the Penitentiray -- </p>
<p>It was proved that M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cardy the deceased was standing at the corner of Montgomery and St Clair Streets hollowing "hurrah for Todd" <hi rend="str">Wie-gert</hi> Eblin who was very drunk cried and hurrah for hell Each continued to hollow until <hi rend="str">Wiegert</hi> Eblin fired his pistol at M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cardy and shot him I have had no quarrel nor unkind feeling between them according to the proof</p>
<p>It was proved by Robt Brauner and several others that for Several years <hi rend="str">Wiegerts</hi> Eblins mind was evidently affected. In their Judgment he was crazy at the time of the killing</p>
<p>It was shown that Wiegert had no arms on him when he first approached M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cardy Eblin <hi rend="str">Wiegert</hi> asked for a knife and a man named Mershon handed him the Pistol with which he shot M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cardy- We Petition the Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. that for to Pardoned</p>
<p>Jno Rodman
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Ths N Lindsey</hi></p>
<p><date when="1861-06-13">June 13. 1861</date></p>
<p>We the undersigned Members of the Frankfort bar unite with Jno Rodman &amp; T M Lindsey in their petition</p>
<p>W. H. Sneed
<lb/><hi rend="underline">S. Hord</hi><pb/>
<lb/>Chas Y. Craddock
<lb/>D. W. Lindsay Jno M Harlan</p>
<p>I defended Eblin, and remember the Evidence of Brauner and Wiegart particularly -- which showd to my mind most clearly that Eblin was and had been a cracked man too crazy to be the subject of punishment. If I remember there was little or no evidence of his sanity, except he was a good hand to work, and fair in his dealings</p>
<p>A. J. James</p>
<p>I think <hi rend="str">the</hi> that Eblin ought to be Pardoned under the circumstances.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J. Harlan</hi></p>
<p>The statements made above are pretty much as I now recollect them to have been made by the witnesses at the time -- with the exception of the fact that the <unclear>snatched</unclear> the pistol from Mershan instead of it handed to the prisoner by Mr M -- I heartily join in the prayer for his pardon </p>
<p>P. U. Major -- com'th
<lb/>Atty prosceuting his case</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
