<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0312"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. J. Martin to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4431</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-1 to BR9-2</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Fleming County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-11-25">25 November 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlette, Govr of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Jeremiah J. Martin, would most respectfully state and show That ^at^ the <date when="1863-09">September Term of the Fleming Circuit Court, 1863</date>, he was by the verdict of a Jury found guilty of permitting unlawful gaming in his ^house^ charged in An Indictment found at a former term of said Court. And there upon, the Court rendered Judgment against him for the sum of $200. the amount found by the Jury. He States that not withstanding the Jury found him guilty, he believes he was not guilty within the Meaning and intent of the Statute upon which the Judgment was had as the Offense was committed without his knowledge or consent. And he now believes that the facts as Stated upon the trial presents, a proper Subject for the interposition of <hi rend="str">the</hi> your Excellency. The proof was substantially this: That at the time of the offense charged, there was assurty given at his house, and there was a considerable collection of young people collected in, and, Some gentlemen from Maysville, were there, and took lodging in a Room in the Second Story of the house, and during the night Some gaming was had in their Room the door of the Room being closed, and your petitioner was below and was not up stars that night, and did not know that any gaming was going on in the house And besides this, he had positively forbid any gaming of Any kind to be had in the house on the Occassion, all the witnesses made these Statements, yet under the instructions of the Court, he was found guilty being required to show that he had no knowledge, of the fact. And he thinks it a hard case, that he should<pb/>
<lb/>be compelled to pay this Judgment for the acts of others of which he had no contral. And his atty fail to prepare the case for an appeal, consequently he is left without any legal remedy. Wherefore he prays, in been of all the facts of the case, that interposition of your Excellency and prays that you would remit the Same. He refers to the letters of Several gentlemen herewith inclosed, who have a full knowledge of the facts of the case, and in duty bound will ever pray.</p>
<p>He further States that since the rendition of the Judgment he has been compelled to replay the Judgt except the <hi rend="str">cost and</hi> attys fee which he has said <hi rend="str">paid</hi> off, he hopes there your Excellency will discharge him from the bond, as he is poor and he believes it unjust that he should pay it.</p>
<p>J. J. Martin</p>
<p>This day the petitioner Jerry Martin personally appeared before me. <hi rend="str">and</hi> L. B. Cox Judge of the Fleming County Court, and swore to the ^facts state in the^ fore going petition this the <date when="1863-11-25">25th day of Novr. 1863</date>.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">L. B. Cox</hi></p>
<p>I was present at the foregoing trial and from the testimony -- the manner the cause was disposed of and the <hi rend="underline">sworn</hi> statements of Mr Martin in the foregoing petition I recommend him to your clemency.</p>
<p>Yours respectfully,
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi>. H. Cord,
<lb/>atty at Law
<lb/>John M Harbeson Clerk
<lb/>Fleming Circuit Court</p>
<p>I heard the trial of the Indictment against Jerry Martin, for permitting gaming in his house -- The wintesses proved that cards were played in<pb/></p>
<p>Governor, I was not present at the trial and cannot say any thing about the testimony but from what Petitioner has sworn to, I think it is a case for Executive clemency, and I would say that you ought in my Judgment to remit the fine.</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>L. W. Anderson</p>
<p>I L B Cox Judge of the Fleming County Court, State that I was present and heard the trial, of this case, and can state that the facts are Substantially Setforth The proof Showed that Mr. Martin forbid the playing of cards, and that he was not upstairs that night, but he was found guilty from the peculiar phraseology of the Statute and the instruction of the Court vs giving the law. Mr Martin is poor with a family depending on him for Support. And it is peculiarly hard on him of he has this sum to pay. I therefore believe that the case presents strong considerations for Executive Clemency. I hope therefore he may be discharged from the payment of same</p>
<p>Respectfully yours 
<lb/>L. B. Cox</p>
<p>I have read the above letter of Judge Cox and although I was not present at the Trial, though from what can learn I have heard of the case, I concur with Judge Cox in his statements</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> L Dudley Clk cty ct</p>
<p>an upper room of his house and the persons who knew of the game passed back and forth to the room, but no witness proved that Martin was in the room where the game was played &amp; that night or that he knew it. But the jury no doubt thought he ought to have known it and found him guilty. I think under all the circumstances the fine ought to be remitted. There was a party at his house on the night<pb/></p>
<p>the playing took place and the witnesses all proved that Martin was engaged below stairs in waiting on his guests.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">L. M. Cox</hi> </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
