<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0535"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George C. Haller to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8987</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-350 to R4-351</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hickman, Fulton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-08-17">17 August 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Hickman Ky <date when="1863-08-17">Aug 17. 1863</date>.
<lb/>His Excellency Gov. Robinson.
<lb/>Sir.</p>
<p>You will receive herewith a petition from M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Mont. G Wilson, asking to have a fine of $20.00 imposed upon him by the Fulton Eq. &amp; Crim Ct. at <date when="1861-05">May Term 1861</date>. for gaming, remitted. as also the recommendation of myself and other loyal officials.</p>
<p>The case is peculiarly hard. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Wilson in consequence of his attachment to the Union has been made to suffer and is now in really distressing circumstances. He is a respectable but poor man, with a small family of children, some of whom are sick. Of great firmness of character, I got him the appointment of enrolling officer for this County -- He has or is just about concluding his duty, which has been laborious and dangerous.</p>
<p>His conviction of the offense is truly stated. It was only the casual meeting of three friends under the circumstances detailed.</p>
<p>If consistent with duty, no one would feel more rejoiced than myself in the remission to him of the fine. This indeed seems to be just in as much as both the others have received your predecessor's clemency</p>
<p>With great respect
<lb/>Your most obt sevt
<lb/>Geo C Haller
<lb/>County Atty.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
