<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2384"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Isaac A. Skeen and Harvy Keer to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7021</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-306</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Whitley Court House, Whitley County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-27">27 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>I. A. Skeen &amp; Harvy Keer
<lb/>Petitions</p>
<p>To his Excellency -- the Governor of the Comlth of Kentucky -- Your Petitioners Isaac A. Skeen and Harvy Keer (Citizens of Whitley County) States that at the <date when="1865-03">march term of the Whitley Circuit Court 1865</date> They were tried and fined fifty Dollars ^each^ under a charge of malicious Stabing -- That their Council Drew a petition for them which petition was forwarded to your Excellency -- (but which Seemes to <hi rend="str">hav</hi> have been miss Laid -- ) That Said petition was for the purpose of asking a remitance of Said fines -- That Said petition was assigned by the Judge and Comlths. Atty -- That their Council is absent from the County That the Judge and Comwlths Atty are also at this time absent from this County Consequently we cannot obtain their Signatures to this petition -- That the witnesses on whome they relied and by whome they Could have made out their Justification -- never returned -- back from the Service of the United States. That James Stephens the man who was ^Slightly^ Stabed had Struck your petitioner Skeen with a chair three times and had knocked your petitioner Keer in the fire with a chair before there was any resistance on the part of your petitioners -- That Keer was Struck for trying to get hold of the chair with which Stephens was Strikeing Skeen -- In Justice we ask your -- Excellency if consistent to remit Said fines -- </p>
<p>I. A. Skeen
<lb/>Harvy. Keer -- </p>
<p>Whitley C H. Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-09-27">Sept. 27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date><pb/></p>
<p>Whitley.C. H <date when="1865-09-27">Sept 27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date></p>
<p>We the undersigned would respectfully ask Your Excellency to remit the fines against Skeen and Keer -- We think it would be but Justice to them to do So -- if Consistent with -- your pardoning power</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Thos owsley
<lb/>Joel Baker
<lb/>P J <unclear/>
<lb/>W C Murphy
<lb/>A L <unclear/>
<lb/>Solomon Cox
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Bowman
<lb/>W. H. Varney
<lb/>J. T. Keenan
<lb/>James F Sullivan
<lb/>W C Cox D S
<lb/>L, L, Sharp
<lb/>James Adkins
<lb/>L. D. Sutton
<lb/><unclear/> tinnen
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> C Bur<unclear/>
<lb/>J. H. Wood
<lb/>J, Q, <unclear>Bartman</unclear>
<lb/>W <unclear/>
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>W <unclear/>
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>Silas Prewit
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Lewis Adkins
<lb/>A I Curd
<lb/>M Richardson
<lb/>J. F. Sutton
<lb/>John <unclear/>
<lb/>Tyrel Foley clerk of the Whitley county court
<lb/>Daniel W Carroll
<lb/>Albert. T. Brown
<lb/>M. V. B. Sutton
<lb/>A. R. Barton
<lb/>M. V. Rany
<lb/>Hiram Faulkner
<lb/>John H Burch
<lb/>J J <unclear/>
<lb/>M. B. Ryan
<lb/>Joseph <unclear/>
<lb/>franklin culberth
<lb/>Ham Meadors
<lb/>Frank Rains
<lb/>C. Hann C, W, C,
<lb/>J. L. Cutberth
<lb/>C, S, <unclear/>
<lb/>Jackson M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Dowell</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
