<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3401"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Patrick Linnehan and Nora Linnehan to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5520</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-275 to BR42-276</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency, Thos E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your Petitioners Patrick Linnehan, and Nora Linnehan, state that at the <date when="1864-03">March Term, (1864)</date> of the city court of Louisville, a fine of twenty dollars was assessed against them (partners) on a trial, for selling liquor without license, The witnesses against them were persons who had deadly hatred against petitioners, Nora Linnehan had Eight hundred dollars stolen from her, &amp; she caused Search warrants to be issued to search the premises of said witnesses for the stolen money and thereupon they appeared before the Grand Jury and upon their testimony said Indictment was found and upon their testimony said conviction was had. They state that, that they as brother &amp; sister keep a boarding house, that they keep a small quantity of whisky at times for the accomodation of their boarders that all of sd boarders appeared in court &amp; testified that they had never paid one cent for drinks taken in their house. Yet the said Prejudiced witnesses stated otherwise. Your Petitions declare that they were guiltless. They ask for a remission of sd fine</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>Patrick Linnehan
<lb/>Nora Linnehan<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned neighbors to the Petitioners know them well &amp; believe that the statements contained in the foregoing petition are true.</p>
<p>Charles Lee
<lb/>James Mahoney
<lb/>Thomas Reagan
<lb/>James Scanlon
<lb/>Daniel Flynn
<lb/>Robert S Donaldson
<lb/>Timothy Brown
<lb/><hi rend="str">B</hi> Robert Hagerty
<lb/>Thomas foughlen
<lb/>John Coleman
<lb/>William Coleman
<lb/>Michle Aherne
<lb/>Daniel Surgan
<lb/>William Noughtlen
<lb/>John Sulivan
<lb/>Mickle Reagan
<lb/>John Seckston
<lb/>John Mahoney
<lb/>Edward Reardon
<lb/>James Doyele
<lb/>John Mccarty
<lb/><hi rend="str">The above un</hi></p>
<p>The persons names above are the immediate neighbors of the petitioners. There was certainly ill feeling between<pb/>
<lb/>the petioners and the witnesses named in the foregoing petitiion.</p>
<p>W. G. Reasor
<lb/>Geo. W. Johnston<pb/></p>
<p>Louisville
<lb/>Refused
<lb/>Thos E Bramlette
<lb/><date when="1864">1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
