<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2184"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James H. Langford to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6821</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-421 to BR14-422</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Rockcastle County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-08-17">17 August 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To Honorable Thomas E Bramlette Governor of the State of Kentucky your Petitioner James Langford states that at the present <date when="1865-08">August 1865</date> term of the Rockcastle Circuit Court, that he was fined fifty Dollars, under the following Circumstances: He was indicted in the year <date when="1861">1861</date> -- for maliciously shooting at and wounding John Griffin -- and that said Griffin did not die thereby -- The Cause came on for trial, and your Petitioner and said Griffin had had a difficulty No person being present but them two -- John Griffin was witness against him= Enough was Elicited from this witness and from some two or three others that had seen the Conduct of their witness and his Character for an afrray -- that under the instructions of the Court the Jury returned in substance the followng verdict=</p>
<p>We of the Jury find the Defendant James Langford not guilty of milicious shooting of John Griffin but we do find him Guilty of shooting John Griffin in sudden heat and passion, without it being in necessary self Defense and affix his fine at fifty Dollars. Now your Petitioner States that he has a family and is a very poor man, and not able to pay said fine -- and he prays your honor to remit the fine of fifty Dollars and as in Duty bound will ever pray</p>
<p>Jas H Langford
<lb/><hi rend="str">H Carpenter</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="str">Wm Mc C</hi></p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>County of Rockcastle }</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to before me by James Langford this <date when="1865-08-17">17<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Day of august 1865</date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">A. Smith</hi> C R C C</p>
<p>We the undersigned State that we are acquainted With the Circumstances of the above Case and<pb/>
<lb/>We join in the Prayer of James Langford and ask your Excellency to remit the fine of James Langford as above state</p>
<p>H Carpenter
<lb/>Mat Ramsey
<lb/>A Chesnut
<lb/>David N. Lewis
<lb/>S, W, Brown
<lb/>N Y hunt
<lb/>Jack Adams
<lb/>Emanuel Minks
<lb/>W H Weber
<lb/>Geo, W, M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clure
<lb/>Wm M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clure
<lb/>Ashley Owens
<lb/>D, G, Colyer
<lb/>John Adams
<lb/>G C R M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Call
<lb/>John Conn
<lb/>J. J. Carson
<lb/>Willis Adams<pb/></p>
<p>Mount vernon
<lb/><date when="1865-08-16">Aug 16<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Gov Bramblet</p>
<p>Dear sir I hope that you remit the Judgement for fifty dollars against James Langford I fully believe that it ought to be remited</p>
<p>Yours Truly
<lb/>Granville Pearl</p>
<p>Gov Bramlette Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Lankford is a poor man beside the man he <hi rend="str">wa</hi> shot was and is a very dangerous &amp; bad man Think He had right believe he was in danger of his life &amp; believe there will bo no wrong in remitting this fine</p>
<p>H F, Finley<pb/></p>
<p>Rockcastle Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Jas N. Langford
<lb/>$50.
<lb/>Shooting John Griffin
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1865-09-13">13 Sept 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
