<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0408"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John M. Casey to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9876</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-134 to MG18-135</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-07-28">28 July 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Covington Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-07-28">July 28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Governor of Ky,</p>
<p>Dear Sir: at the request of Mrs Clarke (mother of D. W. Clarke now confined in the penitentiary under sendence from the Kenton Circuit Court at this place) I am induced to write you a few lines in favor of the prayer of petitioners in this behalf.</p>
<p>Without making any statement of the facts the complete record accompanies the petition.</p>
<p>In only one of the cases is there a bill of evidence and in that case I never thought that there was sufficient proof to warrant his conviction but the jury thought differently and I respectfully defer to their decision as I always<pb/>
<lb/>think that every good citizen should pay reverence to the Courts and their officers,</p>
<p>Granting then the guilt of the young man I am very willing under all circumstances to unite my voice with petitioners in praying for his release.</p>
<p>I think it will result in good. I learn from one of his former employers that he was while <hi rend="str">im</hi> employed ^some time in his service^ honest and industrious. My opinion is that he is not hardened in crime and that his length of confinement has been sufficient to reform one of his years. There are many who know him and his history citizens ^of this place^ of respectability and veracity who assure me that if he is released he will never fall into such errors again, Such representations together with compassion<pb/>
<lb/>for his poor widowed mother who in her present failing health needs his assistance and presence have induced the writing of these lines. I am exceedingly reluctant to petition Executive Clemency and I feel the delicacy of such a position the more in this case as I was counsel for the boy; but his youth, and the well grounded hope I indulge that he is completely reformed overcome my scruples. And through his late sufferings, ^and^ his mother's influence (who is a sincerely pious woman) I am convinced that he will act in the future to justify the hopes indulged in his reformation.</p>
<p>I will add that in both cases the owners recovered their property. His mother will if able go to Frankfort in person, but from her present state of health<pb/>
<lb/>she is doubtful whether she can go. And asking in behalf of her prayer your Excellency's indulgent and merciful consideration whether she appears before you or has to send her appeal by mail -- I have the honor to subscribe myself with sentiments of esteem</p>
<p>Yours Respectfully
<lb/>John M. Casey</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
