<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-031-0318"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">P. J. Honaker to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8058</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Appointments by the Governor, Civil Appointments, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R1-428 to R1-429</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Port Royal, Henry County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-07-23">23 July 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Port Royal Henry Co Ky
<lb/><date when="1863-07-23">July 23 1863.</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>Governor Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> F. Robinson</p>
<p>Dear Sir. I addressed your Excellency some weeks since inquiring, I thought in very respectfull terms after a commission as one of the Justices of the peace elected at the <date when="1863-05">May</date> election by a large Majority of My fellow citizens of this precinct. I supposed at that time that my Commission together with that of M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> George Hamston had been sent, but by some accident or miscarriage of the mails they had failed to reach us. To that letter addressed to your Excellency I have never received an answer. Why I have not your Excellency, can only tell. Since that time I understand that our County Court Clerk (M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> M. B. Pearce) stated that he had had an interview with your Excellency upon the Subject and that you informed him that "you would issue no Commissions to <hi rend="underline">Rebels</hi>" Meaning I could not but suppose that myself and M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Hamston were "<hi rend="underline">Rebels</hi>" (I have been a former resident of your County (Scott) &amp; have heard you plead at the bar in Georgetown but suppose that you were not directly acquainted with me as I moved to this County some three years ago) From all the circumstances connected with this affair I suppose that you have had some statements on charges in reference to my loyalty by<pb/>
<lb/>some person or persons unknown to me who they are or what their charges ^are^ against me I have never yet been able to learn except that which I have by <hi rend="underline">accident</hi> gathered from M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Pearce and I consider it my duty to my own character and standing as a citizen and a man and one I owe my fellow citizens of this precinct to say to your Excellency that if I am a rebel I do not understand the meaning of the term. I have never aided or abetted in any way the rebellion to my knowledge. I have never taken up arms against the Government of the United States or the State of Kentucky -- Neither have I counseled others so to do on the contrary I have advised differently -- I have never furnished those in rebellion against the Government with arms -- amunition -- meat bread or transportation. It is true that I do not approve of M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Lincolns policy in regard to Confiscation -- Negro emancipation and many other Acts which I believe to be unconstitutional. If these opinions of mine constitute me a rebel I will have to plead guilty to the charge, but if they do not I challenge inspection into my Conduct upon the charges. My fellow citizens without solicitation on my part elected me to fill the humble office of Magistrate of this precinct and if I Mistake not I am entitled to the commission as such under the Constitution and laws of my native state Kentucky and that the<pb/>
<lb/>same Constitution &amp; laws require of you as Governor of the state to Commission me as such. I deny that I am a rebel or that I have by act of mine been disloyal to the Government of the U. S. or the State of Kentucky. I have not even been prominent as a village or County politician on the Contrary, an humble tiller of the soil. During the invasion of Ky By General Bragg last year although his soldiers were in the neighborhood and all around me did I have the slightest intercourse with nor did I in any way aid or abet them indeed at no time past or present have I had the slightest Communication with them. I am apposed to a division of the Union and to day Would be as proud as Your Excellency or any other man in Ky, to see the Union restored to its original purpose as intended by the framers of that instrument Which I have always had the highest reverence &amp; respect.</p>
<p>I write Your Excellency these hasty lines entertaining for you the highest respect &amp; confidence &amp; as one of the citizens of that proud Old Commonwealth whose Chief Majistrate you are I ask of your Excellency a <hi rend="underline">chance</hi> to vidicate my character from any unjust importation <hi rend="str">as</hi> upon <hi rend="str">n</hi>either my character as an honest man (with moderate abilities for the post to which my fellow citizens of this precinct have seen fit in their partiality, to elect me) and to indicate as I know I can<pb/>
<lb/>by impartial witness of good standing in this and other parts of Henry, from any Charges of disloyalty. Your informant must be a personal enemy of mine or greatly mistaken or not at all acquainted with my conduct Since the breaking out of the Rebellion. I trust that Your Excellency will find it convenient to answer this communication And believe me</p>
<p>Your most obedient servant
<lb/>P. J. Honaker</p>
<p>Henry Co.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Port Royal
<lb/>Dist
<lb/>P J Honaker
<lb/>Iss <hi rend="str">July</hi><date when="1863-07-01">Aug 1. 1863.</date></p>
<p>Issue Comm to Honaker &amp; send
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J F Robinson</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
