<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2340"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James Kenley et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6977</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-238 to BR15-239</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioners James Kenley Henley T Crowdur and James Lawrence would state that some time last spring they became sureties of Beauford Lawrence for his appearance in the Marion circuit court to answer a charge of Larceny the said Beauford being a mere boy became alarmed and went off to the state of indianna and failed to appear on the day named in his recognizance and the same was acclaimed forfeited and process was issued against your petitioners requiring them to show cause at the <date when="--06">June</date> <gap/> term of said court why judgement should not be rendered against them on said recognizance and said process having only been served in time on your petition H T Crowdur judgment was rendered against him for <hi rend="str">said</hi> the amount to wit <hi rend="str">$300.00</hi> $250.00 and costs execution issued on the judgment and it has been replevied by said Crowdur with James Crowdur as his surety your petitioners are however all liable for said sum as co sureties They further state that said Beauford Lawrence during the last term of the Marion circuit court returned to Marion county and was accidentally shot and killed and as he is now dead must atone in another world to another jurisdiction for all the acts of his life they pray your excellency to release his sureties from the payment of the amount of the replevin bond which is $262.89 cts said bond is dated the <date when="1865-07-24">24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> July 1865</date> all of which your petitioners respectfully represent</p>
<p>James Kenley<pb/>
<lb/>H. T Crowdur
<lb/>James Laurence</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of marion county most cheerfully unite in the prayer of the within petition</p>
<p>John R. Thomas
<lb/>Jam<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H. Fidler
<lb/>B Spalding
<lb/>S A Spalding
<lb/>J, M <unclear>Robins</unclear>
<lb/>C. S Mills
<lb/>F M Chandler
<lb/>R A Benton
<lb/>J C Raney
<lb/>J C Glazebrook
<lb/>James P Shane
<lb/>Charles Peairson
<lb/>Wm P Wade
<lb/>J. C. Bottom
<lb/>R Survant
<lb/>C Monroe
<lb/>Henry Gray
<lb/>John Isaacs
<lb/>William Isaacs
<lb/>Banister Taylor
<lb/>Jacob Sharon
<lb/>R, L Chandler
<lb/>Q, M, Chandler
<lb/>James Hourican
<lb/>C, C, Hourican
<lb/>R L Dillingham<pb/></p>
<p>Marion Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Remit
<lb/>Jas Kenley, H. T. Crowders &amp; James Lawrence
<lb/>$250.
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/><date when="1865-09-28">28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sept/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
