<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3069"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Sheff White et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5188</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR43-193</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Rockcastle County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thos E Brambete
<lb/>Gov. of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioners Sheff White, Fox Jones and Asa Goins would most respectfully represent, that they stand Indicted in the Rockcastle Circuit Court chared with malicously shooting Henry Mullins. And for maliceous stabing John Mullins They would state that they affray that took place at the time the injures were inflicted was in the County of Rockcastle the Petitioners are and were at the time citizens of Clay County were passing through Rockcastle where they insulted by by Henry Mullins John Mullins, Sidney Mullins and Tink Ovens who made an assault on the Petitioner, in which Goins and Jones were wounded by said Mullins &amp;c</p>
<p>That your Petitioners used only such force as was necessary to protect themselves <hi rend="str">against the</hi> from the assault <hi rend="str">of</hi> made on them. They state that they were going peaceably along the public road at the time the difficulty took place with no intention of molesting any one</p>
<p>They state that they live some 40 or 45 miles from Mt Vernon, where they will have to be tried they Have attended severl times and the <unclear/> has been continued they are poor law abiding men, and unable to bear the Expences that they are compelled to incur in attend Courts so far from Home</p>
<p>They therefore incur <unclear/> of the previous and their entire <unclear/> of any <unclear/> <unclear/> <unclear/> most earnestly ask that they be pardoned <hi rend="str">from</hi> and the prosecution against<pb/>
<lb/>them be dismissed.</p>
<p>Sheff White
<lb/>Asa Goins
<lb/>Fox Jones
<lb/><note place="left margin">Rockcastle White</note></p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Clay &amp; Rockcastle counties most respectfully state, that the are acquainted with the Petitions Sheff White, Fox Jones &amp; Asa Goins know them to be Law abiding good Citizens and believe they should be pardoned of the charges against them in the Rockcastle Circuit Court and most respectfully and Earnestly ask His Excellency Thos E Bramlet Gov of Kentucky to Pardon them</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/><cb n="2"/>John Landes
<lb/>L. A. Byron
<lb/>G. M. Asher
<lb/>James H Murphy
<lb/>James Gillilan
<lb/>H. L. Ward
<lb/>Barton Potter
<lb/>W. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Daniel
<lb/>Daniel G Williams
<lb/>John T. Bates
<lb/>Jas G Potter
<lb/>W. H. Bates
<lb/>Theo. Price
<lb/>B. P White P. J. C. C.
<lb/>W S White Clerk C C C
<lb/><cb n="2"/>H L White</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
