<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1113"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Oliver Barnett et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5750</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-202 to BR11-203</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency Thos E Bramlett Govenor of the commonwealth of Kentucky your Petitiner Oliver Barnett would respectfully represent that at the Last term of Lawrence circuit court he was fined Sixty dollars ($60) for retailing ardent Spirits your petitioner has these reasin why he thinks your excellency should remit Said fine</p>
<p>1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Said Indictment was made about the breaking out of this rebelion, and your petitioner volenteered in the 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Vol Regt in the summer of <date when="1861">1861</date> and served in said Regt untill the summer of <date when="1863">1863,</date> and then was discharged for physical Disability</p>
<p>2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> your petiener was Labouring under the impression from the fact of the Length of time between the finding of the indictment and Judgment that Said prosecution was abandoned <hi rend="str">never</hi> their being no court <hi rend="str">after</hi> for a wile after <hi rend="str">court</hi> ^the rebellion broke out^</p>
<p>3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> your petitioner further states that if he had known that said inditement was for trial at the Last term of the court, he had a valid defence, if he had not he would not trouble your excellency with this petition</p>
<p>4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Your petitioner would further state that he is a verry poore man and having ruined his constitution in fighting the battles of his coun-<pb/>
<lb/>-try and should he be fourced to pay said fine it will be ruinous both to himself and family</p>
<p>Relying in your excellincys Mercy and the Justice of your petitioner's request he prays your excellency to remit said fine and in duty will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p>Oliver Barnett</p>
<p>We the subscribers Join in the prayr and endors the facts of the above petition</p>
<p>R. F. Vinson C L C C
<lb/>H. S. Bussey D. C. L, C, C
<lb/>J. B. Hutchison Capt. Capitol Guard
<lb/>J. W. Haws P, J, L, C, C
<lb/>K, F, Prichard Co, atty
<lb/>Wm Vinson
<lb/>Henry M Bond
<lb/>Peyton C Justice
<lb/>Harrison Hicks
<lb/>Jackson Pack
<lb/>J. Spaulding
<lb/>Charles Taylor
<lb/>An Green
<lb/>Archible Muncey
<lb/>Geo. du, Murry
<lb/>M. Dempsey
<lb/>A. J. Conley
<lb/>W M Conley
<lb/>Edmund Osburn
<lb/>Marion Castle
<lb/>Wm F Moore<pb/></p>
<p>Lawrence Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>O. Barnett
<lb/>Remit
<lb/>$60
<lb/><date when="1864-08-08">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Aug'/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
