<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0911"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James H. G. Bush to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5030</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-400 to BR10-401</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Winchester, Clark County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-05-24">24 May 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Winchester Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1864-05-24">May 24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>.
<lb/>Hon<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Thomas E Bramlette Governor of Kentucky
<lb/>Dear Sir:</p>
<p>I am well acquainted with the case of the Commonwealth of Ky. against Albion T Ryon. The killing of Francis M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Donald by by said Ryon took place shortly after the <date when="1864-08">August election in 1854</date> nearly ten years ago. Young Ryon was bailed, by Samuel W Chiles, Caleb Parrish, Richard M Webb and Joseph Jones &amp; Perhaps some others. Ryon stood one trial and the Jury hung. He aftwards absconded and his recognizance was forfeited, leaveing his sureties to pay the Bond. The community here were so well satisfied that <hi rend="str">a petition</hi> the sureties had no hand in geting Ryon to escape and ^they^ being of the opinion that Ryon would Stand in trial. That a petition was very generally signed requesting His Excellency the Governor to interpose executive clemency in behalf of Ryons sureties on his bail bond and the Governor did remit the greater part of said forfeited Recognizance and respited the residue- And so matters Stood until recently by act of the Legislature the agent of the Auditor is empowered to cause execution to issue upon all such bonds-</p>
<p>Caleb Parrish one of the Sureties in said bond is now<pb/>
<lb/>dead- leaveing a widow and children to be supported and educated, and the enforcement of the collection of said bond would operate as a hardship upon them. I believe the gentlemen named <hi rend="str">Were none</hi> in said bond were none of them related to Ryon. They went upon the bond as neighbors and friends, believeing that young Ryon would appear and stand his trial, as He had on all occasions declared his innocence of the charge of murder for which He was indicted allways declareing that he committed the act in his own self defence. Ryon was very poor and his father <hi rend="str">at the time</hi> was and had been for some time before insolvent The family were of good standing and young Ryon as I personally knew had sustained a high character as a gentleman and business young man and as deputy Clerk of the County Court was popular I am sure that if the facts of this case together with its surrounding could be properly presented to you that you would see that this case is one of that class of cases that demands the interposition of your executive clemency for the relief of the sureties of Ryon and that in the exercise of it for the benefit of said sureties your action would be hailed with perfect satisfaction by all of our Citizens including the family &amp; friends of the deceased.<pb/>
<lb/>Francis McDonald. I have no interest or feeling in this matter except that I desire to see the parties to said bond released for the reasons assigned believeing it would meet with general favor in our community. I am my Dear Sir your most obedient servant</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">James H G Bush</hi></p>
<p>To His Excellency Govr
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Bramlette</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
