<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-009-0006"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Unknown, Fair Ground Directory</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1161</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR1-9 to BR1-9a</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Decatur, Macon County, Illinois</placeName>
    <date when="1863-09-17">17 September 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Newspaper</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Constantly Replenishing
<lb/>OUR ALREADY LARGE STOCK
<lb/>Direct from the
<lb/>EASTERN CITIES!
<lb/>And are now just in receipt of a large invoice of
<lb/>ALL KINDS OF
<lb/>STAPLE and FANCY DRY GOODS,
<lb/>Ready Made Clothing,
<lb/>HATS, CAPS,
<lb/>BOOTS, SHOES, &amp;C.,
<lb/>Which were purchased by our partner, just after the late decline and before the last
<lb/>ADVANCE OF PRICES
<lb/>In the Eastern Markets,
<lb/>The benefit of which we most cordially give to 
<lb/>OUR CUSTOMERS,
<lb/>Retaining for our profits only a small commission. Having a
<lb/>PARTNER IN THE EAST,
<lb/>Who is constantly watching the Market, we can at all times avail ourselves of any favorable change in prices, thereby enabling us to offer
<lb/>GREATER INDUCEMENTS TO BUYERS THAN ANY OTHER HOUSE WHO IS NOT POSSESSED OF LIKE FACILITIES.</p>
<p>Hoping that every one who may read this Card will not fail to give us a call at F. Priest's old stand, a few doors south of the Railroad Bank Building.</p>
<p>Respectfully, &amp;c.,
<lb/>A. RUTH &amp; CO.
<lb/>Decatur, <date when="1863-09-17">Sept. 17, 1863</date>. tf<pb/></p>
<p>Fair Ground Directory.</p>
<p>For the information of those who have not visited the fair grounds to see how they have been arranged, we append the following description which will give a general idea of the grounds and appointments:</p>
<p>The enclosure is 80 rods square, containing 40 acres. The four outer sides vary, from being gradually undulating to a moderately high bluff or hill, gently sloping towards the centre, and are interspersed with forest trees, while the centre is nearly level, of natural prairie, forming an almost natural amphitheatre. At the foot of the southern slope of bluffs, springs of rare beauty and pure water gushes out in great abundance; four of these at nearly equal distanced apart, are tastefuly improved, either of which will afford a sufficiency of water for the accommodation of all the visitors regardless of numbers. On entering the gate, which is surmounted by a beautifully decorated arch, the magnificence of the whole grounds, as well as the improvements, are in full view. The cottage at the gate affords the treasurer's office, from the outer side of which tickets of admission are obtained,) while the main building is divided into rooms for offiees for the general superintendent and superintendent of the horse department. The next building to the right a few steps off, is the secretaries' office. Next comes the agricultural and mechanical hall; next farm product hall. Nearly opposite is a beautiful, tasty, small edifice, the presiden's office; next the hall for textile fabrics. Now, by ascending a bluff, you approach an octagon building two stories high, which is used for the quadruple purposes of fruit, floral natural history and fine arts. You are now on the western bluff, immediately in front of which, to the east, is the amphitheatre, capable of seating 8000 persons, which you approach from this point by a bridge extending from this bluff. A beautiful room is constructed in the centre of the amphitheatre for the accommodation of editors and reporter of the press.</p>
<p>The training track is an oval in the centre of the grounds, being 50 feet wide, and distance round, half a mile; the amphitheatre being a half circle, under which are refreshment booths; in front of this stands the pagoda for judges and music, around which cattle and hroses are bro't for committeemen to award premiums. Near the eastern end of the amphitheatre is the dining hall, or rather hotel, where where four hundred persons can be seated at one time, and may be arranged to seat 200 more if found necessary. All of the buildings are either whitewashed or painted, and ornamented with more or less drapery, affording a variety rarely if ever met with at like places.</p>
<p>The cattle and horse stalls extend around the outer enclosure, in front of which are good wells of pure water at convenient distances apart. -- The pens for sheep and hogs diverge from the north side in six different sections.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
