<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1589"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">L. B. Grigsby and James F. Robinson, Jr. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6226</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-22 to BR13-23</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lexington, Fayette County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-03-08">8 March 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Grigsby &amp; Robinson.
<lb/>Lexington, Ky. <date when="1865-03-08">March 8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>His Excellency Gov Bramlett;
<lb/>Frankfort Ky;
<lb/>Dear Sir;</p>
<p>M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Warnock the bearer of this, has been indicted by our Grand Jury for dealing farro. -- We would beg leave to say in behalf of Mr Warock, that he is a poor man or at least in moderate cirucmstances, and with a large family dependent upon him for a support. We have known him long and well, and have always known him to be a man of integrity and peacable and quiet in his demeanor. He is a liberal, social gentleman, and as he will tell you has dealt Faro, for other gentlemen, but the fault of his dealing has always been that of those who bet against him more than of himself. We have never known or heard of his dealing for men who were not of sufficient age or in a proper condition to be perfectly<pb/>
<lb/>responsible for themselves, or of his ever doing any thing to inveigle or entice persons to felony. -- While such a character is an exception among men who deal Farro, we would respectfully submit M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Warnocks case as <hi rend="str">one</hi> one worthy of your Executive Clemency.</p>
<p>We are Gov, truely
<lb/>your obdt Svts
<lb/>L B, Grigsby
<lb/>Jas. F. Robinson jr<pb/></p>
<p>His Excellency Gov Bramlett
<lb/>Frankfort Ky
<lb/><unclear/>vor of
<lb/>M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> J W Warnock</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Remit</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
