<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0559"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">C. C. Lewis to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4678</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-386 to BR9-387</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Bourbon County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-02-13">13 February 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Tho: E. Bramblette. The Petition of C C Lewis_ This petitioner states that he was for a while a Tavern keeper in the year <date when="1860">1860</date> in North Middletown County of Bourbon and that while engaged in that business he was indicted for suffering gaming in <hi rend="str">my</hi> ^his^ home and was fined by the Bourbon Circuit Court at the <date when="1861-04">April Term 1861</date> in the sum of fifty Dollars and costs. This petitioner states further that this fine was imposed upon him unjustly as he firmly believes. He admits that there was gaming proved to have taken place on his home, but the gaming was commenced by those engaged in it without his knowledge or consent. He states that he did not permit or allow gaming to be carried on at the house &amp; he endeavored in every particular to keep an orderly house &amp; to fill in any particular his duty as a Tavern keeper -- He prays that the fine be remitted and that he be relieved by Executive Clemency for in <hi rend="str">as</hi> much thereof as can be Given under my hand this <date when="1864-02-13">13 Feby 1864</date></p>
<p>C. C. Lewis</p>
<p>Sworn to before me as Examiner of Bourbon County Kentucky by C. C Lewis this <date when="1856-02-13">13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of February 1856</date></p>
<p>Tho. P. Smith Examr<pb/></p>
<p>The affidavit of William F Craig affiant states that during the time C C Lewis kept a Tavern in North Middletown Bourbon County he himself resided in the Town of North Middletown and <hi rend="str">principally in the</hi> ^was very frequently in the house^ said Lewis and he had the best opportunity of Knowing what kind of house was kept by him said Lewis_ He knows that Lewis kept an orderly house and that He did not suffer or consent for gaming to be carried on in his house. He states that although he has been idicted &amp; found for suffering gaming in his House he is satisfied that s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Lewis did not keep a gaming house. Given under my hand this <date when="1864-04-12">12 Ap<hi rend="sup">l</hi>. 1864</date></p>
<p>Will F. Craig</p>
<p>Sworn to before me an Examiner of Bourbon County Kentucky by Will F Craig this <date when="1864-02-13">13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of February 1864</date>. </p>
<p>Thos P Smith Exr.</p>
<p>The undersigned respectfully request his Excellency Gov Bramblette to remit the fine against C C Lewis upon such Terms as may be proper <date when="1864-02-13">Feby 13 1864</date></p>
<p>James Paton
<lb/>Geo. W. Williams<pb/></p>
<p>Bourbon Cir Ct.
<lb/>vs
<lb/>C. C. Lewis
<lb/>Gaming
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1861-03-08">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> <hi rend="str">A</hi>March
<lb/><hi rend="underline">1861</hi></date>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">148</hi>
<lb/>1212</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
