<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2753"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">D. W. McGoodwin et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7390</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-442 to BR16-443</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-18">18 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Governor Bramlett,</p>
<p>We, the undersigned, would most respectfully ^state^ to your Excellency, that Walter R. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Chesney, being indicted for murder in the Caldwell Circuit, he togeather A. W. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Chesney, his uncle, acknowled themselves indebted to the Commonwealth of Kentucky in the sum of Fifteen hundred dollars if Walter did not appear and answer said charge; and at the same time, <date when="1863-06">June Term 1863</date>, Walter and Alfred Beckner acknowledged themselves indebted to the said Commonwealth in the sum of Three Hundred dollars to be void if Walter appeared and answer the charge of robbery, for which he was indicted in said Court. We will here remark that prior to the War, Walter was as reputable young man as lived in Caldwell County, that thes two offences were committed by a Company that professed to act in the Confederate service and that Walter was not a member thereof, but your petitioners are not going to accuse or excuse him, though it perhaps would be proper in justice to him to say that it can be shown by undoubted evidence that he was compelled against his will to go with the Company that day on which those offices were committed. Walter remained here in the County, demeaning himself in a commendable manner until in the Fall of <date when="1864">1864</date> when he was conscripted by the Rebils and was taken or went off with them. Be that<pb/>
<lb/>as it may your petitioners have ^no^ hesitation in saying that Walter did not depart from the Country with the approbation or consent of A. W. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Chesney or Alfred Beckner. That at the <date when="1865-06">June Term 1865</date> thoes two recognizances were taken by the said Court rendered a judgment against A. W. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Chesney for the sum of $1500<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> on the 1st, and a judgment for $300<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> against Alfred Beckner in the 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> recognizance.</p>
<p>Your petitioners take pleasure in stating A. W. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Chesney and Alfred Beckner are peaceable citizens, good farmers and ex<hi rend="str">a</hi>emplary Christians. That both have lost a large amount of their property by the War, and since its happy termination the former was robbed of $1000<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> or $1200<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> more than one half of it being in specie and the latter has had a mare, worth at least two hundred dollars, stolen from him. Thes losses render it oppressive on them to have the two judgments to pay. Walter R M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Chesney left no means, known to us, out of which his surities may be indemnified.</p>
<p>We would therefore respectfully aske, if consistent with your view of public justice ^to^ remit the said two judgments that were rendered on the said forfeited recognizances.</p>
<p><date when="1865-12-18">December 18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date></p>
<p>D W M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Goodwin
<lb/>J. C Barnes clk
<lb/>Caldwell Circuit Court
<lb/>F W Dabney deputy clk c c c<pb/>
<lb/>D. Ross. Baker, Sheriff. C. C.
<lb/>R, B, Ratliff
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J H Turner</hi> P J C C C
<lb/>A Reynolds D. S. Sherriff S C C
<lb/>W H <unclear/> Trustee Jury fund C C Ky
<lb/>W. D. Marlow P M
<lb/>W. T. Talbott Police Judge of the Town of Princeton.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
