<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0718"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Daniel Cook et al., Judgment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10186</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-120 to MG19-121</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1859-08-20">20 August 1859</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Daniel Cook being in custody charged with Shooting at one Hutchinson with the intention to kill and being <hi rend="str">admitted</hi> admitted to Bail in the Sum of One Hundred dollars. We J. C Thomas R J Blanford A G. Vanters R. Higden &amp; D Dunn H Dale all of the County of Hancock and State of Kentucky hereby undertake that the above named Daniel Cook Shall appear in the Hancock Circuit Court on the first day of the Next term to answer Said charge and Shall at all times render himself amenable to the Orders and process of Said Court in the prosecution of Said charge and if convicted Shall render himself in Execution thereof or if he fails to perform either of these conditions that in will pay to the Commonwealth of Kentucky the Sum of One Hundred Dollars.</p>
<p>Witness Our hands &amp; Seals this <date when="1859-08-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of August 1859</date>.</p>
<p>Attest K. Patterson, J. P. C. L.</p>
<p>Daniel ^his X mark^ Cook <figure type="seal"/>
<lb/>John C Thomas <figure type="seal"/>
<lb/>A. G. Vanter <figure type="seal"/>
<lb/>R. A. Higden <figure type="seal"/>
<lb/>D Dunn <figure type="seal"/>
<lb/>Henry Dale <figure type="seal"/></p>
<p>A Copy attest
<lb/>James E Stone Clerk
<lb/>H. Crt Ck<pb/></p>
<p>Kentucky Hancock Circuit Court
<lb/><date when="1861-02">Feby term 1861</date>, Tuesday <date when="1861-02-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Feby 1861</date></p>
<p>Commonwealth
<lb/>against
<lb/>Daniel Cook &amp; others</p>
<p>Plaintiffs } on forfeited recognizance</p>
<p>This day Came the attorney for the Commonwealth and the Summons herein having been duly <hi rend="str">Summoned</hi> Executed the Defendants John. C. Thomas R J Blanford A. G. Vanters D. Dunn &amp; Henry Dale, and they not appearing altho. Called It is therefore adjduged by the Court that the Commonwealth of Kentucky recover of the Said Defendants John C. Thomas, R. J. Blanford A G Vanters D Dunn, &amp; Henry Dale the Sum of One Hundred dollars the amount forfeited by them in the recognizance Stated, also the Costs herein Expended &amp;c. As to the Defendants Daniel Cook &amp; R A Higden. this action is continued until the next term of this Court, and an alias Summons is awarded herein against them.</p>
<p>A Copy Attest
<lb/>James E Stone clk
<lb/>H. C. C-</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
