<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2057"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John L. St. Clair to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9133</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-78 to MG24-79</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Marion County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-06-06">6 June 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Hon B Magoffin
<lb/>Govenor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner John L St clair would most respectfully State to your Excellency that at the <date when="1862-05">May Term 1862</date> of the Marion Circuit Court the Grand Jurors empanneled at Said Term found and returned to Said Court a True Bill against your Petitioenr for Dealing Farrow, that during the term of Said Court your Petitioner voluntarily went before Said Court and plead guilty to Said Indictment and confessed judgement for the Sum of Five Hundred dollars, and judgement for that amount was accordinly rendered against Your Petitioener, Now your Petitioner will humbly State to your Excellency that he is not a Gambler by profession, and does not follow the practice of gaming for a Support, that at the time refered to in<pb/>
<lb/>Said Indictment the game was gotten up for mere Sport and pastime and not for the purpose of gain or profits, that the bank was made up by himself and two other gentlemen at the instance and request of several gentlemen present and did not exceed the sum of $60 00, Soley for the purpose of amusement. Your Petitioner would further State that he is a poor mechanic, a Brick mason by trade, and wholly unable to pay Said judgement of $500, that he relies wholly upon his trade for Support and has no property of any kind, that he has always worked and does work at his trade whenever work is offered him, Now your Petitioner would pray Your Excellency that in view of the above facts, taking into Consideration his poor and humble condition that you interpose your Executive clemency in his behalf, and grant to him Such Executive pardon and remission as your Excellency may deem proper and right in the premises, and would further pray a full remission and pardon of the fine imposed, and as in duty bound will ever pray &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi></p>
<p>John. L. S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Clair</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by John L St Clair this <date when="1862-06-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of June 1862 -- </date></p>
<p>John Mauly Examiner M C.</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Marion County Ky join in the Petition of their fellow citizen John L St clair, and humbly pray your Excellency to grant the prayer of the Petitioner</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>N S Ray
<lb/>A Ryder
<lb/>D W Phillips
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/>Green Forrest
<lb/>G. W. Goodman
<lb/>M R Hunter (of Webster Co)<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>Levi Cullen
<lb/>J. G. Campbell
<lb/>B. Spalding
<lb/>H C. Harris
<lb/><hi rend="str">R M Bawman</hi>
<lb/>R M Bawman
<lb/>H T Jackson
<lb/>James M Fogle
<lb/>Jno R O'Bryan
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H Chandler
<lb/>John H. Tucker
<lb/>L S Mill
<lb/>F. M. Ballard
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/>N T Berry
<lb/>J B Wathen
<lb/>Joseph Spalding
<lb/>S A Spalding
<lb/>John Shuck
<lb/>Thos. C. Woods
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Milburn
<lb/>Robt A. Burton
<lb/>Rh M. Spalding
<lb/>J Manly
<lb/>H. H. Hughes<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>We the undersigned Grand Jurors that found the Indictment refered to above humbly ask your Excellency to grant the prayer of the Petitioner -- </p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J G. Phillips</hi>
<lb/>John Spalding</p>
<p>Respite 12 mo
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Marion Cir Ct
<lb/>$500 } Faro
<lb/>Jno. L St.Clair</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-07-22">July 22. 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
