<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1603"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">D. R. Haggard to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6240</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-42</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-03-23">23 March 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville <date when="1865-03-23">March 23<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi></p>
<p>To Satisfy your mind more clearly that this man J. V. Gilbert is an honest truthful. and persecuted man, hunted down. by Some fellows who are either hired by those <hi rend="underline">Faro Dealers</hi> -- or running him for the hope of making Something out of <hi rend="str">th</hi> him because other men who make a living -- by the trade of Gambling are paying, to be let alone -- or that Gilbert will be constrained to pay those fellows hush-money -- as a proof of what I say is true the second Indictment was dismissed upon a simple statement of the facts in the case. The first Case he did deal faro. and he will not deny the fact -- but will not do<pb/>
<lb/>again as I believe -- It is certain that if you can concienciously release him it will be a real disappointment. to those fellows who have concluded they can make him come to Terms -- <hi rend="underline">These days</hi> have developed. other things besides <hi rend="underline">He</hi>. The problem of making money -- has taken the course of the Irish fathers advice to his Son only intensfied -- to Stealing instead a cheating -- It is not according to the principle of strick Etiquette -- probably in the Executive of a great Commonwealth to respond to petitioners -- or petitions but -- Gilbert must feel some anxiety <hi rend="str">as</hi> if not soon released his collateral will go into the pockets of the hungry fellows. that on pursuing him -- Drop me a line which shall be strickly for my own Eye</p>
<p>D R Haggard</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
