<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3377"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George E. Funk and J. S. Rouse to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5496</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-242</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Henderson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> of Ky.</p>
<p>We the undersigned most respectfully petition you to grant to Geo W Shryock a remission of several fines that were adjudged against him in the Henderson Circut Court at its <date when="1864-06">June term 1864</date>- to wit- one fine for keeping a gaming house -- $200&amp; -- again for the same offence $200<hi rend="sup">x</hi> again for keeping a tippling house $50<hi rend="sup">x</hi></p>
<p>There are also pending against s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Shryock nine other indictments, preferred at <date when="1864-06">June term of s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Court 1864</date>- to wit-
<lb/>one for keeping disorderly house
<lb/>Do " Assault &amp; battery
<lb/>Do " Suffering gaming in his house
<lb/>Six " Selling liquor to a slave.</p>
<p>At the time s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Shryock was charged with these misdemeanors, this county was in a condition of general disorder. The civil law was in effect suspened- the country full of guerrillas, bands of ruffians, soldier, white &amp; black- &amp; all society disturbed. In consideration of the then state of affairs, we think the misconduct of any citizen should be judged with more forbearance &amp; lenity than of committed in the time of peace &amp; order. We think there should now be forgiveness &amp; amnesty for the misdeeds of the war, and as s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Shryock is old, extremely poor, &amp; broken down in health, we the undersigned, being his neighbors, urge your excellency to grant<pb/>
<lb/>when a remission of all penalties under the before mentioned indictments, he having given us the assurance, which we accept, that in future he will demean himself as a good citizen. If not granted relief by your excellency, he must be imprisoned, &amp; his frail health would support him <hi rend="str">the</hi> but a brief period. ^in confinement.^ We beg you to extend this mercy to an unfortunate fellow citizen-</p>
<p>Henderson
<lb/>Ky:
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="3"/><cb n="1"/><hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>
<lb/>Geo E. Funk
<lb/>J. S. Rouse</p>
<p>Since the signing of the above, G W Shyrock has been arrested, &amp; is now in the Jail of the County. The Govr. will please direct his response to this petition to J. S. Rouse</p>
<p>Henderson Ky
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Jas Manion sr
<lb/>James Manion Fr
<lb/>James B Harrison
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> R. Long
<lb/>D. H. Sartain
<lb/>Bryant y Murphy
<lb/>John White
<lb/>Charles Zoham
<lb/>J W Canam
<lb/>W. T. Clinger
<lb/>J. H. Shackelford
<lb/>Charles Hape
<lb/>Daniel Altmire
<lb/>Elaxander munro.
<lb/>John McBee
<lb/>Solomon Coker
<lb/>Jefferson Pack
<lb/>J E Gregory
<lb/>N H Griffin
<lb/>Y. L. Williams
<lb/>W. L. Imbler
<lb/>John. McLellan
<lb/><cb n="3"/>Lewis, Hape
<lb/>James Stewart
<lb/>P. T. Scheron
<lb/>Benjamin Burkop
<lb/>John Shepard
<lb/>H Shepperd
<lb/>A C Bryan
<lb/>John Baskett
<lb/>Hilrey Baskett
<lb/>Charles Clay
<lb/>Sam<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Hopkins
<lb/>E Saml Lin
<lb/>G W Grant
<lb/>J. L. Yager
<lb/><unclear/> Griffin</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
