<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0502"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Claton et al. to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8954</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-299 to R4-300</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>James F. Robinson Governor of Kentucky. -- </p>
<p>The undersigned Citizens of Louisville Kentucky would make an appeal to your Excellency on behalf of the wife &amp; family for the Pardon of Frederick Yanner who is now &amp; has been for Four years past confined in the Penetentiary of Kentucky, being convicted and sentenced for Ten years in the Jefferson Circuit Court on the charge of an attempt to commit a Rape on his Step Daughter Anna Smith then under Fourteen years of age, Yanner had been for several years previous to this charge addicted to habits of very great Intemperance in drinking and had become so much reduced &amp; his Physical Energies so much destroyed as to render it very Improbable that he would attempt to commit such an offense &amp; particularly on a child under his care and protection. On the night the offence is charged to have been committed the Mother of Anna left her and Yanner at the house. He being beastly Intoxicated &amp; lying on the floor and Anna &amp; a younger sister on the bed &amp; asleep. And on the return of the Mother, Yanners wife; Anna made the charge &amp; he was arrested tried &amp; convicted Anna being the principal &amp; only witness, some proof was made that the child had marks of violence on her person, Indicating that such an attempt had been made, but whether by Yanner or some one who came into the<pb/>
<lb/>house in the Mothers absence &amp; while Yanner lay drunken &amp; helpless on the floor is matter of doubt, The child was asleep &amp; in her alarm at the attempt made &amp; the drunken step father being aroused by her cries, she may have supposed the wrong was done by him while the Guilty party Escaped in the Darkness. Yanners wife has by her Labor supported herself &amp; two Daughters since his Imprisonment she is now in feeble health &amp; we think it would be right &amp; proper under the circumstances that he should be released. We hope his Long confinement has destroyed the appetite for strong drink &amp; that he will hereafter by his Labor aid in the support of his family -- </p>
<p>Thomas Claton
<lb/>Joseph Jacob
<lb/>Mahail Diez
<lb/>H Link
<lb/>Y Tack
<lb/>E Matz
<lb/>John Bukurt<pb/></p>
<p>Upon a further examination of this case some additional details and upon full conversation and corroboration with Capt Todd taking into consideration the past comportment of Frederick Yanner and paralized &amp; hopeless physical condition I have concluded that policy <unclear/> and probably <unclear/> will be <unclear/> by <unclear/> pardon and do herefore grant him a pardon as prayed for</p>
<p>J F Robinson</p>
<p>Frd. Yanner of Louisville Pettn for Pardon</p>
<p>I cannot find in this Pettn &amp; evidence <hi rend="underline"><unclear/></hi> or <hi rend="underline">safe</hi> grounds in which to interfere in the verdict of the Jury</p>
<p>J F Robinson</p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>F. Yanner
<lb/>10 yrs. Penty.
<lb/>Rape
<lb/>Pardon Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi>
<lb/><date when="1863-08-07">Aug. 7. 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
