<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0530"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. R. Duncan to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8982</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-340 to R4-341</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Winchester, Clark County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-08-03">3 August 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Winchester Ky
<lb/><date when="1863-08-03">Aug 3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> 1863</date>,
<lb/>To His Excellency James F Robinson
<lb/>Govenor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner W. R. Duncan respectfully represents that a Judgement was rendered against him at the <date when="1863-07">July term of the Clarke Circuite Court 1863</date> for the sum of thirty four dollars for standing a Jack in said County during the season of <date when="1862">1862</date> without license, The facts of the case are as follows. On the fourth Monday of Aprile and about the time I commenced <unclear/>ing the Jack he being but a colt that I had bred myself, and not intending to let him to but a few moves &amp; steped into the clerks office for the purpose of geting my license finding him much ingaged at the time and relying on our intimacy and long acquaintance &amp; requested him to issue them at his leasure and I would send him the money so soon as he did so I became ingaged in buisness and forgot to call for them again. He forgot my request and failed to issue them, At the <date when="--05">May</date> term of the of the Court the License Book was sent to the grand Jury soon without my name in the mean time my attention was called to the fact by the Clerk, I at once reminded him of my request but it was then too late to put my name on the Book. I took out Licence however paid for them and<pb/>
<lb/>and had them in my pocket before the Grand Jury made the inditement, I have long been a citizen of the County without violating any Law of the state intentionally in my life. The Judgement was by defalt as I was sick and not in Court at the time it was rendered</p>
<p>Under all the circunmstances of the case I most respectfully request a remission of the Judgement. <hi rend="str">The Judgement being for thirty four dollars</hi></p>
<p>W, R, Duncan</p>
<p>We concur with the petitoner W P, Duncan in his request for remission of the foregoing Judgement and hope the same may be granted</p>
<p>C Egenton
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H G Bush
<lb/>A. H. Buckner.
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Theo</hi>dore Kohlhass<pb/></p>
<p>Clarke Cir. Ct</p>
<p>Pettn W. R. Duncan to remit fine</p>
<p>$34 } Standing Jack
<lb/>Fine Remitted
<lb/>J F Robinson
<lb/>W R. Duncan
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-08-05">Aug 5. 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
