<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1051"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Dishman to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10519</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-138 to MG20-139</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Perry County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-05-17">17 May 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Perry Court House
<lb/><date when="1861-05-17">May 17<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Dear Gov</p>
<p>Jesse Combs jr. was fined sixty Dollars at this term of the perry circuit court for keeping a Tipling House, He plead guilty He was innocently guilty, but according to a Law a case was presented that He was bound to be fined -- It is one of those cases that the fine should be remitted, He Had no intention of violating Law -- did it through a misapprehension of the Effect of the Law -- The whole community would like to see the fine remitted -- I am satisfied that it should be remitted -- Mr Combs is a man in very moderate circumstances, the payment of the fine be of more injury to Him then it would do the Comlth good -- </p>
<p>Please remit the same and oblige
<lb/>Your obt Servt
<lb/>John Dishman<pb/></p>
<p>Respite 12 mo
<lb/>B, M
<lb/>Perry Cir. Ct
<lb/>$<hi rend="str">2</hi>60 } Tipling
<lb/>Jesse Combs
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-08-14">Aug 14. 1861</date><pb/></p>
<p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Gov. of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned your petitioners would most respectfully represent, that at the Present term of the perry circuit court, that Jesse Combs jr was fined the sum of sixty-Dollars for keeping a Tipling House -- They would further state that the same was not done wth any intention to violate law, but the same was done inadvertanly believing that He Had a Lisence to sell, but the same did not cover the House in which He sold -- and was consequently Indicted and fined -- </p>
<p>Now the undersigned, in consequence thereof and in consideration of the Hard times, and the fact that Mr. Combs is a young man with a young wife, and striving to make an Honest support for Himself and family -- and is a man that wishes to see the Laws of the <hi rend="underline">State</hi> Executed, and Has no disposition to violate the same -- we citizens of Perry county would most respectfully ask a remission of the fine -- </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>names
<lb/>E. F. Hogg -- 
<lb/>Andrew. Combs. Judge of,, ^Perry C. C.^
<lb/>J H Combs
<lb/>John S Combs
<lb/>John forbes
<lb/>S. P. Hogg <hi rend="underline">Exam</hi>
<lb/>John B Combs.
<lb/>Hezekiah Combs Shff. P. C
<lb/><cb n="2"/>names
<lb/>R. C. Combs
<lb/>Elijah Combs
<lb/>John Baker
<lb/>H. C. Hogg
<lb/>Jas, B Fitzpatrick
<lb/>Jas Godsy
<lb/>Jeremiah Combs
<lb/>Mathias Lewis<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>names
<lb/>G. W. Morgan
<lb/><cb n="2"/>names</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
