<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3333"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James H. White to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5452</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-172 to BR42-173</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To the Governor of Kentucky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>I am put to the painful necessity of appealing to you to protect me from what I am constrained to believe is rebel vindictiveness and hatred. In <date when="1861">1861</date> I entered the Volunteer Army of the United States as a private in Co B 28<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky Inf. Col W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> <hi rend="str">B</hi> Boone, was Elected Captain of the Company upon the organization of the regiment and served with the regiment in that capacity until <date when="1862-11">November 1862</date>, when I was compelled to resign on account of ill-health. I returned to my home in Louisville and upon regaining my health I again enlisted in the Federal service in the 37<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Mounted Inf and was soon made Captain of my Company. With this regiment I served until it's muster-out. After this I received a Commission as 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Lieut from your Excellency of Co E 55<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky Mounted Inf in which capacity I served, under orders from the Commander of the Dept. of Kentucky, in the County of Carroll in this state during the time just preceding and after the <date when="1865-08">August Election<pb/>
<lb/>1865</date>. Your Excellency is well aware of the orders which emanated from the Head Quarters of the Department of Kentucky just before that Election and in reference thereto. Under these orders &amp; by special instruction from Maj Silas Howe I was at Ghent in Carroll County on Election day and with as much mildness as was possible obeyed the orders of my superiors and in doing so made some arrests. I remained at the polls myself but did not allow my command about them; and I did, where I had sufficient proof of a man's disability under the state laws, prevent some from voting. The name of one man who had voted was erased but this was not by me or my order, notwithstanding, as I learn, it appears on the poll books: "Erased by order of Capt White". For obedience to the orders of my superiors I have been indicted in the Carroll Circuit Court and am now under bail for my appearance there on the <date when="--08">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of it, next August term</date>. Having given a faithful service to my County and Government and knowing the people of that section of the state to be thoroughly disloyal, I feel assured<pb/>
<lb/>that any trial of me in that circuit would be one only in name; that it would be but a Mockery and that I should be disgraced by a conviction and sentence to the state prison. This, for the sake of my wife and young family, I would by all means avert, and therefore appeal to you to protect me from persecution for acts honestly and faithfully done and performed in the line of duty and obedience to orders. My service in the State was not without honor as your Excellency will see from the two appended papers, the one from the Executive dept of Ky and issued by yourself and the other an order from Gen Hobson Comd<hi rend="sup">g</hi> 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Div Dis<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Ky. The acts for which I am now indicted as above were done and performed by me in the same Spirit and were actuated by the same motives as those for which I received the commendatory notices appended hereto.</p>
<p>I ask, Governor, to be relieved from the necessity of submitting myself to a trial under the indictment afores<hi rend="sup">d</hi></p>
<p>I am very respectfully
<lb/>Your Excellency's obt servt.
<lb/>James.H. White<pb/></p>
<p>Gov Bramlette:</p>
<p>It affords me much pleasure in reccommending Capt White to you. I have known him long and well as a private citizen and know too, that he was a gallant soldier. I have little doubt that Secession venom is at the bottom of the prosecution inaugurated against him in the Carver Circuit Court. The Judge &amp; Com<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">ths</hi></hi> atty should protect him, but as in many other instances, they are not doing what it seems to me they ought to do in order that we might have a restored peace- drop all these prosecutions growing out of the late civil strife I trust you will forward Capt White a full pardon</p>
<p>I am very truly
<lb/>Your friend
<lb/>Jo. G. Wilson</p>
<p>Gov Bramlette</p>
<p>Having personal experience of your prompt action in favor of those who have done good &amp; faithful service in the field during the war for the oppression of the accursed Rebellion, I earnestly appeal to you, in favor of the pardon of Capt. White. He raised Company B, 28 Regt. Ky. infty vol. and was an officer of my Regt. discharging his duties with marked efficiency and gallantry until his health became so impaired as to compel his resignation. He should not be now, sacrificed for obeying orders of his commanding officer</p>
<p>Very truly your friend
<lb/>W. P. Boone<pb/>
<lb/>HEAD-QUARTERS FIRST DIV. DISTRICT OF KY.,
<lb/>LEXINGTON, KY., <date when="1864-04-28">April 28th, 1864</date>. }</p>
<p>GENERAL ORDERS,
<lb/>No. 6. }</p>
<p>The thanks of the General commanding are due Captain White, 37th Kentucky Mounted Infantry, for the gentlemanly conduct of himself and men, and the prompt manner in which they discharged their duties while lately on detached service at Harrodsburg.</p>
<p>Several notices have been received from the citizens of that place testifying to the conduct of the soldiers while quartered in the town.</p>
<p>The General commanding hopes that he may have the pleasure of noticing the soldierly bearing of many ofhis officers hereafter.</p>
<p>BY ORDER OF BRIG. GEN. E. H. HOBSON,
<lb/>J. S. BUTLER,
<lb/>Assistant Adjutant General.<pb/>
<lb/>EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENT,
<lb/><hi rend="italic">Frankfort, Ky., </hi><date when="1864-04-24"><hi rend="italic">April</hi> 24, 1864</date>.</p>
<p>As the Chief Executive of the State, I thank Capt. White for the prompt and efficient action taken by him to support the civil authorities by arresting these lawless and violent men. He has performed the duties of a good soldier and citizen, and I trust his commanding General, under whose order he proceeded to act, will take proper notice of his meritorious conduct.</p>
<p>THOS. E. BRAMLETTE,
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
