<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-023-0097"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Daniel Gano et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG3010</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG1-325</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency B -- Magoffin:
<lb/>GOVERNOR OF THE COMMONWEALTH OF KENTUCKY.</p>
<p>WE, the undersigned, citizens and legal voters of the Commonweath of Kentucky, in view of the fact that the present General Assembly was elected nearly two years ago, and neither does, nor can fairly represent the opinions of the people with regard to the questins at present agitating the public mind, upon which questions the opinions of the people must have been formed since the election of their present representatives, respectfully represent unto your Excellency that by the Constitution established by our representatives, and ratified by us, it is explicitly declared that it is one of the general, great and essential principles of liberty and free government, "that the people have at all times an unalienable, and indefensible right to alter, reform and abolish, their government in such manner as they think proper, -- that this inalienable right does not in any degree depend for its existence on the will of the legislative, or other departments of the government; that although the Legislature as well as other departments of the Government ought at all times to submit to the fairly and explicitly declared will of the people, yet their consent is never necessary to confer validity or legality upon the action of the people, that on the contrary, it is eminently proper that in imminent and extraordinary exigencies the measures to be adopted should originate directly with and eminate directly from the people themselves -- and that the proper agent in effectuating the will of the people is the Chief Executive officer of the Government.</p>
<p>Therefore, as citizens and legal voters, we respectfully present to your Excellency this Petition, and whensoever the same shall appear to be the expression of the people in the State, we require you to recognize it as the expression of the will of the sovereign people of the Commonwealth; and therefore we authorize and direct you to issue writs of election for members of a Convention, to meet at the Capitol in Frankfort on some day to be fixed by you, as soon as conveniently may be -- the voters in each district entitled to elect a representative in the lower branch of the next General Assembly, to elect one member in order and to the end that the people of Kentucky may, but their representatives, meet and consult together upon the condition of the Commonwealth, and adopt such measures as may be by them deemed necessary for the assertion, maintenance, and protection of their rights, interests, and honor.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="3"/><cb n="1"/>NAMES.
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Daniel</hi> <hi rend="underline">Gano</hi>
<lb/>Roy Orton
<lb/>G. W. Abel
<lb/>John, Jones
<lb/>Johnathan Baley
<lb/>J M Warring
<lb/>G W Warring
<lb/>Ed Warring
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Culin
<lb/>John Barron
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> Shembrey</hi>
<lb/>S F Brown
<lb/><hi rend="underline">H Tucker</hi>
<lb/>E McKenny
<lb/>James S Moore
<lb/>K H Tish - - -
<lb/>Jas. Offutt
<lb/>Jas. Tucker
<lb/>Richard M Pivent
<lb/>M, Truitt
<lb/>James Taylor
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> <hi rend="str">T</hi>Steackdele
<lb/><cb n="2"/>NAMES.
<lb/>Simeson Griffee
<lb/>Wm. D. Whitton
<lb/>John Crittenden
<lb/>John True
<lb/>E, H, Southwatt
<lb/>James Griffith
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi>, Palmer
<lb/>C S Rice
<lb/>J, H, Covington
<lb/>J, G, Harrison
<lb/>D K Gorham
<lb/>Minor Powel
<lb/>Reuben <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>Breden
<lb/>Bloomfield Johnson
<lb/>Harry Wolf
<lb/>O. Anderson
<lb/>D. Thomson
<lb/>John. Boman
<lb/>Sam. Channing
<lb/>Isaack Kirby
<lb/>Wm southwork
<lb/>D. H. Whitton
<lb/>John Burows
<lb/><cb n="3"/>NAMES.
<lb/>A E Stockwell
<lb/>B, T, Griffith
<lb/>B Alson
<lb/>J J, Browning
<lb/>J G Browning
<lb/>W, R Burows
<lb/>John Zusing
<lb/>P, H, Southworth
<lb/>Robt D Jones
<lb/>E, M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>bee
<lb/>J, W, Alsop
<lb/>D, C, Backbel
<lb/>Jas, Will
<lb/>John Jones
<lb/>D, S, Alsop
<lb/>John Tornny
<lb/>Thos. R Stockdell
<lb/>P, Fightmaster
<lb/>Wm N Penn</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
