<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0176"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Hugh L. Murphy to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9644</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-112 to MG17-113</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Knox County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-11-09">9 November 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Beriah Magoffin, Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>The undersigned your petitioner would respectfully represent that at the <date when="1855-09">Sept term 1855</date> ^of the Knox Circuit Court^ he was indicted ^in two cases^ for Keeping a Tippling house in conjunction with F. M. Goins and at the <date when="1856-03">March term 1856</date> of said Court being advised and believing they could not properly be fined in as much as they were not guilty of a breach of the law they submitted the cases to the court and were fined -- They then petitioned His Excellency C. S. Morehead then Governor of Ky to remit said fines -- He remitted one of the fines against each of them and respited the other for one year on or about the <date when="1859-06-04">4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of June 1856</date>. Each of us has previously replevied said fines so that they can now be made -- But the matter has slumbered from that day until the last few days when ^to our great surprise^ an execution was issued and is now in the hands of the sheriff, and we think it would be a great hardship on us to pay it. The circumstances are these H. S. Vincent was living in &amp; occupying some houses on Cumberland Mountain including the little house in which the Liquor was sold and which had always been occupied as a Grocery by those occupying the houses he was living in and has been ever since<pb/>
<lb/>although it is not on the same lot. It has always been considered a part of the residence &amp; was so placed that the family would not be too much annoyed -- Vincent at the <date when="1855-02">Feb. Term 1855</date> of the Knox County Court obtained license to Keep a tavern in the same premises -- Vinsant and Murphy &amp; Goins were all interested in the Grocery which was Kept under Vinsants license -- a copy of the order gra^n^ting it is herewith referred to as part hereof. The circuit courts generally in 1856 were of the opinion that a man must have his Grocery under the same roof with the house in which the Tavern Keeper lived and hence they were fined. Hoping your excellency may give this matter a favorable consideration and remit the fine he prays in Mercy. <date when="1860-11-09">Nov <hi rend="str">8</hi>9. 1860</date>.</p>
<p>Hugh, L, Murphy
<lb/>Knox County SS.</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Hugh L. Murphy</p>
<p>John C Colson J. P.
<lb/><date when="1860-11-10">Nov <hi rend="str">9</hi>10<hi rend="sup">th</hi>. 1860</date>.</p>
<p>To His Excellency Beriah Magoffin Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner F. M Goins says he endorses the foregoing as a true statement of his case and prays that his fine be remitted. <date when="1860-11">Nov 1860</date></p>
<p>F. M. Goins</p>
<p>Knox County S S.</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by F. M. Goins <date when="1860-11-09">Nov 9 1860</date>.<pb/></p>
<p>John C Colson J, P.</p>
<p>Henry L. Vinsant says that at the time he obtained license to Keep Tavern <date when="1855-02">Feb term 1855</date> of the Knox County Court he was occupying the buildings, including the Grocery on Cumberland Mountain where Murphy &amp; Goins sold liquor &amp; were indicted for it at the <date when="1855-09">Sept term 1855</date> of the Knox Circuit Court -- That he was during that time intoxicated with them in the Grocery -- That the liquor was sold under his license -- That he had obtained the house with the expectation of having a Grocery kept in that house -- That it was then, had been &amp; now is customary for those occupying those buildings to carry on or to have carried on in that house a Grocery.</p>
<p>Henry L Vinsant</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by H. L. Vinsant <date when="1860-11-10">Nov 10th 1860</date></p>
<p>John C Colson J. P.</p>
<p>We the undersigned respectfully ask your Excellency to remit the fines of Goins &amp; Murphy as asked in their petitions.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> L Evans
<lb/>Jas, C, See
<lb/>John Parton
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Turner
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John G. Eve
<lb/>G. M. Adams J<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi>
<lb/>Frank Catson
<lb/>John C. Colson<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Wm H Baughman
<lb/>William Turner
<lb/>Spencer King
<lb/>John Sumner
<lb/>Josiah Rains
<lb/>C turner</p>
<p>Knox Cir. Ct
<lb/>Respited 12 mo 
<lb/>B, M
<lb/>$60. } Tipling
<lb/>H. L. Murphy
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1860-11-22">Nov 22. 1860</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
