<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0568"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Philip D. Yeiser to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9020</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-401</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>We have held a very pleasant court at Blandville -- It is true a few Judges of election were indicted for refusing to record votes for certain men -- but I am sure no prejudice was brought to bear &amp; I am sure too they will never suffer -- but our laws are on the books -- Now my object in writing is to say that I very much fear that thr<hi rend="sup">o</hi> -- such men as Tom Red &amp; Conner the military here will attempt to exercise such dictation over us as to break up this court -- Will you see Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Robinson at once and get him to write to Co<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Ranson at this place to in no manner interfere with our courts -- I am sure if we are left to carry it on ourselves we, will bring it all out right &amp; in fact unless the law books are destroyed such is bound to be the case ultimately &amp; it cant be avoided unless Indiana &amp; Illinois by forces force us to alter our laws &amp; I think in many instances they manifest a disposition to dominance but I'm unacquainted with Col Ransom<pb/>
<lb/>however ^of^ our provost Marshall Capt Dawn I have a high opinion -- Yet is is undeniable that with those commanders heretofore with an exception or two they appear to think &amp; act on it that Kentucky laws dont suit them -- For God sake let our courts go on without Military dictation or else we cannot &amp; will not hold court</p>
<p>Yours &amp;c
<lb/>P D Yeiser</p>
<p>write me at <unclear/>
<lb/>Yeiser</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
