<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1707"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Charles P. Utz to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6344</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-196 to BR13-197</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-04-10">10 April 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Covington <date when="1865-04-10">Apl. 10<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi>. 1865</date>
<lb/>To.
<lb/>Hon Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E. Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky
<lb/>Frankfort</p>
<p>The undersigned Petitioner Charles. Utz. respectfully represents that at the <date when="1864-12">Dec. Term of the Kenton circuit court 186<hi rend="str">3</hi>4</date> he was indicted in six separate cases each being of similar character charging substantially that the s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> petitioner had acted as Insurance agent of the Lorillard Ins. Co. of New York and as such had insured property in Kenton County without having first secured a License from the Auditer of the state of Kentucky The cases are numbered 913. 914 915. 916. 917. &amp; 918. at the <date when="1865-03">March</date> term of the s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Court upon the cases being called for trial no. 916. was tried &amp; upon the introduction of the License of this Petitioner the Court allowed the Commonwealth <hi rend="str">was allowed</hi> to dismiss the same &amp; upon the Examination of all the other<pb/>
<lb/>causes they were all ordered to be dismissed as all of the Policies represented in them were issued subsequent to his License with the exception of no. 917. &amp; this one on examination was found to have been issued a few days before his License he having unwittingly issued a policy for the small premium of $2<hi rend="sup">50</hi>/<hi rend="sub">100</hi> in this Last case Petitioner confessed Judgt. &amp; was fined the smallest sum allowed to-wit $<hi rend="underline">100</hi>= Petitioner says that he is a German &amp; upon being appointed agent supposed he had the right to Insure as he had understood that the company had complied with the Law -- Petitioner says that he had no desire to do anything contrary to the Laws of Kentucky &amp; asks that so much of his fine exclusive of costs be remitted</p>
<p>Chas. P. Utz.</p>
<p>State of Ohio Ham. co } Sct,</p>
<p>Subscribed &amp; sworn to by Chas Utz before me this <date when="1865-04-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Apl. 1865</date></p>
<p>P <unclear>DeKalb</unclear>
<lb/>Notary Public</p>
<p><figure type="seal"><ab>NOTARY SEAL
<lb/>HAMILTON COUNTY O</ab></figure><pb/></p>
<p>I acted as attorney for Mr Chas. Utz in the causes referred to in this petition &amp; am satisfied that he has stated the truth</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">M. J</hi>. <hi rend="underline">Dudley</hi></p>
<p>I think the facts &amp; circumstances as set out in the foregoing petition are Substantially correct, and believe it would be an act of simple justice to grant the relief Sought</p>
<p>A C Ellis D C
<lb/>of Kenton Cir Court.
<lb/>U T Chambers atty
<lb/>H. F. Bowen. Sheriff
<lb/>J. S. Scott D. S.
<lb/>A. H. Herod Jailor
<lb/>J. R. Hallam
<lb/>J. G. Carlisle
<lb/>J. P. Harrison<pb/></p>
<p>Kenton Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Charles Utz
<lb/>Petition<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>$100 -- 
<lb/>Remit<hi rend="sup">d</hi>
<lb/><date when="1865-04-13">13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Apl/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
