<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2178"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James W. Thompson et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6815</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-414 to BR14-415</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Carter County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>We the undersigned petitioners of Carter County would respectfully represent to his Excellency Thomas E. Bramlette Govrenor of the state of Kentucky. that whereas one William Kitchen of said County has been fined the Sum of Three Hundred dollars upon an indictment in the Carter circuit court for a breach of a tavern license -- </p>
<p>Now we would respectfully represent to your Excellency that Said William Kitchen is a good citizen of Carter County a hard working industrious man and one whom we believe never knowingly or intentionly violated the law. That at the time of the trial his family was Sick and a child died during the term of the court at which the case was tried which prevented him from attending court and advising with his lawyer and giving his case any attention whatever -- </p>
<p>The case was urged for trial by the Commonwealth's atty. and the defendant for the reasons above stated not being present, and his attorney not being able to make good grounds for a continuance was forced into trial<pb/>
<lb/>which resulted in a verdict against the defendant -- We think it a case deserving Executive clemency and therefore respectfully petition your Excellency to remit Said fine and as dutiful citizens will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/><cb n="1"/>Jas W Thompson
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Bowling
<lb/>Geo. W. Prichard
<lb/>John,, T, Shepherd P, M
<lb/>Charles Stewart
<lb/>B. F. Crawford
<lb/>E, P, Davis
<lb/>Wylee Prichard
<lb/>John. N, Hood
<lb/>J. B. Ward
<lb/>A. J. Scott
<lb/>R D. Womack
<lb/>A Rucker
<lb/>James Stewart
<lb/>E.. Savage
<lb/>William B Faulkner
<lb/>W R Shepherd
<lb/>J R Strother
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> D Jones
<lb/>James M Chrisman
<lb/>R M Jones
<lb/>Wm,, Hill
<lb/>Gabriel parsons
<lb/>Thomas W Sons
<lb/>A M Bellow
<lb/>Jo<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> M <unclear>Plummer</unclear>
<lb/><cb n="2"/>(I am well acquainted with Mr W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Kitchen of Carter County he is a good loyal citizen I also know the Signers to the within Petition. they are the neighbors of M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Kitchen, and from what I learn this is a case that requires Executive Clemency. I hope you may find it such a case as will relieve Mr Kitchen from the fine</p>
<p>Yours &amp;c
<lb/>A Trumbo<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Byrd Burchett
<lb/>Stephen, Nethercott
<lb/>James ,H, Womack
<lb/>J Havins Strother
<lb/>J M Summers
<lb/>B S Stephens S, C, C(
<lb/>J W. Hudgins
<lb/>Flemmon, Sammons
<lb/>Thos W Banfield
<lb/>John H Burchett
<lb/>James N Barnes
<lb/>H. W. Thomson
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>John P. Stephens
<lb/>Willis Deal
<lb/>William Lewis
<lb/>William Deal
<lb/>Moses Hord
<lb/>A J Lansdowne
<lb/>Richard.P. Flynn
<lb/>Elihu Boggs
<lb/>John galyhew
<lb/>William Kibbey Jr
<lb/>James A Seaton
<lb/>G. W. Crawford<pb/></p>
<p>Carter Cir Ct
<lb/>vs.
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Kitchen
<lb/>$300,
<lb/>breach Tavern license
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1865-08-08">8 Aug/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
