<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2391"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Edmund B. Chapman to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7028</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-318 to BR15-319</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Russell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-20">20 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To Thomas E. Bramlette Esq Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky Your petitioner Edmund B Chapman States that about on the <gap/> day of <gap/> 1865 One John Padgett was arrested by virtue of a Bench Warrant issued by the Clerk of the Clinton Circuit Court charged with a Felony and Committed to jail of Clinton County and was afterward (towit) on the <date when="1865-07-10">10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of July 1865</date> bailed out by your petitioner ^as security^ on the sum of $300 they executing the proper bail bond for the appearance of said Padgett on the first day of the next <date when="--08">August</date> Term of said Circuit Court which was held on the <gap/> Monday in <date when="1865-08">August 1865.</date> Your petitioner States that after the execution of said bail bond said Padgett returned to the County of Russell in which County he resided at the time, where he staid for a short time and without the Knowledge or Consent or approbation of your petitioner departed and left the Commonwealth of Kentucky for parts unknown to your petitioner -- and utterly failed and neglected to enter his appearance according to the condition of his said Bond and in fullfilment of his solemn pledges made to your petitioner And at the said <date when="--08">August</date> Term of said Clinton Circuit Court said bond was declared forfeited and a Summons awarded thereon and he (your petitioner) will be Compelled to pay the same. Your petitioner further States that he is a man of small means and a large and helpless family who are dependent<pb/>
<lb/>upon his daily labour upon a farm for Support He further States that if he had had the least Suspicion that said Padgett did not intend to stand his trial after he had bailed him out, he would have had him arrested and delivered up to the jailer of Clinton County but said Padgett at and before the execution of said bond and at all times <hi rend="str">she</hi> he conversed with him after its execution pledged his sacred word. and honor and evry thing he held <hi rend="str">dear</hi> near and dear to him, that he would ^appear^ in discharge of said bond thereby fraudulently deceiving your petitioner and throwing him off his guard -- The premises Considered your petitioner respectfully asks your excellency to interpose and remit said fine or forfeiture and as in duty &amp;c</p>
<p>Edmund ^his X mark^ B Chapman</p>
<p>Sworn to &amp; Subscribed by Edmund B. Chapman before me an Examiner for Russell County this <date when="1865-09-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Day of September 1865</date></p>
<p>George Bryan Exam R C</p>
<p>We the undersigned <hi rend="str">Subscr</hi> residents of Russell County respectfully ask the Governor of Kentucky to remit the forfeiture Mentioned &amp; set forth in the foregoing petition of Edmund B Chapman</p>
<p><date when="1865-09-20">Septr 20 1865</date>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>George Bryan
<lb/>Jas. L Willoughby
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Andrew Mcgown
<lb/>G W. Twidwell
<lb/>M D Hopper
<lb/><hi rend="str">Isham <unclear/></hi><pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>I defended Padgett He was arrested &amp; tried before the county Judge of Clinton Cty. as an Examing Court &amp; sent to further trial &amp; sent to Jail in default of bail and afterwards bailed by your petitioner Chapman. The proof was that Padgett was with a company some of whom took a horse but the proof positively was by Craft the owner of the horse and others that Padget neither said nor done any thing in the matter &amp; did not go to the stable. I thought Padget would appear because I had honestly advised him that there could not be a conviction without more proof. Chapman is a hard working honest citizen I think</p>
<p>Joseph E. Hays
<lb/>Green Moore
<lb/>H O Bolin
<lb/>Abner Jones
<lb/>A, L, Coffey
<lb/>N. G Wells
<lb/>A, C, Wells
<lb/>W Jones
<lb/>Theo Jones
<lb/>Samuel Lippins
<lb/>Phillip Lawless
<lb/>A A Williams
<lb/>C. R. Coffey
<lb/>R S Pierce
<lb/>W. L. Bagarly
<lb/>John Chapman
<lb/>Lewis Baley<pb/></p>
<p>Russell Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>E. B. Chapman
<lb/>$300
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/><date when="1865-12-11">11<hi rend="sup">th </hi>Dec /65</date>
<lb/>Remit</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
