<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0515"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">S. B. Vance and John Young Brown to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8967</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-319</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Henderson, Henderson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-08-18">18 August 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Henderson <date when="1863-08-18">Aug 18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>J. F. Robinson
<lb/>Sir:</p>
<p>At the <date when="--12">Dec<hi rend="sup">r</hi></date> term of the Henderson Circuit Court, Benj Singleton was tried under the charge of grand larceny, &amp; the jury, failing to agree, he was bailed in the sum of $500 -- Milton Young dec<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> becoming his surety. He failed to appear at the <date when="1863-06">June term 1863</date>, in discharge of his bond, &amp; it was taken as forefeited.</p>
<p>Singleton, when indicted, was in the Federal service, having enlisted in Indiana, of which state he was a citizen, &amp; was a mere boy. His witnesses were members of his regiment. &amp; during the court at which he was tried, were removed from this county to Tennessee. On the trial a majority of the jury were in favor of his acquittal.</p>
<p>In Jany last, Milton Young, who became Singleton's surety from mere kindness -- died, whilst on his way to Frankfort, to attend the legislature, of which he was a member. a widow &amp; eleven children survive him, &amp; it will be a great hardship on them, if compelled to pay off this bond.</p>
<p>We think this a case that commends itself to your clemency, &amp; respectfully &amp; urgently entreat you to remit the forfeiture -- </p>
<p>Yr Obt Svts.
<lb/>S B Vance &amp; John Young Brown Adm<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> of Milton Young decd</p>
<p><note place="left margin">P S No Judgment has been rendered on the bond. &amp; the Com<hi rend="sup">lths</hi> Atty has no interest in it -- Resptfully V &amp;. B</note><pb/></p>
<p>Henderson Ky
<lb/><date when="1863-08-17">Aug. 17th 1863</date>
<lb/>Dr Governor</p>
<p>The facts in this case are correctly set forth in this letter -- I think the case one in which the executive should interfere -- I therefore respectfully request your Excellency to grant the relief asked</p>
<p>Your friend
<lb/>L W Powell</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
