<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2051"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. W. Colger, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6688</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-233 to BR14-234</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Simpson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-06-13">13 June 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Lincoln County Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1865-06-13">13<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">"</hi></hi> June AD 1865</date></p>
<p>The Affiant J W Colger states that he was 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">"</hi></hi> Lieutenant of Capt Brent Purkins Copay C in the 6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">"</hi></hi> Regiment of Kentucky Rebel Cavalry and as such left the state of Kentucky with Genl B Braggs Army in the fall of <date when="1862">1862</date> on the Cumberland Gap Road -- That he together with the Regiment were almost constantly in the rear of the army from the time Bragg Left the County of Lincoln until its arrival at Cumberland Gap -- that they the 6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">"</hi></hi> Kenty Rebel Cavalry never saw Capt Herbert King and the other prisoners from this and Casey County from the Commencement of the retreat of Brgg army to this dy as affiant knows or believes when affiant and his Copay -- and Regiment arrived at Cumberland we were informed that Capt King and his men had been hung by whom hung I know not but my Company was in the advance fall the ballence of our Regiment, 24 hours when we arrived at the place where said men were hung -- and it was impossible for any of the 6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">"</hi></hi> Kenty Cavalry to have been present at the Hanging of said Men as they must have been 25 or thirty miles from the place of Execution at the time it occurred. Capt King and his men as all were informed were hung the day before we arrived at the ford I do not remember whether we were informed whether Mississipians or Texans hung said Men -- but this I swear positively that none of the 6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">"</hi></hi> Kenty were present at the hanging or knew <unclear>anything</unclear> of it whatever until 24 hours after it was done<pb/>
<lb/>and that none of the Regiment Except Co C know of it until two days after the Men were hung -- John Myres of Capt Shanks Compny Come up with the ballenc of the Regiment to the ford 2 dys after the men were hung and -- Could not by any possibility have been present at the hanging or have Known anything whatever of it <date when="1865-06-13">13<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">"</hi></hi> June 1865</date> -- The menbers of our Regiment Universally Condemned as a great outrage and murder the hanging of Capt King &amp; his men -- 
<lb/>J. W. Colger
<lb/>Lt Co. "C" 6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky Cavalry</p>
<p>The affiant Thomas Shanks states that he was Captain of Co. B 6" Kenty Rebel Cavalry -- and in command of his compny and with the Regiment on the retreat of Braggs army from Kenty in the fall of <date when="1862">1862</date> -- he states that his Regmnt were in rear of Brggs Entire army from Craborchard on to Cumberland ford and were the rear guard of Brggs army The entire trip to the ford, he states that he nor none of his Compny saw Captain H. King or any of his men after the Command of the retreat from Danville, arose that his Copay did not arrive at Cumberland ford for two days after the Execution of Capt King and his men as he was informed when he got there, he said John Myres was with Compay the Entire Rout and never did see said persons after the Commencement of the retreat, and Could not have had any hand Either directly or indirectly in the hanging of said persons or any of them -- Every Man I think in our Entire Regiment Condemned the hanging of said personns in the most unmeasured Terms that I heard speak of the matter. <date when="1865-06-20">20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">"</hi></hi> June 1865</date>
<lb/>Thos H Shanks
<lb/>6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky Cav.<pb/></p>
<p>W P Crow states he was Lieutenant of Co B -- 6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">"</hi></hi> Regmnt of Kenty Rebel Cavalry and accompand same on the retreat of Genl Brgg from Kenty in the fall of <date when="1862">1862</date> from Kenty through Cumberland Gap that his Rgmt and Compny were the rear guard of Braggs Army from Craborchrd to Cumberland ford that when the 6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">"</hi></hi> arrived at the ford they were infmd that a part of Braggs -- infantry had two days previously hung Capt Herbert King and others of his command The Regiment and Compny of which I was a member Knew nothing whatever of the matter until two dys after the Execution -- John Myres was of my Compny with me at the time of the Execution knew nothing of it and did not aid in the same either directly or indiretly in any way -- <date when="1865-06-20">20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">"</hi></hi> June 1865</date> -- </p>
<p>W. P. Crow</p>
<p>I was Lieutenant of Co A 6" Kenty Rebel Cavalry have read the above affidavit of W P Crow and certify the statements of the same are true in Every particular -- <date when="1865-06-20">20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">"</hi></hi> June 1865</date> -- </p>
<p>J S. Hughes Jr</p>
<p>I was Capt of Co A 6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">"</hi></hi> Kenty Rebel Cavlry army now Co &amp; Regmnt from Craborchrd to Cumberland Gap Know and certify that the statements of Capt shanks &amp; Lieut Crow and Col Griggsby are true &amp; further that John Myres was with his Compny and knew nothing of the hanging of Capt King &amp; others until two days after the Execution is entirely innocent of the <unclear/> of Capt King &amp; his men had our Regment ben there they would never have been hung in my opinion</p>
<p>R. D. Logan</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
