<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0479"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James W. Crouch, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8931</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-266</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Edmonson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-07-14">14 July 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>James W. Crouch States, that he was presant at the time W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Age is charged with having sold Whisky in the Town of Brownsville and for which said Age, was fined Forty Dollars before the the Edmonson Equity &amp; Criminal Court. he states that the same took place upon the decision of meeting at the County Seat for the Purpose of comparing the Polls -- for an Election of County Officers -- that this affiant was Elected as Constable, the Rebels had heald posession for some time previous of Brownsville and at the request of this affiant said Age purchased Two Gallons of whiskey -- and took the Same to the Courty Seat, as there was no Liquor for sale in Said Town, and this witness and others requsted Age to buy, said Liquor to Town Stating that when he brought it this affiant and others would through in and pay what he had to pay for, the service. this they done though they did not pay the full amt. Age, throwing in the ballance, Age did not sell said Liquor did not by it to sell for proffit -- witness knows this to be the facts. and wittness heard the Testimony in this case and but one witness <hi rend="str">burden</hi> testified he saw money paid and he did not know whether it was thrown in or paid over as above Stated. this witness states that he lives a near neighbour to age, who lives 12 or 14 miles from the County Seat, at the first Term after he was Indited he was fined out at court but was not presant at the Term. this case was<pb/>
<lb/>tried and had no wittness Examined in his behalf and in a few days after trial wittness saw Age and informed him of the trial when Age -- appeared very much astounded and stated that he did not Know that Court was to sit at the time. Witness believes that Age would have attended and could have shown the facts as above had he not been mistaken as to the time of Court.</p>
<p>James W Crouch</p>
<p>Subscribed and Sworn to by James W Crouch this <date when="1863-07-14">14th July 1863</date></p>
<p>Aran Lawson C, E, C, C
<lb/></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
