<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-211-0033"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Isaac W. Scott, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG13681</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Adjt. Gen. &amp; QMG Expenditures, 1864-1865</collection>
      <idno>QMG Box 11; Bundles of AG &amp; QMG Expenditures 1864-65; Bundle 3</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-07-09">9 July 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Dr I. W. Scott late Surgeon General of Ky states that in the month of <date when="1864-03">March 1864</date>, he received of S. G. Suddarth Q. M. General of Ky. the sum of fifty dollars ($50) to defray expenses to St Louis Missouri, to which point he was ordered by his Excellency Thos E. Bramlette Gov of Ky for the purpose of looking after the sick and wounded soldiers belonging to Ky Regiments, and that he expended the sum named for that purpose.</p>
<p>He further states that in the month of <date when="1864-12">December 1864</date> he received of S. G. Suddarth. Q. M. Genl. of Ky. the sum of "five hundred dollars" to purchase necessaries for the sick and wounded Soldiers belonging to Ky Regiments in Hospital in the States of Indiana &amp; Kentucky and that he disbursed the sum named above, for the purposes indicated as per instruction received from his Excellency Thos E. Bramlette Gov of Ky.</p>
<p>He makes the statement and affadavit<hi rend="str">s</hi> and submits the same with the view of accounting for sums named above towit: Fifty dollars and Five hundred dollars in question and request that the Governor will under the power given to him by existing laws or that he be credited with the same amounts.</p>
<p>I W Scott
<lb/>Surg Genl. Genl ky<pb/></p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Frankly County ss.</p>
<p>On this <date when="1864-07-09">9<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of July 1864</date> personally appeared I W Scott to me well Known and subscribed and made oath to the foregoeing statement In testimony whereof I hereto set my hand and seal the day and year above written</p>
<p>John B Lindsey
<lb/>Notary Public</p>
<p><figure type="seal"><ab>NOTARY PUBLIC
<lb/>JOHN B. LINDSEY
<lb/>STATE OF KY.</ab></figure><pb/></p>
<p>Ex Office
<lb/><date when="1867-08-10">August 10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1867</date></p>
<p>The statetment of D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Scott is satisfactory and the Q M Genl will grant him a <unclear>quietus</unclear> -- </p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>Govr of Ky<pb/></p>
<p>Head Quarters Kentucky Volunteers,
<lb/>QUARTER-MASTER GENERAL'S OFFICE.
<lb/>OFFICIAL BUSINESS.</p>
<p>Dr I. W. Scott,
<lb/>Surgeon General of State of Kentucky<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Settlement
<lb/>Cancelled
<lb/><date when="1867-08-10">Aug 10<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> 1867</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
