<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0643"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. H. Condell to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4762</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-516 to BR9-517</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-03-21">21 March 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Covington <date when="1864-03-21">March 21<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>To His Excelency T. E. Bramblett Gov of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner J. H. Condell would respectfully represent that he is Deputy Sheriff for H F Bowen. Sheriff of Kenton County K.y. That at the <date when="1863-12">December term of the Kenton <hi rend="str">County</hi> Circuit Court 1863</date>. A Judgement was rendered against one Iseah M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Knight for the sum of Sixty dollars, and a capias was issued for the arrest of the said M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Knight who evaded the officers from time to time, as he lived some distance from the city of Covington near the Ohio River. After repeated attempts to Make the arrest as it was my duty to do ^and in conformity with instructions of Com<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Attorney^ about the <date when="--12-01">1<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of December last</date> John S. Scott also a Deputy Sheriff and your petitioner watched his house all night but without success, the next night your petitioner ^alone^ watched all night and about 6 Oclock in the morning discovered M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Knight approaching within a short distance of him. your petitioner then commanded him stand, but he would not surrender himself and ran for the Ohio River where a Boat was in waiting to take him to the State of Ohio. Your petitioner still commanded him to stop, that if he would not, your petitioner would shoot him. He continued to run, when your petitioner fired three pistol shots, but had no intention of wounding him, but expected so to alarm him that he would surrender himself and become ameanable to the order <hi rend="str">of the order</hi> of the Court. He still continued to run and finally escaped to the state of Ohio
<lb/>over<pb/></p>
<p>At the present <date when="1864-03">March term 1864</date> of the Kenton Circuit Court at Covington your Petitioner was endited for "Shooting with intent to Kill" the said M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Knight and was fined $25<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> Your petitioner has thus briefly stated the facts as the occured, he believeing that he was only using necessary force to make the arrest. Your Petitioner would therefore pray your Excelency to remit said fine and in duty bound will ever pray</p>
<p>J. H. Condell</p>
<p>Covington <date when="1864-03-23">Mar 23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1864</date></p>
<p>I was atty for J. H. Coudell in the above recited case. I think he has stated ^the^ case, about as strong against himself as it was made by the proof. In addition thereto, it affords me pleasure to say he is a worthy and accommading &amp; efficient officer. At the time of the shooting he was not experienced in the duties &amp; liabilities of his office, I am satisfied he only desires to do his duty.</p>
<p>I am sir
<lb/><hi rend="underline">S M Moore</hi></p>
<p>We of the Jury who tried the case vs J H Caudell, unite<pb/>
<lb/>with him in the request that the fine be remited,</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>F Dorman
<lb/>James Riddle
<lb/>John Stephen
<lb/>John M Ferguson
<lb/>U. Shinkle
<lb/>Elijah Yates
<lb/><cb n="2"/>E. G. Clarkson foreman Jury
<lb/>Henry Wenzel
<lb/>W. J. Hyde
<lb/>Thomas Rosborn
<lb/>J. W. Neal
<lb/>John Baldwin<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>We also recommend the foregoing petition of J H Caudell to the most favorable consideration by His Excellency, The Governor<pb/></p>
<p>From the information which I have obtained in relation to the above case of Mr Condell I have no doubt that justice would be promoted by relieving him of the fine. he is poor and cannot well pay the fine &amp; costs, which are quite as much as the fine, and he is an effective and conscientious officer, and such a man as in needed here- I would be gratified if the fine Would be remitted -- </p>
<p>Very Truly Your Excelency
<lb/>obt Sevt
<lb/>M M Barber</p>
<p>Kenton Cr Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>J. H. Condell
<lb/>$25 -- 
<lb/>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/><date when="1864-04-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Apl/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
