<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0025"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Unknown, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9493</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17A-80</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-01-28">28 January 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Caldwell County sct,</p>
<p>Some time in the Month of <date when="1859-09">Sept</date> or <date when="1859-10">October 1859</date>, I was selected or Called on by M Dudley a then acting Justice of the Peace in and for Caldwell County, to preside and determine upon the fact, as charged in a Peace Warrant, which had been issued by S<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Dudley at the instance of S, B, Wadlington against Mach Cartwright which I did and upon a hearing thereof dismissed the WT the trial of the warrant, was had in the office of the Police Judge of Princeton and the warrant, left by me in said office the same being a mater of record properly belonging ^to^ the Office M. Dudley Esqr and took no further notice or care over it and thus as I Suppose the warrant and proceeding was lost. I supposing it to be or constitute no part of my records, haveing been as before stated called in by Dudley &amp; If I mistake by Judge Linsay in behalf of T. B. Wadlington which I did and as I supposed was an end to the labours &amp; duties revolving upon me, in the premises, The foregoing is a true and full statement of the facts, as they occured, pertaining to the loss of the warrant, &amp;c.</p>
<p>Att <unclear>J Micah Sumer</unclear> P J
<lb/><date when="1861-01-28">Jan<hi rend="sup">y</hi> 28/61</date>.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
