<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2357"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas W. Napier to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6994</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-262</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency -- Gov Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Bramlette -- </p>
<p>Your Petitioner Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> W Napier states that about the year 1860 -- one Reuben Hammonds <hi rend="underline">shot</hi> <hi rend="underline">at</hi>, without wounding, one Willis Barnet -- of this County -- Said Hammonds was arrested and tried before an Enquiring Court, and by Said Court sent on for further trial -- and by the Grand Jury of Lincoln Co was indicted for <gap/> shortly thereafter the Petitioner became said Hammonds Bail in the Circuit Court for $250 -- Before the trial of Hammonds he was run off, by soldiery, and his life threatened -- and well nigh being taken; over his <hi rend="underline">Supposed</hi> <hi rend="underline">connection</hi> with the Killing of one James Furguson. He has never returned to live permanently, but came back once to stand his trial, and was the second time ran off, Whereupon his Bond was forfeited, and Judgment went against your Petitioner for the sum of $250 -- afs<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Now Your Petitioner begs Your Excellency to remit the Com<hi rend="sup">ths</hi> part of said Judgment -- because Hammonds was not permitted, by Soldiery &amp; others to remain here for trial. All of which is respectfuly submitted to Your Excellency.</p>
<p>Thomas W Napier</p>
<p>Governer. The above facts as stated by Judge Napier are ture, and we earnestly join with him in the pray for the<pb/>
<lb/>Executive Clemency -- The Judgment was rendered at the <date when="1864-09">Sept<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Term of the Lincoln Circuit Court 1864</date>,</p>
<p>Fon. T. Fox
<lb/>M H Owsley
<lb/>T, P, Hill
<lb/>H. T. Harris
<lb/>G, A, Lackey</p>
<p>Lincoln Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> W Napier
<lb/>$500,
<lb/>Gam<hi rend="str">g</hi>ing
<lb/>Faro
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-09-16">16 Sept /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
