<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1247"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Theodore Davis to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5884</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-418 to BR11-419</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Bramlette Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>your petitioner Theodore Davis would respectfully represent that at the present, <date when="1864-10">Oct. Term 1864,</date> of the Franklin Circuit Court, he was fined the sum of Two Hundred Dollars. for permitting "<hi rend="underline">gaming</hi>" in his house in Frankfort Ky. He would represent the facts in the case to be as follows -- In <date when="1864-09">Sept. 1864</date> -- He rented a room in the city -- and set up therein a Table, called a "Pigeon hole" Table -- That the table was never used or designed for any purpose except for ^the^ amusement of those who visited his house -- That the game is a similar one to that called "Billiards" &amp; that he charged each person playing at the tables five cents. for the priviledge of playing each game of 300. up. that in return for the money received he gave to each player a check that entitled him to five cents worth of refreshments, That he paid the city of Frankfort a license for the priviledge of <hi rend="underline">running</hi> his table, that the game called "Pigeon Hole" is a very common one <hi rend="str">in</hi> That these facts together with the proof that he on every &amp; all occasions -- positively prohibited all betting -- on the table -- Constituted all the proof before the jury -- <pb/>
<lb/>Your petitioner is a very poor young man not yet 21 years of age. &amp; that if forced to pay the whole of said fine he will have to go to jail</p>
<p>Wherefore he asks that your Excellency will remit all of the said fine with the exception of that part due to the officers of the court,</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>Theo Davis</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Frankfort -- would respectfully unite with the Petitioner Theodore Davis in his above petition. We have known young Davis for a number of years. he is a young man of most exemplary character sober moral &amp; industrious. he is very poor. &amp; unable to pay said fine assessed against him -- </p>
<p>Respectfully.
<lb/>Ths N Lindsey
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Craik
<lb/>S. Black
<lb/>D. W. Lindsey
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> E Cox
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> G. Lobban
<lb/>Louis Weitzel
<lb/>Robert M Hotton
<lb/>John B. Dryden
<lb/>H B Innes sheriff<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned members of the Jury in this case of young Davis -- would recommend him to Executive Clemency</p>
<p>Respectfully -- 
<lb/>Robert Church
<lb/>S. O. Crockett
<lb/>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> S Philips
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi> ^m^ Pierce
<lb/>R. Long
<lb/>D Epperson
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Hulett
<lb/>C: G: Hearn
<lb/>L. L. Sullivan
<lb/>J A. Richardson
<lb/>Thos J Ford<pb/></p>
<p>Franklin Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Theodore Davis
<lb/>Petition -- to the Govenor<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>$200,
<lb/>Remit.
<lb/><date when="1864-10-14">14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Oct/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
