<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0436"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George B. Kinkead to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8888</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-200 to R4-201</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lexington, Fayette County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-06-19">19 June 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Lexington Ky <date when="1863-06-19">June 19. 1863</date>.
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>Gov Robinson
<lb/>Frankfort
<lb/>Ky.
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>At the late term of the Fayette Circuit Court there was a fine of $40 -- imposed on B. Brennan for Keeping a disorderly house in the City of Lexington, On another indictment for the same offence there was a verdict of not guilty, The proof was that the house was kept by B<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> wife (He being a day laborer,) and that she sold groceries in a very limited way when waggoners -- black &amp; white -- would be seen as they came into or went out of town But not a witness -- though neighbours, including the City Judge Goodloe, even called <hi rend="str">or</hi> Said that they had ever witnessed any disorder or noise about the house -- and <hi rend="str">that</hi> all agreed that the neighbours were not disturbed by it</p>
<p>The indictment was found over a year ago.<pb/>
<lb/>The fine to the parties (&amp; it will fall heaviest on the wife) is a very heavy one, for the proof. No witness ever saw any body drunk in the house. And none, but one, that he had ever seen a drunken man near the house Although it is on Main Street -- and the witness had no reason to believe that that man got any liquor from this house.</p>
<p>The fine not within your Constitutional power to remit, together with the Costs will be just as much as they can bear, and he may have to go to the prison for that,</p>
<p>I hope your Excellency will, deem it not incinsistent with your duty to remit as far as you can the fine. I would not ask you if I did not think you ought.</p>
<p>I am Very Truly
<lb/>Your Obt St
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Geo B Kinkead</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
