<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0622"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Joseph E. Hays et al. to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9074</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-477 to R4-478</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Robertson:</p>
<p>Your petitioners Reubin Butler and John Butler state that the grand Jury for Russell County Ky prefered an indictment against John W. Patterson for felony and your petitioners went his security in a bond of $250 for his appearance at the <gap/> term of the Russell Circuit Court to answer said charge. Said Patterson prior to said charge resided &amp; had married in the state of Tennessee in which state he was arrested &amp; brought back to said county to answer said charge &amp; after giving bail returned to his wife in Tennessee where as petitioners are informed and believe he died &amp; for that reason failed to appear and answer said charge &amp; the bond was forfeited &amp; Judgment will be rendered thereon vs. petitioners unless your excellency shall intervene &amp; pardon said bond. They cannot go to Tennessee &amp; take proof of his death, on account of the Rebellion &amp; war. They cannot get such evidence by letter for want of mail. They are poor &amp; unable to pay the bond &amp; the accussed has no property left &amp; was the nephew of said Reubin &amp; the cousin of said John &amp; had lost his mother when only two weeks old &amp; his father had remarried &amp; the child on account of discord &amp; disapprobation of the stepmother &amp; wandered from home &amp; fell into bad company &amp; was not more than 18 years old when charged &amp; was of a good family on both sides rendering him an object of much sympathy in this matter even if guilty. Said Reubin has a considerable family &amp; is getting old with no means of supporting his family except his labor &amp; he is unable to pay the bond. They pray for Executive clemency &amp; that the bond be pardoned, &amp; rely upon their neighbors &amp; acquaintances, who may sign this petition, for confirmation of the facts stated. May your excellency forward a pardon to the address of petitioners or to Joseph E. Hays at Jamestown,<pb/>
<lb/>Ky. We whose names are underwritten concur with petitioners in the facts &amp; reasons relied on ^by^ them for executive interposition &amp; hope their prayers for Executive clemency may be granted.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Joseph E. Hays atty.
<lb/>James Winfree
<lb/>John B Winfree
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Lucas
<lb/>W, P, Payne
<lb/>Nathan M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>clure
<lb/>William Selby,.
<lb/>G. M. Wolford
<lb/>Jas. Selby, ,
<lb/>P. C. Harding atty.
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi>, A. Gaar
<lb/>John Price
<lb/>James. T. Jones
<lb/>W. D. Wolford
<lb/>Thomas Collins
<lb/>Ruffus Sparks
<lb/>R H Perryman
<lb/>Lewis Wilkerson
<lb/>Bengnon Selby
<lb/>J N Coffey
<lb/>J. A Smith
<lb/>Logan Coffey
<lb/>George W Moore
<lb/>A. R. Sparkes
<lb/>W G Murrell
<lb/>John Collins
<lb/>Abner Jones
<lb/>William Jones
<lb/>S, P, Collins
<lb/>Berry Warren
<lb/><cb n="2"/>George Bryan
<lb/>William T. Jackman
<lb/>George Tweewell
<lb/>Allen Jones
<lb/>Isaac Shrill
<lb/>Jacob William Atty
<lb/>William.G. Ludduth atty
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> E. Russell. atty,
<lb/>F,, T Fox atty
<lb/>Thomas E. Bramlette atty
<lb/>Robert M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>lain
<lb/>James Garnett
<lb/>Josseph Mclain
<lb/>Sidney Murry
<lb/>Thomas Sparks
<lb/>Elil Grant
<lb/>William Rowe
<lb/>P. G. Clayton
<lb/>Humphrey Coffey
<lb/>Milton Lester<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Pettn of R. &amp; G. Butler of Russell County to remit forfeited bond</p>
<p>No reliable proof of Pattersons death if proven would evidence to <unclear/></p>
<p>I do not think it safe to remit before judgement upon uncertain proof made by the Parties interested</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
