<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1424"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">A. F. Gowdy to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10892</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-387 to MG21-388</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Campbellsville, Taylor County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-09-18">18 September 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Campbellsville Taylor Co Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-09-18">Sept 18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>B. Magoffin Esq<hi rend="sup">r</hi>.
<lb/>Governor of Kenty</p>
<p>At the present September Term of the Taylor Circuit Cour, M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> James C Wood was convicted for assaulting &amp; Cuting One Thomas Cox with intention to Kill and was Sentenced to Confinement in the Penitentiary One year.</p>
<p>I have learned from good authority, the best citizens of our County that if the Convict <hi rend="str">T</hi>had had a fair trail and all the evidence in the Case been laid before the Jury there would have been an acquital. There was one witness who would have<pb/>
<lb/>proven that Cox assaulted the prisoner first but he could not be gotten before the Court, The prisoners Counsel made a mistake in the witness who was to prove the assault by Cox on prisoner until after the trail commenced.</p>
<p>There was much prejudice against the prisoner by Some of the witnesses Sworn on the Trial, and one his own Cousin whose evidence Convicted him when the absent witness would have sworn differently to his cousin which prisoner Says would have been the truth.</p>
<p>If your Excellency will pardon the prisoner from the petition &amp; facts presented to you, I have no doubt will be satisfactory to our citizens and doing an act of Justice &amp; Clemency to the prisoner which would<pb/>
<lb/>be in your legitimate power to do so, Provided you are Satisfied of the facts presented before you.</p>
<p>In this case I have no personal interest now way, and I have but little acquaintance with the prisoner, his relatives are people of good character &amp; stand high as Citizens of our county</p>
<p>Yours &amp;c
<lb/>A. F. Gowdy</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
