<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2111"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Alvin Mainor to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9187</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-168 to MG24-169</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency Beriah Magoffin Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky your petitioner Alvious Mainor states that about <gap/> the day of <gap/> <date when="1862">1862</date> his brother Henderson Mainer who resided in the state of Indiana and had for many years had made a visit to see your petition who resides in Pike county Kentucky -- He states that his brother on his way home was arrested at Cattletsburg Ky -- on a charge of passing counterfeit money and was required to execute a Bond before the Court of inquiry in the sum of $500 -- he being unable at the time to give security was confined in the Greenup jail there being no jail in Boyd county -- ) Your petitioner was informed of the part left his home and went to see his said brother becoming satisfied as to the persecution of his brother his brother being unlettered and ignorant had received the money from a counterfeiter himself who was passing the same to him defrauding him and for the affiliation for his brother who he had every reason to believe was honest that he was raised honest entered into to the bond for his appearance and he left for his home he says that said bond was executed for the appearance of said Henderson Mainor on the <date when="1860-10">first day of the next October</date> term of the Boyd circuit court to wit <date when="1860-10">Oct <gap/> 1860</date> and this said petitioner knowing the great pressure that would fall upon him to pay<pb/>
<lb/>the $500 -- went to Indiana to get his said Brother to come and entered his appearance discharger of his said Bond in Bond of this petitioner -- and found him unable to make his appearance from his health -- hence the Bond was forfeited by an order of the Boyd circuit Court -- and a summons has hence issued against your petition to recover the $500 -- Now in consideration of the promises he asks your excilency to remit him from the said penalty on the following ground -- He states that the condition of the country by the Civil War which has distroyed every thing in a manner on the sandy water which he with others has had to <unclear/> -- the deplorable devastations has become noted as among the worst that has attended the civil War Nelson and his Brigade -- and <unclear/> and his band of privates that stole and devastated what they could reach -- and last and not least of the scourges the flood in sandy River has receipt almost the balance farms sadly <unclear/> -- in this condition starvation is almost the consequence what little property is left without price he is unable to meet the same he asks your excellency to discharge him from the said penalty intercourse has been prevented with Indiana or his said Brother -- for some time unsafe<pb/>
<lb/>to travel -- but little doubt but that his brother is in the wrong -- or he would again seek for him to appear -- unless your excellency will remit the said penalties he will be forced by judgment of the Boyd circuit court to answer the penalty -- he thinks he has had his shear of troubles as aforesaid he asks in mercy &amp;c</p>
<p>Alvin Mainor</p>
<p>We not personally acquainted with the foregoing statement -- say that Alvious Mainor is a good well behaved citizen -- that he went west in same in his return as he stated to get his brother to enter his appearance &amp;c -- to his statements we cannot from his character doubt -- the distress of the people of sandy seems to be without a paralel we think your excellency taking the terms and condition of the petition from ravages of war &amp; Flood it would be right to remit the obligation as to him the surety</p>
<p>George N. Brown
<lb/>Sa<hi rend="underline">m</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Short
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> M, Rice</p>
<p>Commonwealth vs. Morgan 14 B. M. 392
<lb/>" " vs. Sproggins 18 B. M. 513 -- <pb/></p>
<p>No Judgt
<lb/>Maynor
<lb/>to } Petition
<lb/>Govenor</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
