<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-021-0042"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Robert Ellis, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG3112</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Apprehension of Fugitives from Justice Papers, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG8-132</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>STATE AND COMMONWEALTH OF KENTUCKY,
<lb/>JEFFERSON COUNTY AND CIRCUIT, SCT.
<lb/><date when="1860-10">October Term of the Jefferson Circuit Court, in the year of our Lord, one thousand eight hundred and sixty-<gap/></date></p>
<p>The Jurors of the Grand Jury, impannelled and sworn to inquire in and for the body of the County of Jefferson, in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, on their oath, present that Robert Ellis a free man of color late of said Connty, laborer on the <date when="1860-05-23">twenty third day of May in the year eighteen hundred and sixty-<gap/></date> in the said County of Jefferson, and State of Kentucky, with force and arms Bank notes for the payment of money to wit; for the payment of fourteen dollars and silver coin of the value of two dollars and seventy five cents and one pair of gloves of the value of fifty cents of the goods and chattels of Tabitha Perry then and there being and found, feloniously did steal, take, and carry away, contrary to the form of the Statute, in that case made and provided, and against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky:</p>
<p>E S Craig atty
<lb/>for the Commwth 7" dist</p>
<p>Witnesses for the Commonwealth:
<lb/>Sarah Perry
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Clayton
<lb/>M Howard
<lb/>Tabitha Perry</p>
<p>A copy
<lb/>att
<lb/>Jas P Chambers c
<lb/>Jeff Cir ct<pb/></p>
<p>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Indict larceny
<lb/>Robert Ellis f m c</p>
<p>A true bill</p>
<p>Tho Quiggley foreman</p>
<p><date when="1860-10-17">1860 Oct 17</date> Rec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> from Grand Jury &amp; Filed </p>
<p><date when="1860-10-24">Oct 24th</date> <unclear/> <unclear/> Jury laid over</p>
<p><date when="1860-10-25">25</date> Jury met, unable to agree, dischgd deft reco in $300. M Woodson Bail &amp; Court</p>
<p><date when="1861-01-14">1861 Jany 14</date> Reco forftd Sci fa and Cont &amp; Capias</p>
<p><date when="1860-05-06">May 6 Cont &amp; capias</date></p>
<p>Att J P Chambers c</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
