<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0545"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. Henry Holt to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8997</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-366 to R4-367</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mount Sterling, Montgomery County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-08-27">27 August 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Mt Sterling Ky,, <date when="1863-08-27">Aug 27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>Hon J. F. Robinson
<lb/>Governor of Ky.</p>
<p>I address you in order to obtain the remission of a forfeiture of a recogniszance in a case where it would be a <hi rend="underline">great</hi> hardship for the men to pay it, or any portion of it. The two men liable are of the first standing in Powel Co. though not wealthy, and are Union men. As your Excellency is aware, you have the power of remitting the whole of the fine, including the District Atto<hi rend="sup">s,,</hi> share at any time before a Judgment upon the forfeiture (18 B. M. 512)</p>
<p>As the forfeiture is a heavy one for the payment of the Atto<hi rend="sup">s,,</hi> share would be very oppressive, and unjust under the circumstances, though<pb/>
<lb/>the strict letter of the Law might forfeit it. At the last term of the Powel Circuit Court the trial of the recognizance was continued till the next term. In order that your Excellency may understand the facts of the case I will make a statement of them in the form of an Affidavit. If other proof should be required it can Easily be obtained.</p>
<p>Very Resply, W. Henry Holt</p>
<p>The affiant, W. Henry Holt states that in the year <date when="1860">1860</date> an affray took place near Stanton, County of Powel, between two families, named respectfively Bowen &amp; Hall. The cause of the affray was a land dispute &amp; the fathers of the families &amp; a number of the sons of each were Engaged in it, as well as a man by the name of Wilbourn, now in the Union army.</p>
<p>One of Hall's sons was killed &amp; the<pb/>
<lb/>Bowens (Father &amp; three sons) &amp; Wilbourne were indicted for manslaughter. A <hi rend="underline">Brother</hi> of the old man, Bowen, by the name of W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Bowen &amp; a certain Mr Stone, rather than see the old man &amp; sons go to Jail, entered into a Recognizance for them &amp; Wilbourn. The case was continued from time to time by the District Atto. the Bowens appearing <hi rend="underline">regularly</hi> at each Court since <date when="1860">1860</date>, and desiring a Trial. Last November term of the Court, however, the Bowens failed to enter their appearance though they were in the vicinity -- at home: and hence the Recognizance was forefeited. They started to come to the <date when="--11">November</date> Court &amp; <hi rend="underline">got</hi> <hi rend="underline">over</hi> <hi rend="underline">half</hi> <hi rend="underline">way</hi> to the Court House, when they were informed by a <hi rend="underline">number</hi> of <hi rend="underline">persons</hi>, that the Halls said they <hi rend="underline">would</hi> <hi rend="underline">shoot</hi> <hi rend="underline">them</hi> if they came to Court &amp; were prepared to do so. As they knew feeling ran high in regard to the matter, they did not<pb/>
<lb/>dare to come farther &amp; turned about and went home. This was the reason why they did not appear -- through no neglect of their own, or wish to avoid the Court's decrees. At the term of the Court Just closed (<date when="--08">August</date> Term) they were promptly in attendance &amp; anxious for trial; but the case was continued by the District Atto. (One son was not present, he having died lately.) They allege by affidavit that they have always been ready in the case &amp; they have been promptly at Court in every case, Except when the Recognizance was forfeited -- and then were absent for the reasons above stated. The amt. of the recognizance Entered into by Mr W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Bowen &amp; Mr Stone, and which they ask to have remitted, was $500. for each of the alleged offenders.</p>
<p>W. Henry Holt says the statements above are true to the best of his knowledge &amp; belief.</p>
<p>W. H. Holt</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by W H Holt this <date when="1863-08-27">27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Aug. 1863</date></p>
<p>J E Garrett clk</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
