<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2407"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Holloway et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7044</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-339 to BR15-340</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Henderson, Henderson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-08">8 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><date when="1865-09-08">Sept 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date></p>
<p>We the undersinged <hi rend="str">S</hi>Citizens of Henderson County State that we have Known A. J. Marr<hi rend="str">s</hi>s for many years, we believe the the statements in his petition are true.</p>
<p>That said Paul J Marrs has always. before the war Conducted himself as a good, sober, &amp; discreet Citizen, that Since his return home he has in all respects Conducted himself as an honest, sober, &amp; orderly person</p>
<p>We think that his Case presents strong Consideration for the indulgence of Executive Clemency and respectfully ask that the prayer of his petion be granted</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> J Holloway</hi></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>I have Known the Petitioner Paul J Mars from his Boyhood until he Joined the confederate Army, and believe him to be a young man of Strict integrity &amp; honor, and that it is ^his^intention to conduct himself as a loyal citizen of the united states and I reccomend him to the clemency of your Excellency</p>
<p>Arch Dixon
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Richard Stites
<lb/><hi rend="underline">C, H, Hillyer</hi>
<lb/>D Banks
<lb/>V E Mitcherson
<lb/>F B Cromwell
<lb/><hi rend="underline">C, W, Hatcher
<lb/>C. Bailey</hi>
<lb/>Arch<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Dixon Jr
<lb/>T F Cheaney
<lb/>late Depy Pro Mar
<lb/>S, W, Rankin
<lb/>Leon<hi rend="sup">d</hi> H. Lynne
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clain
<lb/>Jackson M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clain
<lb/>Alexander H. Major<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Henderson Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-09-20">Sep 20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date></p>
<p>Hopkins Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Pardoned
<lb/>Paul J Marrs
<lb/>Indicted <date when="1865-05">May term 1865</date>
<lb/><date when="1865-09-22">22<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Sept /65</date><pb/></p>
<p>Henderson Ky. <date when="1865-09-18">Sept 18<hi rend="sup">h</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>To his Exellency
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Bramlet
<lb/>Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Paul J. Marrs would respectfully request that he has been indicted in the Hopkins County Circuit Court for the offence of "Invading the State to make war upon it"</p>
<p>He says he was a soldier in the army of the Confederate States and Came into the State with the rigement to which he belonged under and by virtue of order from his officers, which as a soldier he at the time Concieved he had no right to disobey -- </p>
<p>That Since the Settlement of the National difficulties he came to his former home at this place believing that he could remain unmolested so long as he obeyed the laws and Conducted himself as a peaceable Citizen that he has endeavored so to Conduct himself Since his return.</p>
<p>He respectfully asks that you pardon, remit the penalties of the Said indictment and forever acquit, release and discharge him from the Same.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Paul J Marrs</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
