<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3090"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Peter Connelly, Deposition</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5209</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno/>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Peter Connelly</p>
<p>I was at the house of Bradlies twice on the night of the murder, once before the shooting &amp; once after.</p>
<p>On my first visit to Bradlies I drank with accused &amp; he said he would be revenged on some one in two weeks.</p>
<p>Later in the night I was returning to the house of Bradlies, in about a half square from Bradlies I saw accused in company with an other Soldier going in the direction of the barracks, &amp; one of the party fired off a pistol. I proceeded immediately to the house of Bradlies which did not take over a minute &amp; I found deceased in a dying condition.</p>
<p>Julia Bradley</p>
<p>Accused was at my house on the night deceased was killed. He did not leave my house for ten minutes after Miss Casey &amp; deceased<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header"><hi rend="str">6</hi> 6</note>
<lb/>had left. he stood Talking pleasantly with me for that length of time &amp; then left the house bidding me good night as he left He made no threats against any one to me</p>
<p>It is conseded that the house of Bradlies in on Water Street one door from Bullit Street.</p>
<p>Deceased was killed on the night of the <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> <date when="--04-15">15th of April</date> a little after nine Oclock</p>
<p>Accused was Tried the first week in May following</p>
<p>Accused made an affidavit for a continuance of his case untill the next term of the Court which was over ruled. He set forth in the affidavit that he could not safely go to Trial without the presence of William Millian. Said Millian is a soldier, &amp; was at Exchange Barracks with accused <hi rend="str">accused</hi> the night that deceased was killed.<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header"><hi rend="str">6</hi> 7</note></p>
<p>Accused set forth in said affidavit that he could prove by said Millian that on the night that deceased was killed, that as he accused left the house of Bradlies that at the door of said house he was accosted by Said Millian &amp; that they remained togeather untill they went to Exchanged Barracks, where accused stood guard untill late in the night.</p>
<p>Accused is about nineteen years of age &amp; proved a good character, he proved that he had alwais been a good boy &amp; that he sent his money home to his mother when he received it from the PayMaster.</p>
<p>All of the witnesses except as to character were Commonwealth witnesses</p>
<p>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Millian the soldier alluded to in the affidavit of accused was stationed at Exchange barrack at the time of the killing &amp; had been at said barracks for some time before.<pb/>
<lb/>Accused set forth in the affidavit that he made for a continuance that he could not safely go to trial with out the presence of Corporal Hoosier. Said Hoosier had the disposition of the guard on the night that deceased was killed &amp; he <hi rend="str">knows th</hi> would prove that accused &amp; William Millian returned to the barracks in company &amp; that accused was put on guard</p>
<p>King never attempted to make his escape but was arrested while in bed</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
