<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2417"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Peter T. Phelps et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7054</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-356 to BR15-357</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Richmond, Madison County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-11">11 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Richmond Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1865-09-11">September 11' 1865</date>
<lb/>Hon. Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E. Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioners Citizens of Madison County Ky, respectfully represent that Franklin Morris Ennis Morris, and Richard Morris were indicted at the <date when="1865-03">March Term 1865</date> of the Madison Circuit Court for the Murder of Andrew Thornsburg -- </p>
<p>On the trial of said parties before the Examining Court it was proved that it was a sudden affray -- there were no weapons used except a Knife -- (no Knife has been seen except a Pocket Knife) which was used by Franklin Morris, who stabed Andrew Thornsburg, from which he died -- No blows or licks were struck by Ennis Morris -- </p>
<p><hi rend="underline">John W. Thornsburg</hi>, <hi rend="underline">the Father of the Man</hi> <hi rend="underline">who was stabed</hi>, was <hi rend="underline">Foreman</hi> of the Grand Jury that indicted the Morris's -- He used all his influence with the Grand Jury in having Ennis Morris &amp; Richard Morris included in the indictment so as to prevent them from being witnesses for Franklin Morris -- </p>
<p>Ennis Morris is a very poor man over 52 years of age -- is a man of good Character &amp; Standing &amp; a good union man, and Richard Morris is only 15 or 16 years of age.<pb/>
<lb/>Both have been lying in Jail for ^nearly^ three months, being unable to give the Bail required of them -- The old man is very frail &amp; infirm &amp; of feeble constitution -- Ennis &amp; <hi rend="str">Richard</hi> Franklin Morris both have Families -- Their crops have gone to waste for <hi rend="str">it</hi> want of attention -- their families greatly need their assistance &amp; they have had no opportunity to make preparation for their defense -- We <hi rend="str">great</hi> regard it as a great hardship upon Ennis Morris &amp; we believe he is not guilty -- &amp; that he was merely included in the Indictment to prevent him from being a Witness -- </p>
<p>We earnestly pray your Excellency to grant Ennis Morris an immediate Pardon.</p>
<p>Peter T Phelps one of the justices that tried the morris's
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Williams one of the Justices that tried the Morises
<lb/>John <unclear>Bennett</unclear>
<lb/>R. R. Harris
<lb/>D. <unclear>Bush</unclear>
<lb/>James H. Embry
<lb/>Will Rodes<pb/>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">S <unclear>Turner</unclear></hi>
<lb/>S P Walters <hi rend="underline">Banker</hi>
<lb/>G. B Broaddus
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> M. Irvine
<lb/>Brutus Crooke clk in BK
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Will J Walker</hi>
<lb/>W. W. Embry -- Prst Farmers National Bank -- 
<lb/>S. S. Parker clerk " " " "
<lb/>Silas T. Green
<lb/>G W Park
<lb/>C J. Walker M. D.
<lb/>A. B. Lyman M D,<pb/></p>
<p>Ennis Morris<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Madison Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Ennis Morris
<lb/>for Murder
<lb/>Pardoned <date when="1865-09-12">12 Sept /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
