<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0087"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Conrad Koll to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8539</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-136 to R3-137</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-10-14">14 October 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellancy the Governor of the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner would respectfully state that he is the keeper of a small Coffee house situated at the Corner of Flay &amp; Market Street that about two Months Since he was Considerable <unclear>annoyed</unclear> by a boy throwing Sand dirt &amp; even rocks into his Bar Room -- that he requested s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> boy to desist which the boy would not do. The annoyance was so great that it was necessary for your petitioner to have it stopped Consequently he was obliged to get rid of the anoyance as best he Could hence he had to drive s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> boy out of his bar room that he did not use any violence whatever. Still s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> boy was induced by his Mother to have your petitioner indicted ^for assault &amp; battery^ on the City Court. That by the testimony of s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> boy &amp; his Mother the jury at the trial of the the Cause which occured and the <date when="1862-10-06">6th day of October 1862</date> assessed the fine against your petitioner at twenty five dollars. Your petitioner was not aware at the time of the trial that some facts whereon to ^by sd boy^ were not true otherwise he would have forewarned the attendance of witnesses who <hi rend="str">been</hi> since the trial have informed him that these certain facts were not true. This information he acquired too late to be of any use to him whatever.</p>
<p>Your petitioner would respectfully state that he has a family of five small children a wife depending on him for a support -- that he is illy able to pay such a fine inasmuch as his business though at best has a small one has been very much injured by the recent order requiring Coffee Houses to be closed. Your petitioner would respectfully ask your Excellancy to<pb/>
<lb/>interpose by remitting the same as if he be compelled to pay the same it will be a great hardship &amp; as in duty bound will ever pray</p>
<p>Conrad Koll</p>
<p>Subscribed &amp; sworn to before me this <date when="1862-10-14">14th day of October 1862</date></p>
<p>Jo<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Clement, Justice of the peace Jeff Co Ky</p>
<p>We the undersigned Citizens of the City of Louisville are personally acquainted with the petitioner Conrad Koll ^&amp; know^ that he is a clever quiet and orderly, and loyal Citizen that we believe the statements made in his peitition are true &amp; that he is deserving of Executive clemency</p>
<p>Jo<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Clement
<lb/>H Russell<pb/></p>
<p>Pettn of E. Rott to remit fine
<lb/>Read not granted</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
