<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0066"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Richard Hunter, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9534</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17A-139</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-02-12">12 February 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Kentucky Caldwell County.</p>
<p>Richard Hunter says he lives a neighbor of Thos B. Wadlington, and has been long acquainted with him, and his general moral character. He says his genl moral character is that of a good honest and peacable citizen -- He says he also is well acquainted with the witnesses Prince and Blalock, and he states in his opinion that said Prince and Blalock are not entitled to credit on oath as sworn witnesses. He says he is well satisfied that said witnesses swore falsely against said Wadlington on said trial, and that ^said^ Wadlington was wrongfully condemned by the false testimony of said witnesses. and he does confidently believe that the act of Killing ^by Wadlington^ was done in necessary self defence, and to save his own life. He says said Cartwright was regarded as a dangerous, and violent young man.</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed before me by Rich<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Hunter. This <date when="1861-02-12">12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Feby 1861</date>.</p>
<p>Richard Hunter</p>
<p>Kentucky Caldwell County</p>
<p>Richard Hunter says he believes the statements above made are true.</p>
<p>Richard Hunter</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed before me by Richard Hunter. This <date when="1861-02-12">12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Feby 1861</date>.</p>
<p>J. C. Barnes D. C.
<lb/><note place="footer">(over)</note><pb/></p>
<p>Kentucky Caldwell County</p>
<p>James Cantrell, Bailous M. Stone, Riley P Dawson and John S. Ford say they were present when the foregoing affidavit of Richard Hunter was written and subscribed by him, and after hearing the same and fully understanding its contents do most cordially adopt said affidavit as given by said Rich<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Hunter, and believe the statements as made in said affidavit are true.</p>
<p>James Cantrell
<lb/>Bayless M. Stone
<lb/>R P Dawson
<lb/>John S. ^his X mark^ Ford</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed before me by James Cantrell, Bailous M. Stone, Riley P. Dawson, and John S. Ford. This <date when="1861-02-12">12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Feby 1861</date>.</p>
<p>J. C. Barnes D. C.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
