<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1851"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. John Hunt, Verdict</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6488</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-419</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky</p>
<p>Pleas before the Honorable P B Muir Sole Judge of the Jefferson Circuit Court at the Court House in the City of Louisville on the <date when="1865-05-29">29 day of May 1865.</date></p>
<p>The Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Indictment felony
<lb/>John Hunt.</p>
<p>John Hunt who has been indicted by a Grand Jury of this Circuit for felony, and who is bound by recognizance to appear and answer the same this day appeared in discharge of said recognizance and being arraigned upon said indictment plead not guilty thereto and for his trial put himself upon the Country and the attorney for the Commonwealth likewise, Wherefore to try the Issue joined let a Jury Come, &amp; thereupon Came a Jury towit: W P Shephard, Jo<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Enders, Geo Swope Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Ketchum, Jno Cross A Campbell, G F Downs, Luther Wilson, F M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Carthy J V Cowling Jno Long Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Hall who being duly elected, tried and sworn well and truly to try and true deliverance make between the Commonwealth and the accused upon oath returned into Court the following verdict. "We of the Jury find the Defendant John Hunt guilty as charged in the within<pb/>
<lb/>indictment and say that he shall be confined in the Penitentiary of the Commonwealth of Kentucky for the space of two years, and in consideraion of his tender age recommend him to the clemency of the Governor of the state.</p>
<p>G F Downs foreman.</p>
<p>and thereupon the prisoner was remanded and taken to jail accordingly</p>
<p>A Copy
<lb/>att <hi rend="underline">Jas P Chambers clk J C C</hi></p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Co of verdict &amp; Judgment
<lb/><hi rend="underline">John Hunt</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
