<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1161"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">E. E. Barrow et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10629</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-316 to MG20-317</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Woodstock, Pulaski County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-24">24 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><date when="1861-06-24">June 24/61</date>
<lb/>Woodstock Pulaski Co Ky.
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>Beriah Magoffin</p>
<p>Your petitioner would Respectfully state that In <date when="1860-10">Oct. last</date> before the poleice Judge of Somerset he was fined $18.00 and cost under the following circumstance to wit that one William Mounce (who is now in the state prison) he was and had become a terror to the County and threatened mine together with other mens lives and In the mean time Broke open Robed and after Put astore on fire and I together with others had been Endeaving to arrest him and finally after many days In which the whole County were more or less Engaged he was arrested by same men and carried to town on hearing of his arrest I Immediately went to assist in seeing he was safely guarded on comeing up Mounce and myself had some words not thinking or knowing but what the said Mounce was armed and knowing he had threatened my life, I drew apistole and Said to him If he felt like carrying out his threat I was Ready for him on being spoken to by the Gentleman having the prisnor<pb/>
<lb/>In charge and matters Explained I put up my weapon that I had carried for no other Reason but Self Defence the Marshal consiquently notified me to appear before the police but having to go with the prisnor to trial I made no defence and being quite a poor man and Rather a new beginner In the world I feel unable to pay the Same and ask your honer to Remit said fine</p>
<p>John A. Kindrick</p>
<p>P S my address is Woodstock Ky.</p>
<p>We the undersigned would Respectfully State that from what we know and what we have understood that the Statement Set forth by the forgoing petitioner is true and we would Respectfully State that we consider It wrong and quite hard that Mr Kindrick Should Even pay the <unclear/> as the prisnor was an out law and become a terror to the whole community and would have been Linched had he been In many neighbourhoods we hope your honer will Remit Said fine as we consider It ^in^just for Mr. Kindrick to pay It and we dont think there is a man In this County would say he ought to </p>
<p>E. E. Barron
<lb/>Wm Starns<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Logan Owens
<lb/>W. C. Swinney
<lb/>David Lee
<lb/>James Bernard
<lb/>J. L. Dye
<lb/>J C Patton
<lb/>S. Thompson
<lb/>R. G. Ferrell
<lb/>Silas Price
<lb/>Jonas, Sutton
<lb/>Robert Todd
<lb/>Henry Warren
<lb/>Larken Hicks
<lb/>F G Yancey
<lb/>John H. Neely
<lb/>C. Stegall
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Greer
<lb/>R. H. Pierce
<lb/>Robt. Clark
<lb/>Harden Wilder
<lb/>W B Kelly
<lb/>William Hable
<lb/>Richard Sowers
<lb/>Daniel Lewis Sr
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> L Gaynes
<lb/>A. C. Surlin
<lb/>G Q Reynolds
<lb/>Jeferson Gerber
<lb/>Armstrong Adams
<lb/>A B Surber
<lb/>W D Black
<lb/>Thomas Z Moroon
<lb/>County Attorney
<lb/><cb n="2"/>T. M. Parchal
<lb/>C. Greer
<lb/>John Yancey
<lb/>G.. Woods
<lb/>B.. Lawson
<lb/>James Wilder
<lb/>Samuel Gipson
<lb/>Robbert Sell
<lb/>James Pence
<lb/>George Coal
<lb/>Harden Wilder Sr
<lb/>James Lewis
<lb/>David Burge
<lb/>L S Gill
<lb/>R. Staint
<lb/>Henry Todd
<lb/>Wm H Todd<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M<pb/></p>
<p>Somerset Po Ct
<lb/>$18
<lb/>Jno. A Kindrick
<lb/>Remission Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi>
<lb/><date when="1861-07-18">July 18 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
