<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3281"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Samuel Miles to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5400</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-93 to BR42-94</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Govenor Bramlett of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Samuel Miles will Respectfully state to your Excellency, That in <date when="--09">September last</date> that his son William ^Miles^ was arrested on a charge of Robery, and was by the Examing court bound over to further trial in a bond of Three thousand dollars, your petitioner being the father of the said William Miles as aforesaid_ and not believing the charge to be true, knowing that your petitioner had raised his son, up to Industrious and honest habits Went upon the aforesaid bond of Three thousand dollars for the said William Miles appearance at the <date when="--09">last September Term</date> of the Ballard Circuit Court, but the said William Miles being young and inexperienced and it being the first time he ever was brought into court charged with crime <hi rend="str">became</hi> from some cause not Known to your petitioner become frightened and intimidated and left the country before the court to which he was bound to appear came on - and is gone to parts unknown to your petitioner, Your petitioners further states that he is now nearly sixty years of age and has a large and helpless family, to support, and that he has is a little farm consisting of one Hundred and thirty acres<pb/>
<lb/>of Land, Which would not pay the bond if sold, and if sold to pay said bond would leave your petitioner and family in a helpless conditiion. In consideration of the foregoing statements your petitioners humbly prays your Excellency to remit so much of said bond Which has been taken for forfeited as ^is^ in your power to remit, and he will ever pray, &amp;c</p>
<p>Samuel Miles</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Ballard and M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracken counties, Respectfully state that the petitioner is an old citizen of M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracken County Ky, and has always and is as yet regarded as an honest Industrious old Man, &amp; concur fully in the statements made in his petition We therefore Respectfully pray your Excellency to Interpose in behalf of the old Gentleman </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. H. Corbett
<lb/>B. F. Billington
<lb/>Richard Midleton
<lb/>S. Tally
<lb/>W T Tally
<lb/>M D Smith Sr
<lb/>T. W. Taylor
<lb/>N M. Shoode
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> White
<lb/>W. S. Watson
<lb/>J. H. Stovall
<lb/>David Miller
<lb/>George Gord
<lb/>G B Stranghn
<lb/>D B Frass
<lb/><cb n="2"/>R J Crouch
<lb/>J T Wyatt
<lb/>C C Ternell
<lb/>W H Duncan
<lb/>G Blance
<lb/>G T Johnson
<lb/>S S Lee
<lb/>J T odonlay
<lb/>S C Hook
<lb/>J A Carpenter
<lb/>N H Jackson
<lb/>Carrel Armstrong
<lb/>T. F Harvey
<lb/>Rufus MC witt<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>G A Flood
<lb/>Jacob Hamilton
<lb/>F N Neal
<lb/>W. L. Stahl
<lb/>S S Stall
<lb/>S. L Powell
<lb/>A. F. Howle
<lb/>H G Black
<lb/>M M Hall
<lb/>W. D. Dean
<lb/>W. L. Skinner
<lb/>J. T Taylor
<lb/>William Kidd
<lb/>J. H Crouch
<lb/>R E Gholson
<lb/>Wm H McGee
<lb/>W A Howell
<lb/>D. B. S. P. Robertson
<lb/>B F Hawirth
<lb/>E R Hall
<lb/>A T Adams
<lb/>G. H. Ashbrook
<lb/>A. Austin
<lb/>H Ryan
<lb/>W N Puckett
<lb/>G B Stigall
<lb/>John. A. Ashley
<lb/>Jaret. M. Ashley
<lb/>B. Willingham
<lb/>W. H. Dillion
<lb/>J. A. Masheu
<lb/>A Mathews
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J.. B.. Ross
<lb/>W. H. Parkam
<lb/>J. C. Minor
<lb/>J. C. Womble
<lb/>J. V Powell
<lb/>James Scott
<lb/>B.. F.. Coglier
<lb/>J. A. Brackin
<lb/>William Crabtree
<lb/>W D Page
<lb/>Benjamin Kimmel
<lb/>J. B. Cross
<lb/>Charles Roark
<lb/>J<hi rend="sup">no</hi> E Jett
<lb/>Wm R Rudolph
<lb/>F M Harris
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> A. Jett
<lb/>E. P. Overstreet
<lb/>B. Fauntleroy
<lb/>T.. S.. Steger
<lb/>D R Wilson
<lb/>Henry Unsell
<lb/>P M Unsell
<lb/>P. M. Scott
<lb/>A.. J.. Trice
<lb/>A T Colwell
<lb/>H H Sternes
<lb/>J. D. White
<lb/>Z. W. Bugg
<lb/>Paul ,W, Turrell<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>Ballard County
<lb/>Refused<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>C. L. Gate P J B C C &amp; by me the cause was tried as an Examing court
<lb/>W M Ransom.
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Joseph Terril
<lb/>Lafayett Rich
<lb/>David Hogan
<lb/>Samuel Caruthers</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
