<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1030"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Henry Taylor, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10498</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-105 to MG20-106</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Muhlenberg County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-05">5 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">1</note>
<lb/>Pleas before Hon Tho C. Dabney Judge of the Muhlenberg Circuit Court at the Court house in Greenville <date when="1861-05-13">May term, May 13th 1861.</date></p>
<p>Muhlenberg Circuit Court
<lb/><date when="1859-11-12">Nov<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. 12, Nov<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. term 1859.</date></p>
<p><note place="left margin">Recognizance</note>
<lb/>Comnlth of Kentucky Plaintiff
<lb/>against } Grand Larceny
<lb/>Henry Taylor Defendant</p>
<p>This day came the attorney for the Commonwealth &amp; the defendant Was brought to the bar in custody of the Jailer and the defendant by his attorney moved the court to admit him to give bail which motion is sustained and the defendant is admitted to give bail in the sum of Three hundred dollars &amp; thereupon the defendant Henry Taylor together with Geo W. Bryan of McLean County Kentucky his security here personally present in court <hi rend="str">&amp;</hi> acknoweldged themselves jointly indebted to the Commonwealth of Kentucky in the sum of Three hundred dollars to be void upon the condition that the defendant Henry Taylor makes his personal appearance in this Court on the second day of its next term to answer the Indictment for felony found in said Court against him &amp; shall not depart without leave of the Court -- <pb/></p>
<p><note place="header">2.</note>
<lb/>Muhlenberg Circuit Court
<lb/><date when="1860-05-17">May 17, May term 1860,</date></p>
<p>Comlth of Ky Plaintiff
<lb/>against } Larceny
<lb/>Henry Taylor Defendant</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Recognizance Forfeited</note>
<lb/>This day came the attorney for the Commonwealth &amp; the defendant being called failed to appear in discharge of his recognizance, It is therefore ordered that his said recognizance be and the same is hereby taken as forfeited and that a summons issue agaist his security George W. Bryant returnable to the next term of this court to show cause if any he can why the Commonwealth shall not have Judgment against him for the sum of Three hundred dollars that being the amount in which he acknowledged himself indebted at the last term of this court in this cause for the appearance of the defendant Henry Taylor at the present term &amp; further to do &amp;c And it is ordered that a Bench Warrt issue against the defendant Henry Taylor to be endorsed bail may be taken in the sum of Three hundred dollars with good security. -- </p>
<p>Muhlenberg Circuit Court
<lb/><date when="1861-05-13">May term May 13, 1861,</date></p>
<p><note place="left margin">Judgt</note>
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against } On Forfeited Recognizance
<lb/>Henry Taylor &amp; George W Bryant</p>
<p>This day came the attorney for the Commonwealth<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">3</note>
<lb/>and the defendant George W. Bryant having been served with process &amp; failing to answer, It is adjudged by the court that the defendant Bryant make his fine to the Commonwealth of Kentucky in the sum of Three hundred dollars, the amount of his forfeited recognizance taken in this cause &amp; her cost herein expended. And this cause is cont<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> as to Henry Taylor. -- </p>
<p>Kentucky Muhlenberg Circuit Sct,</p>
<p>I Tho. J. Jones deputy for J. H. Reno Clerk of the Muhlenberg Circuit Court, do certify that the foregoing is a true copy from the Record of the Recognizance, Forfeited Recognizance, &amp; Judgment in the case of the Comlth vs Henry Taylor &amp; Geo W. Bryant in the Muhlenberg Circuit Court,</p>
<p>Given under my hand as deputy for J. H. Reno clerk as aforesaid, this <date when="1861-06-05">5th day of June 1861,</date></p>
<p>Tho. J. Jones D. C.
<lb/><hi rend="underline">for J. H. Reno C. M. C. C.</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Muhlenberg Cir. Ct
<lb/>Comlth of Kentucky
<lb/>vs } Copy of <hi rend="underline">Record</hi>
<lb/>Henry Taylor &amp;c</p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-09-10">Sept 10. 1861</date></p>
<p>fee 75¢</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
