<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3426"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">C. S. Randale et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5545</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-314</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Fulton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To Hon Thos E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned petitioners respectfully represent to Your Excelency. That at the <date when="--09">last September Term</date> of the Fulton Circuit Felix G Binford was sentenced to serve four years in the Penitentiary under an indictment for Horse Stealing and that he is now confined in the State Prison at Frankfort_ Petitioners further state that the proof on the trial showed that said Binford was in the Town of Hickman verry Drunk that while in this situation some soldiers passed through the Town and one of them took said Binford up behind him and they left and went to the House when one of the soldiers ordered the Horse "brought out" that the negro did so and the soldiers assisted Binford to Mount him and that he rode the horse away and it was also proved that when they reached the Town of Clinton Binford proposed to sell the Horse but that he was still at that time very drunk. That the next day the horse was found and recovered by Mr Woods. Believing
<lb/><note place="left margin">Fulton C't Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>G. Binford.</note><pb/>
<lb/>that all the wrong done by said Binford was <hi rend="underline">done</hi> when he was so much under the influence of Liquor as to be incapable of committing crime Wherefore we respectfully urge Your Excellency to Pardon him_</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>C. S. Randle
<lb/>J. S. Murphy
<lb/>E Tearman
<lb/>J. Amberg
<lb/>Jno. Amberg
<lb/>John D Walker
<lb/>G. M. Wilburn
<lb/>W. Heron Snr.
<lb/>J. S. Newberg
<lb/>P. R. Cunningham City Marshel
<lb/>B F Easley Sheriff
<lb/>T. J. Memhern 
<lb/>A L Strert
<lb/>H. K. Mullens
<lb/>J. H. Morhead
<lb/>S. B. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Intosh
<lb/>A S Jones
<lb/>C Cunningham
<lb/>J. P. Cheatham
<lb/>John K patrick
<lb/>B B Barker
<lb/>T.. D.. Shelby
<lb/>H W Cambell
<lb/>W F Steele
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Sam<hi rend="sup">l</hi>. Landrum Judge Fulton County Court
<lb/>R E Millet Police Judge city Hickman
<lb/>W A Brevard clerk Fulton Cir court
<lb/>Jno A Wilson Clk. F. Co. C.
<lb/>H. S. Campbell</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
