<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1449"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John S. Nixon and S. R. Grant to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6086</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-252 to BR12-253</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency, Thomas E. Bramlette,
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>The undersigned respectfully represent that in the Spring of <date when="1862">1862</date> one Simon Shepherd, a negro man, was arrested, in Covington charged with coming into Kentucky, from a free State, in violation of the Statute; when taken before the Mayor of Covington, he was required to give bond, in the Sum of one Hundred Dollars for his appearance at the next term of the Circuit Court. Your petitioners firm sympathy for the helpless man, who complained of being sick, became Surety on his bond for his appearance -- he failed to appear and the bond was forfeited and judgment has been rendered thereon against your petitioners, which now, with interest and costs amounts to $<gap/>. Your petitioners caused to be issued by the Governor of Kentucky, upon the Governor of Ohio (Todd) a requisition for the arrest and delivery of the negro man, as a fugitive from justice, but the Governor of Ohio declined to order the arrest. Your petitioners, very respectfully appeal to your Excellency that the ends of justice do not require that they should pay the judgment, so rendered against them, we behalf of<pb/>
<lb/>the Commonwealth. The per centum of the Commonwealth's attorney together with the accumulated costs will amount to more than half the penalty of the two which your petitioners submit is quite punishment enough for an inconsiderate and (perhaps) mistaken act of humanity. Your petitioners therefore, respectfully request your Excellency to pardon and remit the said judgment excepting costs and fee of the Commonwealth's attorney.</p>
<p>Very respectfully &amp;c
<lb/>John S. Nixon
<lb/>S. R. Grant</p>
<p>I have no doubt of the truth of the statements of Mr. Nixon &amp; join in asking a remission of the fine.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">M. M. Benton</hi>
<lb/>R. Richardson
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J. OHara Jr</hi>
<lb/>J. R. Hallam
<lb/>Acting Comlths Attorney
<lb/>J S Scott D, S
<lb/>John F. Fisk
<lb/>B W Foley Clk <unclear>C C</unclear>
<lb/>A. C. Ellis D C<pb/></p>
<p>I was city marshal of Covington and made the arrest of the negro man Shepherd -- He came to Covington, as I learned at the time, to bring over from the Louisville Mail boat Mrs. Genl. U. S. Grant, ^&amp; her children^ and was returning, with his boat, when I arrested him. I knew that Mr Nixon endeavored to have brought back to stand his trial</p>
<p>Clinton Butts<pb/></p>
<p>Kenton Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Nixon &amp; Grant
<lb/>$100,
<lb/>Remit
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1865-01-13">13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Jany 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
