<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1957"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">F. G. Dannecker et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6594</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-88 to BR14-89</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov of Ky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Lohn would respectfully State, that he is a young man 25 years old; and that on the <date when="1864-10-23">23<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of Decbr. 186<hi rend="str">5</hi>4</date> he was arrested on a charge of <hi rend="str">Larceny</hi> Burglary and on the <date when="1865-01-19">19 day of January 1865</date> he was tried and convicted of said Crime in the Jefferson Circuit Court, and sentenced to confinement in the Penitentiary at Frankford for a Term of four years, where he since been confined at hard labor,</p>
<p>Your Petitioner says he had been living with his Uncle for Some time, doing and tending to smal earents for him and your Petitioner unfortunately and to his great Sorrow and regrett, drank to much ardent Spirits, and was charged with ^breaking in and^ stealing some <hi rend="str">money</hi> goods from his uncle and this was whilst he was ^so^ Intoxicated that he did not know what he was doing.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner fother Says he was prosecuted with a Great deal of ill fealing from his uncle, for which however he does not blame him <hi rend="str">however</hi> as he had done wrong, but Since his uncle has found out <hi rend="str">that your</hi><pb/>
<lb/>and is satisfied that your Petioner greatly regrett what he has done he is very desirious for his release your Petitionor says that this is the first and only crime he has ever been guilty or charged with and that as he did not have his mind sufficiently Clar to know what he was about he therefore hopes and earnestly prays that your Excellency will exercise Your Pardoning power and grant your Petitioner a Pardon, as he has alreddy suffered greatly in body and mind Since his arrest and confinement,</p>
<p>Respectfully Submitted</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizen of Louisville and officers of the Court would respectfully State that we consider the above a proper Subject for the interposition of your Excellencies Executive clemency and we respectfully pray your Excellency to grant him a Pardon</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>F G Dannecker
<lb/>Geo Jonas Inter C. C.
<lb/>W G Reasor
<lb/>J D Duncan
<lb/>M. E. Burkhart
<lb/>S. A. Atchison jr.
<lb/>J. D. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Carthy
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Jo<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Clement. P J H
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Sam</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> Matlock</hi> J. P.
<lb/>L. A. Wood.
<lb/>Jack Fry
<lb/>W. C. Mills
<lb/>E. W. Rutledge C J C 3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> District
<lb/>Selby Harney<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Brent. Hopkins, Depty
<lb/>Com<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Lou: Chy Court.
<lb/>James Harris
<lb/>Jacob Mayer
<lb/>Henry Greve
<lb/>Julius Esthmann
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Henry Knofel</hi>
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Vogt
<lb/>Fred. Frishe N. P.
<lb/>Geo W Doan J. P. J. C
<lb/>R. M. J. Pound
<lb/><hi rend="underline">C. Henry Finck</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J Dolfmyre</hi>
<lb/>Jacob <hi rend="underline">Krieger Sr</hi>
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Phil Tomppert Jr
<lb/>A. Akers Deputy Marshal
<lb/>Ed Megleney Dep Mar
<lb/>August Stein
<lb/>J. Haathauser
<lb/>H Reiling
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Philip Speed</hi><milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>The firm of Greve Buhrlage &amp; Co was the party of whom the goods were taken and who had W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Lahn prosecuted, they now ask that the Governor pardon him, He has served since <date when="1865-05">May 1865</date> in the penitentiary</p>
<p>Greve Buhrlage &amp; Co</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
