<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2049"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James F. Stephenson to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6686</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-227 to BR14-228</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Albany, Clinton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-06-14">14 June 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Camp Near Albany, Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-06-14">June the 14<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Thos E. Bramblett, Gov of Kentucky
<lb/>Dear Sir,</p>
<p>I hope my address will be agreeable with you upon this occasion. I was <hi rend="underline">1st</hi> <hi rend="underline">Lieut</hi> of Co (E) 13<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky Cavl. and while in Comd of the Company, I give One of my Souldiers a pass appd By the Comd of the Post to Procede to Russell Co Ky, and bring up two Government Horses, left by my Company when on a march from Camp Burnside To Burksville Ky.</p>
<p>the Souldier Started to perform the duty proceded to Jamestown Ky, where he was arrested, by the Sheriff the Souldier informed the Sheriff that he had a pass and was on duty, and he would mutch rather he would permit him to return to his comd, but the Sheriff informed him that he would commit him to Jail and if his Commanders did not like it they could deal with him, for he considered that he had the authority to do so, and the pass was<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nt</hi></hi> worth a farthing, the Souldier then said to the Sheriff that if he would make application to the comdg. officer. that they would give him up to Sivil authority for trial. but the Sheriff informed him that he would take no Such trouble on him-self, that he had him and he would ceap him, at all events, and if his commanders did not like it they could help themselves, when I get reliable information of his proceedings. I thought it my duty to go and see something about the Souldier as he was rather a favorite one and had been a faithful and Obedient one I asked permisson to the commander of the Post. to go rescue the Souldier, until the Sheriff was disposed to condecend to ask for him ^the souldier^ to be turned over to him the Comd'g officer, granted it, and I proceded to Jamestown and the Sheriff was absent, or absented him-self when I got there, so I did not get to see him, and finding that<pb/>
<lb/>the Sheriff was intoxicated, when he mad the arrest and had treated the Souldier with violence and disrespect, I become excited, and probably as passionate as the Sheriff was when he mad the arrest, but I respect my Souldiers and considered I was doing my duty I called on the Jailer for the keas and taken possession of the Souldier and returned to my Comd at Burksville, Ky, this was in <date when="1864-09">Sept 1864</date>, and I <hi rend="str">wa</hi> informed the Sheriff, that if he had anything agan the Souldier, if he would com and make propper application for him that the Col. would give him up but we Served from then until the <date when="1865-01-10">10<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of Jan 65</date> and, nearley all the time in a days ride of Jamestown. But I suppose the Sheriff was contrary and let it pass never called for the souldier, atall, and he was mustered out of service with the rest, the Sheriff Indited me at last Circuit Court, and the court found a true bill again me, I give Bond for my appearnce at <date when="--10">Oct</date> Court. Governor I have been in the armey for the last thirty-five monhts. I have served a good portion of the time as a Private, I ^have^ ever endeavered to do my duty as a Souldier, and believed I was doing my duty when I rescued the Souldier, I have Commanded detachments, in different portions of this Country, and have always rendered satisfaction, I can establish my-self by every promenent Citizen in this Country as being a Law abiding man for that is what I have been fighting for all the while, I am a poor man, too, and think it verry injustice to have to pay our money for the prejudice of such men, as sheriff Jackman, of Russell Co. and others that has done but little for their Country.</p>
<p>I am yet in the service and generally has as mutch on hand as I can attend.<pb/>
<lb/>Governor if you wish any information concerning my caracter, pleas drop a note to Maj. J. M. Bristow with whome you are acquainted</p>
<p>S. W. Hurt, R F. Bryson, Clinton Co Samuel B. Fields and Winfrey of Columbia ore any Other prominent Citizens in the Country that is acquaitned with me even from repirtation. and Governor if you think it Justice, I will be under many Obligations, if you will. Cause the Court of Russell Co. Ky. to relieve me from the hand and withdraw are throw the cases <hi rend="underline">out</hi> of court Govener Bramblett I would not ask it if I did not think, I was doing my duty in which I was indited for, if you can do any thing for me will you be so kind as to drop me a line at -- Albany Ky pleas excuse me for bothering you with Such an extensive letter.</p>
<p>I am your Obdt Servt. -- 
<lb/>James F. Stephenson
<lb/>1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Lieut. Co (E)
<lb/>S C Batt,<pb/></p>
<p>Albany Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-06-14">June 14" 1865</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Stephenson James F
<lb/>Lt Co "E" S. C. Bat (State)
<lb/>To Gov.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Gives facts in case of arrest of soldier of his Command while in the 13<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">"</hi></hi> Ky Cav -- by Sheriff of Russell Co. Ky -- &amp; his retaking him has been indicted by Comd -- asks that you relieve him -- in some way -- Gives references -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Rec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> A. G. O. <date when="1865-07-20">July 20" 1865</date></p>
<p>Russell Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Jas H. Stephenson for Rescuing John Rollins from Jail
<lb/>To be further considered
<lb/>Pardoned
<lb/><date when="1866-01-11">11 Jany/66</date></p>
<p>Write to him to know what is the offence for which he is indicted. to send copy of Indictment or statement of the clerk as to the offence Charged in the Indictment</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
