<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-030-0002"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. M. Mills, John S. Hays, and J. H. Garrard, Report</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7638</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Special Studies and Reports to the Governor, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R1-16 to R1-19</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-05-18">18 May 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Report</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">1.</note></p>
<p>Frankfort Ky <date when="1863-05-18">May 18<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>Hon James F. Robinson
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>The undersigned having been appointed by your Excellency as inspectors of the Ky Penitentiary, would respectfully announce that we accepted the commissions and entered upon the discharge of our duties. Regular visits have been made each week as the law directs, and after a thorough inspection of all departments of the institution, the following report is presented in reference to <hi rend="str">the</hi> its condition, as we found it at the time the present keeper took it in charge.</p>
<p>The New Building or Hemp House.</p>
<p>This building is used for the manufacture of rope and bagging, and hackling hemp. It contains an engine for the double purpose of running the machinery and heating the several apartments by steam. With a view of supplying the engine with water, a large well was dug in the interior, about midway the length of the house, but near the foundation. In consequence of this, the earth between the excavation for the well and foundation gave away, causing the latter to sink and producing a crack in the brick wall and falling of the cornice above. This defect has not been repaired, and at the portion of the sunken cornice the roof leaks in rainy weather, and the wall already shows signs of injury which should be remedied before further damage ensues. The boilers are contained in a one story house adjoining the main building. The roof covering them is rather low, but being very near the point specified in the injured wall, when the necessary repair is made in that, the roof could be raised with trivial expense. 108 panes of glass were broken in the window in this building.<pb/></p>
<p><note place="header">2.</note></p>
<p>The Black-smith Shop.</p>
<p>The roof is very old, defective and leaks badly. The flues of two of the forges need repairing -- one of them is so devoid of draft, that whenever the fire is kindled, the sparks ascend directly to the ceiling and greatly endanger the safety of the building. We were informed, that on more than one occasion fire had resulted from this cause, and the matter was tested in our presence to such an extent <hi rend="str">sufficient</hi> as to satisfy us that the information was correct. 59 panes of glass were broken in the windows of this building.</p>
<p>The Carpenter Shop.</p>
<p>The condition of this building decidedly bad in every respect. The rafters are sunken at various points, the roof almost worthless and the walls deficient in strength. One of the undersigned whilst making a sanitary inspection in connection with another physician of the city, observed pools of water standing on the floor on a rainy day <hi rend="str">to such as</hi> and the mechanics were thereby prevented from engaging in their accustomed work at some of the benches. 66 panes of glass were broken in the windows of this building.</p>
<p>In this connection we would venture the following suggestions.</p>
<p>1. That the repairs necessary for this building should be immediate.</p>
<p>2. That the undertaking can be greatly facilitated by the resource for material already in the yard. This resource exists in an old building formerly used as a hemp house, but is now appropriated for the storage of corn and hay. As no branch of industry is carried on ^in^ it, it could be torn down and the quantity of brick and lumber it contains be very servicebly applied for the purpose indicated, and its removal would give<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">3.</note>
<lb/>more room as well as add to the appearance of the yard. The condition of the carpenter shop is such as to require prompt attention, and as there exists sufficient material in it and the other structure alluded to, to form one good substantial building, it would doubtless be a matter of economy to raze them both and rebuild.</p>
<p>The Wash House or Soap Manufactory,</p>
<p>Is a small building that stands near the kitchen, having a furnace and three kettles for making soap. It is defective in the following particulars,</p>
<p>1. It should be provided with a ventilator to carry off the fumes generated in making the soap -- and this is more essential in cold weather when the door of the room must be closed. These fumes are certainly injurious to the health of the persons here engaged,
<lb/>2. There should be a fireplace or stove in it, to assist in ventilation as well as serve the comfort of the manufacturers. At present, the only means by which they can warm themselves in Winter is by drawing some of the fire from the furnace, and to carry off the smoke the furnace door has necessarily to be kept open at times when the manufacturing process requires it to be shut.
<lb/>3. The floor should be brick or stone throughout. Now it is only partly so, just within the entrace, while the balance being earth, becomes soft from the quantity of water that has to be used in and about the kettles.</p>
<p>The Chapel.</p>
<p>This building is used for dining room, kitchen, chapel and shoe shops, the first two departments being in the lower, the latter in the upper story. The fire wall needs repairing immediately<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">-4</note>
<lb/>and the upper floor is sunken and unsteady. 66 panes of glass were broken in the windows of this building.</p>
<p>The Meat House</p>
<p>Needs repairing in the wall just above the foundation. The bricks are softened and falling from their places, which is a very common result in buildings used any length of time for such purposes. The meat after it is first salted, is piled upon the floor previous to its being suspended for smoking, and the action of the salt is such as to produce crumbling of the bricks and mortar.</p>
<p>The Fire Engine House</p>
<p>Should ^be^ weather-boarded anew and needs a new roof. The floor also needs attention. The hose belonging to the engine are in bad order, and would be of little service in case of fire. The engine is a substantial one, but rather small to be very effective.</p>
<p>The Cells.</p>
<p>The bedding here was very old and worn, and the covering whollly insufficient for inclement weather, many of the inmates having been compelled to pass the Winter with only one blanket and quite a number of these very indifferent in character. The straw in the ticks had not been renewed for sometime. There was but one stove in each walk around the cells where there certainly have been two, to have insured a reasonable degree of comfort.</p>
<p>It is but due to Capt. H. I. Todd, who has recently assumed charge of the institution, to say that he has commenced the work of reform in this department. The cells have all been whitewashed and cleansed, new ticks are being prepared<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">5</note>
<lb/>additional covering provided, and he has promised that due attention shall be paid to its preservation, as well as having the ticks refilled and ventilated. The gutters about the building need repair, some of the joints having separated and staining and dampness of the wall ensued.</p>
<p>The Yard</p>
<p>Has been undergoing a cleansing process which would require some days to accomplish in consequence of the great amount of accumulated dirt and the number of filthy pig pens that were in it. Two pools of stagnant water were observed West of the carpenter shop, which were used by the coopers and chairmakers and although they may be considered necessary for those branches of business, yet they are shallow and enclosed by wooden boxes and they <hi rend="str">water</hi> can easily be emptied from time and refilled, thus preventing any injurious effects from stagnation. At the time of our last inspection, it was evident that this precaution had not been attended to.</p>
<p>External Inspection.</p>
<p>In examining the lots of ground East of the enclosure, the fence surrounding them were very bad, some of the pannels entirely gone. A Stable stands near the wall, the posts and frame work of which were good, but the roof and weatherboarding of no value. We estimated it at the sum of thirty dollars.</p>
<p>The present keeper has enlarged and refitted it since the above observation, and also repaired the fencing.</p>
<p>The Ware House</p>
<p>Is in want of a new roof. and the fire wall at one end of the building is falling away. The lower floor needs relaying.<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">6</note></p>
<p>The Sewer.</p>
<p>This is of so important a character as to require great watchfulness to prevent its becoming obstructed, and secure as large a flow of water through it as possible. The head or commencement of this sewer is guarded by a large grate, just exterior to which is a pit, designed to catch the settlings and dirt as the water approaches the entrance. Care should be taken that this pit does not fill up, as is the case at present, else the water continuing to flow the dirt is carried forward, accumulates in the sewer, <hi rend="str">and</hi> obstruction is thus created and the water forced back in the opposite direction. A bad feature connected with the matter, and one that should long ago have received attention, is, that the principal ditch for draining the lot in which the head of the sewer is located, has the wrong inclination and a good supply of water is lost that might otherwise be obtained.</p>
<p>The Private Dwelling.</p>
<p>This building needs the usual renovation bestowed on residences, such as painting, papering, plastering &amp;c, but in some respects has been greatly neglected. The banistering was broken, the slopes of some of the floors, (the dining room particularly) were sunken rendering the floors unsteady, the glass broken in several windows, some of the shutters void of slats, grates need resetting, hearths to be laid anew and closets need repair.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">The Division Fence</hi> between the yard and adjoining premises is a poor affair, having very few good planks on it, while the <hi rend="underline">fence</hi> in rear of the lot, separating it from the alley was entirely worthless except three of the posts.<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">7.</note></p>
<p>The Out Buildings</p>
<p>Were in very bad condition. <hi rend="underline">The Privy</hi> -- was almost destitute of weatherboarding. The floor in the <hi rend="underline">Milk House</hi> is stone, but completely disjointed, and the floor of the <hi rend="underline">Kitchen</hi> should be constructed anew. The two last named apartments are contained in a long building used for these purposes and for negro quarters. Near the foundation a good portion of the weather-boarding is torn away and the roof very defective. The house if promptly repaired is susceptible of being made a good one, but unless this is done, it will soon go to decay.</p>
<p>A small building stands in the yard near the dwelling, which was originally designed as the private office of a former keeper, but has been variously appropriated for a corn crib, carriage house and storage for coal. Its condition is bad and it might well be removed to contribute the better part of its material to assist in essential repairs on other portions of the premises.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">The Hydrant</hi> was defective and leaking -- the waste water has been permitted to settle around it, finding its only escape underneath the fence against which the hydrant stands. The distance from the hydrant to the main sewer is short and a connecting drain could have been easily established and prevented the street from being constantly wet and muddy as heretofore.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">The Police Force</hi> of the prison <hi rend="str">consects</hi> consists of four assistant keepers, and five guards.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">The Sanitary Condition</hi>, of the institution, has since the time of our appointment, been greatly improved. The small pox which then prevailed so extensively among the inmates has entirely disap-<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">8.</note>
<lb/>peared and the attending physician is using his best efforts to have the Hospital department properly supplied with good bedding and other articles necessary for the comfort of the sick.</p>
<p>In the above <hi rend="str">report</hi> we have presented a correct statement of the condition of the institution and grounds <hi rend="str">adjoining it</hi> connected with it, as we found them. We shall endeavor to comply with the law under which we were appointed, and make all <hi rend="str">reports</hi> inspections as thorough and all reports as impartial as possible.</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>J. M. Mills
<lb/>John S. Hays } Inspectors Ky Penitentiary
<lb/>J. H. Garrard</p>
<p>Kenty Penitentiary
<lb/>Inspection Report</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
