<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0787"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Brockman to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4906</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-213 to BR10-216A</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thomas E. Bramlette</p>
<p>Your Petitioner William Brockman says that at the present term of the Jefferson Circuit Court he was tried on a Indictment for the murder of one Adolph Logel. found guilty of manslaughter and sentenced to serve ten years in the penitentiary of this commonwealth. He did not deny on the trial and does not deny now that he struck Logel a blow which unfortunately proved fatal but he asserted then and still asserts that he struck said blow in self-defense and under circumstances that justified it He says that he lives in the suburbs of Louisville not far from the old Oakland Race Course at which point the general government Keeps stabled a large number of horses and mules &amp;c the chief part of which have been worn out in the military service of the government, considerable numbers of these animals die daily and the persons having them in charge were in the habit of hauling them to a strip of woods near petitioner's House and there leaving them to rot. Your Petitioner had obtained leave to take the skins off of<pb/>
<lb/>these carcasses on the condition he would remove or burn the carcasses to avoid having a nusance to the detriment of the health of the neighborhood The deceased Logel without having obtained leave as petitioner did, to take the skins, was in the habit of taking the skins and leaving the carcasses on the ground neither removing or burning them This created a nusance for which petitioner was indicted and fined Petitioner apprised Logel of the facts and told him he must not skin any more of the animals without burning or removing the carcasses but Logel insisted that he would skin them without removing the carcasses and continued and persisted in so doing. At the time the difficulty occurred Logel had just skinned ^one^ of said animals ^a cow^ when your petitioner approached him and requested him to remove the carcass Harsh language and a quarrel ensued, Logel had a Butcher Knife with which he had just skinned the animal, in one hand and a stick in the other Your petitioner had<pb/>
<lb/>only a stick in hand but it was pretty heavy one. Logel struck your petitioner twice with the stick and cut him on the hand with the knife before petitioner struck at all whereupon your petition struck Logel with the sitck which was in your petitioner's hand a blow which knocked him down and unfortunately proved fatal Your petitioner had no idea that the blow would prove fatal and had no intention of killing Logel and struck him only in self=defense. Your petitioner insisted that he did not have a fair trial in the circuit court and that the verdict was obtained only by a conspiricy on the part of the principal wintesses for the commonwealth He states that the prinicpal witness for the state Donheimer not only testified differently in very material points from what he did in the examining court and far more unfavorably to the accused than he there testified but also as is showen by the accompanying affidavits of John Shrader Augusta Shrader and Charles Samuel Baker, procurred the witness for the com=<pb/>
<lb/>monwealth Huber, by bribery, to swear falsely on the trial of the case in the circuit court and thereby to make statements corroberating his said Donheimers, false testimony, all of which your petitioner was not made aware until after said trial.</p>
<p>Joseph Clements one of the justices who composed the examining court testified in the trial in the circuit court that the witness Donheimer stated in the examing court that the deceased had a stick with which he was punching accused at the time accused struck him, whereas Donheimer testified on the trial in the circuit court that accused approached and ordered Logel to put down the skin and thereupon without anything further struck deceased upon the back of the neck a blow which produced his death. The witness for the accused Frend also testified that Donheimer attempted to procure him by bribe to swear against accused and that said Donheimer had said in his, Friend's<pb/>
<lb/>hearing that he wanted to have accused hung or sent to the penitentiary. Cathrine Barbarer testified that Donheimer sayed he would have accused hung The witness Simms who with the witnesses Haber and Donheimer was the only witness for the commonwealth who pretended to have seen the diffculty contradicted Donheimer by stating that the accused and the deceased "quarrelled" and fussed and contended over the skins for some time, and although he Simms then testified that he did not see but heard only one blow struck and thereafter looked and saw deceased lying on the ground, he is there in contra^dicted^ by Mr L A Wood an atty at law who testified on the trial in the circuit court that he was present as a spectator at the examining trial and that Simms there stated that deceased had a knife in his hand with which he struck at accused and L. A. Wood further testified that accused in the examining trial had a cut on the back of his hand.</p>
<p>The court refused a continuance applied for by accused at this present term on the ground<pb/>
<lb/>of the absence in Tennessee of accused's principal witness whose name is Rudolph Christler and who is a soldier in the Federal army and was so at the time of the difficulty and by whom accused could have proved on the trial in the circuit court as he, did prove by said witnesses in the examining court that he Rudolph Chrisler saw deceased strike at and strike accused with a stick before accused struck deceased and that deceased had a knife in his hand during the difficulty with which he cut accused on the hand Your petitioner had a subpoenas for this witness and it was returned by, the sheriff "not found" and petitioners counsel asked leave of the court to introduce evidence of what the witness Chrisler had testified in the examining and which the court refused to do Your petitioner says that if we could have obtained the testimony of Christler it would have fully corroborated, and supported the testimony of DeFlour in the trial in the circuit Court and established the innocence of the accused of the charge Your petitioner states that he has<pb/>
<lb/>a large family depended on his exertions for support</p>
<p>All of which your petitioner would respectfully submit and implore the exercise in his behalf of your Excellency's clemency</p>
<p><unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>translation William Brockman</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Louisville join in the prayer of the foregoing petition and aske that William Brockman be pardoned</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Nat. Wolfe
<lb/>R. N. Rousseau
<lb/>J H Honesby
<lb/>Chas Kahnt
<lb/>Dr. V. Donhoff
<lb/>F. Bender
<lb/>Byron Bacon
<lb/>F. Goine
<lb/>A M Gayley
<lb/>Jack Fry
<lb/>S. A. Atchison
<lb/>Jeff. Brown.
<lb/>W. W. Fry
<lb/>James A. Beattie
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> W. Gibson
<lb/>W A Memoistre
<lb/>Jno Hanna
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Jo<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. Clement
<lb/>W. C. Wood
<lb/>W. P. McDowell
<lb/>Lewis N Demlitz
<lb/>Martin Byrn
<lb/>S. S. Bash
<lb/>A. G. Shivell
<lb/>L. A. Wood
<lb/>Isaac P Miller
<lb/>Franz. A. Kramer
<lb/>E D Craig
<lb/>W. B. Hoke
<lb/>Sam B. Smith
<lb/>C. Ormsby
<lb/>R. J. Ormsby<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Wm. F. Wood
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Hamilton Pope</hi>
<lb/>Alfred T. Pope.
<lb/>M S Fields
<lb/>James Harris
<lb/>J. P. Sullivath
<lb/>John N. Mattingly
<lb/>Jno. K. Miller
<lb/>John G. Barbon
<lb/><cb n="2"/>F G Dannecker
<lb/><hi rend="underline">H. S. Burkhard</hi>
<lb/>T. Jack Conn
<lb/>R H Woolfolk
<lb/>Q. M. Sherley
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Thos. Q. Griffiths</hi><pb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Brockman</p>
<p>This is a case which demands Executive clemency and a pardon is ordered</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/><date when="1864-04-29">Apl 29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date> Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi>
<lb/>10 years
<lb/>Manslaughter</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
