<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0320"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. B. Carpenter to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4439</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-14 to BR9-16</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Cynthiana, Harrison County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-11-08">8 November 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Cynthiana <date when="1863-11-08">Novr 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>Thos E Bramlette
<lb/>Dear Governor</p>
<p>At the present Term of the Harrison Circuit Court George Sidle was indicted for the murder of Richard Jameson and convicted of manslaughter. The proof was that the prisoner and deceased had some ill feeling in this town on that day, but that had been settled &amp; late in the afternoon Sidle and his son a young man twenty four years old left town for home, and that shortly afterwords that deceased &amp; his brother Lewis Jameson both of whom were nighbors of Sidle left for home. The latter overtook the former about a mile from town, and the prisoner and the deceased rode on together and Lewis Jameson &amp; young Sidle for about half a mile when a dispute arose about a horse being glandered -- Prisoner told decd that the neighbors said that he had brought<pb/>
<lb/>a horse into the neighborhood that had the glanders-deceased replied that any person who said So was a d -- d lior The prisoner replied I believe he had the glanders and I believe you beleve it deceased said if you say that again I will take you off your horse -- prioner repreated the statement and deceased took him by the collor and they both came to the ground on their feet between their horses -- prisoner immediately drew a large revolver and deceased caught the barrell in his left hand about one inch and a half from the muzzle and held it up to keep prisoner from shooting him - Young Sidle then went up &amp; caught hold of the pistol with his left hand on the barrell and deceased with his right and told his father not to shoot deceased Should not hurt him, then Lewis Came up and put one hand on prisoner and the other on his brother &amp; told the prisoner not to fire that Dick should not hurt him - That suddenly prisoner drew his arm back bringing the pistol in range of the head of deceased and fired Killing deceased almost instantly<pb/>
<lb/>The prisoner then said he has shot himself and a moment afterwords said I have killed him why did you let me shoot him - both replied they had done all they could to prevent it. Prisoner and deceased were about equal in Strength, and the latter was not armed This was the substance of the proof, by the mouth of Jameson &amp; Young Sidle All the parties and strangers to me, but in my opinion there was no pretence even of self defence, and no occassion to kill Jameson where these men &amp; a pistol were protecting the prisoners and upon no proof was offered tending to show that Jameson even attempted to strike him - Jameson &amp; Sidle were the only witnesses and it cannot be for a moment supposed That the son would fail to make as strong a case for his father or truth warranted In my opinion the verdict of the Jury was a merciful one and this man ought not to be pardoned - I Should be gratifyed if your Excellency would adopt Some rule<pb/>
<lb/>at least requiring a statement of the facts from Judge Doniphan or myself in cases of applications for pardon in all cases within dist</p>
<p>Very Respcty
<lb/>Your obt Servt
<lb/>R B Carpenter</p>
<p>P S Instructions so Libal that Messrs Davis and Trimble accepted them without <unclear/> were asked by me &amp; given by the Court including one upon the questions of self difence in accordance with the doctrine laid down in Ropps case 14 BM - &amp; Comr in Meredith 18 B M -- </p>
<p>R B C<pb/></p>
<p>Harrison Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Geo Sidle</p>
<p>Heretofore acted upon</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
