<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1981"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. G. Henant et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11449</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Bradley Strait</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG23-441 to MG23-442</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency Beriah Maggoffin Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky,</p>
<p>Your Petitioner John G. Hennet would most respectfully represent to your Excellency, that at a called court held in Butler County <hi rend="str">held</hi> in <date when="1862-05">May 1862</date> by the Equity and Criminal Judge for the 4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Judicial district in the State of Kentucky he was fined in the Sum of forty dollars in said ^court^ for a supposed violation of the laws against tippling. Your petitioner states that he Sold nothing but peppermint cordial, that the court at which he was fined was not a regular term of said court, that it was called on short notice, that he had no witness present when the trial was had, and that the Atty. for the Commonwealth had told him before the case was tried that he would dismiss the prosecution against him. He further states that, if he had known that said case would be taken up at said called Court, that he could and would have proved that what he had sold was nothing but peppermint cordial. -- He sates that he is a poor man with a large family and if he has to pay the fine it will much oppress him. Your petitioner prays your Excellency to remit said fine and as in duty bound he will ever pray. Your petitioner would further state that he had no idea of violating the laws of Ky as the same article had been sold in Butler County Ky for some 25 or 30 years preceading the time at which he Sold it, and no notice was taken of it by the Judicial authorities<pb/>
<lb/>of said county. 1</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J, G, Henant 2
<lb/>L W Moore 3
<lb/>Charles D, Davenport M. D. 4
<lb/>G, C, Flener 5
<lb/>J D Gavins 6
<lb/>Thomas L. Davis 7
<lb/>J. B. Bratcher 8 
<lb/>M. S. Keykendall 9
<lb/>James. A. Moore 10
<lb/>H Berrymore 11
<lb/>J. N. Phelps 12
<lb/>H. R. Senour 13
<lb/>G. W. <unclear/> 14
<lb/>V. H. Jones 15
<lb/>B L D Guffy 16
<lb/>J. M. Forgy 17
<lb/>W C Rogers 18
<lb/>G B Dockery 19
<lb/>Henry Clark -- 20 I hope the above fine will be remitted
<lb/>Samuel Austin 21
<lb/>W R Wilson 22
<lb/>John Tigert 23
<lb/>G Rone 24
<lb/>J. C. Carson 25
<lb/>E Dudley Walker 26
<lb/>James Butler 27
<lb/>P Baynes 28
<lb/>J C Howard 29
<lb/>J N M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Coun 30
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> C. Skillem 31
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> P Ward 32
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J C <unclear/>
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> V. Loving
<lb/>A W Graham<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>J T <unclear/>
<lb/>Edward Renfrain
<lb/>Alvin West
<lb/>T M Allison
<lb/><unclear/> M. Roach
<lb/>Pete B <unclear/>
<lb/>W F Leach
<lb/>E R Green<pb/></p>
<p>Butler Eq Ct
<lb/>$40. } Liquor
<lb/>Jno G Henant
<lb/>Remission Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1862-06-09"><hi rend="underline">June 9 1862</hi></date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
