<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0472"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">T. L. McNary to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8924</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-258</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Princeton, Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-07-22">22 July 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Princeton Ky. <date when="1863-07-22">July 22. 1863</date>
<lb/>Governor Robinson</p>
<p>D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Sir by the request of Mr. T. W. Pickering I will address you on the subject of a fine assessed against him on acct. of his haveing accepted the office of confederate Shariff &amp; indeed I thought at the time he deserved to be fined ten fold of what he was fined &amp; I still think under ordinary circumstances the punishment could not be too great but now he is heavily involved in security matters &amp; after having been an industrious saveing ^man^ he will be well nigh broken up &amp; if this additional fine should have to be paid by him -- he will ^be^ very near the mouth of the spout with an upward tendency tho. these reasons alone are not sufficiently good to base the release of his fine on tho. in addition I think he has become convinced of errour &amp; will never be guilty of such an other piece of foolery &amp; indeed he was misled &amp; wholy ignorant of the responsibility he was incuring -- I am a stranger to you I have some acquaintance with a few gentlemen in your city &amp; I will refer you to Mr P. Swagert Col<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">n</hi></hi> Hodges J. B. Temple &amp;c tho. my acquaintance with them is quite limited &amp; now if in your cool &amp; better moments of reflection you can give him some material relief it will be highly appreciated -- tho. in the main I am opposed to such extentions of relief</p>
<p>Mosest respectfully
<lb/>Your Humble Servnt.
<lb/><hi rend="underline">T. L. McNary</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
