<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0910"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Hiram Hogg et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10378</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-447</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Whitesburg, Letcher County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Whitesburg Letcher County Ky.
<lb/>To His Excelency B. Magoffin Govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your pettioner William Nash, states that one Samuel Ramsey (his Brother-in-Law) was arested under a warant sued out by one George W. Adams -- Charging said Ramsey with perjery or fauls swaring -- said Ramsey was tried be fore Hiram Hogg judd of the Letcher County court -- when the prisnor at bar was held to bale in the sum of 400 dollars to appear in the Letcher Circuit Court on the first day of its next turm. <hi rend="str">B<unclear/> B<unclear/></hi> Being his Brother-in-Law -- and beleaving that the prosecution was malisious and based on <hi rend="str">false</hi> fauls pretences -- and that Ramsey would stand his trial your pettioner was indused to go his bale for his appearance in said Court -- Your pettioner here wishes to call your attention to the assigneiner of purgurey and the proof to sustane it.</p>
<p>Ramsey was a witnes in a suit tride in the Quartley court of this county betwen Moses Adams and Joseph Gilley for fraud in a horse swap -- the jurey hered the testimony in the case and retired to there room to make a verdict. Whilst in there room -- Ramsey was Called in -- and when he entered he was informed that he was called to tell what had become of the old mare that was in dispute -- Ramsey said he had took her to verginna and traded her of -- <hi rend="str">so</hi> one portion of the jurey sais that ^the^ next question asked him was, what did moses adams git for the mare, he (Ramsey) answered nothing. The other portion of the <hi rend="underline">same</hi> jurey says that the question was -- what did you git for the mare in verginne -- asnwer nothing the way things turned out -- <pb/>
<lb/>the charge of perjuery is that Ramsey <hi rend="str">swore</hi> stated before the jurey whilst in there room -- that moses adams got nothing for the mare -- when it is proven that he pa^i^d moses 15 bushels of corn. The jurey differing as to what the question was, that was asked by them, and the fact that they was not in open court as the law required, and that none of the jurey could tell what Ramsey swore in open court -- and the malis displayed on trial -- caused your pettioner to beleave that Ramey was not guilty of the charge -- your pettioner was led to beleave with out a doubt he would appear and defend himsell. before the next turm of the court -- he left the Commonwealth, uppon his falure to ancer the charge -- judgment was rendered on the bond against his securiety. now your pettioner states that he beleaves that he would not have fled the commonwealth -- had it not been for the fauls-hoods that was accumulating against him; Your pettioner feling himself a greaved by the immediate and surrounding sircumstances; throes him self on your mersies &amp; Chariety any ever prey your Exelency to remit the judgmen on the forfeiture, feling that in his presant condition it would greatley <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> embaris him <hi rend="str">if</hi> to pay the judgment -- he ever askes and prays that all or any part may be remited</p>
<p>We the under signed sitezens of Letch. county beleave the statemens of the pettioner to be true, join in prear to your Exelency that he be released from said judgment.<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Hiram Hogg J. L. C. C
<lb/>J, S, C, Taylor M D
<lb/>Jno. C. Fugate
<lb/>E. S. Fugate
<lb/>W. T. B. Brashears
<lb/>Abner Lewis S, L, C
<lb/>Randle Patty
<lb/>Manfred S Friens
<lb/>David White
<lb/>Ira.. Baker
<lb/>Isaac.. Williams
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Sawer, Atty.
<lb/><cb n="2"/>D..W.. May Atty at Law
<lb/>Ezekiel Brashear C J C C
<lb/>J. E. Brashear Jaler L C -- 
<lb/>A. D. Hale D. C.<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Respite 12 Mo
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>Letcher Cir. Ct
<lb/>$400. } Recog
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Nash
<lb/>Iss <date when="1861-04-09">Apr 9 1861.</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
