<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2025"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Ambrose W. Mooney, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6662</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-187</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Webster County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-06-24">24 June 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Kentucky Webster County } sct</p>
<p>A W Mooney says that he is Citizen of Dixon the County seat of Webster County Ky that he is well acquainted with John A Brooks late of said town. That said Brooks is said now to be in the Teritory of Colorodo That Brooks has a wife and child now living in Dixon -- That Brooks was a practising lawyer in the Webster Circuit Court That he was said to be a comissioned lieutenant in the regiment of Col A R Johnson of the Army of the so Called Confederate States during the year <date when="1862">1862</date> or a part there of That during the early part of the year <date when="1863">1863</date> he took the oath of allegiance gave bond and <unclear/> was released by Col Foster Commander of the Post at Henderson That he returned to his home in Dixon and behaved himself well and peacebly during the time he remained and attended to his business as a lawyer but that during the <date when="1864">summer of 1864</date> some officers and soldiers of the 52<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> Ky Regiment passed through Dixon &amp; Without any apparent Cause threatened said Brooks and ordered him to leave the Country which he did and which in affiants estimation it was prudent and safe for him to do There was at the time great prejudice in the minds of the Federal Soldiery against those who had been in the Rebel army an^d^ especially those under the said A R Johnson</p>
<p>Ambrose. W. Mooney<pb/></p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to by A W Mooney before me the <date when="1865-06-24">24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of June 1865</date></p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Herron J P W C</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
