<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0511"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Isaac Cox to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9979</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-293 to MG18-294</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Whitley County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-01-12">12 January 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To the Excelence of the Governor of the Commonwealth of Ky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Isaac M Coxyold Respectifull Represent to your <hi rend="str">honor</hi> Excelence that <hi rend="str">Some</hi> he is a Resident of the state of Alabam but was Rased in Whitley County Ky and that he Returned to Whitley on a visit and had ben trawlin all the time tell <hi rend="str">he</hi> a bout <hi rend="str">and</hi> <hi rend="str">or</hi> two ^or three^ days when they was a warnt is^ued^ by a justice of the peace against him for Carering conceald deadley wepons and he was fined by said justice $50.<hi rend="sup">00</hi> he states that if he has the same to pay that he will not have money a nough to cary him and his wife Back home and that he is a way from home and his busisness call him hom your petitioner further States that he did not know that the law of Ky forbid caring conceld weapons he <hi rend="str">has</hi> had no intention of violating the law in carrying<pb/>
<lb/>the wepon he prays that your Exelence will Remite the fine and for all <hi rend="str">other</hi> proper Releif</p>
<p>Isaac Cox</p>
<p>Isaac M Cox states that he believs the statements in the fore going petition to be true</p>
<p>J M Cox</p>
<p>Swon to before me by J M Cox this the <date when="1861-01-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Jany 1861</date></p>
<p>L. D. Sutton P J W C</p>
<p>we the under signed Request that your Exelents Remite the fine as your petitioner was Rased a viry pore boy and we do not believe he knew that he was violating <hi rend="str">to</hi> the law by caring the wepan</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>names of subsribrs
<lb/>John Smith
<lb/>James Cutbirth
<lb/>Wm C Cox
<lb/>Wm A peabler
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J. L. McCarty
<lb/>Jiss Garnet
<lb/>Thomas Cox
<lb/>P.. Meador
<lb/>R Bird
<lb/><hi rend="str">D. B. <unclear/> Cox</hi>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Abeslam Cox
<lb/>M C Roche
<lb/>T. D. Sutton
<lb/>Isaiah Bird
<lb/>F Nicholson
<lb/>A. D. Brooks
<lb/>S P Brawner
<lb/>W F Denham
<lb/>W C Murphy
<lb/>J N Vye
<lb/>Amber Parker
<lb/>W J Tye
<lb/><cb n="2"/>
<lb/>To his Excelency Beriah McGoffin Govener of Kentucky Mr Isaac N Cox was tried before me for caring conseald weapons other than a ordinary pocket knife and the right of Jury was waived by our county attorney and after having Heard the proof and not being able to find any law to Justify a traveler for carring consealed weapons &amp; fined the said cost fifty Dollars I think it nothing but right the same should be remited by your Exelency I am conferdent he is a citizen of Allbamer and did not no it was against the Law to carry the same</p>
<p>G. L. Moret J. P. W. C<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Whitley
<lb/>J. P.
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>$50 } Weapons
<lb/>J. M. Cox
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-01-30">Jany 30 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
