<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0802"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Barr et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4921</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-238 to BR10-239</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Owen County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-05-16">16 May 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thos E Bramlette Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Whereas Tank Hodson of the County ^of Owen^ charged with Stabbing Taylor Wingate on the <gap/> day of <date when="1864">1864</date> with intent to Kill was held to bail ^by the Examining Court^ in the sum of two hundred &amp; fifty dollars for his appearance at at the <date when="1864-05">May term of the Owen Circuit Court 1864</date> and Andrew Hodson together with John Barr became the sureties in said Bail Bond and the prisoner failing to appear the Bond was forfeited at the <date when="1864-05">May term 1864</date> of the Owen Circuit Court- Now the undersigned citizens of Owen and the Neighbors &amp; acquaintances of Mr Barr beg leave to say that he is an honest, upright &amp; industrious man and a good citizen, that he has a family ^consisting of himself &amp; wife &amp; 7 children^ to support and of only moderate means and that the payment of this Bond if coerced would fall heavily upon him. They say that the other surity is the father of the prisoner and it is extremely doubtful whether any part of the Money could be made out of him therefore the whole Burden of payment would fall upon the security Barr. They say that Wingate has gotten well &amp; Hodson the accused is reportid to have enlisted in the Federal Service.</p>
<p>They say that they are satisfied that Mr Barr was induce to enter upon the Bond as Surety from <unclear/> <unclear/>, assurances that the accurate<pb/>
<lb/>would render himself up to the court according to the provisions of his Bond &amp; as an act of <unclear/> kindness toward the father of the accused. They say that both the accused &amp; Wingate were quite young being only about 16 years of age.</p>
<p>Mr Barr says for himself, that the absince of the accused was without his <unclear/> or consent or knowledge^ and the others whose Names are attached hereto ^<hi rend="underline">for</hi> him^ that they beliave that that the subscriber of the accused or his failing to appear, was wholly without the priority, knowledge or consent of the said Barr, and he is therefore to be the sufferer for his kindness to his neighbor_ In view of all the circumstances the undersigned believe that it would be one act of Mercy, on the part of His Excellency to remit the payment of the penalty of the Bond forfeited as a <unclear/> as far as his in the power of the executive ask John Barr And they therefore pray that his Excellency will remit the same as to John Barr except attys fee &amp; costs &amp; further they will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p>Owen County <date when="1864-05-16">May 16, 1864</date></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>John Barr
<lb/>James Fitzgerald P J M
<lb/>John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Lawrence
<lb/>Edward C Shipp
<lb/>W. H. Lawrence
<lb/>Henry Wingate
<lb/>R. H. Smith
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/>John. T. Graves
<lb/>J M. Smithers
<lb/>W F Ellis
<lb/>W J Nerd
<lb/>Aaron Jacobs
<lb/>M. Buclyes
<lb/>J. F. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Fadden<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>J. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Daniel
<lb/>W Siers
<lb/>William Juett
<lb/>W. H. Canghte
<lb/>D. C Hoover
<lb/>H Roberts
<lb/>W. H. Walker
<lb/>G. W. Cardin
<lb/>J. E. Duvall
<lb/>Samuel Wise
<lb/>N Traylor
<lb/>J. S. Willhite
<lb/>S. S. Sanders
<lb/>A. L. Bell
<lb/>John Barr
<lb/>W.. M Barr
<lb/>William Webb
<lb/>Jane H Luety
<lb/>Geoge Hebb
<lb/>Jisor Franz
<lb/>B. F. Webster
<lb/>A. J. Webster
<lb/>Jackson M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Enella
<lb/>John Budden
<lb/>Geo M Pearson
<lb/>D. S. Clark
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/>Charles Taylor
<lb/>Y Q Robertson
<lb/>Joeph R Olson
<lb/>Lewis Wright
<lb/>Richard Curring
<lb/>John Fitsgwills
<lb/>Wm.. G.. Haydon
<lb/>John G. Hayden
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Long
<lb/>James Long
<lb/>Geo. W. Karsner
<lb/>J. C. Karsner
<lb/>Jona. Karsner
<lb/>L S Prentiss
<lb/>James Y. Wilhoite
<lb/>T. B Ferah
<lb/>C P Sanfers
<lb/>W. H Arnold
<lb/>James Haydon
<lb/>A. H. Gruey
<lb/>Otho Vaught
<lb/>John Montgomery
<lb/>S M Clark
<lb/>Churchill Fitzgerald
<lb/>J. W. Smith
<lb/>Levi B Kemper<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>John Barrs
<lb/>Petition</p>
<p>Owen Cit Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John Barr &amp;c</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
