<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0810"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John D. Hale to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4929</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-250 to BR10-251</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mercer County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-06-20">20 June 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Hon Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. E. Bramlette Govenor of the state of Kentucky,</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Jno. D. Hale a citizen of Mercer County Kentucky respectfully states, That during the months of <date when="--03">March</date> &amp; <date when="--04">April</date> last past, he was engaged in raising a company of troops for service in the Federal Army &amp; defence of Kentucky. &amp; that he had raised a nomber of men and had there enlisted, &amp; that the recruiting office was in Harrodsburg Mercer County Ky, &amp; that among the recruits. was one John Patterson, who had volunteered &amp; had been duly sworn into service, that your petitioner received notice to get his men <hi rend="str">who</hi> had been recruited to gather, &amp; report them, that he made every effort to do so as a good citizens &amp; union loving man, that said John Patterson was one of the men who had volunteered, &amp; sworn into the service, that while looking out for those who had volunteered he understood that s<hi rend="sup">d</hi>. Patterson was<pb/>
<lb/>in the court House, &amp; he with several men who belonged to the Company went into the Court House with him &amp; said Patterson came to him &amp; delivered himself over to him, &amp; he received him. He states that he or any of the men with him on the occassion did not say a word, did not interupt the Court by any remark, use <hi rend="str">of</hi> violence or otherwise, and he states that he did not intend to violate any laws or interfere with the proceedings of the Court, that he had been advised by a captain who had been in the military service of the U. States that he had a right &amp; that it was his duty to receive his men &amp; take them at any place, &amp; being so advised, &amp; believeing it true he did receive said Jno. Patterson &amp; take him as one of the Company who had volunteered as afs<hi rend="sup">d</hi>__</p>
<p>He states that he would not have done what he did in this matter if he had not believed at the time that he was fully &amp; faithfully discharging his duty to the law, &amp; to his country &amp; that so<pb/>
<lb/>soon as he discovered the error in the matter, he forthwith delivered over to the Commonwealth of Kentucky the said John Patterson through the civil authorities, &amp; who now hold him according to law He states that for this proceeding he has been Indicted in the Mercer Circuit Court. for <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> and on the charge of rescuing the said John Patterson from the Mercer Circuit Court. He states that his intent &amp; purpose was to do right &amp; that he has always been a law abiding citizen, &amp; still intends to remain such, &amp; in view of the facts in the case he prays your Excellency to pardon him of the said charge &amp; he referes to the proof accompanying this Petition, &amp; to petition of the citizens of Mercer County__</p>
<p><date when="1864-06">June 1864</date>. J. D. Hale</p>
<p>Mercer County Ky</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by John D Hale this <date when="1864-06-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day June 1864</date>.</p>
<p>J. W. Cardwell N P
<lb/>Mercer Co Ky</p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">J W C
<lb/>N P
<lb/><date when="1864-06-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> June
<lb/>1864</date></note><pb/></p>
<p>John D. Hales
<lb/>Petition &amp; c</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
