<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1768"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">M. D. Hay to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6405</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-286 to BR13-288</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Greenville, Muhlenberg County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-05-26">26 May 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Greenville Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-05-26">May 26<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Gov Bramlette
<lb/>Frankfort Ky</p>
<p>D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Sir: At the present <date when="1865-05">May Term 1865</date> of the Muhlenberg Circuit Court a Judgment was rendered against Thomas Jenkins of this county for $80.00 on an Indictment "for Shooting with intent to kill without wounding"</p>
<p>At the request of Mr Jenkins and quite a number of citizens of this county I am induced to write to you and request an interposition of Executive clemency. Mr Jenkins is a good citizen a quit peaceable man and one that is generaly esteemed. The facts are these "Mr Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Jenkins was going home from Greenville (in company with a Mr M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cubbin who has since moved to Wisconsin)<pb/>
<lb/>as they passed Mr Sweeny's McCubin spoke to Henry Jenkins and Tom Jenkins did not which seemed to offend Henry. When Henry made an exceedingly vulgar and offensive remark to Tom which aroused the anger of Tom when there was a good deal of crimenation and recrimenation. Tom got down off of his horse and told Henry that he was willing to fight him in any manner at the same exhibiting his pistol but not in a shooting atitude. After Henry had declined fighting in any mode Tom turned his back to Henry and was in the act of geting on his horse with the rein of his bridle in his hand and his foot in the stirup when Henry gathered up a plank about 6 feet long and 4 inches wide and about an inch in thickness and struck him two blows over the head the second one felling him to the ground Tom immediately arose and fired at Henry two<pb/>
<lb/>shots as he ran -- Henry being about 30 feet from him at the first fire This is the substance if not the entire facts as detailed by the commonwealths witnesses Henry Jenkins and B Sweeny -- It is propper to state that the two had been unfriendly for some time prior to this meeting The testimony in another trial showed that the blow from the plank fractured Toms skull and that he was confined some three weeks from the wounds That there was a wrong in both parties I do not deny but it seemed hard to fine Tom heavily and let the other who was certainly the most to blame go free -- Both parties were tried for a breach of the peace and Henry was fined $25 and Four ten before a Justice of the Peace -- If from the facts as detailed you think that it is a propper character of case for the exercise of the clemency of the Gov it would confer a favor on Mr Jenkins and meet with ^allmost^ universal approbation. I should have stated that Judge Joseph Ricketts and myself were of counsel for Jenkins and that Henry Jenkins had employed counsell to assist in the prosecution</p>
<p>yours Respectfully
<lb/>M D Hay<pb/></p>
<p>Thos. E. Bramlette
<lb/>Govenor of Kentucky
<lb/>Frankfort. Ky</p>
<p><figure type="postmark"><listPlace><place><placeName>GREENVILLE KY.
<lb/><date when="1865-05-19">MAY 19</date></placeName></place></listPlace></figure></p>
<p>Muhlenburg C C
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Thos. Jenkins
<lb/>ans<hi rend="sup">d</hi></p>
<p>Refused
<lb/>Ans<hi rend="sup">d</hi>,</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
