<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2662"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas H. Hanks to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7299</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-284 to BR16-285</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lawrenceburg, Anderson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-11-13">13 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Lawrenceburg Ky <date when="1865-11-13">Nov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 13<hi rend="sup">t</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E. Bramlette
<lb/>Frankfort Ky
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>You will please pardon me for troubling you at this time and in my own behalf, and certainly would not, but from the fact that I feel your Executive ^clemency^ will be properly exercised by granting my humble petition which is based upon the following facts.: In the months of <date when="1864-10">Octo</date> or <date when="1864-11">Nov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> 1864</date> W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Simmons who was in the Jail of Mercer County <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>on the charge of having stolen a small amount of bacon and myself and Daniel Hackley Executed a bail bond before the judge of the aforesaid County in the sum of $800<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> for his appearance in the Mercer Circuit Court -- at the next term of the Court after the bond was Executed the Grand Jury failed to indict and after said Simmons had served out the time for which he enlisted or rather at the close of the war he was mustered out of the<pb/>
<lb/>Service &amp; returned home, and is now in the custody of the ^custody^ and in fact ^in jail^ awaiting his trial, he having been indicted at the second term after he went into the Union army ^<hi rend="str">and while</hi>^ The Commonwealth has by her attorney caused a Summons to issue, on the ^bond^ requiring me &amp; my co Security to show cause why Judgment shall not be rendered vs Hackley &amp; myself for the $800=</p>
<p>I most respectfully ask your Excellency to give us relief in the premises, believing it is a clear case, for your clemency</p>
<p>The man was indicted while in the Army, and the bail bond forfeited before he got home, and soon as he was mustedred out of the service he was lodged in the jail of Mercer County &amp; is still in Jail; He is a very poor man and within the reach of the law and no indictment having been found at the first term <hi rend="str">and</hi> it does look unreasonable<pb/>
<lb/>that his securities should have the bond to pay</p>
<p>The facts as herein stated are true &amp; I am willing to make affidavit to them</p>
<p>The Mercer Circuit Court begins on next Monday So that we would be happy to receive our immediate remission because we are unable to see that there is the sleightest cause of justice for us to be pursued on the bond</p>
<p>With the highest regard
<lb/>I am yours respectfully
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> H. Hanks</p>
<p>Thos H Hanks states that the Statements above are true as he very believes</p>
<p>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H, Hanks</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H Hanks <date when="1865-11-13">Nov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date></p>
<p>C. H <unclear/> C, A, C, C
<lb/><stamp type="revenue"/><stamp/></p>
<p><hi rend="str">Whereas</hi>As the man for whom Hanks and <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>Hackley became sureties was in the army when the forfeiture occurred -- &amp; as he is now in the custody of the law, I trust that the Governor, will remit the forfeiture<pb/>
<lb/>of the bond, &amp; that the remission include both M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Hanks &amp; M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Hackley -- </p>
<p>The next Court at Mercer meets on the <date when="1865-11-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov/65</date> -- </p>
<p><hi rend="underline">John M Harlan</hi></p>
<p>Mercer Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H Hanks &amp; Dennis Hackley
<lb/>$800,
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-11-14">14 Nov /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
