<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2089"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">David W. Lafollette et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6726</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-292 to BR14-293</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Floyd County, Indiana</placeName>
    <date when="1865-07-22">22 July 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E. Bramlette
<lb/>Gov. of Kentucky.</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of the State of Indianna would respectfully state that we have known William Ramsey, Jr from his child <hi rend="str">child</hi> hood up to the time he became implicated with one Josiah Eaton in the charge of ho^r^se-stealing. His farther, W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Ramsey, Sr. we have long known as a most highly respected, honest, upright, exemplary Christian gentleman and he has raised a large family bearing the same general character. This boy, a youth of 16 or 17 years old at the time, we believe, from all we can learn of the facts, was seduced into trading in horses which Eaton stole in Kentucky, brought over here, -- at the first enterance of the Union Army into Kentucky -- and represented to the boy that he had captured them. We have great sympathy for the boy as well as the grief-stri^c^ken father, the boy volunteered, as we learn, in the Union Army, a short time after he was bailed by his father, and has served 3 or 4 years therein.</p>
<p>In consideration of the premises, we pray most earnestly that your Ecxcellency will pardon <hi rend="str">him</hi> the boy, and remit the amount of the bail-bond against his father.</p>
<p>David W. Lafollette,
<lb/>W. F. L. Morgan City Att
<lb/>R. Robertson x Trustee</p>
<p>x I am acquainted with the Father but not with the Son.<pb/></p>
<p>I am acquainted with both Father &amp; Son Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. Sackett A. F. C.</p>
<p>Acquainted with both father son. ^Josiah Given^ Recorder Floyd Co. Ind.</p>
<p>Acquainted with the Father only R M. Meir, Clerk of City of New Albany</p>
<p>Acquainted both with Father &amp; Son P -- McKeply Treasurer Floyd Co</p>
<p>I was well acquainted with the boy' Father in the Mexican War, W. L. Sanderson Mayor City of New Albany</p>
<p>I am well acquainted with both Father &amp; Son
<lb/>Steward Sandford
<lb/>Sheriff. F. C.
<lb/>W T Kendall
<lb/>Deputy marshal</p>
<p>State of Indiana
<lb/>Floyd County, Sct;</p>
<p>I W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H July clerk of the Floyd Circuit Court Certify that I am acquainted with the persons professing to have signed the above that I believe all the Signatures hereto are genuine, and furthermore that I am acquainted with both<pb/>
<lb/>Father and Son, and can fully endorse all contained in the body of the foregoing</p>
<p>Witness my hand and Official Seal <date when="1865-07-22">July 22<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W. W. July </hi>Clrk
<lb/><stamp/><note place="stamp"><unclear/></note><pb/></p>
<p>Wm Ramsey Sr
<lb/>To Gov } Petition of Judge Lafollett &amp; others</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
