<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1245"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John B. Wilgus and Isaac N. Sheppard to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10713</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-106 to MG21-107</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>The Governor of Kentucky,</p>
<p>Your Petitioners John B Wilgus &amp; Isaac N Sheppard state that Judgment was obtained against them at the last <date when="1861-02">Febuary</date> Term of the Circuit Court for Fayette as Surities for Davis Sheppard's appearances on Several indictments for Misdemeanors for Running disorderly house &amp;c in Lexington. Sheppard having failed to appear Judgment was rendered as above stated, was replevied &amp; is now about to be enforced against them Your petitioner John B Wilgus further states that he is Surety on a <unclear/> <unclear/> bond for Said Sheppard in a case for ^a similar^ Misdemeaner which he carried to the Court of appeals for $250 the case being there affirmed This $250 he will be compelled to pay. The original Judgment thereon was rendered at the <date when="1859-02">Febuary Term 1859</date> of the Fayette Circuit Court.</p>
<p>Your Petitioners State that Davis Sheppard has left the State of Kentucky and is now living in Paris Ill. that he is a poor man with five children and wholly unable to pay it without injuring his family: That he has made the state of Illinois his home; is living on a farm and behaving himself as a good citizen They believe that the prosecutions got up against him here were got up maliciously and he left the State of Ky because he believe he could not get a fair trial</p>
<p>Your Petitioner as his sureties pray ^that he &amp; they^ <hi rend="str">to</hi> be released from the payment of the above Sums as they believe it is a proper case for the interferences of the Executive</p>
<p>J B Wilgus
<lb/>I. N. Sheppards<pb/></p>
<p>We recommend the remission of the above fines, &amp; bonds.</p>
<p>L. P. Young
<lb/>B F Graves
<lb/>E. D. Burke
<lb/>John B Payne Jr
<lb/>G C Graves
<lb/>W. W. Graves
<lb/>Thos <unclear>Ghomat</unclear>
<lb/>F H Shaurer
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> L Lyons
<lb/>W O Root
<lb/>Z Sanckart
<lb/>W. Mentelle
<lb/>H. B. Searcy
<lb/>H D Hulett
<lb/>C Tuttles
<lb/>G. W. Fothergill
<lb/>Michael Hogarty
<lb/>Jas. W. White
<lb/>James M Graves
<lb/>Geo A. Shely
<lb/>P. C. Hartnett
<lb/>P. R. Ramsey
<lb/>W. H. Marriott
<lb/>H. Lancaster<pb/></p>
<p>Respite 12 Mo<hi rend="sup">s</hi>
<lb/>B. M.<pb/></p>
<p>Fayette Cir. Ct
<lb/>$250 } Forfeited Recognizance</p>
<p>J. B. Wilgus &amp; Isaac N Shepherd
<lb/>Resp<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 12 Mos.</p>
<p><hi rend="str">Iss</hi><hi rend="str"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi><hi rend="str"> July 10 1861</hi>
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/>B. M.</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-07-11">July 11. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
