<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2592"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William B. James to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7229</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-143</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Munfordville, Hart County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-21">21 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Munfordville Ky <date when="1865-10-21">21 Octr 1865</date></p>
<p>An Indictment is pending against Robert L Douthat, and Angeline Finn in the Simpson Circuit Court charging, Said Angeline with the crime of Polygamy and the Said Douthat with being accessary to the Crime</p>
<p>A Petition will shortly be presented to the Governor by them asking a pardon, The prosecution has not yet been tried,</p>
<p>Mrs Finn and Said Douthat married each other, The lady at the time being the wife a Mr Finn from whom She had Separated. Douthat was a widower. Both the parties are ignorant as to legal matters, and Since the illegal marriage, the lady has obtained a divorce, and they have remarried, and are living together reputably as husband and wife, I recommend a pardon at once If they are tried they will be convicted, and would then apply for pardon, and I am fully Satisfied the Governor would have no hesitancy in granting it, The trial would create an exposure that the parties would regret, and that the Community would prefer if possible Should be awarded, No person deserves Conviction,</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> B James atty for the Comth,
<lb/>approved Asher W Graham
<lb/>Judge of Circuit Court</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
