<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2231"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Willis G. Hughes et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9307</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-366 to MG24-367</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To the Govenor of Ky</p>
<p>The undersigned Citizens of Union County respectfully Petition your Excellency to pardon Ro P Warring who stands charged by Indictment in the Union Equity &amp; Criminal Court with the Murder of <hi rend="str">Ro</hi> W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Buckman -- </p>
<p>The facts are about these, Buckman had been living with Peter Abell who married a sister of Ro P Warring, &amp; had made an attempt ^by force^ to accomplish an illicit intercourse with Mrs Abell, on their way home from a neighbours while She was under his care &amp; protection, and was <hi rend="str">at</hi> only prevented from it, by <hi rend="str">the</hi> her screams <hi rend="str">of,</hi> this was Communicated by her to her husband &amp; Brother and in a short time thereafter Buckman was found killed on the road near where she had told her husband &amp; Brother<pb/>
<lb/>the forcible attempt had been made most of us even on the ground immediately after the occurance of the deed or heard the testimony of the witnesses who were there, And no sign of Warring having been on the ground was to be found, And the only evidence agt Warring was some threats made about the time his sister told him of the insult &amp; attempt at force on her by Buckman.</p>
<p>Abell &amp; Warring were Indicted Abel has been acquitted &amp; Warring <hi rend="str">state</hi> is charged <hi rend="str">with</hi> &amp; <unclear/> -- </p>
<p>We ask you to pardon him, and refrain from any <unclear/> of opinion about others Convicted with the affair</p>
<p>Warring is poor &amp; unable to meet the expences of such a trial, and is in fast failing health &amp; as we learn cannot live long -- We join with her Mother in asking you to pardon him, while living, and hope<pb/>
<lb/>you will do so</p>
<p>Respy
<lb/>Willis G Hughes
<lb/>H B Eaty
<lb/>George payne
<lb/>J B payne
<lb/>Jno T. Borne
<lb/>W. H. Wheeler
<lb/>James Threlkeld
<lb/>Wm W Threlkeld
<lb/>N W Waggener
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Ben. D. Cissell</hi>
<lb/>J. H. Grifin
<lb/>J S Giger M. U. C. C
<lb/>D. H. Hughes<pb/></p>
<p>Warrings case -- Union
<lb/>Rejected -- 
<lb/>B. Magoffin</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
