<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-007-0083"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James D. Shreve, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1748</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Appointments by the Governor, Civil Appointments, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR1-476 to BR1-477</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Burlington County, New Jersey</placeName>
    <date when="1863-12-31">31 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of New Jersey
<lb/>Burlington County</p>
<p>Personally appeared before me James D Shreve Justice of the Peace in and for the County of Burlington, Joseph C. Clark who having been appointed by the Governor of Kentucky a Commissioner to take the ackowledgement &amp; proofs of Deeds and other instruments of writing &amp;c &amp;c &amp;c in the State of Kentucky; resident in New Jersey, doth hereby solemnly swear that he will to the best of his knowledge and ability perform the duties of the said office</p>
<p>Joseph C. Clark</p>
<p>Sworn &amp; Subscribed before me in Mount Holly this <date when="1863-12-31">31 Day of December 1863</date></p>
<p>James D. Shreve
<lb/>Justice of the Peace<pb/>
<lb/>State of New Jersey
<lb/>Burlington County } ss</p>
<p>J. Ames Gibbs Clerk of the County Court in and for the county and state above named do hereby certify that James D. Shreve before whom the within affidavit was made, and who has thereunto signed his name was at the time of so doing a Justice of the Peace in and for the County and State above named duly commissioned and sworn, that all his official acts as such are entitled to full faith and credit, and that his signature thereunto is <unclear/></p>
<p>In testimony whereof I have hereunto signed my name and affixed by official seal <date when="1864-01-01">this first day of January eighteen hundred &amp; sixty four</date></p>
<p>Amos Gibbs clk
<lb/><figure type="seal"/>
<lb/><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">A G 
<lb/><date when="1864-01-01">Jan 1
<lb/>1864</date></note><pb/></p>
<p>Mt. Holly <date when="1864-01-01">Jany 1. 1864</date>
<lb/>E S Vanwickle Esq
<lb/>D Sir</p>
<p>I beg leave to send you my affidavit as taken before James D. Shreve a Justice of the Peace for our County, also a certificate of the County Clerk -- </p>
<p>Please notify me of the receipt and State if the papers are satisfactory</p>
<p>I remain very respectfully
<lb/>Your <unclear/>
<lb/>Joseph C. Clark<pb/></p>
<p>Com<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Deeds
<lb/>New Jersey
<lb/>J.C. Clark</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
