<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0656"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. F. Jones et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4775</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-8 to BR10-9</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. E. Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioners J. F Jones, L. W. Kincheloe, H. D. Rothbrock, John Clark, and John R Nichols respectfully shewith, that a man by the name of Milton Purdy was arrested in this (Muhlenburg) County on a charge of shooting a man by the name of D. W. Stewart with intent to kill, and was brought before the Judge of the Muhlenburg County Court for examination. Said Court after hearing the Evidence, bound him over for his appearance at the next term of the Circuit Court in the sum of $400<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> who gave bond with your petitioners ^and others^ as his securities A short time after the execution of said bond the said Purdy being in Hopkins or Christians Counties was arrested by Military Authority and taken off and where he is they do not know. His arrest took place before the Term of the Muhlenburg Circuit Court next succeeding the execution of said bond without their knowledge. He was not in Court when the case was called<pb/>
<lb/>and said bond was forfeited process issued on said bond and was executed only ^on^ your petitioners. At the <date when="1863-11">November term 1863</date> of the said Court a Judgment was rendered against them for said $400<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> and an execution for said <hi rend="str">same</hi> sum is now in the hand of the sheriff of This county for collection, and they will be compelled to pay the same unless your Excellency will interpose in their behalf. They paid the Commonwealths Attorney $120.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> the amount allowed him on such Judgments. They state they knew said Purdy well and beleived him to be a gentleman, and he haveing a <hi rend="str">large</hi> family they went his bail to keep him out of Jail. They beleive and state as true if he had not been taken by the military he would have been at said court and stood his trial They state that if they knew where he was, which they do not, they could not take him from Military authority and deliver him to court. As this is a hard case on them, they being poor, under the circumstances they pray the clemency of your Excellency<pb/>
<lb/>in releiving them from said Judgment and Execution, and by thus interposeing in their behalf you will lay them under lasting obligations.</p>
<p>We are Respectfully
<lb/>Your Obedient Servents</p>
<p>J F Jones
<lb/>H. D. Roshrock
<lb/>John Clark
<lb/>J. R. Nyeholls
<lb/>L W Kincheloe</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Muhlenburg and Ohio Counties being well acquainted with the parties and facts in this petition ask the interposition of the Governor in their behalf.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>B. C. Bennett
<lb/>J F Davis
<lb/>Daley Durham
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Bruce
<lb/>S H Curd
<lb/>T. A. Pittman
<lb/>W. H. H. Faris.
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> B. Wickliffe
<lb/>E M Blackfoot
<lb/>Jas.. F.. Morehead
<lb/>Presley Morehead
<lb/><cb n="2"/>B. E. Pittman cty Atto
<lb/>J. W. Hollowell
<lb/>John B Hughes
<lb/>A G Ferguson
<lb/>A M Jackson
<lb/>W G Martin
<lb/>S M Kennedy
<lb/>W. H. Walker
<lb/>James C. Moorman
<lb/>C. F. Robertson
<lb/>Aaron Wickliffe
<lb/>John Kittinger
<lb/>Joe Rutherford<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>Jesse N Reno
<lb/>T. J. Jones
<lb/>Joseph Ricketts
<lb/>Charles Eaves
<lb/>B J Shaver
<lb/>P. Priscoe
<lb/>Jo. Jones
<lb/>P. H. Baker
<lb/>Enos Hunt
<lb/>J Wood
<lb/>J. R. Strange</p>
<p>Please address to "John Clark &amp; others"
<lb/>South Carrolton
<lb/>Ky."</p>
<p>P. S. Please find communication from M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. E. R. Weir, and bail bond &amp;c enclosed</p>
<p>Muhlenburg Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Remit except fees &amp; Costs
<lb/>Richard T Jacob</p>
<p>Lt &amp; Act Gov
<lb/>John Clark &amp; others
<lb/>sureties of
<lb/><date when="1864-04-16">16<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Apl/ 64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
