<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0717"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Green Circuit Court, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10185</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-117 to MG19-119</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Green County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1858-11-09">9 November 1858</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Green County Ky. Sct.</p>
<p>Thomas Kersey being in Custody charged with the offense of stealing a bay mare the property of Shelton Headgen, and being admitted to bail in the sum of Five Hundred Dollars, Now we James M. Anderson of the County of Barren &amp; William Thompson &amp; Elizabeth Kersey of the County fo Green (Securities) hereby undertake that the above named Thomas Kersey shall appear in the Green Circuit Court in the first day of its next <date when="--02">February term</date> to answer said charge, and shall at all times render himself amenable to the orderes &amp; process of said Court in the prosecuting of said charge &amp; if convicted shall render himself in execution thereof; or if he fail to perform either of these Conditions that he will pay to the Commonwealth of Kentucky the Sum of five Hundred Dollars-</p>
<p>Witness our hands this <date when="1858-11-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of November 1858</date>.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Taken and subscribed
<lb/><cb n="2"/>James M. Anderson
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Thompson by<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>before me as presiding Judge of the Green County Court, this <date when="1858-11-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of November 1858</date></p>
<p>Thomas R. Barnett
<lb/>J. P. G. C. C.
<lb/><cb n="2"/>James M. Anderson his attorney in fact.
<lb/>Elizabeth Kersey by W. T. Ward her attorney in fact.<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>And afterwards at a court held for the Green Circuit on the <date when="1859-03-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of March 1859</date>, the foregoing bond was forfeited &amp; summons ordered to issue-</p>
<p>And afterwards again at a Court held for the Circuit aforesaid on the <date when="1859-06-14">14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of June 1859</date>-</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Judgement agst. Thompson</note></p>
<p>On motion of the attorney for the Comth. an alias summons is ordered to issue against the defendant Elizabeth Kersey &amp; the case is continued as to her.</p>
<p>And the defendant William Thompson having been duly summoned &amp; failing to answer, it is adjudged by the court that the Commonwealth of Kentucky recover<pb/>
<lb/>of the said Deft. Thompson Five Hundred Dollars the amount of said forfeiture &amp; the costs herein expanded.</p>
<p>And again at said court on the <date when="1859-09-07">7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of September 1859</date></p>
<p><note place="left margin">Judgement agst. E. Kersey</note></p>
<p>The defendant Elizabeth Kersey having been duly summoned and failing to answer. It is adjudged by the Court that the Commonwealth recover of the Said Deft. Elizabeth Kersey Five Hundred Dollars the amount of said Forfeiture &amp; the costs herein expanded-</p>
<p>The Replevin bond executed by W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Thompson reads as follows.</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Replevin Bond.</note></p>
<p>We William Thompson principal <gap/> Security, bind our selves three months after date to pay the Commonwelath of Ky. on forfeited bail bond (the plff. in Execution) the sum of $517.51 cents, with interest thereon from this date, being the amount of principal interest &amp; cost of an Execution No. 1236, which issued from the clerk's office of the Green<pb/>
<lb/>Circuit Court, on the <date when="1859-06-28">28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of June 1859</date>, in favor of the Comth. for the sum of,</p>
<p><table rend="rules">
<row>
	<cell>Principal</cell>
	<cell>$500.00</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Interest</cell>
	<cell><hi rend="str">9.50</hi></cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Costs</cell>
	<cell>4.50</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Shffs. half bond.</cell>
	<cell>12.61</cell>
</row>
<row>
	<cell>Writing bond</cell>
	<cell>.40</cell>
</row>
</table></p>
<p>And we the said principal and <gap/> security have replevied the same-</p>
<p>Witness our hands and Seals, this <date when="1859-08-15">15<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of August 1859</date>-</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Attest W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Bale
<lb/><cb n="2"/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Thompson<figure type="seal"/>
<lb/>Elizabeth ^her X mark^ Kersey <figure type="seal"/></p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Green Circuit Court</p>
<p>I Sam<hi rend="sup">l</hi> T. Wilson clerk of said Court, Certify that the foregoing three pages &amp; part of this page, Contains a true Copy of the Bail bond, Judgments &amp; Replevin bond, in the Case of the Commonwealth agst W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Thompson &amp; Elizabeth Kersey</p>
<p>Witness Sam<hi rend="sup">l</hi> T. Wilson clerk<pb/>
<lb/>of said Court the <date when="1859-11-03">3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> day of Novr. 1859</date>.</p>
<p>S. T. Wilson clk<pb/></p>
<p>Green Cir. Court
<lb/>$500 } Forfeited Recognizance
<lb/>Eliz. Kelsey
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Thompson
<lb/>Resp<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 12 mos
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1859-11-05">Nov. 5, 1859</date>
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-02-07">Feby 7, 1861</date></p>
<p>Respite 12 mo<hi rend="sup">s</hi>
<lb/>B. M.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
