<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0951"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Liberty Langford to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5070</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-464 to BR10-465</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-06-23">23 June 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excelency Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Bramlette</p>
<p>Your undersigned petitioner states that he was fined at the <date when="--03">February Term</date> of the Rockcastle Circuit Court, one hundred and sixty two dollars for obstructing a county road on his own premises, That said obstruction was made by building a fence about twenty yards long in the road He states that this obstruction was done after he had made a better piece of road running side by side with the fenced up piece the fence ring just in the old road, The change made commenced when the fence commenced in the road and intersected just beyond when the fence stoped in said road, and that before he made said obstriction he showed the changed piece of road to the overseer of said county road, and he accepted the change piece and said he was glad of it for he would have had to of made said change himself, He states that the changed piece of road is much better than the piece obstructed that said obstructed piece <hi rend="str">is</hi> was a very bad piece of road He says &amp; insists that the said change was a benefit to the general public, and that since he was fined as afsd said changed piece of road has been examinined by county court commissions and they reported it a better way than the old road fenced and the county court has received said changed piece and it is now the actual county road That said changed piece was just in the same fix at the time the county court received it as when the afsd fine was assessed. He states that it is very hard on him to pay so much for doing no harm but for doing good to the general public. He says he has sent<pb/>
<lb/>to your Exelency a former petitioner asking a remitance of said fine signed by signed by various persons He says that when said petition was drawn up the county court had not accepted said change and that the other facts may have not been properly presented</p>
<p>He says this petition presents a true history of the case He calls the attention of the Governor to said facts and humbly begs a Remitance of his fine</p>
<p>Liberty Langford</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Liberty Langford <date when="1864-06-23">23<hi rend="sup">th</hi> June 1864</date></p>
<p>E T Fish C. R. C. C.</p>
<p>We are acquainted with Liberty Langford and the history of the case he presents in his forgoing petition and believe he has given a true statement and think it Justice &amp; right for his fine to be remitted.</p>
<p>E T. Fish C. R. C. C
<lb/>B K Bethurum Judge of the Rockcastle County Co
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> McClure S R C<pb/></p>
<p>Liberty Langford
<lb/>Rockcastle
<lb/>Pet for Remission for obstructing road
<lb/>$162-
<lb/>Remit
<lb/><date when="1864-07-11">11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> July/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
