<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0543"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">C. Donnelly to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8995</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-363</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-08-01">1 August 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency J F Robinson -- 
<lb/>Governor of the State of Kentucky:</p>
<p>Your Petitioner, Charles Donnelly, respectfully represents that he was tried before the Kenton Circuit Court at Covington at its <date when="1863-06">June Term 1863</date> for a Breach of the Peace and fined $25 and costs. Your Petitioner is a laboring man with a family and a resident of the City of Covington. The proof in the case showed that Petitioner at the time of the offence was a hostler at the Drover's Inn and that the difficulty was not begun by himself and that he took no part in it until his brother was knocked down and lying upon the floor when he attacked the assailant as he believed he ought to do in defence of his brother. The assailant of his brother had first offered to strike Petitioner but had been prevented, and Petitioner had gone to another part of the room and was engaged in settling his accounts with the Landlord of the Hotel when he heard the noise of the assault upon his brother and then rushed forward to protect him. Your Petitioner respectfully represents that so much of the fine as goes to the Commonwealth's Attorney together with the costs<pb/>
<lb/>will be sufficient punishment in any view of his conduct, and he prays a remission of the remainder of the fine, or that the Executive clemency should be extended to him in some form.</p>
<p>C, Donnelly,</p>
<p>Covington Ky <date when="1863-08-01">August 1, 1863</date></p>
<p>We, the undersigned citizens of Covington respectfully join in the prayer of the petitioner,</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W M Kettell
<lb/>Geo. F Cooke
<lb/>Geo James
<lb/>Thad Reed
<lb/>S K Hathaway
<lb/>Capt. Lewis
<lb/>Col. Stricklands
<lb/>Chas Barlow
<lb/>G, F, Cook
<lb/>Michael Roads
<lb/>T. Edsell
<lb/>H Edwards
<lb/>J. Garrison
<lb/>W, J, Donnelly
<lb/>Geo Brown
<lb/>Jas. Sands
<lb/>Dr. E. U. Jonston
<lb/>Capt. Thomas</p>
<p><cb n="2"/>A H Bowen
<lb/>John Herold
<lb/>B. B Weidler
<lb/>J C Bryan
<lb/><unclear/>
<lb/>Geo H. Kole
<lb/>Emanuel Wolf } Jurors</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
