<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0875"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Patrick U. Major to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4994</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-344</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Mr Campbell Dear Sir</p>
<p>In compliance with your request, I will say that the judg't I obtained against you in the Owen Circutt Court in favor of the Comth, was a very hard case on you and I always thought that the fine should be remitted I recollect the facts perfectly and they are about these, there was but one witness to the offense shooting with the intent to kill and wound without wounding, and that was the man who said he was shot at, and his story of the affair was not a very probabal one, there was proof of a previous difficulty. the aggression was then made by the com'ths witness in your case, he was proven to be a large stout quarrelsom and aggressive man, while you were small and delicate <unclear/> feeble, in comparison with him. and peaceable and law abiding as it appeared from the evidence, in view of these facts, and the further fact that you utterly denied even having attacked the witness, and the fact that he admitted feeling bitter and horbile to you and there was no corroborating evidence that you had attacked him, I will cheerfully sign a petition to the gov'r to remit your fine or you may hand to him with your petition this letter</p>
<p>Respectfully your friend
<lb/>P. U. Major
<lb/>guardian com'ths Atty of
<lb/>the 8th dist</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
