<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0515"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John D. Williams to Daniel P. White</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9983</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-301</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Green County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-01-14">14 January 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Green County Kty <date when="1861-01-14">January the, 14<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861</date> -- </p>
<p>Dear Friend you Requested me to Rite to you Respeting my case Now Sir I do think it is a Straing thing to me why M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Towls and M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Spencer has Failed to attend to the mater For me as I had Boath thare Faithfull promis to me that theay ^woud^ attend to it But I Suppose the Reason was That the States attorny Give up his Claim a Gainst me in Riting and assiand his name to it and I have it Now in my in my pocket when he Done that theay Said theay Did not think I Ever woul hear of it a Gain Now Doctor I Dipend on you and my worthy Friend Doctor Wolten to attend to ^the^ Busness For me For I have Nothing to Throw a way For you know that I have a har time to Seport my Family For I am yet a Cripple in my leg yet in a Great Degree and has No help But some Girls For the matter at First was Gotten up threw Spite and Malis and By har swaring as For my keeping a tipling house or Gambling Never at No time my wife is Now Forty years old and Never has seen a gGame of Cards play in her life Nor my Family Now my Friend Dont neglect this matter atoend it as soon as posable and send me a letter to monroe post Office and I want you to well acquaint Mr. Magoffin of my Suitatain I had Confidence in him and Done all I could to help him in his Election and I have yet Confidence in him that he will Give me his aid in this matter your with Respect</p>
<p>John. D. Williams<pb/></p>
<p>To Dr -- 
<lb/>Daniel -- 
<lb/>P. White</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
