<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0981"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Edward Hall, Sr. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10449</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-37 to MG20-38</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi>. of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Edw<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Hall Sr father of Edw<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> S Hall who is a minor, would respectfully represent that his son about Christmas times had a pistol about his person in company with other youths &amp; was presented &amp; fined fifty doll<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. in the city court of Louisville. the father says he replevied the Debt to Keep his son out of the workhouse &amp; which will be due in a few days but that in consequence of the hard times &amp; his business almost entirely stopped (which is a sadler) he is wholly unable to pay having a large family to support the youth has heretofore conducted himself in a orderly &amp; modest manner &amp; will not again I am sure offend ag<hi rend="sup">st</hi>. the law I pray y<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Excellency to remit his fine &amp; I will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p>Respectfully y<hi rend="sup">r</hi> obt Serv<hi rend="sup">t</hi>
<lb/>Edw<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Hall<pb/></p>
<p>We would most respectfully ask y<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Excellency to remit young Halls fine of fifty dolls the costs are penalty enough respectfully y<hi rend="sup">r</hi> ob<hi rend="sup">t</hi> serv<hi rend="sup">t</hi></p>
<p>John Joyes
<lb/>W. G. Reasor
<lb/>O H Strattan Clk C C
<lb/>W R Hydes Marshall C C L
<lb/>T H Crawford Mayor
<lb/>D W Wilson</p>
<p>To His Excellency the Govener of Kentucky</p>
<p>I am well acquainted with M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Hall the father of the boy against whom the fine ^is^ imposed. I know nothing of the particulars: M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Hall is one of our oldest citizens and much esteemed by his old friends. He is somewhat embarassed, with a large family and to pay the fine of his son will be very hard upon him I hope if consistent with Executive clemency it may be remitted -- </p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>E. S. Craig</p>
<p>I prosecuted in the above case but do not now remember the particulars of the case. I heartily concur with M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Craig, as to the good character of the father of young Hall</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>R. J. Elliott.<pb/></p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>Louisville City Ct
<lb/>$50. } Weapons
<lb/>Ed. S. Hall
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi>. <date when="1861-04-09">Apr 9. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
