<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1113"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John McEntire to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10581</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-221 to MG20-222</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Boyd County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-05-11">11 May 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency B Magoffin Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky your petitioner John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Entire states at the last <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> <date when="1860-10">Octo</date> Term of the Boyd circuit court he was indicted by the Grand jury of said county for having sold Liquor to a minor. and at the last <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> <date when="1861-04">April Term (1861)</date> he was absent from the county unavoidably having gone to Texas -- The inditmen<hi rend="str">t</hi>t was taken as true without any defense and fined the sum of $50 -- and he has been fined to Replevy the same with Mordicai Williams security -- He says that he could have clearly proven that he did not sell the Liquor that he had none himself that he hapened to be in the Bar Room of Scott Gilkey at whose House he was boarding in the Town of Catlettsburg and a neighbour boy came in who he was well acquainted with and stated his mother had sent him for some Liquor that she was sick your petitioner knew the condition of the woman and satisfied it was right for her to have it without waiting for Mr Gilkey to come in waited upon the Boy. The Liquor was for M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> Frasheur who was sick if any money was paid he is not certain he may have paid ten sents for the little Whiskey that was put in the bottle brought by the Boy and he satisfied the same was not used by the Boy but taken by him to his mother -- In consideration of the facts and circumstances he prays your excellency to remit the fine he believed at the time he done the act he was doing the suffering an act of kindness -- and that had no other motive whatever for the liquor was not his nor was he compensated in any shape
<lb/><date when="1861-05-11">May 11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861 -- </date></p>
<p>John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Entire<pb/></p>
<p>Boyd County sct -- </p>
<p>I C. S. Gelkey, states that he has examined the petition of John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Entire and can say that at the time he was indicted he was boarding at my House (Tavern) also at the time of the alledged sale to a minor and had been for some time -- and further say that he had no interest in the Liquor sold nor was he emplyed by me he is further satisfied that the same was on his part an act of kindess for M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> Frasheur who was sick <hi rend="str">and</hi> her house House was but a few steps <hi rend="str">from</hi> <hi rend="str">off the</hi></p>
<p>C. P. Guilkey</p>
<p>We the undersign citizens of Boyd county acquainted with Doctor John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Entire who resided in this place for some time and was boarder at M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Scott Gilkeys we are satisfied he was in noway engaged in the Liquor trade we heartly unite in the prayer of the petitioner for the remission of his fine</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>L. J. Hampton J. P. B. C
<lb/>Q M Riely
<lb/>D. H. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Ghee
<lb/>M L Baner
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> J Ewing
<lb/>S S M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Crayer
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> H. Johnner
<lb/>John Fauleones
<lb/>John Meck
<lb/>James C Ely
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Runyon
<lb/>Robt Cristy
<lb/><cb n="2"/>George N Brown
<lb/>R Grinstead
<lb/>W. H. H. Eba
<lb/>R B M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Call
<lb/>C. L. Guilkey
<lb/>Henry Barton
<lb/>K, N, Harris
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Pugh M<hi rend="underline"> D</hi>
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. J. Layns
<lb/>W. O. Hampton
<lb/>H Widrow
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Runstman
<lb/>T. E. Henderson<pb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>
<lb/>Jeremiah Burns
<lb/>W S Clark
<lb/>O. W. Martin
<lb/>L Stephenson</p>
<p>Catlettsburg <date when="1861-05-13">May 13<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861.</date>
<lb/>Messrs. L. Roberts, and John M. Rice,</p>
<p>You will please, present the petition, to the, Governor, get the remission for, Mcgntire, as I do believe, he should have it; we are all well; -- tell, Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> J. Fraseir, to send me a stand of Arms; consisting of Sharps Rifle a good pair of sharps pistols and I will use them prudent by driving and keeping, off the <hi rend="underline">Dark</hi> <hi rend="underline">republicans</hi>; <hi rend="underline"><unclear/></hi> has no use for the arms; and I have, Sinclair you bring them home to Me.</p>
<p>my Respects to friends. I am &amp;c.
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> M. Rice</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Remitted
<lb/>B M</note><pb/></p>
<p>Boyd Cir Ct
<lb/>$50. } Selling Liquor to a minor
<lb/>John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Entire
<lb/>Remission Issd
<lb/><date when="1861-05-16">May 16 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
