<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2372"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">P. M. Hale to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7009</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-288 to BR15-289</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mercer County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-30">30 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency, Thomas E. Bramlette, Governor of Kentucky;</p>
<p>Your petitioner, P. M. Hale, States that on the <date when="1864-03-30">30<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of March 1864</date>, he, in conjunction with Jas_ P_ Hale became the Surety ^in the bail bond^ of one Miner Morgan, a free boy of Color, in the Sum of one hundred dollars, for the appearance of the Said Miner Morgan in the Mercer Circuit Court on the first day of the <date when="1864-07">July term, 186<hi rend="str">5</hi>4</date> to answer a charge of petit larceny, in which Said bail bond Your petition obligated himself as principal. Petitioner states that at the <date when="1864-11">November term, 1864</date>, of Said Court the said bail bond was forfeited and Summons issued on Same to show cause &amp;c; And he further States that at the <date when="1865-05">May term, 1865</date>, of Said Court Judgment was rendered in the forfeited bail bond against petitioner -- </p>
<p>Your petition states that before the said <date when="1864-07">July term, 1864</date> of the Mercer Circuit Court the said Miner Morgan joined the Federal Army and became a Soldier in the United States Service and for this reason the Said Miner Morgan ^being absent in Said Service^ did not appear in the Court in accordance with the bond of petitioner, who could not for the Same reason have the said Miner in Court or coerce his appearance by arresting him or otherwise, he having left and joined the army as stated, and petitioner<pb/>
<lb/>knew nothing of his whereabouts -- He states that the Said Miner Morgan is Still a Soldier in the U. S. Service and has been ever since he so joined as Stated, heretofor -- but of his locality or whereabouts petitioner knows nothing; that had it been possible to have the said Miner in Court in accordance with Said bond he would have done so, but for the reason stated petitioner could not -- </p>
<p>Petitioner States he is poor and dependent on his labor for a support and does not feel able to pay said judgment, in justice to himself and dependents, if it can be honorably avoided; that it will be coerced out of him Shortly unless Your Excellency grants him relief -- He says the foregoing Statements are true, and for these reasons petitions Your Excellency to remit Said Jugdment to the extent that lies in your power -- </p>
<p>P. M. Hale</p>
<p>Subscribed and Sworn to before me by P. M. Hale this <date when="1865-09-30">30 day of September 1865</date></p>
<p>Richard Board C, M, C, C
<lb/><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp"><unclear/>
<lb/><unclear/>
<lb/>1865</note><pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned Citizens of Mercer County would respectfully State to Your Excellency that we know well P. M. Hale, and that he is a worthy and reliable man -- We would be gratified to see your Excellency Grant his prayer -- </p>
<p>Ben. C. Trapnall
<lb/>John C. Kyle
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J, W, Cardwell</hi>
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s </hi>Edwards P J M C C
<lb/>C, P, Abell
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H Hardin P. J. T, H,
<lb/>Richard Board Clerk Mercer Circuit Court
<lb/>Thos J Olmsdall D S S m C<pb/></p>
<p>Mercer Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>P. M Hale
<lb/>$100,
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/>Remitted</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
