<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0155"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James Flanagan to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8607</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-235 to R3-236</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Winchester, Clark County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-01-30">30 January 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Winchester Ky <date when="1863-01-30">Jany 30" 1863</date>
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>Hon Jas F. Robinson Gov of Ky
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>I have seen the petition in circulation on behalf of Fielding M. Bush, recommending him to Executive Clemency, I rarely sign any petition, and when I do it must be under a firm conviction that there are extenuating circumstances surrounding the case &amp; that no outrage to public justice will ensue by the pardon of the Executive being granted</p>
<p>The young man Fielding M Bush, whose case will be presented to you, is the son of Fielding Bush Esq of Clark Co, who is one of our most respected citizens<pb/>
<lb/>and noted for his having always heretofore been one of the conservative land marks of the County I learn that the young man Fielding M. Bush has voluntarily returned from the Southern Army and surrendered himself to the U S Military commandant at Lexington &amp; take the oath of allegiance &amp; given the required bonds and is now at home, with the intention of remaining a peaceable &amp; law abiding person. He is quite a youth, and has been heretofore remarkable for his good behavior &amp; gentlemanly course, His case is one that presents many considerations for clemency, and his friends here believe, that if it is extended to him, that it <pb/>
<lb/>will have a good effect in restoring others to the side of the government, who have been wavering or inclined to be against it.</p>
<p>He is a relative of our worthy Senator Judge Bush, and he will not misrepresent him, when he <hi rend="str">stay</hi>states that he is a young man of fine impulses &amp; manly in his instincts &amp; of integrity of Character</p>
<p>Your ob<hi rend="sup">t</hi> svt
<lb/>Jas Flanagan</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
