<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2585"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">P. D. Yeiser to E. J. Bullock</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7222</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-133 to BR16-134</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Paducah, McCracken County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-26">26 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Paducah Ky <date when="1865-10-26">Octr 26<hi rend="sup">th</hi>/65</date>
<lb/>Col E J Bullock
<lb/>D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Sir</p>
<p>Your favor without date asking a Statement from me in regard to W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Miles came to hand yesterday &amp; I herewith return it with my answer</p>
<p>At the <date when="1863-09">September term of the Ballard circuit Court 1863</date> while I was count atty the grand Jury brought into court three indictments each against Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Hudgins, Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Taylor <gap/> Edwards &amp; W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Miles respectively charging the robbery of M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cutchin, Dalton &amp; Brummell each robbery charged to have been committed the same night -- Taylor &amp; Hudgins were tried on two of the indictments, proven guilty &amp; sentenced to the penitentiary, Taylor met his death on his way to Frankfort &amp; Hudgins is now in the penitentiary -- I prosecuted in these cases &amp; recollect the evidence well, it was strong &amp; conclusive as to Taylor &amp; Hudgins but not so as to Miles &amp; Edwards for the whole evidence came out in the trial -- the main proof as to Miles was his being in company with T &amp; H on the forenoon of the day of the Robbery &amp; with him at Woodville 7 or 8 miles from the Robbery about noon &amp; no proof was adduced to show where Miles &amp; Edwards were all the afternoon until about 8 or 9 oclock at night &amp; about the time of the robbery they came to Golsons &amp; remained all night about 2 1/2 miles from Brummels &amp; that is about the time of night Brummell was robbed &amp; he swore he thought the man who robbed him was Miles but could not be certain, he also as well as other witnesses swore Hudgins &amp; Miles were very much alike in person &amp; Hudgins was well identified as the man robbing Dalton &amp; M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cutchin -- all three of the men robbed lived in the same vicinity &amp; not far apart -- I thought at<pb/>
<lb/>the trial the proof was pretty strong to implicate Miles yet felt some doubt might exist even on the proof as to him -- but about the time the trials of T &amp; H closed &amp; when there was no hope for them I conversed freely with each prisoner separately and both solemnly assured me that they alone comitted the robbery &amp; that Miles &amp; Edwards were not present=Hudgins said he &amp; Taylor suggested it to Miles in the morning &amp; he appeared to agree to it but when they parted at Woodville Miles failed to meet him &amp; Taylor as agreed &amp; never did meet them and they did not see him any more until the next day -- Hudgins said more that he had some misgivings as to Miles any how &amp; did not believe he intended to take part in it although he had promised Taylor told substantially the same as Hudgins but was disposed to curse Miles for cowardly backing out after agreeing at or near Woodville to go with them -- from Taylor &amp; Hudgins manner of detailing to me alth<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi> they were felons I am inclined to believe they told the truth</p>
<p>I understand Miles has been for a long time in the Federal army &amp; now wishes to return home &amp; help his old father make up the money he has paid for him &amp; while I am sure has sorely oppressed the old man who is a verry worthy &amp; christian man -- From what I can hear of Bill Miles former life, I think if pardoned he wont make a good citizen -- his father tells me he would come home and stand his trial but has no one to go his bail or money to pay expenses of a trial &amp; he is unwilling to lie in jail<pb/></p>
<p>As you well remark this war has caused much domestic misery &amp; there being a general feeling now with every one to be friends rub out and begin fresh. I heartily endorse it, yet would not feel willing to carry that spirit to the extent of freeing bad men. I however am led to the conclusion that Bill Miles is not a vicious man &amp; I always feel its better to reform than punish especially when the punishment already inflicted works the reformation -- I believe I have answered your letter as fully as I well can</p>
<p>Yours truly
<lb/>P D Yeiser</p>
<p>P. S. Taylor &amp; Hudgins was sharp, Keen &amp; calculating so far as I can learn not so with Miles -- My opinion is Miles at most was the victim of sharpers, but yet did not take any hand in the robbery, that he at first on their importunities agreed to do so but before it was done <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> he abandoned the enterprize either from fear or from the honsety that was in him</p>
<p>Yeiser</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
