<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1479"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. W. Miller, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6116</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-295</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-01-21">21 January 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>R W Miller on oath states that a little over five years since he was going on a steam boat from Cincinnati to Louisville and got into a game of cards and lost all his money -- He had Known Geo Woodruff in New York where both had lived and discovered him with his wife in the same steamboat He applied to said Woodruff for money stealing he could &amp; would refuse it as soon as they got to Louisville, Woodruff loaned him $55 and this he lost at cards -- At Louisville they put up at the Louisville Hotel and there Woodruffs wife was taken sick the money he had loaned affiant was pretty near all that he had He seemed much disposed when affiant told him he could not find his friend to get the money In this state of case affiant and said Woodruff were walking together on the street when they met a man affiant had made the acquaintance of on the Steam boat comeing from Cinc<hi rend="sup">i</hi> -- Affiant had told that man that he affiant was a merchant going to Louisville to buy goods and represented himself to be a successful merchant when he &amp; Woodruff met this man this affiant conceived the plan to obtain money from him -- He had learned from the men he was going off on a boat up the river and affiant pretended he was going on the same boat and when they met on the street affiant suddenly thought of a bill of $100 worth of goods he had to pay for and he stated the circumstance to the man and asked him to let him have the money &amp; he would repay it as soon as<pb/>
<lb/>as he got to the boat.</p>
<p>The man let him have the money, with it he paid Woodruff $55 the amt he had borrowed of him -- They were shortly afterwards arrested <hi rend="str">&amp; the money found on them</hi></p>
<p>This affiant states most solemnly that Woodruff had nothing to do with the trick other than to be the passive companion of the affiant</p>
<p>He states further that he has served out the five years in the penitentiary inflicted on him as the punishment that Woodruff who was sent for the same time made his escape from a guard when out of the prison and was gone for some two months or a little more -- that he was recaptured &amp; tried for the escape but acquitted -- that the keeper is holding him to make up the time he was absent -- this affiant has no other means of maknig Woodruff any reparation for the wrong done him than to make this affidavit &amp; ask the Governor to discharge him by pardon</p>
<p>R W Miller</p>
<p>Test Th N Lindsey</p>
<p>Sworn to by R W Miller before the undersigned at Frankfort Ky <date when="1865-01-21">Jan 21 1865</date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Geo W Gwin</hi> J. P.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
