<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-001-0005"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas E. Bramlette, Proclamation</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG0855</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Joshua D Farrington</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Proclamations, 1863-1865</collection>
      <idno>BR1-364</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-04-17">17 April 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Proclamation/Legislation</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>STATE OF KENTUCKY,
<lb/>EXECUTIVE DEPARTMENT,
<lb/>Frankfort, <date when="1865-04-17">April 17, 1865.</date></p>
<p>By the hand of an assassin a great grief has been brought upon our country. The Chief Magistrate of the Nation, the President of the United States, ABRAHAM LINCOLN, has fallen a victim to rebellious hate under the vengeful blow of an assassin. He has fallen at a time when his great qualities of humanity were so hopefully invoked for the healing of our National woes! With no stain of vindictive nature upon his soul -- with a great heart of generous sympathies and broad humanities -- his untimely fall has bowed a Nation's head in mourning.</p>
<p>On WEDNESDAY, the <date when="1865-04-19">19th inst.,</date> at the hour of 12 o'clock, A.M. (the hour of his funeral), let every church bell be tolled throughout the Commonwealth; and on that day let all business be suspended, and all business houses be closed, the public offices closed, and draped in mourning.</p>
<p>The citizens of Kentucky are invoked to pay that homage to the National grief which such a great calamity inspires.</p>
<p>THOS. E. BRAMLETTE, <hi rend="italic">Governor of Kentucky</hi>.<pb/></p>
<p>Proclamation by the Governor
<lb/><date when="1865-04-17">17<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Apl /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
