<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2056"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Joseph Henin to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9132</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-76 to MG24-77</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-07-07">7 July 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Hon. Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Govener of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner, Joseph Harris would respectfully represent with Your Excellency, that one Paul Gans, a French man, was keeping a Mill by one Jack Dawson near New Haven Ky, -- in the year <date when="1860">1860</date>_ Said Dawson, owned a colord girl named Curella, who was much in the command of the employees of the Mill At the time said Gans went to the Mill he had a capital of $18.00 -- of this he lent much of it to said Dawson. In the Spring of <date when="1861">1861,</date> Dawson being desirous of getting rid of Gans, caused <hi rend="str">a</hi> warrants to be issued against him, accusing said Gans of endeavoring to steal and entree away said Negro girl. Your petitioner, also a Frenchman, and a friend to said Gans, knowing the malice that had prompted Dawson to have said Gans arrested, and of his innocence became the bail of said Gans, who in a short time, being entirely out of employment here, went to Memphis in the capacity of Mill <unclear/>, where travel from there he was entirely <unclear/> tempted. At the time of the trial, the war had broken out so extensively that it was impossible for<pb/>
<lb/>Gans to attend -- all travel and communication had been entirely cut off, and consequently Gans was unable to attend said court in discharge of said bond, and defend himself agt the unjust accusations of said Dawson. Your Petitioner states that if he had known that he could have attended said trial and made these matters appear before the court he would have done so -- He states that said Gans and himself are ignorant of the laws and customs of this country, and have had no intention of viiolating them in the slightest degree* <note place="left margin">*He states that said Gans will <hi rend="str">attend</hi> return just as soon as communication is sufficiently open, and attend said trial and defend himself against the charges.</note> He says it will be a great hardship for him to pay said forfeiture under the circumstances, when he knows of the innocence of said Gans, and his desire to attend the trial if it had not been for the present Revolution cutting off all communication between the North and South. He prays that Your Excellency may remit said fine and forfeiture.</p>
<p>J Henin</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Jefferson County</p>
<p>Joseph Henin states that he believes the statements contained<pb/>
<lb/>in the foregoing petition are true</p>
<p>J Henin</p>
<p>Sworn to before me this <date when="1862-07-07">7 day of July 1862.</date></p>
<p>Jeff Brown
<lb/>Notary Public Jeff. co.
<lb/><hi rend="str">T G Raynor</hi> N. P.</p>
<p>We the undersigned are acquainted with the <unclear/> Petitioner as well as Paul Gans, and know them to be worthy Frenchmen, and law abiding in habitants and believe the statements contained in the foregoing petition are true, and a join with him in his prayer</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>G. H. Kellar M. D.
<lb/>W. H. Lyle M. D
<lb/>P Peters
<lb/>frechn
<lb/>Conrad Crelier
<lb/>F Parrott
<lb/>W. A Caswell
<lb/>G. Vandersyppe
<lb/>Wm H Tilliman
<lb/>Charles Schuster
<lb/>T. Wolf
<lb/><hi rend="underline">James H. West</hi>
<lb/>H. Wolf.
<lb/>H Harris
<lb/>D J Bowles
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> E. Gilpin M D.
<lb/>Eugene Fourine
<lb/>T Harey
<lb/>A Morel
<lb/><cb n="2"/>H Raynor
<lb/>Nicholas Berger
<lb/>T,, Besancon
<lb/>Eugene Martin <unclear/>
<lb/>J C Brooks
<lb/>V. Besancon
<lb/>Joseph frielz
<lb/>Mickel Langel
<lb/>F. Pasquier
<lb/>A. B. Besancon
<lb/>Marcillin Elin
<lb/>G. W. Fenley
<lb/>J. W. Clark
<lb/>W Blind
<lb/>U. Soutter
<lb/>D. clark <unclear/>
<lb/>P Courman
<lb/>D. B. Grable
<lb/>W B Grable<pb/>
<lb/>Jhon Woillard
<lb/>A. Marais
<lb/>C Marais
<lb/>W C. Heaton
<lb/>A. Parguy
<lb/>J. M. Ryder
<lb/>A. P. Welch
<lb/>W C, Jones
<lb/>T<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">eavis</hi></hi> Degraurve
<lb/>F. Lousardin
<lb/>F Barrier
<lb/>A Parke
<lb/>D. S. Johnson
<lb/>Jacob Ott
<lb/>J G MCormick
<lb/>W Cy Hatch
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> G Strong
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Dermott
<lb/>Ch<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Dayné
<lb/><hi rend="underline">H. W. Morgan</hi>
<lb/>M W Moran
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Jos. Pargny
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Mix
<lb/>A N Caft
<lb/>H. W. Norton J P. J C
<lb/>U. C. Sherrill
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Shively JPGK
<lb/>C Garnier
<lb/><unclear>P L B de Coutz</unclear>
<lb/>Jo<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Clement Justice of the Peace Jeff Co. K.y.
<lb/>B J Newman
<lb/>A. Koerner
<lb/>Louis Lartrue
<lb/>Jackson Coom
<lb/>Jules Pluvier
<lb/>Isidore Vanhorabeker
<lb/>Joseph Keller
<lb/>Frank M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Caulery M D
<lb/>William Earch
<lb/>Henry Dubourg.M. M.
<lb/>George Pentenste
<lb/>Ch<hi rend="sup">s</hi> M. Thrustan</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
