<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0804"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">B. M. Cunningham to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10272</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-264 to MG19-265</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Harrodsburg, Mercer County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner B M Cunningham respectfully states to your Excellency that on the <gap/> day of <date when="1861-02">February 1861</date> a judgment was rendered against him in the Police Court of Harrodsburg for $10 as a fine for an alledged Breach of the peace. He states that ^at the time^ <hi rend="str">upon</hi> the trial had of him upon said charge he was sick in bed and unable to attend to his defense, which he has no doubt he could have done successfully had he been able to attend at the trial. He states here the facts upon which said charge was made against him as they really occurred. He <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>was in company with one James Patterson who had a fight with one John Chinn at the house of said Chinn he had gone there with said Patterson without any intention or expectation of a difficulty, and so far as he knew Patterson himself was friendly with Chinn and on his part had no thoughts of any between himself and s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Chinn. He states that while there an altercation of words took place growing out of occurrences ^and causes^ which <hi rend="str">which</hi> then and there first had a beginning, and ended in a fight between them ^Patterson &amp; Chinn^ he your petitioner had no part nor hand in it struck no blows nor attempted nor threatened to strike, neither was he struck. After he was out of the house, seeing the violence of Chinn, and the fight at intervals still kept up between them, he did take up an axe but never used nor attempted to use it nor did he intend in any event to use it <hi rend="str">in</hi> hostilely toward s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Chinn nor any other person unless it should become necessary to do so in self<pb/>
<lb/>defence but happily no such necessity arose. ^And this and none other is your petitioner's case in which s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Judgment was rendered^</p>
<p>Your petitioner states that he is a young person in his twenty first year averse to fighting and publick disturbances and feels equally averse to paying a fine for an offense of which he is not guilty and very respectfully prays for the interposition of your executive clemency and to be released from paying said fine</p>
<p>B M Cunningham</p>
<p>State of Kentucky Mercer County.</p>
<p>Personally came before me J P Haggin Examiner for Mercer County <hi rend="str">the above</hi> B M Cunningham whose name is subscribed to the above petition and made oath that he believes the statements thein contained are true.</p>
<p>Jno P Haggin Examiner</p>
<p>To his Excellency the Governor</p>
<p>The undersigned was counsel and attorney for James Patterson at the trials of him and B M Cunningham and present and heard the evidence on the <gap/> day of <date when="1861-02">February 1861</date> before the Police Court of Harrodsburg charged with breaking the Publick Peace on the <gap/> day of <gap/> <date when="1861">1861</date> and the evidence there adduced disclosed substantially the state of case and facts so far as s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Cunningham was concerned which he has stated in his petition. And believing his petition one of merit and strong claims to your clemency most respectfully unites in the prayer made as above by him the<pb/>
<lb/>said Cunningham</p>
<p>Jno P Haggin</p>
<p>To his Excellency the Governor</p>
<p>The undersigned unite in the prayer of the foregoing petition of B M Cunningham</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">James Harlan Jr
<lb/>O S Poston</hi></p>
<p>I was present at the trials of Jas Patterson and B M Cunningham alluded to in the foregoing petition of s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Cunningham and heard the evidence there adduced and the case circumstances and facts there disclosed by the evidence was substantially the same which s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> Cunningham has stated as above.</p>
<p>I consider his case one meriting the clemency of the Governor and very willingly unite in the prayer of the petition of s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Cunningham</p>
<p>John Slavens<pb/></p>
<p>Harrodsburg
<lb/>Po. Ct
<lb/>B M Cunningham
<lb/>to } Petition
<lb/>The Governor</p>
<p>Respite 12 months</p>
<p>$10 } Breach
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-03-14">Mar 14. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
