<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1287"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John H. Bates to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10755</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-172 to MG21-173</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency, the Governor of Kentucky:</p>
<p>Your petitioner, John H. Bates, respectfully represents that about the middle of <date when="1861-01">January, 1861,</date> as he is informed &amp; believes, one Isaac Rosenbaum was put in Jail in Louisville Ky, in default of bail in the sum of $300 to answer an indictment for felony, in the Jefferson Circuit Court.</p>
<p>That on the <date when="1861-02-06">6th Feby 1861,</date> your petitioner was applied to by one of the brothers (a resident of Indiana) of said Rosenbaum to become the surety on the bail bond; and, on that day, unfortunately for your petitioner, he consented and went on the bond. On the <date when="1861-05-06">6th May, 1861,</date> when the case against Rosenbaum was called for trial, he failed to appear and had absonded -- whereupon, a forfeiture was then entered, &amp;, on the <date when="1861-05-21">21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> May 1861,</date> a judgment on said forfeiture, as against your petitioner was rendered in the Jefferson Circuit Court for the sum of $300 &amp; costs.</p>
<p>From the collection of this judgment your petitioner humbly prays to be released by a remission at the hands of your Excellency.</p>
<p>He makes this prayer respectfully yet Earnestly, &amp; for the following reasons, which he trusts &amp; believes will meet with your Excellency's favorable consideration. Your petitioner was induced to go on the bond through sympathy for the prisoner Rosenbaum, (who, however, was an Intire stranger)<pb/>
<lb/>it being stated, &amp; your petitioner having first informed himself of the truth of the statement, that he was lying in Jail sick, &amp; had been for some days.</p>
<p>Besides, it was represented to your petitioner that Rosenbaum was a good man &amp; would certainly be present &amp; stand his trial, so as in no wise to involve your petitioner. And again, the minister of the Jewish Synagogue in this City, also joined in the request &amp; in these representations to your petitioner; And, upon the request of the Minister &amp; the brother of Rosenbaum, your petitioner went the security, without fee or reward directly or indirectly, &amp; solely for the purpose of befriending a sick stranger &amp; as your petitioner was informed &amp; thought a wronged &amp; innocent man.</p>
<p>Your petitioner supposes he was applied to by the brother of Rosenbaum on account of a business acquaintance which he had previously formed with him, and in this wise -- Your petitioner is a house painter by trade &amp; carried on the business in Louisville, Ky; in connection with this he has, from the savings of his labor, been enabled to open a store, on a small scale, for the sale of paints, glass and such articles as are used in his business. Rosenbaum, the brother of the prisoner, lives in M<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Vernon, Indiana, and, on his visits to Louisville on several occasions, made purchases from your petitioner's store -- sometimes for cash &amp; sometimes on credit, &amp; always settled fairly with your petitioner, who, from this intercourse,<pb/>
<lb/>believed him to be an honest &amp; honorable man; &amp;, when applied to by him to go security for the brother -- the application also being joined in by the Jewish Minister, &amp; the prisoner being sick in Jail, your petitioner, unfortunately (he now sees) consented &amp; became bound as the surety.</p>
<p>In thus Endeavoring to do a kind action, and without fee or Expectancy or hope of reward, he has involved himself, and to such an extent that, if forced to satisfy the judgment, he will be seriously injured. Your petitioner has a wife &amp; child to support by his labor &amp; what sales he can make from his little paint Establishment; &amp; he prays your Excellency to relieve them &amp; him by a remission releasing him from the payment of so much of the aforesaid judgment as may be in the power of your Excellency; and, as in duty bound, your petitioner will ever pray &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi>.</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>Jno H Bates</p>
<p>I am the minsiter referred to in the foregoing petition, which I have read, &amp; certify to the truth of the statements therein. I hope your Excellency will remit as prayed, for I am satisfied Mr Bates was only influenced by sympathy to go on the bond, and that he was governed to a great degree by my representations &amp; request. I am sorry that I have been instrumental in having him thus involved, but<pb/>
<lb/>I was acting innocently &amp; from the purest motives &amp; never dreamed but that the prisoner would be on hand at the time to stand his trial.</p>
<p>Very respectfully,
<lb/>B. H. Gotthelf Minister of the German Hebrew Congregation, Louisville</p>
<p>I am well acquainted with the petitioner &amp; know him to be a clever, good &amp; industrious citizen, whose statements are entitled to the fullest credit &amp; having read his petition. I cheerfully join in his prayer to your Excellency to grant the remission.</p>
<p>Robert J. Elliott</p>
<p>I am well acquainted with Rev<hi rend="sup">d</hi> B. H Gothelf of this city whose statement is made above. He is a most worthy Estimable Gentleman &amp; Minister of the Hebrew Congregation, a man of warm Sympathies and kind heart, I have the fullest confidence in his statement</p>
<p>Geo. W. Johnston.</p>
<p>Jefferson Cir. Ct
<lb/>$300 } Recog
<lb/>Jno. N. Bates</p>
<p>Resp<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 12 Mo</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-07-18">July 18. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
