<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2106"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. A. Glenn et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9182</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-160 to MG24-161</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Elkton, Todd County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-05-25">25 May 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Elkton Ky. <date when="1865-05-25">May 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>His Excellency 
<lb/>Thos E Bramlett</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Todd County Kentucky State that at the <date when="1862-04">April Term 1862</date> of the Todd Circuit Court the Grand Jury of said County returned into said Court an indictment <hi rend="str">against</hi> against William A Dowdy, J H Millen, Georg Harrel, and Al Tolbert Jr. charging them with the crime of robbery in taking from W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> B Downey several Sacks of sugar. and a pistol.</p>
<p>At the time the offence is charged to have been committed. the parties accused were confederate soldiers in a camp near Allensville Ky. and were recruited. and commanded by a man called Col Hornsby They had complete Military possession of this county. William B Downy started. from Elkton. towards Greenville with several sacks of Sugar and when six or eight miles from Elkton in the direction of Green river he was over taken by a squad of Rebel Soldiers in command of George. Harrel who was first Lieutant. and the sugar was seized &amp; taken through Elkton and as we were informed to the camp at Allensville where it was used by Col. Hornsby's command. The pistol was returned to Downey, and after the rebel soldiers left W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> C Harrel (the father of George Harrel) who is a very worthy clever farmer of this county paid Downey <hi rend="underline">full</hi> <hi rend="underline">price</hi> for all the sugar We are well satisfied the sugar was taken by a direct order from Col Hornsby. Some twelve months after Hornsby left Leut. Harrell resigned, came home took<pb/>
<lb/>the oath of allegiance conducted himself as a good citizen, and remained <hi rend="str">with</hi> for some time then went to Canada to ^avoid^ arrest and trial under said indictment, where he now is</p>
<p>Young Harrel both before, and after his enlistment in the army sustained the character of an upright honorable young man Now stood better</p>
<p>His father promptly paid for every thing taken in this neighborhood when he was along and he left because he feared the prejudices against his associates might cause his conviction</p>
<p>We have full confidence that George Harrel if allowed to return will make a worthy moral &amp; valuable member of society -- and if consistent with your views of duty and property We respectfully ask the interposition of Executive Clemency in granting to sd George Harrell a pardon for the offence charged or such other relief as may seem just and proper to Your Excellency</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W A Glenn
<lb/>G Wallace. Gatte
<lb/><cb n="2"/>H. G Petree
<lb/>S H Perkins
<lb/>J. G. Hollingworth
<lb/>S Crabb
<lb/>G. B. Lewis
<lb/>J W. Lewis
<lb/>E. R. Price
<lb/>S W Kennedy
<lb/><hi rend="underline">S. H. Grooms</hi>
<lb/>H. G. Bibb
<lb/>Jesse Russell
<lb/>W H Roberts
<lb/>J O M Ghee<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Can't pardon any one who has fled from custody -- 
<lb/>Refused</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
