<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-033-0048"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Henry E. Reynolds and Sarah Reynolds, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11599</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Andrew P Patrick</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>1st - 2nd Regiments Kentucky Cavalry Muster Rolls</collection>
      <idno>Box 46, Bundle 2</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-01-13">13 January 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Co A. 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Regt Mtd Vol.
<lb/>Kentucky, Franklin County: SS</p>
<p><hi rend="str">John D</hi>Henry E Reynolds states that he is the identical person mentioned in the discharge signed Robt B Mitchell Brig Genl commanding Post dated Nashville <date when="1862-12-25">25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of December 1862,</date> by which he was discharged from the U S Service, as a private of Capt John D Wickliffe's Company "A" 2 Ky Regt Mounted Vols, on account of physical Disability. He has ever since, and now, labored under the same disability, being liable to fits caused by exposure.</p>
<p>about three weeks ^since^ he, was, as he was afterwards informed, enlisted in the company of Artillery being raised under State authority by Capt S Goins. He was under the influence of liquor at the time of his alleged enlistment, and not aware of what he was doing. He is physically unfit for the service, on last Friday when assisting Capt Goins to fine the cannon -- soon after, he was attacked with the same kind of fit <hi rend="str">the</hi> for which he was discharged.</p>
<p>He asks that he be released from said enlistment as he <hi rend="str">did not</hi> is not able to stand the service, and<pb/>
<lb/>enlisted into the contract of enlistment when he was drunk and <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> not capable of Knowing what he was doing.</p>
<p>Sarah Reyonds states that she is the mother of said Henry E Reynolds, and that his statements are true -- Since his return from The army he had had frequent fits, as often as two &amp; three times a week, and he is Thereby totally unfit for any kind of service in the army -- He was drunk on the day it is said he was enlisted -- </p>
<p>Henry E Reynolds ^his X Mark^
<lb/>Sarah Reynolds ^her X Mark^</p>
<p>Sworn to before me a Justice of the pease for Franklin County</p>
<p>John J. Quinn <hi rend="underline">J. P. F. C.</hi></p>
<p><stamp type="revenue"/><note place="stamp">J J Q
<lb/><unclear/></note><pb/></p>
<p>Refered to Inspector Genl, who will Cause discharge if the facts are satisfactorily made out -- </p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette</p>
<p>issue discharge in such form that he cannot impose upon a recruiting officer in the future</p>
<p>D W Lindsey
<lb/>Insp Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi></p>
<p>Discharged <date when="1864-01-13"><hi rend="str">D</hi>Jany 13/64</date><pb/></p>
<p>2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Cav Co A -- Cav
<lb/>Frankfort. Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-01-13">Jany 13<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Reynolds H. E</hi> 
<lb/>D. W. Lindsey
<lb/>Ins Genl of Ky<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>The discharge of H. E. Reynold in a Company of artillery to be raised for State defense, to take effect <date when="1864-01-13">January 13<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Granted <date when="1864-01-13">Jany 13' 64</date>
<lb/>See L. B<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Recd A. G. O. <date when="1864-02-06">Feb'y 6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
