<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2282"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Charles Hilton to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6919</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-142 to BR15-143</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Camp Nelson, Jessamine County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-08-14">14 August 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Camp Nelson Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-08-14">August 14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Thomas R. Bramlet
<lb/>Govner Of Ky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>I have the honor to Make a Short asstatement to you in reguard to my long confinement Sir I was Arrested on the <date when="1863-12-15">15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day Of December 1863</date> On Charge Of Assaulting the wife of Capt Thomas Rusell, in a Rude Manner and while under the influence of Liquer I was Tride by A General Courtmartial On the <date when="1864-03-14">14<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of March 1864</date> At the City Of Louisville Ky I Enlisted in the united States Service On the <date when="1862-10-27">27th of October 1862</date>.</p>
<p>I have a Destitute Family Liveing in the Eastern Part of Kentucky</p>
<p>I wish to Apply for Pardon so that the unexpired Portion Of My Sentence ^may^ be Remited I hope that you will take interest in the Matter and assist Me. I am Sentenced<pb/>
<lb/>to hard Labor and Confinement for the period Of (3) three years. Govner it seems hard that I have to Encounter with such A Sentence as I do for the Offence that I was Guilty of. I was not Guilty of the Offence that I was charged with I will send the Heading of the Order Promulgating My sentence. I hope that you will Assist me in being Relieced from confinement. My Pay and allowances is All forfeited all that I can ask for is to be Relieced so that I can Return Home to my Destitute Family. Govner I will Leave this with you to Deside</p>
<p>I hope to hear from you soon</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>your Humble servant
<lb/>Charles Hilton
<lb/>2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> Lieut. Co. "F" 39<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky. Vol.
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Mtd</hi>. <hi rend="underline">Inft</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Head Qrs. Dept. of Ky
<lb/>Louisville, <date when="1865-09-09">Sept. 9/65</date>
<lb/>E &amp; M. 470 -- Vol. 2 -- D. K. -- <date when="1865">1865</date></p>
<p>Respectfully returned to His Excellency, Thos. E. Bramlette, Gov. of Ky -- </p>
<p>The charges against this man being of a heinous nature. I can not consider this application favorably. Attention is invited to enclosed extract from General Order promulgating his sentence.</p>
<p>John M Palmer
<lb/>Major General -- <pb/></p>
<p>H -- 383 -- DK -- Vol -- 2 -- /<date when="1865">65</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Military Prison Camp Nelson Ky <date when="1865-08-15">August 15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Hilton Charles 2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> Lieut C<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi> F 39. Ky Mounted Infantry<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Askes to be released from confinment, and to have the unexpired portion of his Sentence remitted<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Office Provost Marshal
<lb/>Camp Nelson <date when="1865-08-15">August 15 1865</date><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Respectfully forwarded and approved I have always found the within named man honest faithful and obedient and of general good character. I think that his case is one which deserves clemency</p>
<p>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Harkins
<lb/>Lieu<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> and Provost Marshal
<lb/>Commanding Military Prison
<lb/>Camp Nelson Ky<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Referred to Maj Genl Palmer with request to release this man from further punishment</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi></p>
<p>What record
<lb/>W. H. C.</p>
<p>See G. O. No 89 Dept of Ohio
<lb/>Recd -- DK -- <date when="1865-08-18">8-18-65</date></p>
<p>Head Qrs. Dept. of Ky -- 
<lb/>Louisville, <date when="1865-08-28">Aug. ^28^/65</date></p>
<p>Respectfully referred to Major W. H. Coyl. J. A. for remark. By command of Maj. Gen. Palmer.</p>
<p>Ben. W. Sullivan
<lb/>Lt &amp; A. A. A. G.</p>
<p>Head Qrs Dept of Ky
<lb/>Louisville <date when="1865-08-30">Aug 30<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 65</date>
<lb/>Respectfully returned.</p>
<p>This man's sentence is promulgated in Genl order No. 89. Hd Qrs Dept of the Ohio series of <date when="1864">1864</date>. He seems to have been found guilty of crimes which fully justify his sentence. There is no other record of him in this office</p>
<p>William H. Coyl
<lb/>Judge Advocate
<lb/>Dept of Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
