<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0584"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Hines et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9036</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-423 to R4-424</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thomas E. Bramlette, Governor.</p>
<p>Your Petitioners Thomas Hines, R. Enders &amp; Henry Enders would most respectfully state, that on the night of the <date when="1863-07-20">20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of July 1863</date>, a runaway negro, from the state of Tennessee, broke into the Tobacco ware House in this place and stold therefrom two bolts of domestic and Some gunny bags, and next morning, just after your petitioner Hines was opening his store, the negro came and offered to sell them to Hines, and Hines, thinking something was not right, engaged him in conversation, telling him he would buy the articles, and was <hi rend="underline">jewing</hi> him, merely to gain time, until some one could come in, so that information could be given of the theft; in about 20 minutes, the deputy Marshall did call in, for the express purpose of caching the negro, he having a few minutes before, had been informed of the theft; Whereupon Hines told him<pb/>
<lb/>(the officer) and that was said and done, and when the negro came to his house, and the cause of Hines detaining him &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi> the officer took charge of the goods &amp; delivered them to the owner, and also arrested the negro and Hines -- for the Felony -- The negro was tried before the examining Court and sent on for further trial, and as Hines was an important witness for the Commonwealth, the <hi rend="str">examining court</hi>deputy Marshall, took his bond with R. Enders &amp; H. Enders as his security, <hi rend="underline">in a felony</hi> case instead of as witness for the commonwealth -- They being informed by Fuller the Deputy Marshall, that it was a bond to appear as witness and it was not read over to them; The officer had blank bonds, and the parties signed the blanks without reading -- The negro before court, together with other negroes, broke jail and ran off from the state, and at the <date when="1863-10">October Term 1863</date>, through some oversight, the bond<pb/>
<lb/>of Hines &amp; Enders as security was taken as forfeited, a copy of said bond and order of court, are filed herewith -- </p>
<p>Now your petitioner Hines, Says that he is <hi rend="underline">Seventy Nine years</hi> old, and has resided in this County since its foundation, and has always sustained an irreproachable reputation, that he was not charged or suspected with a felony that the foregoing facts are true. That the Deputy Marshall told him he would notify him, whenever the Circuit Court wanted him as a witness -- He received no notification and never heard of any steps being taken in the case, till after court and a summons served on him and his Security -- That the deputy Marshall had no authority to take such a bond even if your petitioner was guilty, for the Code expressly says all such bonds are to be taken by a Sheriff -- See Criminal Code Sec 79, page 318 Stantons Edition -- </p>
<p>Wherefore Your petitioners pray<pb/>
<lb/>that your Excellency remit the amount of said forefeited recognizance -- Your petitioners would further state, that Hines has a large family, including grandchildren dependent on him for support, as the father of his grandchildren is now in the U. S. Army, and it is as much as he can do, in his old age and limited means to make a support -- They <hi rend="underline">earnestly</hi> and<hi rend="underline"> imploringly</hi> ask your clemency -- </p>
<p>Thomas Hines
<lb/>Robt Enders
<lb/>Henry Enders</p>
<p>Dear Governor. At this instance and request of the foregoing Petitioners, I have drawn up the petition, embodying the facts in the case, as known to be true. I was present when the negro was sent on and know that he was the thief; from all the proof -- I join in the above prayer -- without fee or hope of reward -- I could get a large number of names, but my experience is, that it is useless.</p>
<p>Yours truly
<lb/><hi rend="underline">John Q. A. King</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
