<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2519"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Joseph McCarroll and J. B. Gowen to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7156</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-29 to BR16-30</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Christian County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-27">27 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned Sheriff and deputy Sheriff of Christian County Kentucky respectfully represent, that one Jesse Gray a free man of Color residing in Christian County, was indicted in the Christian Circuit Court for stealing a mule, and entered into bond for his appearance and the undersigned became bound a surety for him, that said Gray appeared at one or more terms of said Court, and the case was Continued -- said bond was for $500 -- Subsequently said Gray was arrested charged with stealing a two horse load of corn, which he alledged that he bought of ^a^ slave belonging to the owner of said corn, and upon said last mentioned arrest the said Gray was brought before two magistrates of Christian County to enquire into the matter and the said Gray not having been able to get the negro who sold him the corn before said magistrates the case was laid over for two or three days and the said Gray required to give bond in the sum of One hundred dollars for his appearance and the undersigned Jos M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Carroll became bound as surety for him, said Magistrates did not meet at the time fixed for the appearance of said Gray, and since that said Gray left the State and went to the state of Tennessee and is now there as reported</p>
<p>They State that the attorneys for said Gray represented to them that the proof in case of the Indictment would<pb/>
<lb/>as they believed release said Gray from the charge of Stealing said mule, and hence they went upon his bond, they would further state that said Gray had resided in Christian County for a number of years, near the town of Hopkinsville and had always bourne a good Character, and was looked upon as an honest man -- They state that neither charge agst him has been tried, that said Gray failed to appear and answer said charges and the bonds upon which they were bound as surety for him have been forfeited and they will be compelled to pay them unless Executive Clemency can be obtained, wherefore they humbly pray your Honor to interpose in their behalf and release them from paying that portion of said bonds which is due to the State of Kentucky and as in duty bound will ever pray &amp;c
<lb/><date when="1865-10-27">Octo 27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date></p>
<p>Jo. McCarroll
<lb/>J, B, Gowen</p>
<p>H A Phelps says that he was one of the attys for Jesse Gray afs<hi rend="sup">d</hi> and from the proof which said Gray Could have made in the case of Indictment for stealing the mule he did not think he was guilty of the charge the other case for stealing the <hi rend="str">mule</hi> Corn he did not converse with any of the witnesses -- </p>
<p>He respectfully asks that the amount of the said bonds due the Commonwealth agst said M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Carroll &amp; Gowen be remitted -- 
<lb/><date when="1865-10-27">Octo 27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">H. A Phelps</hi><pb/></p>
<p>The undersigned State that they are well acquainted iwth Jesse Gray and that he was always regarded as an honest citizen prior to said charges and they respectfully solicit your Honor to release said M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Carroll and Gowan form the payment of that portion of Said bonds which is due the Commonwealth of Kentucky -- 
<lb/><date when="1865-10-27">Octo 27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date></p>
<p>H, R, Littell County Judge
<lb/>Joab Clark clk cir. cts
<lb/>A H Clark Trustee J fund
<lb/>G. H. Lawson clk. Co Court
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E. Lawson D. C. Co. ct
<lb/>B H Bristow<pb/></p>
<p>Christian Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Jo<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Carroll &amp; John B Gowan
<lb/>$500.
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/>&amp;
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Jo<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Carroll
<lb/>for
<lb/>$100,
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-11-03">3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Nov /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
