<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-022-0110"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Henry Porter to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG12033</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>37th - 76th Regiments Enrolled Militia Primary Source Documents (1861-1866)</collection>
      <idno>Box 81, Folder 71st Regiemnt 1863-1865 Col. Vick's Correspondences</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Greenville, Muhlenberg County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-10-24">24 October 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Greenville <date when="1864-10-24">Oct<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 24 -- 64</date>
<lb/>Hounerd. Sir</p>
<p>I take the privilege of adresssing you as old chief magistrate of Ky. knowing of no other source of redress that I have under present. circumstances, Co<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Vick who commands a company of home Guards in this County, is doeing the citizens a great amt. of injury, and doeing us no good in the way of protection, 12 Robers came into our Town about 10 days ago, and robed the citizens of between 4 and 5 thousand dollars in money &amp; goods he never followed them nor made any effort to capture them, he has followed several gangs, but allways manages<pb/>
<lb/>to keep a respectful distance behind them the comunity about hesitate to inpute his tardiness to <hi rend="underline">Cowardice</hi> his men are the last scrapings of this comunity, they insult Ladies indiscriminately where ever the go, they are drunk <hi rend="underline">generally</hi>, (as it respects your humble servant I have been one of the first home guards although 64 years of age and took an oath to support the Consitution of the U. S. and the state of Ky. I still feel bound by that oath, but I am for ^McLelland^ for our next president, believeing he will respect the Constitution, M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Ware of our Town is for Lincon he is sustaining Vick, to keep<pb/>
<lb/>the McLelland men <hi rend="underline">down</hi> the drowth has cut our Crops short, I have scarcely Corn to make bread for my family Vicks men has taken two loads, ^(of corn)^; and a load of oats (and no pay) and I will have to buy bread I have a large family to support Vick is worth nothing and never was, there can be nothing made out of him, <hi rend="str">I will</hi> two of his men came to my house this morning and demanded breakfast my wife told them breakfast was over and nothing cooked he said she was a damned lyar, and he would have it, from 8 to 16 of them eats at my house and feeds their horses about once<pb/>
<lb/>a week) I can obtain signers to a petition of from 20 to 50 of the most respectable citisens substantiating all that I have stated, I am afraid of a private injury if my name is given to him unless in a petition and I will be the first sighner and will forward imediately if you desire it, your attention to the foregoing so as to afford me some protection will be gratefuly remembered by one who has and will support you as long as you pursue the indfendant and manly course that has marked your public life heretofore</p>
<p>your humble Servt.
<lb/>Henry Porter<pb/></p>
<p>Muhlenburg Co.
<lb/>71
<lb/>Greenville Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-10-24">Oct 24" 1864 -- </date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Porter Henry<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>To The Govnr<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Complains in regard to many acts of Col Vick and his command<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>An<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. <date when="1864-11-15">Nov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 15 -- 1864</date>
<lb/>on L. B. B. Page 136<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Rec<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> A. G. O. <date when="1864-10-28">Oct 28" 1864 -- </date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
