<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2294"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Buriston, Jr. et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9370</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG25-45 to MG25-46</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Govenor Magoffin</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Madison county would respectfully represent that they were present at the trial of L D King at the present term of the Madison circuit court for the Killing of Jas Lackey.</p>
<p>It appeared in the Commonwealths evidence as well as that of the defence that the killing took place under these circumstances. Lackey was somewhat drinking though not fully drunk &amp; went along the road avowing that he intended to have sexual intercourse with a woman before he left Madison county &amp; he was then going in a direction that lead him to the county line in about two miles or a little over &amp; he came where Kings wife &amp; a lady by the name of Irvin at or near a spring about forty steps from Kings house &amp; thereupon unbuttoned his pants &amp; drew his privates &amp; avowed his intention to have sexual intercourse with Mrs King at all hazards -- Mrs King was frightened &amp; her husband not at home &amp; she ran for protection to the house of two gentlemen by the name of <unclear>Froan</unclear> which was only some sixty or eighty yards from her own and called out<pb/>
<lb/>from the fence for the Mr Froans to come &amp; protect ^her^ crying &amp; excited tole what had occurred &amp; her husband happened to be at Froans &amp; heard her &amp; sprang up excitedly and ran to where Lackey had insulted his wife and found Lackey still there and struck him once or twice with his fist and once or twice with a rock form the effects of which blows Lackey died. During the trial it was the unanimous opinion of all but the prosecutors &amp; relations of Lackey that King ought to be acquitted &amp; had done no more than he ought to have done &amp; than we would have We therefore ask your excellency to Pardon King forthwith before he leaves the Madison Jail It appeared by all the testimony that Mrs King was a modest well behaved <hi rend="str">woman</hi> chaste woman of good reputation in all respects</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/> Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Buriston Jr
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Smith Collins
<lb/>Lewis. E,, Francis
<lb/>William Harris
<lb/>E F. Hollinay
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Bonnett
<lb/>A C Turner
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J S Reppert
<lb/>Alfred Stone
<lb/>P. P Ballard
<lb/>E F Pigg
<lb/>Esqr. David Tudor
<lb/>S V Rowland
<lb/>S Wherritt Jr<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>C C Ball
<lb/>J H Berry
<lb/>J D Smith
<lb/>Geo Dejarnatt
<lb/>C A Lisle
<lb/>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> H Newton
<lb/>H. C. Sea
<lb/>John P Jarman
<lb/>Samuel Burnett
<lb/>Daniel, H. Williams
<lb/>D. Nuller Chenault
<lb/>Jon P. Estill
<lb/>George W Smith
<lb/>Thomas.T. Smith
<lb/>Owen W Walker
<lb/>E Richardson
<lb/>Samuel Fox
<lb/>Robert French
<lb/>Squire Lowry
<lb/>Silas Newland
<lb/>J, C, Arvin
<lb/>Jo<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Fiks
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John Bennett
<lb/>Alexander Black
<lb/>B F Richardson
<lb/><hi rend="underline">T W Ball</hi>
<lb/>R P White
<lb/>Michael C Hennessey</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
