<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-028-0040"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Rob Morris to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7695</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Appointments by the Governor, Military Appointments, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R2-172 to R2-173</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-09-09">9 September 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Approved by Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Finnell
<lb/>Rob Mallory</p>
<p>To the Governor.</p>
<p>The undersigned, now in command of Home Guards at the Fair Grounds, would respetfully submit: -- </p>
<p>That the efficiency of Home Guards when properly officered and disciplined has been amply tested in Oldham, Henry, Montgomery and Mercer Counties.</p>
<p>In Oldham 4 companies of Home Guards under a few weeks of rigorous discipline have preserved the line of Railroad, overawed the disloyal population around them and without any expense to the State preserved order and government there.</p>
<p>The Undersigned have enjoyed <hi rend="str">much</hi>many <hi rend="str">military</hi> opportunities for military experiences -- the former in Texas during the guerilla warfare of 18<hi rend="str">4</hi>36-40, the latter for more than 30 years in the organizing and governing militia corps in <hi rend="str">this</hi> Kentucky.</p>
<p>They are familiar with the Country and people of Oldham, Henry, Trimble, Owen and adjacent Counties and possess, they think, the confidence of the loyal population of that section. Their experience with <hi rend="str">They therefore pr</hi><pb/>
<lb/>Home Guards is second to none in the State, and their zeal and love of government they <hi rend="str">possess</hi> trust are <hi rend="str">well</hi> known to your Excellency.</p>
<p>They therefore propose to raise a Regiment of militia for 3. months service to consist of ten companies of not less than 50 men each. officered and arranged as required by military law. This they can do in two weeks.</p>
<p>Each man shall furnish his own horse, clothing and arms.</p>
<p>We will go wherever your Excellency directs and subsist on the country trusting on the bounty of Union men and the fears of disloyal men to feed us. If allowed to operate in the section above indicated we will guarantee to afford an efficient military police there -- to restore the respect for State and Federal authority now so sadly shaken, -- preserve the publlic records, overawe the disloyal and in all the hearts of true men.</p>
<p>All we ask of the State is ^ammunition and^ the ordinary pay of the Federal service omitting all bounties, rations,<pb/>
<lb/>and clothing -- <hi rend="str">and what ammunition is necessary</hi> But if the State can aid us in <hi rend="str">The</hi> procuring flannel shirts <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>muskets and sabres it will increase our efficiency by that much.</p>
<p>The undersigned submit to your Excellency that no plan so prompt, cheap and efficient as this can be suggested. Our men are ready. The exigences of the times call loudly. Our hearts glow with the desire of usefulness and honor and as respectfully tender our proposition to your Excellency.</p>
<p>Rob Morris
<lb/>Col. Com.<hi rend="sup">g</hi> Home Guard
<lb/>S. W. Hunt
<lb/>Lieut. Col. Home Guard.</p>
<p>I know the gentlemen well, who submit the forgoing proposition to Gov. Robinson, and recommend a favorable consideration by your Excellency. <date when="1862-09-09">Sept. 9. 1862.</date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">A. G. Hodges</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Messrs Morris &amp; Hunt
<lb/>Proposals to raise Regts</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
