<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1824"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Ebenezer B. Miller to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6461</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-377 to BR13-378</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-05-09">9 May 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thomas E. Bramlette Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Ebenezer B Miller states that at the <date when="1861-11">Nov term 1861.</date> of the Washington Circuit Court he went the bail of his brother Harrison Miller who was confined in the Washington County Jail under an indictment for killing James Thompson. The bail bond was for four thousand dollars. That at the <date when="1862-11">Nov term 1862</date> of said ^court^ Miller failing to appear in answer to said indictment. the bail bond was taken <hi rend="str">for</hi> ^as^ forfeited, and at the <date when="1863-11">November term 1863.</date> of said Court Judgment went against your petitioner for the sum of five thousand dollars the full amount of said bail and costs, That upon said Judgment he has paid three thousand five hundred dollars. <hi rend="str">at</hi> leaving <hi rend="str">th</hi> fifteen hundred dollars unpaid. Your petitioner sates that said forfeiture was caused in no wise by his counsel or connivance -- but was done by said Miller without any aid or advise on the part of your petitioner. Wherefore he most respectfully asks you to remit the unpaid part of said Judgment. <date when="1865-05-09">May 9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865.</date></p>
<p>E. B. Miller</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Washington County join in the prayer of the above petition and ask That the relief sought may be granted him</p>
<p>Rich J Brownes
<lb/>&amp;#9758;over<pb/>
<lb/>Jas. P. Barbour Clk Washington Ct Court
<lb/>M. G. Gorin Police Judge Springfield
<lb/>C R Craycroft Deputy Sheriff
<lb/>William H. Phillips D. C. Washington Ct Ct.
<lb/>James R Hughes -- 
<lb/>Anthony C M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Elroy.
<lb/>Hugh L M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Elroy
<lb/>L J Truett
<lb/>S. E. Booker coroner of Washington County
<lb/>C B Butner County attorney
<lb/>John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Intire " Judge
<lb/>G. J. Bosley J. P. W. C
<lb/>C. F. Bosley Shff W Co
<lb/>R S Peters Trustee Jury fund W Co</p>
<p>As Trustee of the Jury fund for Washington County Ky I certify that E B Miller as the surity for W H Miller on his bail bond has paid to me Two thousand dollas and has paid in addition to L H Noble Commonwealths attorney Fifteen hundred dollars -- </p>
<p>R S Peters
<lb/>T. J. F. W. C<pb/></p>
<p>Washington Cir Ct
<lb/>vs</p>
<p>Petition of Ebenezer B Miller of Washington County. to be released of a judgement on a forfeited bail bond gone as bail of W H Miller as the Washington Circuit Court.
<lb/>Presented <date when="1865-05-16">16' May 1865</date></p>
<p>Remit the unpaid balance of $<hi rend="underline">1.500</hi> -- 
<lb/>hand to R J Brown</p>
<p><date when="1865-05-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> May 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
