<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0103"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">C. M. Mathews, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4222</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-152 to BR8-153</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>New Castle, Henry County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-09-14">14 September 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>New Castle <date when="1863-09-14">Septr 14. 1863</date></p>
<p>About Eighteen months since some two or three Horses were stolen at or near Eminence Henry County Ky. Three days before the Horses were missing a man living in Washington County Indiana ^Geo Myres^ was at Eminence looking for Horses for sale. Suspicion rested on this man The Horses were never found. but were traced across the Ohio river. The owners of the Horses went to Myers house in Indiana told him he was suspected &amp; asked him to come with them to Ky and satisfy them as he said he could that he was at home when the Horses was stolen &amp; he could then return home. He came without hesitation &amp; as soon as he arrived on the Ky side of the river they had him arrested &amp; brought to New Castle for trial. The Justices W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> A Perry &amp; Gideon King after a full investigation of the case announced from the bench to Myres that thus was no Evidence to convict him. But as there possibly might be other evidence found they would hold him to bail &amp; fixed his bail at $750 -- Myers was unable to give bail and went to prison. It was freely known on the trial that on the day the Horses were stolen He was at home at church with his family<pb/>
<lb/>He remained in Jail three or four months &amp; untill Circuit Court. At court all the witnesses against him were present and he urged and through his counsel begged for a trial. The court however under the belief and aprehension that the confederate forces were about to enter the town adjourned &amp; Myers case was countinued. His wife was present &amp; his two birth children. Mrs Myers importuned with tears C M Mathews to go his security the prosecuting atty M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Scott also joins in this request and it was done -- Myers has not since made his appearance and Judgement has been rendered against C M Mathews for the amt of the bail bond $750 -- C M Mathews is a poor man with a large family &amp; asks the clemency of the Governor of Ky in the remittance of so much of this fine as he has the power to remit.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">C M Mathews</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Henry County Sct</p>
<p>The undersigned Justices of the Peace in &amp; for the County of Henry State That they have read the within paper setting forth the facts connected with the arrest and trial &amp;c of Geo Myers and find the same to be correct as far as they know and believe. They hope and ask that the Goven<hi rend="sup">t</hi> will remit the Judgement against M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> C M Mathews -- </p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> A Perry J.P.H.C
<lb/>G. King JPHC</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
