<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0799"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">David Berry to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4918</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-233 to BR10-234</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Carlisle, Nicholas County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-05-11">11 May 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Carlisle <date when="1864-05-11">May 11, 1864</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>Gov. Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. E. Bramblet -</p>
<p>Your Petitioner David Berry states that at the <date when="1859-03">March Term of the Nicholas Circuit in 1859</date> he was fined by the Court $25. for alledged Comtempt of Court in inducing a witness to leave Court when summoned to attend. and also was fined by the Court $20. at the same Term for failing to attend as a witness himself in a suit pending in the Court, and also by verdict of a Jury he was fined twenty Dollars for Gambling.</p>
<p>He says he was not guilty in the 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> &amp; last named cases &amp; was not wilfully Guilty of the 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> offence.</p>
<p>The facts of the first case are briefly these A Mr. Snapp was a witness in a case against this Petitioner &amp; another but left the Court before the Case was called for trial &amp; when called upon to answer for the Contempt he stated that this Petitioner had induced him to leave, whereupon the Court fined your petitioner $25. though he filed a written affidavit denying the charge &amp; purging the Contempt. The facts in the 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> case are these, He was summoned as a witness in a Case pending in the Court, but did not attend, though he intended to, but being at the time a Constable &amp; very busy was called from Town &amp; detained<pb/>
<lb/>The suit was unexpected Called in his absence. As he said before he was not guilty of the Charge in the last case and he cannot account for his run of bad luck in being fined in the Cases-</p>
<p>He says Your Predecessor respited the fines &amp; as your Petitioner thought had remitted them. No steps have been taken till quite lately to Collect them</p>
<p>Now Executives are in the <hi rend="str">off.</hi> Sheriffs hands &amp; pressing for collection.</p>
<p>He states that he is poor &amp; the payment of the Claims above would greatly oppress him. He is now doing services for his Country as an orderly in Co <gap/> 40<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Cavalry Refiment &amp; stationed at Gill Mills in Bath County. He prays that these fines be remitted &amp; will ever pray</p>
<p>David Berry
<lb/>by F. Munger</p>
<p>Hon Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. E. Bramblet
<lb/>Gov. of Ky.</p>
<p>Dear Sir at the Request of Mr. Berry I have written &amp; signed his name to the foregoing Petition</p>
<p>I saw Mr. Berry a few days ago &amp; he authorized me to state substantially the facts<pb/>
<lb/>above. Mr. Berry in the Federal service and for this Reason if for no other I think he ought to be released from these old fines that he thought had been remitted. The fines are excessive &amp; ^it is^ unaccountable how they happended to be imposed.</p>
<p>Your Ob<hi rend="sup">t</hi>. Sev<hi rend="sup">t</hi>.
<lb/>Fitch Munger</p>
<p>We Concur in recommending the Prayer of the foregoing Petition</p>
<p>John. W. Campbell
<lb/>James L. Arnold</p>
<p>Mr. Campbell is our Representative &amp; Mr. Arnold is our Circuit Court Clerk.</p>
<p>F. Munger<pb/></p>
<p>Nicholas Cir Ct
<lb/>Refused</p>
<p>As Judge may err in inflicting fines for contempt but, I will not err by remitting fines for such offences.</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/><date when="1864">64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
