<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3340"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. N. Todd et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5459</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-182 to BR42-183</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Barren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>Thos. E. Bramblette
<lb/>Gov of the State of Ky.</p>
<p>We the undersigned respectfully state and petition (viz) on the <gap/> day of March 1865 we were Indicted by the grand Jury of the Barren Co. Circuit court. at its <date when="1865-03">March term for the year 1865</date> of the crime of Larceny or Robery. viz. taking forcably feloniously &amp;c from one Woodford Bradshaw ^a pistol^ which charge we deny emphatically The history of the case is as follows on the <date when="1865-02-08">8" day of February 1865</date>. -- Jones (late Federal soldiers.) was under arrest (for some petty offence) and killed by Esqr. Dorsey &amp; Esqr. J. P. Taylor, for trial, and guarded by four Rebel Soldiers and one Union man. we (being not willing to see one of our comrads arrested and guarded by men that we and himself, had been fighting as enemies of our govt) went to the party and run the four Rebels off. and told the Justices of the Peace Taylor &amp; Dorsey. that we would guard our friend untill he was tried for his offence and if they were proposed, to try him then, they seen cause to release said Jones But in the retreat of the four Rebel guards one of them states and claims to have lost a pistol worth $15.00 Woodford Bradshaw one of the Rebel guards is the man who states<pb/>
<lb/>an oath that we took his pistol from him this we deny, we never said we had in our possession the pistol. we know nothing about it now nor did we then said pistol may have been lost by the rebel party, but it never came to our possession we were upon these grounds Indicted for Robery and 23 of the grand jury men were rebels who have have no conscientious scruples for a federal soldiers Justice we think we ought not to be indicted for this alleged offence further more we are all poor men and not able to pay Lawyers fees and other expenses in defense of lawsuits we furthermore state that we are not afraid of conviction under the truth but dont believe we can have justice by a Jury on trial owing to the great element of rebel feeling existing in this county we do not confess the alleged crime in the Indictment aforesaid but have made in this a correct statement of the facts and appeal to your Executive Clemency for our full &amp; free pardon for the causes above named</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> N Todd late of the 9th ^vol^
<lb/>H C Steenberger
<lb/>the other is <unclear/><pb/>
<lb/>To Gov. Thos. E. Bramblett of Ky we Loyal citizens and late soldiers to the to the Govt of the U. S. respectfully state and petition for the release of the party named as being Indicted in the foreoing statement we think it is rebel anamosity and believe the party should not be punished for the aforesaid alleged offences</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names.
<lb/>R. M. Holloway Post Master
<lb/>John. W. Jones Sen.
<lb/>James Lane lieut 9th Ky
<lb/>Joel T. Simmons 9th rebel
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/>J G Simmons
<lb/>J J Tingsly
<lb/>J H Johnson 9th Ky vol
<lb/>J J Wheat 9 Ky vol<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>I am personally acquainted with Geo. W. Anderson and William Todd who are Indicted for depriving Woodford Bradshaw of a pistol I am also acquainted with John Carrier &amp; H. C. Stermburger ^from character^ and believe they are innocent of the charges in the aforesaid Indictmint Mr. Anderson was a private and good soldier of the 37" Ky Mtd Inft Vols. Co A and Mr. Todd was a private soldier Co. K. 9" Ky. I. Vols and I believe their high sense of honor and right would <unclear/> them to discountenance and not incourage such an offence as they are accused of and hope that the Gov of Ky. will pardon them of the charges as stated in the Indictment</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>M. J. Goode 9 Ky vol
<lb/>John Benedit
<lb/>Elexander Bibe 9th Ky vols
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Samuel Martin
<lb/>Late Maj 27" Ky vols
<lb/>Wm. P. Carrier
<lb/><unclear/> of Malitia<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>William Bowley 9th Ky vol
<lb/>Ephraim Berry
<lb/>J. E &amp; P E Bineley
<lb/>Isaac Benley
<lb/>E Jones 37th Ky
<lb/>Aron Johnson
<lb/>F M rigdon
<lb/>T C Beneley 37th Ky
<lb/>T W Steemburgan
<lb/>J R Johnson
<lb/>James Lane Sen
<lb/>George Lane Jun
<lb/>B Francis Jr
<lb/>J. Corver Sr
<lb/>H,, Hunt
<lb/>W Dawsey 9th Ky vol
<lb/>Jasper F. Harrison 9 ky
<lb/>Robert Littrell
<lb/>E G Steenburgin
<lb/>B Francis
<lb/>Josiah Mcgins
<lb/>James Mesher
<lb/>B,, Carver
<lb/>H payne
<lb/>Joseph P Jones D. Po.
<lb/>John Bradshaw
<lb/>John W Jones Jr
<lb/>H Eaton
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Bucker Lane Sr.
<lb/>H steen Burgan
<lb/>Josiah Duckett
<lb/>James Taylor
<lb/>W R M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Adams
<lb/>Carel Eaton
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Taylor
<lb/>Charles Austin
<lb/>Benjamin Bibee
<lb/>Jno. R. Gregory
<lb/>Willis wood
<lb/>W. F. Austin Late Capt. ^of^ 9 Ky
<lb/>C. M. Bishop 9th Ky
<lb/>John W Britt 9th Ky
<lb/>George W rigdon 9th Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
