<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0445"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. William Byerback, Statement of Evidence</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4564</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-201</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Statement of Evidence in case of the Comlth vs. W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi>" Byerback -- malicious cutting</p>
<p>The evidence for the commonwealth, showed that a party had been Given near the house of the Byerbacks, that a serenade was being Given at the place where the party was, -- that Byerback with a young friend, went to the house, and listened to the serenade, and after a short time left_ went out on the street, accompanied by his friend, followed by <hi rend="str">the</hi> some two or three persons, one of whom, was Landrath, the person cut. After the parties had followed Byerback some distance down the street, the person cut, approached Byerback, and after some conversation, between, them, Byerback, was knocked down in the Gutter by Landsrath, Byerback got up very muddy, &amp; The same parties met after he got up &amp; Byerback cut him, with a pocket knife, I understand that the same witnesses were Examined the Circuit Court That were Examined in the Examining court, <hi rend="str">which</hi> when I prosecuted this case.</p>
<p>W. G. Reasor
<lb/>city attorney<pb/></p>
<p>Statement of the Evidence in the case of the Commonwealth against Wm Byerback by W. G. Reasor Comlth atto.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
