<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-022-0100"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">C. H. Blakey to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG12024</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>37th - 76th Regiments Enrolled Militia Primary Source Documents (1861-1866)</collection>
      <idno>Box 81, Folder 69th Regiment 1861 Logan Co. Home Guard</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Black Licks, Logan County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-21">21 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Black Licks P. O.
<lb/>Logan Co. Ky-
<lb/><date when="1861-06-21">June 21 1861</date>
<lb/>Secty. Military Board
<lb/>Dr Sir</p>
<p>Some three weeks since a Co. of Home Guards was formed at this place The County Judge superintend the election of Officers &amp; adminstered the Oath <hi rend="str">of</hi> required by law to officers &amp; men -- We then sent Mr. Jno, biers to Frankfort with the Bond of the Captain drawn up by the county Judge &amp; certified by him to be good with 4 securities, to make application for arms -- He was informed that the Board had not acted yet &amp; we must wait<pb/>
<lb/>I was elected Captain of the Company which numbers 70 men -- We have been drilling twice per week and are anxious to get arms -- We have a large slave population &amp; are on the Rail Road track to Tenn- and feel insecure in life &amp; property &amp; feel that the state should supply us with arms -- </p>
<p>I am ready to comply with any requirement your Board shall make</p>
<p>Russellville now has over 100 guns of the state then -- I think all the arms for this county should not be concentrate at that point I am Colonel of the Logan Militia and assure you the arms shall<pb/>
<lb/>be taken care of and used only in the spirit of the Law authorizing this distribution -- </p>
<p>Hoping to hear from you at an early day I remain
<lb/>very respectfully
<lb/>C. H. Blakey
<lb/>Capt. Home Guard<pb/></p>
<p>3
<lb/>C. H. Blakey
<lb/>Home Guards
<lb/>Logan Co
<lb/>Rec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> of <unclear/> <date when="1861-06-25">25 June 1861.</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
