<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2269"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Delaney Sanders, Judgment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6906</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-113</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The Commonwealth of Ky Plft
<lb/>against } Indictment for Erecting fence in Road
<lb/>Delaney Sanders Defendant</p>
<p>This day came the atty for the Commonwealth and the Defendant by his attorney for plead<hi rend="str">ings</hi> says he is not guilty of the charges alleged in the indictment and thereupon came a Jury to wit David Alsop, John C Thomas, Augustus Lewis, Peter Brenner Jr. Jas Mason Davis Richey, John Bogarth, N C Davidson C, B, Duncan D, S, Thomas, W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Estes &amp; Jesse G Marlow, Who were sworn to try the issue Joined and render a true verdict according to the Evidence returned the following verdict Viz "We of the Jury find the Defendant guilty and assess the damages at One Hundred and Twenty dollars</p>
<p>N C Davidson
<lb/>Foreman</p>
<p>Where upon it is adjudged by the court that the Defendant make his fine to the Commonwealth by the payment of One Hundred and twenty dollars and cost herein Expended and may be taken &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi></p>
<p>On motion of the Commonwealth <hi rend="str">of</hi> attorney an order of arrest is awarded against Thomas Richards Sr to be endorsed that he may give Bond for his appearance &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi> in the sum of Fifty Dollars</p>
<p>A Copy attest
<lb/>J B <unclear/> D C
<lb/>for E E Pate clk H. C. C.<pb/></p>
<p>The Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } <hi rend="underline">Indictment</hi>
<lb/>Delaney Sanders</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
