<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-022-0006"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Nathaniel C. McLean to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG2904</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Requisitions for the Return of Fugitives from Justice, 1859-1861</collection>
      <idno>MG7-161 to MG7-166</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Cincinnati, Hamilton County, Ohio</placeName>
    <date when="1861-03-20">20 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>United States Clerk's Office,
<lb/>Southern District of Ohio
<lb/>Cincinnati, <date when="1861-03-20">March 20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861.</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency,
<lb/>The Governor of Kentucky:
<lb/>Honored Sir:</p>
<p>The within affidavits are sent for the purpose of obtaining a Requisition for parties therein named, who have violated the Laws of Kentucky. If it is necessary to name some officer in Kentucky to whom the Warrant should issue, I would, by the request of the injured citizens, ask that the Warrant issue to Clinton Butts -- Marshal of Covington, Ky. It would also save time and promote the interests of the parties to have it mailed to me at the United States Clerk's Office, Cincinnati, Ohio.</p>
<p>With Great Respect,
<lb/>Nat. C. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi> Lean Jr.<pb/></p>
<p>Issue requisition
<lb/>B. M<pb/></p>
<p>United States of America,
<lb/>Southern District of Ohio. } SS:</p>
<p>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> S. Stone being duly sworn states that he is a citizern and resident of the County of Davis and State of Kentucky. That he had just returned home from New Orleans when he heard of the frauds and deceptions which had been practiced upon the citizens of said County of Henry Swartz and Morris Swartz, otherwise known as Henry and Morris Hall and mentioned in the foregoing affidavit of Samuel B. Taylor, who was during his absence visiting his house, all of which affidavit he believes to be true. -- That upon receiving the information of their extensive and unlawful proceedings, and at the urgent request of his neighbors he and three of his ^friends^ <hi rend="str">neighbors</hi> started in search of said Henry &amp; Morris Hall alias Henry and Morris Swartz: That they proceeded from Owensboro to New berg, Indiana, thence to Evansville and<pb/>
<lb/>there first ascertained what he supposes to be their correct names, to wit Henry &amp; Morris Swartz: that he also found that they had there sold one of their horses, which they drove to their buggy: thence they proceeded to Mt. Vernon, and there learned that their other horse &amp; their buggy was there, and that they, the said Halls or Swartz had disposed of a portion of the Silver Ware which he believes to have been fraudulently &amp; unlawfullly obtained, and that they had attempted to dispose of other portions: there he ascertained that they had taken passage on board a boat for Cincinnati, Ohio.</p>
<p>That they ^the said affiant &amp; companions^ the<hi rend="str">m</hi>n returned to Evansville and notified by telegraph the Mayor of Cincinnati, Ohio, upon which notice and information he is informed and believes that one of said parties, to-wit: Henry Hall alias Henry Swartz has been arrested and is now in Said State of Ohio, as is also a large portion of said Silver<pb/>
<lb/>Ware, now here awaiting the aid and assistance of your Honor to enable them to be returned to Kentucky for trial where they have been guilty of a crime against the Laws of said State of Kentucky.</p>
<p>That among the Silver Ware recovered, and now in custody at Cincinnati, Ohio, he recognized &amp; identified his own set of spoons, referred to in the foregoing affidavit of Saml. B. Taylor, bearing his name, and also his Butter Knife. Among the goods &amp; silver ware in said trunk, so recovered, Are articles which affiant has examined and which he thinks are the property of Jesse A. Moorman, Miner Pate, Mrs. John S. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Farlan, Charles Winfrey and -- Dean and Miles Lancaster and Mrs. Bennett. and others of his neighbors and acquaintances of Kentucky. Affiant is informed and believes that said Henry Hall alis Henry Swartz &amp;<pb/>
<lb/>Morris Hall alias Morris Swartz are both in the State of Ohio, and are out of the reach and jurisdiction of the Laws of Kentucky, without the requistion of Your Honor as Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Said Morris Hall alias Morris Swartz was about 5 ft. 6 in. in height, weighing about 135 pounds, dark hair &amp; dark eyes about 30 years of age. -- Said Henry Hall alias Henry Swartz was about 5 ft. 8 ^or 9^ in. in height, weighing about 130 pounds, long auburn hair inclined to curl, with red whiskers &amp; mustache &amp; light eyes, about 23 years of age. -- </p>
<p>The are both Jews as he believes.</p>
<p>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi>. S. Stone</p>
<p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this <date when="1861-03-20">20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of March A. D. 1861.</date></p>
<p>Jno M<hi rend="sup">c</hi> Lean Jr</p>
<p>Clerk U. S. Courts
<lb/>Cincinnati, Ohio.<pb/></p>
<p>United States of America,
<lb/>Southern District of Ohio. } SS.</p>
<p>Samuel B. Taylor being duly sworn upon oath states that on or about the <date when="1861-02-06">6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of February A. D., 1861,</date> he was at the house of Mr. W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> S. Stone, in the County of Daviss and State of Kentucky, when two men came to said house, and giving their names as Henry Hall and Morris Hall, respectively, represented themselves as Jewelers and manufacturers and repairers of Silver Ware at N<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi> 310 Main Street, Louisville, Ky. and solicited from the wife of said Stone the business of repairing, strengthening and improveing of her silver ware. That upon their pretences, representations and promises she entrusted to them one set of Silver Desert Spoons, vauled at about <hi rend="str">and</hi> <hi rend="str">over</hi> thirty dollars and one silver Butter Knife, for the purpose aforesaid, of mending and repairing the same. That he was present and an eye-witness to the delivery to the said Henry Hall and Morris Hall of said articles and heard their pretences and promises; and says<pb/>
<lb/>that in support of their pretended characters as Jewelers &amp; at N<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi> 310 Main Street they exhibited their business cards as such. <hi rend="str">That said Morris &amp; Henry Hall then and there exhibited silver spoons, silver Goblets and silver pitchers and various other and numerous valuable and costly articles which they had obtained from other citizens and residents of said County of Daviss and State of Kentucky in like manner and by such pretences and representations to the amount of some thousands of dollars</hi>. That upon inquiry and investigation he ascertained that there was no such establishment as that represented by said Halls in Louisville at N<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi> 310 Main Street nor at any other place in said city. That he has seen their cards as Jewelers in Lexington, Ky. That all of said pretences and representations are false and were falsely and fraudulently made for the unlawful purpose of defrauding and deceiving the citizens of said Da-<pb/>
<lb/>viss County, Kentucky.</p>
<p>That he came to Cincinnati O. in company with Mr. William S. Stone in search and in pursuit of said Henry Hall and Morris Hall who have fled and escaped from the State of Kentucky into the State of Ohio: and that they now go under the names of Henry Swartz and Morris Swartz which he believes to be their true names. That he is informed and believes that one of said parties has been arrested in Cincinnati and is as, he believes now in said city, and is unable to be removed and returned to the State of Kentucky for trial, where said offence was committed, and where the same is an offence and crime against the Laws of Kentucky, without the requisition of Your Honor as Governor of said State of Kentucky.</p>
<p>S. R. Taylor
<lb/>Clerk U. S. Courts.</p>
<p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me this <date when="1861-03-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of March 1861</date></p>
<p>Jno M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Lean Jr.<pb/></p>
<p>United States of Americ
<lb/>Southern District of Ohio</p>
<p>I John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Lean Jr Clerk of the U. S. Courts for the Seventh Circuit and Southern District of Ohio, hereby certify that the within named William S. Stone and Samuel B. Taylor were duly sworn to the truth of the foregoing affidavits and I do further certify that I am well and personally acquainted with both of said witnesses, and know them to be truthful and reliable persons</p>
<p><figure type="seal"><ab>SEAL OF THE CIRCUIT COURT
<lb/>SOUTHERN DIST. OF OHIO</ab></figure></p>
<p>In testimony where I have hereunto set my hand and affixed the seal of the Circuit Court of the United States for this district this <date when="1861-03-20">twentieth day of March A D 1861</date> and of American Independence the 85th.</p>
<p>Jno M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Lean Jr Clerk</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Franklin County Sct.</p>
<p>William S. Stone this day came personally before this undersigned a Justice of the peace for said County and made oath that the statements contained in the within instrument of writing are just true and correct Witness my hand this <date when="1861-03-21">21 day of March 1861</date></p>
<p>G. W. Gwin J. P.<pb/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Ohio</hi>
<lb/>Demand for Henry &amp; Morris Swartz
<lb/><hi rend="underline">alias</hi>
<lb/>Henry &amp; Morris Hall
<lb/>Felony
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-03-21">Mar 21<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> S. Stone
<lb/>Agent</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
