<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0047"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. Stuarts to Daniel W. Lindsey</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14076</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1864</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Brandenburg, Meade County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-07-06">6 July 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Brandenburg
<lb/><date when="1864-07-06">July 6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date></p>
<p>Dr Sir The object of my letter to the Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> was to ascertain whether a small band of citizens could be organised at public expense to do independent local duty &amp; to be subject to the order of no One but their mean partisan leader Such a troop could be improvised here within a few days but no company could be had of State Guards Our experence has been that as fast as a man gets under the Control of general authority he is needed at Louisville or Lexington as on a Rail Road &amp; that is the last that is seen of him until he is killed or dies or is discharged to come home &amp; ever thereafter busy himself in doging bands of neighbourhood marauders who hold as permanent empire here abouts as that of the state Cabinet at Frankfort. The truth is I <unclear/> not have anything like a state Guard it never did guard anything and never can what could any bodies guard do in this thickett -- da<hi rend="str">mn</hi>unted region -- of course the efficient man must operate in the breaks where he<pb/>
<lb/>was cradled, he is then even handed with the miscreants he is hunting They must also know of themselves those who harbour, the Guerilla, they must know his habits, &amp; connexions in fact must be turned loose as free as the winds to give him war on his own terms, with the privilege to scatter of need be <hi rend="underline">fish berries</hi> to stop them from making Guerillas, The infernal Devils will within a month shoot every loyal man in this region as take him &amp; swear him not to oppose them or devulge upon them It seems to me a Commonwealth is about in its last throws when its citizens may not even utter a syllable of loyalty, without expecting to hear a Gun crack -- No troops can be got for state or Federal service You can enforce no draft for either service who is to serve notices of a draft an collect up the men drafted it cant be done here -- I have to announce that no State Guard can be induced to volunteer here, and they are to poor to arm &amp; equip themselves &amp; loose their time from labour, so as to get up a sure barrier to the public enemy</p>
<p>I shall endeavour still to get<pb/>
<lb/>some one to go in on<hi rend="str">ly</hi> the state Guard plan but from all I see I will have to say that whoever undertakes it must subsist<hi rend="str">s</hi> &amp; provide the arms &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi> <hi rend="str">there</hi>for the men as he gets them up &amp; if he feels in the requisite number, must disband &amp; loose his expense, for the Legislature would not pay the Lords anointed for a new atonement if it were ascertained that the old one had moved out.</p>
<p>o<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">btly</hi></hi> &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi> J. Stuarts</p>
<p>Wont we have fine healthy &amp; loyal elections in August, when all the shffs are Davis men what a time his parasites wil have in getting for him the revenues of the state &amp; then in Nov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> we will pick up the richest squad of Electors as for me I take it our expectancy is a lively hope of a speedy interest in death hell &amp; the Grave.</p>
<p>Stuart</p>
<p>D W Lindsey
<lb/>Inspect. Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Ky.<pb/></p>
<p>Ky State Guard
<lb/>Brandenburg. Meade Co. Ky.
<lb/><date when="1864-07-06">July 6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Stuart. John. <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Says the object of his former communication was merely to enquire if a body of citizens could be armed &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi> at the expense of the State and then a it as an independent scout subect to the orders only of their partisan leader. Given the reasons why their should be such an organization -- urges objections against the State Guards &amp;c<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Ansd page 501 Ltr BK A<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Rec. I. G. O. <date when="1864-07-09">July 9<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
