<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1888"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">S. D. Delany and E. Y. Cowgill to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11356</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Bradley Strait</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG23-305 to MG23-306</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Morganfield, Union County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-05-01">1 May 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Governor of Kentucky, your petitioners S D Delany and E Y Cowgill will state that at the <date when="1860-10">October Term of the Union Circuit Court 1860</date>, a Presentment was made by the Grand Jury of Union County against John B. Talcott, for a Breach of the peace, Upon which a Bench warrant was awared by the Court, requiring said Talcott to give Bail and the sum of three hundred dollars, and your Petitioners became his sureties for that sum for his appearance at the next term of the Union Circuit, Court</p>
<p>And at the <date when="1861-04">April Term 1861</date> of said Court, said Bond was taken as forfeited, no other action since that time, has been had in said case,</p>
<p>That Mrs -- Dolley is set down at the foot of the Indictment, as the only witness, on whose information said Indictment was found, and that she did soon after said Indictment was found, leave this state for parts unknown -- and was a woman of bad fame and reputation -- </p>
<p>That said Talcott was Marshal of the Town of Morganfield at the time said breach of the peace was alledged to be committed<pb/>
<lb/>And had just arrested Thomas Dolley, the keeper of said -- Dolly under a ^2^ charge^s^ of selling spirits to slave^s^, which upon the trial was proven </p>
<p>Under all these circumstances, your Petitioners believing said Talcott an honest and upright man went his Bail Surity -- </p>
<p>Since that time, said Talcott, has joined the Federal Army and is now in that service, Wherefore we ask to be released as Bail for said Talcott</p>
<p>They further say that Mrs -- Dolly was a woman of doubtful character and her whereabouts is now unknown 
<lb/>Morganfield Kentucky <date when="1862-05-01">May 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1862</date></p>
<p>S. D. Delany 
<lb/>E. Y. Cowgill<pb/></p>
<p>The undersigned members of the Bar &amp; Citizens of Union County know Dr Delany &amp; Cowgill and are satisfied that this statement is true &amp; Join in their petition</p>
<p>D H Hughes
<lb/>J. M Bucknan S U C
<lb/>W. Howell D C
<lb/>John S Geiger clk Union
<lb/>Circuit Court
<lb/>Hiram M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Elroy
<lb/>J. A. Spalding
<lb/>Crom<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Adair
<lb/>Sam C Hughes</p>
<p>Govr Magoffin</p>
<p>I was acting as Atty for the Commh by Pro tem Appt at the time the Bond referred to was taken as forfeited -- I think you ought to release Delany &amp; Cowgill from the Bail Bond </p>
<p>I am Your Friend 
<lb/>W G Hughes<pb/></p>
<p>Morganfield Kentucky 
<lb/>Union Circuit Court </p>
<p>I John S. Geiger Clerk of the Union Circuit Court, state that the Punishment for Breach of the peace against John B Talcott, has only the name of Mrs Dolly set down at the foot of the said Punishment and the said Mrs Dolly has left <hi rend="str">the Commonwealth</hi> for parts unknown, and no judgment has been rendered upon the forfeiture of the Bond named written this the <date when="1862-05-03">3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> day of May 1862</date></p>
<p>John J Geiger clk
<lb/>Union Circuit Court</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
