<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0395"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Holeman R. Crow to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4514</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-123 to BR9-124</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-01-26">26 January 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency Thomas E Bramlett
<lb/>Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioners Eli Crow and Holeman R Crow would respectfully state that at the <date when="1859-04">April term 1859</date> of the Mercer Circuit Court Milton Crow a son of petitioner Eli Crow and brother of petitioner Holeman R Crow was indicted in said Court on a charge of forging a promisory note That bail in the sum of $750 was required of said Melton Crow for his appearance at the <date when="1859-11">October term ^1859</date>^ of said Court. That before said Court Came on said Milton Crow moved to the State of Missouri and has never return. That your petitioners luent his bail for his appearance. That in Consequence of said Milton Crows failing to ^appear &amp;^ have his appearance entered at the ^said^ term he was recognized to appear,the <hi rend="str">rego</hi> recognizance on which your petitioners were securities was forfeited and ^and Judgment rendered at the <date when="--04">April term</date> of said Court $60 and at the <date when="1863-10">October term of said Court 1863</date> another Judgment was rendered for $750 &amp; costs on which^ and execution for the above amount &amp; costs issued against your petitioners. That they have paid all the clerks and sheriffs fees and that ^part^ of the amount of the bail bond to which the Commonwealths aty was intited the <unclear/> also paid That said Milton Crow i<unclear/> cripple for life, and unable to do <unclear/> hard labour for a living. That he i<unclear/> still continues to be a poor man a<unclear/> nonresident of Kentucky. That said <unclear/> avowed to your petitioners at the term <hi rend="str">of the <unclear/> on the b</hi><pb/>
<lb/>they signed the bail bond as securities that he was not guilty of the charge That at the time of signing said bail bond said Milton Crow resided in Mercer County and your petitioners resided &amp; still reside in Jessamine County Ky. Your ptitioner Eli Crow is a very old man about seventy years of age. Your petitioner <hi rend="str">further</hi> further states that they did not encourage the said Milton ^Crow^ <hi rend="str">to</hi> move and <hi rend="str">not to</hi> did not directly or indirectly <hi rend="str">abuse</hi> ^advise^ or encourage him not to appear &amp; stand his trial. But upon the contrary your petitioner Eli Crow advised his son Milton to appear in Court and stand his trial. Wherefore in as much as your petitioners are without relief and will have to pay the <hi rend="str">balance</hi> ^said Judgment^ on <hi rend="str">of</hi> said bail bond as sureties unless your excellency enterposes your executive power and <hi rend="str">cleman</hi> clemancy which your petitioner most respectfully ask you to do. <hi rend="str">and remit the amount of the bail bond for which are bound as sureties</hi> and pray that you may remit <hi rend="str">the balance of said the</hi> ^the said two^ Judgments on said recognizance which they are still bound to pay. ^That they did not know anything about the 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Judgment until the Sheriff some two or three months ^ago^ demanded of them to repleny the Judgment ^which was done^ the comths aty part &amp; sheriff &amp; clerks fees was paid on the first Judgment and that Ju <unclear/> ted^</p>
<p>H. R. Crow</p>
<p><unclear/>an R Crow one of the petitioners <unclear/> that the Statements Contained in the <unclear/> petition are true^ </p>
<p>H. R. Crow</p>
<p>sworn to before me by Holeman R Crow this <date when="1864-01-26">26th day of Jany 1864</date></p>
<p>John G. Kyle P. J. H.<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned Unite with the petitioners in requesting the Governor to remit the two Judgments in this petition mentioned</p>
<p>James D Hardin
<lb/>John G. Kyle
<lb/>O S Poston
<lb/>Ben C. Fressnall
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W. A. Hooe</hi>
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Edwards PJMCC
<lb/>Tho C Bell S.M.C
<lb/>Chas A Hardin
<lb/>Jno P Haggin
<lb/>J.L. Smedley
<lb/>E Gabbert
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. W. Varnon
<lb/>R. J. Browne
<lb/>Joshua F Bell<pb/></p>
<p>Mercer Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/><hi rend="str">W. R.</hi> Eli &amp; H R Crow
<lb/>Bail Bond
<lb/><date when="1864-01-27">27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Jany 1864</date></p>
<p>750
<lb/><hi rend="underline">30</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">2.25</hi>.<hi rend="sup">00</hi></p>
<p>
<lb/>Remit all except attys fees and costs of the Judgement rendered at the <date when="1863-10">Oct term 1863</date> and remit $250.<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> of the Judgment rendered <date when="1860-04">April term 1860</date>.</p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette</p>
<p>Eli &amp; H R Crow</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
