<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2632"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John H. Taylor to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7269</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-205 to BR16-206</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To. His Excellency
<lb/>Govenor Bramlett</p>
<p>The undersigned John H Taylor petitions your Excellency for pardon</p>
<p>Nearly two years ago he was Indicted for receiving stolen corn Nearly all the witnesses in the case are now gone, and the charge still remains against him. He is a resident citizen of Ohio, which state he expects to make his home, but has kindred here whom he desires occasionaly to see He is a free man of color, and owing to an unjust prejudice against that class of persons at the time the indictment was found, and yet he was advised that he could not get a fair trial He protests his innocence One or two persons seek to annoy him from personal prejudice The indictment has been filed away, and he is assured would not prosecute him further except for the said one, or two persons.</p>
<p>He refers to a copy of the indictment and order a part of this <hi rend="str">indictment</hi> petition</p>
<p>He was born free and is poor and appeals to your Excellency to grant him a pardon, and he knows that the ends of justice will not be interrupted by it</p>
<p>John H Taylor
<lb/><note place="footer">(over)</note><pb/></p>
<p>Lexington, Ky, <date when="1865-11-02">November 2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi>, 1865</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>Govenor Bramlett</p>
<p>The author of the above petition John H. Taylor is my brother, and like myself is a free man of color. He is now a resident of the state of Ohio, which state he expects to make his home.</p>
<p>His mother, another brother and myself, reside in this city, where we were born, and where I am now in business as keeper of a livery stable He has great desire to visit his aged mother occasionaly, but can not now do so, without risk of prosecution He always had a good character, and had a reputation as an honest, well behaved, and industrious man, which I am sure he would be unwilling to forfeit by participating in, or abetting any theft I was entirely unacquainted with the nature of the transaction, with which he was charged at the time the indictment was found but I have since become convinced that he is entirely innocent, and that the charge was set on foot and has since been agitated by those, who <hi rend="str">f</hi>bear him personal malice, assisted by the prejudice thin and now existing against free men of color</p>
<p>In view of these facts, and moved by a sense of the great injustice of this undeserved prosecution I make bold to join my prayer with his, for pardon and the interposition of executive clemency in his behalf</p>
<p>Wm L Taylor<pb/></p>
<p>Lexington <date when="1865-11-02">Nov 2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1865</date>,</p>
<p>William Taylor a free man of color and a substantive and honest citizen, has this morning by his councel <unclear/> a line to your Excellency from me in regard to the case of his brother John Taylor. I have Known John Taylor for several years by reputation Until the finding of the Indictment he was regarded and respected as an honest man. I never heard a word to the contrary and was astonished at the charge to man of any color has a better reputation than his brother William The indictment has been filed away for over a year John Taylor is a resident of the state of Ohio The other statements of the Petition are substantially true</p>
<p>W. S Downey
<lb/>Com atty
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W W Denden</hi> s. f. C</p>
<p>We recommend the release of John Taylor.</p>
<p>L. Gibbons
<lb/>Jno B Norton Clk
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> A Lindsay<pb/></p>
<p>I know William L Taylor well. He is an upright and clever citizen &amp; has that reputation and his Brother John H who was indicted had a first rate reputation up to that time -- I have inquired into the case &amp; feel perfectly free to say to you that I am sure the ends of Justice would not suffer by his pardon I freely recommend it &amp; think you would be doing right</p>
<p>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> B Huston</p>
<p>Fayett ct ct
<lb/>John H Taylor Cold
<lb/><date when="--11-02">2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Nov</date> Pardon issued</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
