<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2043"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Oliver A. Patton to Richard T. Jacob</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6680</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-219 to BR14-220</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Flemingsburg, Fleming County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-07">7 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Flemingsburg Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-09-07">September 7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>.
<lb/>Hon Richard. T. Jacob.
<lb/>Dear Governor.</p>
<p>I have just prepar<hi rend="str">par</hi>ed statements of my case and handed them to my counsel Judge Alexander and Col D. K. Weis. I have requested letters of credit from my friends Hon J W Stevenson John G. Carlisle &amp; W. E. Arthur of Covington with whom I was associated in the practice of Law during my eighteen months of professional life. as well as life long acquaintances. Hon Bel. J. Peters of Court of Appeals Col Thos Johnson, late of P. C. S. A formerly enjoying the cognosance of "General" (of Mt Sterlling) Dr Duke -- and others. I thought that a few of such men would answer the purpose and annoy your excelency less than by pursuing the usual course of sending elaborate petitions signers &amp; -- -- I regret that my old commander Genl Williams is not permitted to return to the State -- I think that Col Weis whom your Excelency knows to be (what he said of your Excelency) a "sincere gentlmen"</p>
<p>I will not oppress you further with this subject more than to say You have the humble and<pb/>
<lb/>most affectionate sentiments, of his gratitude whom you wish to honor in his sad and unfortunate wretched and humiliating atitude.</p>
<p>If your excelency will permit me to whisper in his ear I will say that it will be a happy relief to one of Kentuckys fairest and noblest daughters who father has been a "woman of strength" (I speak of Miss Kittie B. Todd), if I am saved from this humiliation -- </p>
<p>I have just written a long letter to my sister in which I communicated your kind message. (that you "will write immediately") They will rejoice to hear from you -- And when you are weaned of duties and toils and wish to visit the southland feel assured that nowhere will you be more welcomed than at the beautifull tho' unostentatious village of Lenoir N.C. Where you will see a blending of all natures beauties, ridiculous as well as subllime. However you will be surprised to see the talent and cultivation, to be found among the old Scotch-irish residents. -- not withstanding its near proximity to "Buncomb Co" -- </p>
<p>It is the scene of my friend Col. Thos. L. Jones childhood to which he<pb/>
<lb/>often loves to refer. It is often sought as a summer resort for invalids it is immediately adjacent to the beautifull "valley of the Yadkin"</p>
<p>I hope I may have the honor of meeting you there sometime. Pa will perhaps move to some more southern city as soon as sisters have completed their education at the town of Lenoir presenting the finest facilities having one of the finest female colleges.</p>
<p>I hope you have entirely recovered from your recent indisposition I would be happy to hear from you very soon when convenient -- </p>
<p>Your very Humble and obedient servant and grateful friend
<lb/>Oliver A. Patton</p>
<p>My health is growing quite feeble -- from so close confinement as I am undergoing. and it succeeding the active life of a cavalry man -- </p>
<p>Patton.</p>
<p>I have forwarded this <hi rend="str">papers</hi> statement to Frankfort. I hope you will not regard me imprudent &amp; presumptions in emploring your immediate attention to the matter. Patton.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
