<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2877"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Leon L. Moore to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7514</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-181 to BR17-182</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Gov Bramlette</p>
<p>Your petition states that on the <gap/> day of <date when="1865-12">December 1865</date> he loaned W. H. Turner; a free negro, (the barber) a double barrel shot gun to hunt with -- Petitioner did not lend it to him for any unlawful purpose, nor has said negro boy used it for any improper use -- He asked petitioner to lend it to him to hunt, and petitioner did it because had been kind, obliging &amp; polite to him, and is well-behaved negro</p>
<p>Petitioner states that before said negro had returned said gun to petitioner<pb/>
<lb/>it was seized by <hi rend="str">one of</hi> David Kirkpatrick one of the night watchmen of the city of Frankfort under 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sec -- art 4 chap 93 of Revised Statutes (<hi rend="underline">Vol</hi> <hi rend="underline">2</hi> <hi rend="underline">page</hi> <hi rend="underline">368</hi>) for forfeiture &amp; he claims said gun as his -- </p>
<p>Petitioner says that unless your Excellency interferes said gun may be forfeited, &amp; <hi rend="underline">vested in</hi> <hi rend="underline">said</hi> <hi rend="underline">Kirkpatrick</hi>, and it <hi rend="str">will</hi> may then be too late for the interference of your Excellency. -- </p>
<p>Your petitioner asks that said forfeiture be released to said Turner or to your petitioner so that he can get his gun. He<pb/>
<lb/>does not suppose that this case is within the meaning and spirit of the law -- If it is, he asks inteference by the Governor for there has been no purpose to violate the law. Petitioner did not when he loaned said gun to said negro for the purpose simply of hunting that he was violating any law of the State.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Leon L. Moore</hi><pb/></p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Turner</p>
<p>The case will be acted on to-morrow, (<date when="1866-01-04">Jan 4 1866</date>) which accounts for the seeming hurry.</p>
<p>having &amp; carry a gun</p>
<p>Remit &amp; once &amp; send to me for Signature</p>
<p>T. E B
<lb/> 
<lb/><date when="1865-01-03">3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Jany/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
