<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2521"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Leonard C. Anderson and William W. Jennings to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7158</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-33 to BR16-34</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-10-31">31 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To the Hon Thomas E Bramlette Governor of Ky</p>
<p>Your petitioners Leneord C Anderson and William Jennings both citizens of Mason County Ky. respectfully represent that for nearly a year past they have been <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>carrying on business in partnership in said county, and were all the time regularly <hi rend="underline">licensed</hi> "<hi rend="underline">coffee</hi> house" keepers -- At the last <date when="--10">October</date> term of the Mason Circuit Court they were indicted by the "<hi rend="underline">Grand</hi> <hi rend="underline">Jury</hi>" for selling liquor to three "<hi rend="underline">minors</hi>", and on learning the fact they appeared before the Circuit Court at the same term, and plead <hi rend="underline">guilty</hi>, and a fine was assessed against each of your petioners of $50 -- and the costs -- They now respectfully ask your Excellency to remit said fine for the following reasons, To wit</p>
<p>Said <hi rend="underline">Minors</hi> for whome your petitioners were indicted for selling liquor to were all young men near their majority, and in appearance seemed to be really young men of <hi rend="underline">full age</hi>, and as the parents of these young men had given a general <hi rend="underline">verbal</hi> permission to all the <hi rend="underline">bar</hi> <hi rend="underline">keepers</hi> of the neighbourhood to sell their sons liquor when called for by them -- Your petitioners thought they were doing ^no^ wrong in this case, and in fact only committed the error of omitting to require of each of the young men a <hi rend="underline">written</hi> order from their parents as the <hi rend="underline">strict letter</hi> of the law requires -- We hope your Excellency will see that we did not designedly break the laws, and that our only wrong was in taking a <hi rend="underline">verbal</hi> permission to sell liquor to these young men, and<pb/>
<lb/>we therefore most respectfully ask your Excellency to relieve us by <hi rend="underline">remitting</hi> said fines as far as you have the power to do so</p>
<p><date when="1865-10-31">Oct 31 1865</date></p>
<p>Leonard C. Anderson
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Jennings</p>
<p>The undersigned Citizens of Mason Count Ky would respectfully state that they are neighbors of the above named petitioners -- that they believe the statements in the foregoing petition are substantially true and they unite with said petioners in their prayer for a remission of the above named fines</p>
<p><date when="1865-10-31">Oct 31 1865</date></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Arthur F. Dobyns J. P. M. C
<lb/>Richard C Terhune
<lb/>William J Adams
<lb/>John. B. Voll
<lb/>P J Anderson
<lb/>J W Masterson
<lb/>Leonard Bullock
<lb/>Ephraim Burton
<lb/>F. C. Mitchell
<lb/>Thos A Curran
<lb/>E. Q. Ross
<lb/>John F Tabb
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H Anderson
<lb/>Daniel Peck
<lb/>R, L, Soward
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> C Rise
<lb/>Jno. A. <unclear/>
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Jasper Creekburn
<lb/>A Rajers
<lb/>C M Jennings
<lb/>M Smith
<lb/>R, M, Owens
<lb/>John W Brock
<lb/>W B Crupper
<lb/>A, D, Veach
<lb/>James Highland
<lb/>John Anderson
<lb/>Willis D, Lee
<lb/>P N Jennings<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Mason Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Jennings &amp; L. C Anderson
<lb/>$50, each
<lb/>Selling to Minors
<lb/>Remit
<lb/><date when="1865-11-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
