<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2882"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. A. Duncan to Ephraim L. Van Winkle</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7519</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-189 to BR17-190</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Owenton, Owen County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-28">28 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Owenton Ky <date when="1865-12-28">Decr 28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>E L Vanwinkle Esqr
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>I presume -- on our former acquaintance formed in 1855 while we were both members of the Ky Legislature to ask a favor of you -- </p>
<p>You will find herewith a petition to the Governor for the remission of a Judgment in favor of the Commonwealth vs T A Berryman and Myself -- the petition explains the record -- </p>
<p>The facts outside are these -- N G Walter was jointly indicted with one Lyter for horse stealing. the offence was Charged to have been committed in the fall of <date when="1862">1862</date> while Kirby Smith's troops were occupying this part of the State -- Walter and Lyter were both Union Men and had to flee from their homes as many others of us had to do -- they both left the County on the same night and myself &amp; many others did so too &amp; went to Indiana -- they Both Came to court ready for trial without any arrest plff was not ready -- &amp; causes Continued -- we believed Walter innocent and as he was a poor man with a large family<pb/>
<lb/>which was bound to suffer without his labor we went on his Bail Bond. Owing to the troubles of the County here he removed to Indiana at the next term of the Court he was not able to get here until the Second day of the term in the mean time the recognizance had been forfeited &amp; the cause continued -- Since that I heard from at intervals until the last 12 months since which I can hear nothing from him &amp; think he must be dead -- </p>
<p>From the proof on the trial of Lyter for stealing the same horse the proof showed conclusively that Walter had nothing to do with the horse. and even then Lyter was not convicted -- </p>
<p>It will be a very great hardship on us to have this Money to pay we have both lost heavily by the war in various ways having been compelled to remain away from home <hi rend="str">dur</hi>Considerable time during th Rebel occupation of this Country, loosing many debts and a large number of negroes -- &amp;c<pb/>
<lb/>Although our acquaintance was not intimate yet I trust your Kindness to hand this petition to the Governor with a favorable recommendation that its prayer be granted -- By so doing you will Confer a great favor which will reciprocated with interest whenever opportunity offers.</p>
<p>Enclosed please find $2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> your fee I believe in such Cases -- </p>
<p>Very truly Yours
<lb/>J A Duncan</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
