<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0234"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Andrew Straus, Brief</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4353</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-364</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Jefferson Circuit Court
<lb/>Commonwealth Ky Plff
<lb/>vs } Brief for Straus before the Governor
<lb/>Andrew Straus Deft</p>
<p>I would suggest to your Excellency, that this is a case pending in the Jefferson Circuit Court of The Commonwealth vs Andrew Straus- a Scirefacias on an old bail-bond given in <date when="1855">1855</date>, as Surety for one Charles Wicke. The facts are Stated in Straus' petition, &amp; the letter of W. A. Ronald, Sheriff.</p>
<p>There is no Judgmt yet against Straus. The summons was not Served in time for the <date when="--10">Oct term</date> of our court. And I think it is a case where the the remiting power can be Judicially and properly exercised to to prevent a Judgement.</p>
<p>For your power to remit the whole of it I refer you to "Article 3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Section 10 of "The New Consitution Ky." Stanton's Rev. Statutes page 129 of 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> vol.</p>
<p>And also the case of Commonwealth vs Morgan 14. B Monroe 392. And the Commonwealth vs Spraggins. 18. B. Monroe 513.</p>
<p>I would not be understood as desiring<pb/>
<lb/>to deprive the officers of the Circuit Court of their legitimate fees, nor the Commonwealth's atty. But this is a case wherein the ^present^ States attorny has had no trouble; nor would he ever have Set this prosecution on foot, if it had not been for this man Fehrrenback. It appears to me that this is a case where excutive interposition is demanded. The Commonwealth Should not be made the instrument through and by which to grati the personal Spite of one <hi rend="str">individual</hi> ^citizen^ toward another=; and especially where no public good can result from it, as in this case. The Judgmt against F. is about all Straus is worth; and if he is made to pay the $800 recognizance it will ruin him</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>L. A. Wood</p>
<p>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Straus, 3</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
