<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2420"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. A. Bogard et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7057</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-360 to BR15-361</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Trigg County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-18">18 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Trigg County</p>
<p>The under<hi rend="str">stood</hi>signed state that Lofton Mitchell of this county has been indicted by a Grand Jury of this county for Robbery. We Know Mitchell to have been an ardent and active Union Man from the beginning of the war, and in the Fall of <date when="1862">1862</date> he enlisted in the 8 Regt of Ky Cavalry then forming at Henderson Ky to which place he went as a refugee and for the purpose of enlisting in said service and served through the term of said Regt and was honorably discharged after having made a gallant and active and enterprising soldier. That after the Regt was mustered out of service, he and a number of his neighbors united for the purpose of protection from Guerilla Bands prowling about and who were particularly vindictive and cruel towards all who had been in the Federal service. While thus engaged a Rebel Col. or Major named Bob Martin made ^a raid^ into the Counties of Trigg, Christian, Muhlenburg and Caldwell counties, and were pursued by the forces of the 3rd Ky Cavalry, Col Murray and driven again across Cumberland river and on their retreat encamped between Cumberland and Tennessee on his return loaded with booty. These Home guards got together and prominent among those were Lofton Mitchell pursued Martin and attacked him in Camp and routed him and <unclear/> near all his booty arms &amp;c<pb/>
<lb/>They returned the horses taken from neighbours and turned over the other possessions to Col C. H. Murray at Hopkinsville. These men performed diverse other services to union cause which must not be mentioned. in all of which Mitchell was at all times an active cooperater. In <date when="1864">1864</date> these men under Capt <unclear/> were organized as State or Capital Guards in Company (B) 3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> Battalion of Capital Guards for six months and served his Term and was honorably discharged on the <date when="1865-02-12">12 Feby 1865</date> by the expiration of the Term at Paducah, by Major M. A Parin commanding their Reg<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi>. While in this service Capt Henry E. Luton <unclear/> orders from Parin his Major to go to Canton &amp; Linton on Cumberland River in this county with orders to press horses of Disloyal men to Mount the Regt. Genl Paine then Comma<hi rend="str">d</hi>nding at paducah gave them Steam Boat transportation for this trip and under Capt Lutan Lofton Mitchell was acting as an <hi rend="str">private</hi> ^orderly sergeant^ and acting under the orders of his captain the horse of E. Degraffenried <hi rend="str">was</hi> a rebel ^was pressed^ which horse was assigned to Lofton Mitchell to ride while in the service last aforesaid. Now at the present Term of the Trigg circuit court, the Grand Jury composed almost wholly of rebels have indicted said Michell for Robbery in taking and riding the horse under the above circumstances. We know the petit Juries to be composed nearly altogether of Rebels and Believe if the case comes to trial they will if permitted by the court find him guilty.</p>
<p>We know there is in the minds of most<pb/>
<lb/>Rebels and Rebel Sympathizers a deep hostility towards all active union men and more especially toward those who lent their services to their country as soldiers to put down the Rebellion. There is a great disposition to oppress and persecute them. We hope you will at once give him a full and free pardon and we will every pray &amp;c</p>
<p>W. A. Bogard formerly of the 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky. Cav
<lb/>G H Mitchersson of 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Cavalry
<lb/>John Martin of 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky cavalry</p>
<p>The foregoing was subscribed and sworn to by W A Bogard G W Mitchersson and Jno Martin before me this <date when="1865-09-18">18<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of Sept 1865</date></p>
<p>J W Nunn J. P. T. C</p>
<p>W. A. Bogard 2d Lieut of Capital Guard
<lb/>W W Higgins of Capital guard
<lb/>Thomas W. Rhoades of Ky capital guard
<lb/>F M Higgins of Capitol Guard
<lb/>J C Lane Seargeant C<hi rend="sup">o</hi> B Capital Guard
<lb/>John Martin Seargant C<hi rend="sup">o</hi> B Capital Guard</p>
<p>The foregoing statement was subscribed and sworn to by M M Higgins Thos M Rhoads F M Higgins and J C Lane before me Given under my hand this <date when="1865-09-19">19. Sept 1865</date></p>
<p>J. W, Nunn J. P. T. C<pb/></p>
<p>Trigg Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Lofton Mitchell
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Bogard
<lb/>Futrell Foard</p>
<p>Pardon the offense and remit the penalties thereto affixed by law</p>
<p>T E Bramlette
<lb/><date when="1865-10-20">Oct 20<hi rend="sup">th </hi>/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
