<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1443"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Allen Wilhoit, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10911</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-3 to MG22-4</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Boone County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-09-10">10 September 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Examination of Allen Wilhoit Made at his house, Boone County Ky <date when="1861-09-10">Sept 10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>Question 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Did you examine James Landrum, at your house, on the morning of the <date when="1858-01-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Jan 1858,</date> and take from his pocket book Eighteen dollars &amp; 40 cents,</p>
<p>Answer He was searched here, but I do not remember the day and the moth, about that amount was taken from his pocket book</p>
<p>Question 2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> The said <hi rend="str">sak</hi> Sasher swore on the <date when="1858-02-21">21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> day of Feb of the same year</date> in his complaint before a Justice of the peace in Boone County that said Landrum, had stolen and Carried away from your house the above named amount, now did you not, on the morning of the <date when="1858-01-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Jan</date> above named give up to said Sasher the Eighteen dollars &amp; forty cents, which you took from Landrum, in presence of Landrum &amp; others</p>
<p>Answer
<lb/>I think that Landrum gave the money up to Sasher &amp; <hi rend="str">go out</hi> and told me to go out to Sasher &amp; compromise the matter with him, by giving him up part of the money and if he would not do that, to give him all</p>
<p>3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> Question At the examination held before the Justices did you not hear Sasher Swear, that<pb/>
<lb/>on the day of the night <hi rend="str">He said Sasher</hi> in which he alledged that he was robbed by said Landrum he the said Sasher left Covington, and had on his person but $300 or $3,25, and if <unclear>so</unclear> did not Sasher make the statement under oath, did we not hear the Counsel in the pleadings make this statement, as having <hi rend="str">as</hi> <hi rend="str">has</hi> been sworn to <hi rend="str">before</hi> by the said Sasher, without denial or objection, on the part of Sasher or his Counsel and if you did hear this, how could you subsequently go before the Grand jury, and aid in procuring and indictment against said Landrum for stealing $18.40 from a man who admitted under oath that he had in his possession but $300 or $3,40</p>
<p>Answer, I was not present at the time or in the room at the time that Sasher gave his evidence, but I heard Sasher say the amt and kind of money he had lost, at at the examination of Landrum that Amount was found, and in the kind of money that Sasher claimed to have lost </p>
<p>4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Question
<lb/>Are you not a strong personal <hi rend="str">eney</hi> enemy of Grubbs; and have you some very Slanderous &amp; villainous charge against his character in the presence of Moses Rice, Kennett &amp; others?<pb/></p>
<p><note place="left margin">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Question.</note> Are you not an avowed personal enemy of the said Grubb's? Ans, I am no <hi rend="str">enymy</hi> enemy to him, I am no enemy to any one.</p>
<p><note place="left margin">7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ques.</note> Did you see anyone, and if so who<hi rend="str">m</hi> give to Sasher, on the morning of the search the $18.40</p>
<p>Ans, No I did not see any one give him the money</p>
<p>Lucinda Willhoit</p>
<p>Mr. Haggerty</p>
<p>Dr Sir: Please see to it that at the examination Mrs &amp; Mr Wilhoit be not present at <unclear/> other examinations as this is not a civil case</p>
<p>Yours Wm Grubbs</p>
<p>This may certify that I Albert Stephens a justice of the peace for Boone County had the foregoing questions propounded to the above subscribed Lucinda Wilhoit, after having swore her to answer twenty such questions as might be propounded to her, and her answers were reduced to writing in my presence and signed by her as witness my hand this <date when="1861-09-10">10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of September 1861</date></p>
<p>Albert Stephens J P B C<pb/></p>
<p>Examination of Mrs. Wilhoit</p>
<p><note place="left margin">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Question</note> Did James Landrum give you his pocket-book on the morning of the <date when="1858-01-09">9<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> of January 1858,</date> which it is alleged contained the money that the said Landrum was accused of stealing from William Sasher on the preceeding night? Ans He never gave it me</p>
<p><note place="left margin">2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> Question</note> Did the said Landrum on handing you the pocket-book request you to give the money alleged to have been stolen to the said Sasher and to say to him that he the said Landrum took it when he was drunk and did not know at the time what he was doing? I never heard that said</p>
<p><note place="left margin">3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> Question</note> Were not <hi rend="str">some</hi> <hi rend="str">such</hi> <hi rend="str">declaration</hi> <hi rend="str">as</hi> th<hi rend="str">oe</hi>se <hi rend="str">made</hi> <hi rend="str">by</hi> <hi rend="str">you</hi> <hi rend="str">to</hi> <hi rend="str">lawyers</hi> <hi rend="str">Armstrong</hi> <hi rend="str">or</hi> <hi rend="str">Rankins</hi></p>
<p><note place="left margin">4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Question</note> Were not some such declarations at the above made by you, and were they not made for the purpose of having them reported to the accused Lundrum with the intent to intimidate him, and drive him off, hereby causing him to forfeit his bail, and for the express purpose of compelling his surities to suffer? Ans, No.</p>
<p><note place="left margin">5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Question.</note> Did you never express to some of your female neighbors the wish that the accused Landrum would run off, so that his surety Grubbs would have his bail to pay as he was the only responsible one of said Landrum's Surities? Ans I do not recollect that I ever expressed any wish about it</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
