<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0984"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas B. McIntire to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10452</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-43</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Brownsville, Edmonson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-04-05">5 April 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Brownsville Ky <date when="1861-04-05">April 5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861</date><hi rend="str">
<lb/>Hon</hi> To His Excelency Beriah Magoffin Esqr
<lb/>Dear sir</p>
<p>Enclose please find 2 Petition on of Joseph Lewis sr &amp; one of Green Gilbert asking your honor to remit a fine the Petitions both state facts Mr Lewis is not a man that is in the Habit of Gambling and the Proof in the cause was that he bet but Ten cents and that he was Drunk when he bet that the case of Gilbert he is but a Boy and very Poore and <hi rend="str">Since</hi> and will not be abel to pay the fine or any<pb/>
<lb/>part theirof and I think from the Proof in the cause that he did not Know that he was violating the Law at the Time I am the Clerk of the circuit Court and heard Both Trials and am of the opinion that they are Both Case that Demands Executive interposition tho a general thing I am, not in faver of Remitting fines</p>
<p>yours Respectfully
<lb/>Thos B M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Intire</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
