<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0847"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James T. Goalder to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10315</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-331 to MG19-332</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Greensburg, Green County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-03-01">1 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Greensburg Ky,
<lb/><date when="1861-03-01">March 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Governour</p>
<p>I herewith inclose the petition of James B. Moore from which you will see that he has been "eating potatoes" and the dogs are after him, he is one of "<hi rend="underline">our</hi> <hi rend="underline">hogs</hi>", I remember that you said on the next morning after you and Bell addressed the people of Cumberland County at Burskville and after you had spent quite a sleepless night in consequence of the boisterious &amp; riotous conduct of myself &amp; Judge Bramlette and two of your very particular friends, Jo Ryan &amp; Jim Franklin who were our right bowers in every thing but politicks, "that if any man who staid in our room that night got into a<pb/>
<lb/>difficulty he might work out his own Salvation if you should be Governour for you would do nothing for him," but I knew you did not say it with malice, and when I explained to you that they were your best friends and that we could not take the liberty to restrain them, you said "If they are our hogs all right" Now this is one of "our hogs" he is the son of Maj. R. L. Moore who I have no doubt is favourably known to Your Excellency</p>
<p>I know the facts in his petition are true, his was never a tippling house, and he never intended to violate the law, he thought when he obtained coffee house that the authorities who granted them, required him to pay all that the law required<pb/>
<lb/>and as soon as he was informed there was a state tax to pay, he paid it, but I knew that his coffee house license was no legal protection till the state tax was paid and as he had sold a few weeks under said license before he paid the state tax I knew that he could not successfully defend the prosecution and advised him to let Judgement go by default and apply to Your Excellency for relief believing the case called for executive clemency, and I hope your Excellency will so regard it and remit the fine</p>
<p>Respectfully Yrs
<lb/>James T. Goalder</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
