<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0695"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. Lindsay et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10163</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-48 to MG19-49</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency B Magoffin Governor of Kentucky=</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Hickman County would most respectfully represent to your Excellency that at the <date when="1860-05">May Term 1860</date> of the Hickman Equity &amp; Criminal Court S A Clark was indicted for malicious Stabbing, a change of venue was granted him to the Fulton Equity &amp; Criminal Court, and the executed bond in the sum of One Thousand dollars to appear at the <date when="1860-11">November Term 1860</date> of said court with J J Clark as his surety= Said S A Clark ^who is a man of no property at all^ failed to appear at said Term of said court and said bond was taken for forfeiture. Between the said Terms his surety J J Clark deserted his wife and taking another woman fled from this state and has not been back since, he left a small amount of property. And also a wife and three small children= His wife now has a suit pending in the Hickman Equity &amp; Criminal Court praying a decree of divorce and alimony= We would further represent that if said bond is collected out of the property of said J J Clark. That it will exhaust the whole of same, and there will be nothing left to give his said wife by way of alimony= and The consequence will be that his said wife and children will be left in destitute cirsumstances. His said children are very young, are uneducated, and unable to earn a livelihood, and The payment of said bond will affect Them and Their mother alone<pb/>
<lb/>In view of these facts, we think this case presents strong grounds for executive clemency, and we respectfully ask your excellency to remit said bond, and thereby save a helpless family from absolute want=</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W Lindsay
<lb/>T. R. Jordan
<lb/>S. W. Rennick
<lb/>Thad S Dodge
<lb/>John M Stoner
<lb/>J D Hays
<lb/>R. W. Walker
<lb/>J. E. Ashley
<lb/>H O <unclear>carle</unclear>
<lb/>L J Hume Jr
<lb/>E R Ray
<lb/>W F Boon
<lb/>D A Outlaw
<lb/>G W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Rennick
<lb/>S W Glayden</p>
<p>Ed Crosslane asks in the name of children worse than orphans that the above pryer be granted</p>
<p><cb n="2"/>Thomas G Poore Clerk
<lb/>Hickman Equity &amp; Crimal Court
<lb/>C. D. Davis
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Hales
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> M Kemp
<lb/>F M Roy
<lb/>John M Johnson
<lb/>A. J. Burton
<lb/>R H Emerson
<lb/>G. W. Jordan
<lb/>W. A. Jordan
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Smallhouse</p>
<p>W. R. Branley, Justice demands that the prayer of the petition be granted</p>
<p>J Cook
<lb/>A J M Caldwell<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Fulton E &amp; C Ct
<lb/>Respite 12 mos
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>$1000.} Forfeited Recog
<lb/>J. J. Clarke
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-02-15">Feby 15.<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>To Governor Magoffin</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
