<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1379"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. F. Baird et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6016</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-136 to BR12-137</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-12-08">8 December 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thomas E. Bramlette Governor of the Commth -- of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>Your Excellency will be informed by this Petition that John G. Beck was indicted at the now pending Term of the Jefferson Circuit court on a charge of Larceny -- He was charged with ^having^ stolen a sett of Buggy Harness of <hi rend="underline">very</hi> <hi rend="underline">small</hi> value -- the fact was he bought the the harness of a stranger and had no witness to prove the transaction. He was found <hi rend="underline">in</hi> <hi rend="underline">possession</hi> and was unable to account for it -- It was on the whole a very meager case -- the Jury fixed his Term in the State's Prison at one year and to use their own language "earnestly recommend" him for Executive pardon -- We hope your Excellency will immediately pardon him -- He has an amiable and excellent wife, and babe six weeks old, and has served in the war for the Union <hi rend="underline">three</hi> <hi rend="underline">years</hi> <hi rend="underline">and</hi> <hi rend="underline">a</hi> <hi rend="underline">half</hi> -- He proved former good character by many witnesses and is ^in^ our<pb/>
<lb/>humble estimation an innocent man -- We hope your Excellency will send his pardon to the care of his attorneys before the Sheriff of the County start to Frankfort with the prisoners Convicted -- We refer your Excellency to the subjoined recommendations and pray his release -- </p>
<p>R. F. Baird
<lb/>J. H. Price
<lb/>F G Dannecker } Attos -- 
<lb/>	
<lb/>I earnestly recommend John Beck to your Excellency's clemency.</p>
<p>Martin Bijur
<lb/>Atty for Commonw<hi rend="sup">th</hi>
<lb/>pro tem</p>
<p>I think the case one for Executive Clemency.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">P. B. Muir</hi>
<lb/>Leo Chambers DC<pb/></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Jefferson Circuit Court
<lb/><cb n="2"/><date when="1864-10">October Term 1864</date>
<lb/><date when="1864-12-08">December 8 1864</date><milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>Commonwealth Plff
<lb/>v  Indictment for felony
<lb/>John G Beck Deft</p>
<p>We of the Jury find the defendant guilty and ^say^ that he shall be confined in the penetentiary one year; but earnestly recommend him to the clemency of the Governor</p>
<p>W Ross foreman</p>
<p>A copy attest
<lb/>James P Chambers c
<lb/>by Lee Chambers D C<pb/></p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John G Beck
<lb/>Pardoned
<lb/><date when="1864-12-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Dec/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
