<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1165"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. D. Gilliss to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5802</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-291</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Whitley Court House, Whitley County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-08-25">25 August 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Whitley Court House
<lb/>Whitley County Ky.
<lb/><date when="1864-08-25">August 25<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864,</date>
<lb/>His Excellency.
<lb/>Thomas E. Bramlette
<lb/>Govenor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner J. D. -- Gilliss would respectfully ^represent^ to your Excellency that in the Whitley Circuit Court at its <date when="1864-03">March Term 1864,</date> he was indicted and at the present <date when="1864-08">August Term</date> of said court he was fined ^$20.00 (twenty Dollars^ upon said indictment for Tipling -- or selling Liquor without being sworn as required by a late act of the Legislature.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner states that at the request of a friend the owner of a Grocery. he (your Petitioner) went into the Grocery to aid the Clerk in keeping order &amp;c. -- that he was engaged in the Grocery but little more than one day, that he had no interest in the Grocery. that he was not sworn and consequently was indicted and fined.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner states that he did not know of any Law making it necessary for him to be Sworn; and as he did not intend to violate any Law. and as he is not well able to pay -- even so small a fine as $20,00. -- he asks your Excellency to remit the fine.</p>
<p>J. D, Gilliss</p>
<p>Gov. Bramlette the above is a law abiding citizen &amp; I have no doubt that he innocently violated the law think his fine ought to be remitted &amp; hope your Excellency will remit the same</p>
<p>H F Finley<pb/></p>
<p>Whitley Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>J D Gilliss
<lb/>$20 -- 
<lb/>Remit
<lb/>Tipling
<lb/><date when="1864-09-09">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sept/64</date><pb/></p>
<p>Gov Bramblet</p>
<p>I hope that you will remit this fine I know that it ought to be remited</p>
<p>Granville Pearl</p>
<p>and So do I.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">W. H. Randall</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
