<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1156"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Ruth Ingles et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5793</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-274 to BR11-275</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-08-09">9 August 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency,
<lb/>Thomas E. Bramlette,
<lb/>Govenor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner, Ruth Ingles, would most respectfully represent that at the present <date when="1864-08">August term</date> of the Fayette Circuit Court she was fined in the sum of Sixty Dollars upon an indictment for "keeping a tippling House" -- She would represent that the folowing are the facts in the case. Her husband was, previous to his death, the keeper and proprietor of a grocery in the city of Lexington, Ky. and being poor she, to save the expense of a clerk in the same, herself sold provisions &amp;c., therein that he had for sale liquors, whiskey, &amp;c., and sometimes sold the same and she by his direction did the same; that on the <date when="1864-11-04">4 day of Nov. 1864,</date> her husband died leaving her the grocery in charge but that so soon as she came to the same in her own right she did not sell, but positively refused to carry on this illicit business; That even though she sold during his life time and by his direction as charged she is responsible in the eyes of the law (as she is informed) but she avers that even at the time she sold<pb/>
<lb/>as charged that she was aware of committing any offense against the law -- She would further represent that she is a widow and is <hi rend="underline">wholly</hi> dependent upon her own efforts for support -- </p>
<p>In consideration of the premises your petitioner most respectfully ask a remission of said judgment except costs and fees as she believes it will be according to justice &amp; true right upon the facts &amp; she will ever pray &amp;c -- </p>
<p>Ruth Ingles says that the facts set out above are true -- </p>
<p>Ruth ^her X mark^ Ingles
<lb/>att <hi rend="underline">Speed. S. Goodloe</hi></p>
<p><note place="left margin">James Jeffries says that the facts stated within are true to the best of his knowledge &amp; belief -- </note></p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Jas. Jeffries and Ruth Ingles this <date when="1864-08-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of August 1864.</date></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Speed S. Goodloe</hi>
<lb/>J. L. C. C</p>
<p>We the undersigned would recommend the within to Executive clemency -- </p>
<p>Jas. C. Morris -- 
<lb/>Hunter &amp; Bruce
<lb/>John. S. Miller
<lb/>lewis Ramsey
<lb/>H D Hulett
<lb/>Simon Hopper
<lb/>Matson Goins
<lb/>Thomas White
<lb/>Thomas Adems
<lb/>W T Scott
<lb/>T. M. Bell
<lb/>Scott Dudley
<lb/>L C Goins</p>
<p>I am informed by a respectable gentleman, a <hi rend="underline">member of the Bar</hi> that the facts in the petition are true as he believes, and by another gentleman, that Mrs Ingles is poor and ignorant but honest, and did not know that she was violating the Law. If possible a remittance will gratify</p>
<p>your obt Servant
<lb/>W. S Downey<pb/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Thade B Glover</hi>
<lb/>R Cox
<lb/>H. T. Duncan
<lb/>G. W. Graves
<lb/>John Holland<pb/></p>
<p>Fayette Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Ruth Ingles
<lb/>$60
<lb/>Tipling
<lb/>Remit
<lb/><date when="1864-09-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sept/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
