<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-022-0039"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John L. Helm to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11964</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>37th - 76th Regiments Enrolled Militia Primary Source Documents (1861-1866)</collection>
      <idno>Box 80, Folder 861 HARDIN COUNTY Recruiting &amp; Raising Company 49th Rgt. Ky. Militia</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-08-30">30 August 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><date when="1864-08-30">August 30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Govr Bramlett</p>
<p>I write you at the request of a number of our most respectable Citizens without destruction of party M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> M Gore proposes to raise an independent Company for the avowed object of clearing our Country of Guerillas</p>
<p>There are those in this community who know the men gathering around him who believe they have a practical motive widely deferent from the avowed object, and Some of their acts are confirmatory of that Supicion. If their conduct was represented to you as it has been to me, you would not hesitate to refuse organization to such a body of men. I am not a Sufferer and therefore make my personal Complaint, but many do complain &amp; bitterly complain of their course of Conduct</p>
<p>I refer you to Capt<hi rend="sup">n</hi> Burke provo marshall of this place Isaac Radly the Collector of Revinue, John Stuart assessor of revenue, Sam<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Haycraft Clerk of the circuit Court D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Denton Geoghegan local Surgen of Federal army at E Town. James Hill present Sheriff all good Union men and many others that might be named. I refer you to these men, that you may derive such information aS will satisfy you as to the propriety of the organization of the Company. It is desired that any action be suspended till you are advised I would have no hesitation in giving you my opinion but prefer your receiving it from the Source I mention.</p>
<p>We are aware of the danger that all men who are men of property subject themselves to by <hi rend="str">th</hi> thwarting Such men in their views, I ask therefore that the communication be a secert between you and I. And if you shall write to the men I named that the Secrecy.. Consistent with the publick safety be observed.</p>
<p>I see Hardin County is placed on the list to fill her quota of the coming draft at Something over one thousand and Credited by some 400 leaving near Six hundred to be drafted I think there is a great error in that number <hi rend="str">and when credited it is Stated there</hi> I am Satisfied near 300 negroes have been enlisted from Hardin County. I am told a credit of some 41 is all that <hi rend="str">is</hi> ^has been^ allowed. How shall this matter be remidied My judgment is; a draft in K at this time would furnish the South more white men than it will furnish the North. <hi rend="str">And</hi></p>
<p>Yours truly
<lb/>John L Helm<pb/></p>
<p>Head. Qrs. Ky. State Guard.
<lb/>Hardin Co. <date when="1864-08-30">Aug 30<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Helm, John L.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Requests that the authority given M. Gore to raise a Company, be revoked. From the character of the man, and of the men he is gathering around him, he believes his objects are widely different from those expressed.</p>
<p>Refers to divers Federal and State officers in E. Town as to the character of this man. Desires that this letter, and also any that may be written to or rec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> from the parties refused to be regarded as private &amp; confidintial -- <figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Answered <date when="1864-09-01">Sept<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 1. 1864</date>
<lb/>on letter book B. P. 58<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>R. I. G. O. <date when="1864-09-01">Septr 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
