<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0049"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James F. Robinson to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14078</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1864</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Georgetown, Scott County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-08-08">8 August 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Georgetown <date when="1864-08-08">8 August 1864</date>
<lb/>Gov. Thos E. Bramlette</p>
<p>Dear Sir -- The continuance and increase of the guerillas in the hills in this northern part of Scott and adjoining counties render this place in deadly danger.</p>
<p>They have arranged several times to make a raid upon us but were prevented by the presence of troops sent for the purpose</p>
<p>Under an order by Genl. Burbridge we have offered and enrolled all the citizens of the town to be drilled armed and just in readiness for the defence.</p>
<p>We are without arms &amp; were directed to apply to you to furnish the Town with 100 Ballard Carbines with ammunition if in your power from the State Arsenal</p>
<p>They shall be taken care of and returned and will be of great value to us at this moment. We have some arms belonging to individuals which will be<pb/>
<lb/>used and <unclear>with these</unclear> we ask will arm from 150 to 200 new enrolled <unclear>member</unclear></p>
<p>I think the organization a good one and will <unclear>increase</unclear> the defence of the <unclear>town</unclear> against these bands of Robbers &amp; Guerillas. Please answer at your earliest convenience</p>
<p>Yours truly
<lb/><hi rend="underline">J. F. Robinson</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Inspector Genl</p>
<p>Let the arms be issued give instructions how to get them<pb/></p>
<p>Ky State Guard.
<lb/>Georgetown Scott Co. Ky.
<lb/><date when="1864-08-08">August 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Robinson Hon. Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> F.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>To the Gov. Stating that Georgetown is clearly in danger of a guerlla raid. Under an order from Gen<hi rend="sup">l</hi> Burbridge the citizens have been offered and enrolled for its defence. This letter has been referred by Gov. Bramlette with this endorsement thereon "Inspector Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> let the arms be issued -- give instructions how to get them"<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Blanks forwarded and communication answered on this <date when="1864-08-09">Aug. 9-64</date> on Letter book B. Page 20<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>R. I. G. O. <date when="1864-08-09">Aug 9<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date></p>
<p>Scott Co. &amp; surrounding counties in danger</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
