<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-003-0050"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Brutus J. Clay to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1567</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR5-73 to BR5-74</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Washington, District of Columbia</placeName>
    <date when="1864-01-15">15 January 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Washington D.C.
<lb/><date when="1864-01-15">Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">y</hi></hi> 15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date>.
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. E. Bramlette
<lb/>Gov. Kentucky
<lb/>Dear sir</p>
<p>There is a subject, which has been upon my mind, for some time, and I had intended to address you, before this in regard to it.</p>
<p>It is: this; The subject of recruiting Negro soldiers for U S service, in Kentucky. Now, my Dear Sir; I would urge upon you the importance of resistance to this measure in every legal way, the recruiting of Negroes, the property of our Citizens in the Military service, and more particularly by Agents sent from other states for that purpose, if they are to be recruited at all, it should<pb/>
<lb/>be in behalf of &amp; for the state of Kentucky and be credited to the quota of troops called for -- </p>
<p>It is rumored here that Agents have been sent from other states for that purpose. This thing of plundering our people ought &amp; should be stopped if possible, even recruiting for our own quota would be injurious &amp; demoralizing to our Slave population by the consent and approval of the owner himself I think a firm stand taken by you against it, would have a good effect and even prevent the U. S. Government, from attempting it in our State.</p>
<p>The North is disposed to encroach upon our Constitutional rights and &amp; interest in every possible way she can. &amp; if we truely submit there is no telling where the encroachment will stop. I believe a firm &amp; decided resistance in all legal ways will have a benificial effect here.</p>
<p>Yr most Obt. Srt.
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Brutus J. Clay</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
