<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0533"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. John H. Taylor, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4652</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-344</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Fayette County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="left margin">1</note>
<lb/>Fayette Circuit Court,
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against
<lb/>John H Taylor F M C</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Fayette County, in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, accuse John H Taylor, free man of color of the crime of Grand Larceny committed as follows, viz: The said John H Taylor on the <date when="1864-02-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of February 1864</date>, in the County aforesaid, feloniously took and carried away Four Barrels of Corn the personal property of Caleb Tarlton of the value of more than Four dollars against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>And the Grand Jurors of the County aforesaid, in the name and by the authority aforesaid, further accuse the said John H Taylor of the crime of Receiving stolen property, knowing that the same was stolen, committed as follows, towit, The said John H Taylor on the <date when="1864-02-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of February 1864</date>, in the County aforesaid, did receive Four Barrels of Corn the personal property of Caleb Tarlton, knowing at the time that he received Corn that it was stolen, said Corn so received was worth over Four dollars, against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>W S Downey
<lb/>Commonwealths Attorny.</p>
<p>Witnesses:
<lb/>Caleb Tarleton
<lb/>James Kenyer
<lb/>John Stevenson
<lb/>W H Cromwell
<lb/>A J Gorham
<lb/>E C Gorham</p>
<p>Returned into Court <date when="1864-02-10">February 10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date>.
<lb/>Amount of Bail Bond $800.</p>
<p>(And afterwards, towit: at a Court continued and held in and for the Circuit aforesaid, on the <date when="1864-02-22">22<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> day of Feby 1864</date>.)<pb/></p>
<p><note place="left margin">2</note>
<lb/>The Commonwealth came by her Attorney and the Defendant was called and failed to appear in discharge of his Bail Bond herein.</p>
<p>W L Taylor surety of said Defendant was likewise called who failed to produce the body of his prinicpal.</p>
<p>Wherefore it is ordered that the Bail Bond herein be and the same is hereby forfeited and that a Summons issue thereon in the name of the Commonwelath returnable to the next term.</p>
<p>(And afterwards, towit: at a Court continued and held in and for the Circuit aforesaid, on the <date when="1865-02-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of February 1865</date>.)</p>
<p>On motion of the Attorney for the Plaintiff, it is ordered that this case be filed away with leave to reinstate the same on the Docket at anytime hereafter.</p>
<p>True Copies -- Att Jno B Norton C f C C
<lb/>By Chas F Lowry D C</p>
<p>Comwth Kentucky 
<lb/>vs.
<lb/>Taylor John H
<lb/>Copy Indict &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>For W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> L Taylor</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
