<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3255"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Robert D. Erwin et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5374</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-51 to BR42-52</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Carter County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Carter County Ky
<lb/>Mr T E Bramlett</p>
<p>Govenor of Ky to your excellency the under signed Petitioners your Honor to use your hand of mercy in favor of there Petition in this cause and <hi rend="str">they</hi> as there is one Robert Alexander of our county was fined ten Dollars for intr Rupting Publect worship in our county and we woull Repsent to your honor that that he did not do it intentionally if he Did it at all the Proof was not of Sutch a caracter that woud warrant a conviction under it and the Jury did not under stand the law fully on the Subject and was Predgist to wards his cause and there mines was mis led there fore they would asque your honor to use your hand of mercy in his favor</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Isom Daniel
<lb/>James H. M. Dean
<lb/>James.M. Bond
<lb/>Henry Lawson
<lb/>James S. Henderson
<lb/>Solomon J Ward
<lb/>Thos W. Banfield
<lb/>R. J. Henderson
<lb/>James Hollan
<lb/>O. J Smith
<lb/>James Henderson
<lb/>Samuel Henderson
<lb/>George W Bond
<lb/>Gona Brinigar
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Robert D. Erwin
<lb/>James H Armstrong
<lb/>B. M. Taber
<lb/>D R Eliott Burden
<lb/>Wm. R. Willburn
<lb/>B S Bond
<lb/>J. W. Williams
<lb/>Vincent <unclear/> Geeson
<lb/>J. B. Williams
<lb/>T. Thomas <unclear/>
<lb/>N. M. Williams
<lb/>R. s. Williams
<lb/>Solomon Brinagar
<lb/>Morgan Brinigar
<lb/>James M Mead<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>Stephen Mckinney c c c<pb/></p>
<p>Olive Hill
<lb/>Carter County Ky</p>
<p>Mr Thomas E Bramlet sir I would Say to ^your^ Excellency that that the facts Set forth in this petition is true and I think that you would not do the citizens of our county any wrong in Remitting this fine against Robert Alexander in favor of the Commonwealth if so I would not asque you to Do so for I have been Serving those Same citizens as Justice of the Peace for ten years and and Know them all well and I was present at the trial and know the facts Set forth in the petition to be true</p>
<p>By so doing you would Do your humble Petitioners a great favor</p>
<p>Harvey Henderson Judge
<lb/>Carter Co. Court</p>
<p>Thos E Bramlet
<lb/>Governer of Ky<pb/>
<lb/>Carter Cir Ct
<lb/>R Alexander
<lb/>court <unclear>scct</unclear>
<lb/>Petitions</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
