<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3322"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James Stuart, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5441</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-158</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Commonwealth vs Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> J. Dennis</p>
<p>This was an Indictment for a tipling house. The Deft was found guilty of retailing and of twice selling &amp; fined $40. The proof was that at a liquor stand, at a Barbacue he sold two drinks. The proof further showed that this was a certain Ge<hi rend="sup">o</hi> Bells liquor stand &amp; Bell testified that the Deft had no interest in the affair, that he wishing at One time to engage in the dance requested the Deft. to attend at his stand &amp; sell for him while he danced which he did Bell was a soldier in the state Guard stationed at Hawesville, &amp; his Capt &amp; Major had given him leave to attend the Barbacue &amp; peddle the liquor</p>
<p>I think that both Bell &amp; the Deft considered the permission of his officers was a sufficient license to Bell. There were several liqour stands on the ground</p>
<p>James Stuart
<lb/>Judge</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
