<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1264"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">H. C. Lilly et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5901</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-437 to BR11-438</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Irvine, Estill County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-12-26">26 December 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Irvine Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1864-12-26">Decr. 26th 1864</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency the Gov. of Ky -- </p>
<p>The undersigned Citizens of Estill and Owsley counties, would most respectfully represent that William Huddleston and Eveline his wife were Indicted for Grand Larceny at the <date when="1864-06">June Term 1864</date> of the Owsley Circuit Court and, there being no Jail in Owsly, by consent the case was changed to the Estill Circuit Court. The facts of the case ^are^ substantially as follows, to wit: In <date when="1863-12">Decr. 1863</date> Mr<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Joseph Hampton, while traveling along the Public highway from Boonville to her Fathers lost $1500 -- which had been entrusted to her care by her husband and M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> Huddleston found it and believeing that she was entitled to keep it failed to make the fact known to her husband or any one else for several days, but afterward did so. Hampton having learned about his money went and got it all back and we understand that he and his wife are satisfied and ^do^ not want to appear as witnesses Some of the witnesses live a great distance from Irvine and never have attended Court to testify in the case<pb/>
<lb/>We doubt whether the Commonwealth can ever get ready to give them a trial. <hi rend="underline">They</hi> <hi rend="underline">are</hi> <hi rend="underline">very</hi> <hi rend="underline">poor</hi> <hi rend="underline">and</hi> <hi rend="underline">we</hi> <hi rend="underline">believe</hi> <hi rend="underline">were</hi> <hi rend="underline">overcome</hi> <hi rend="underline">by</hi> <hi rend="underline">temptation</hi>. "Lay not temptation before man" is the Scriptural injunction. Except this charge we have never heard aught against their characters. They bear the name of honest industrious people. In view of all the facts and circumstances in their case we most humbly ask you to grant them Executive Clemancy and stop all further prosecution against them upon the charge in the Indictment.</p>
<p>We are very Rest. your Obt. Servts.
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/> H Gaither
<lb/>E Herndon
<lb/>D. R. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kinney
<lb/>Wm Herndon
<lb/>Morton M Price
<lb/>Robert. W. Smith
<lb/><cb n="2"/>H. C. Lilly
<lb/>A A Curtis
<lb/>Thomas Sewell
<lb/><unclear>A</unclear>B McGuire
<lb/>J. N. Cardwell
<lb/>R. B. Dameson<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>Ansil. D. Powell
<lb/>D. B. Scholl
<lb/>W J Ashcraft
<lb/>H Cockrill</p>
<p>To his Excellency the Gov- of Ky-
<lb/>Sir:</p>
<p>I have talked with Mr Joseph Hampton in regard to the case Mr. &amp; M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi> Huddleston and he does not desire that they should be prosecuted any further They have lived in &amp; near Irvine, within one mile of my house ever since they were bailed out of Jail and have be haved themselves so well that they gained the good opinion of their neighbors &amp; I am satisfied the people do not want them prosecuted any further. Our Judge &amp; Comth. Atty. each ^I believe^ desire to throw the responsibilty upon the other in all such cases &amp; consequently it is almost impossible to get a case ^of Felony^ dismissed.</p>
<p>I hope you will grant the prayer of this petition -- </p>
<p>yours truly
<lb/>H.C. Lilly<pb/></p>
<p>Owsley Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Huddleston
<lb/>&amp; wife
<lb/>Refused</p>
<p>50/100 000</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
