<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2299"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Edward Garrett to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9375</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG25-51</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency B Magoffin
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner Edward Garrett would respectfully State that at the <date when="1860-03">March term 1860</date> of the Taylor Circuit Court he was fined on indictment in Said court for carrying concealed weapons the sum of fifty dollars, that at the time said fine or judgment was rendered he was absent from home and did not have a chance to defend the same, that if he had been present at the trial he could have shown that he was not guilty of the charge, the facts were as follows, he was present when a difficulty occured in Taylor county bettween Willis Chelf &amp; Jeff Youget when the latter drew a pistol and threw it the former and your petitioner picked it up to take care of it and prevent any mischief being done with it, and Same persons who saw him with the pistol and not knowing how got it presented him to the grand jury and an indictment was found against him, and trial and judment had thereon as above stated -- The states, he did not carry the pistol concealed or for any other reason than the one above stated -- <pb/>
<lb/>He says he is poor and unble to pay the said fine, and unless your Excellency will remit the same he be put in jail for the same The pray for a remission of the said fine</p>
<p>Edward Garrett</p>
<p>We join in the prayer above for a remission of the said fine and state that we believe the case one that ought receive executive clemency -- </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Joseph <unclear>Heff</unclear>
<lb/>F. J Hustan
<lb/>Joseph H Chandler
<lb/>Wm Harr
<lb/>William Dearen
<lb/>J H Robinson
<lb/>Jas. Durrett
<lb/>George Gribbins
<lb/>Wm. Wolly
<lb/>Izer garyte
<lb/>George Gunter
<lb/>A Harmon
<lb/>george Harmon
<lb/><unclear/> Gideon
<lb/>M T grelins
<lb/>W. P garbin
<lb/>Charles g Vilbin
<lb/>Beren Phillips
<lb/>maleatus Saly
<lb/>Pleasant phillips
<lb/>Daniel F. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Near
<lb/><cb n="2"/>E S Barker
<lb/>D B Moore
<lb/>Rufus Jenkins
<lb/>W R. Panott
<lb/>John Spurling
<lb/>S E Tanay
<lb/>Lewis Brown
<lb/>J. N. Turner
<lb/>A. J. Gowdy
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> D. Hord
<lb/>D. M. Manning
<lb/><hi rend="underline">A H Buckman</hi>
<lb/>Joel, M, Avary
<lb/>W. D. Vancleave
<lb/>R Davis
<lb/>M O Robinson
<lb/>J C Sanders
<lb/>P C Sanders
<lb/>Jno H Chandler
<lb/>J P Davis
<lb/>Thomas Sumers
<lb/>George Saly</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
