<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1573"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">T. E. Moore et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11041</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-207 to MG22-208</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Pendleton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-12-09">9 December 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Govenor M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin.</p>
<p>Your petitioners would respectfully represent that David Boner and Joseph Hendricks were at the present <date when="1861-10">Oct</date> Term of the Pendleton Circuit Court found guilty by the verdict of a jury of breaking into the store house of Thomas Wheeler in the County of Pendleton with intent to commit a fellony. They are mere boys, have always sustained a good character, and whether guilty or not your petitioners believe that their pardon, would be promotive of their reformation. They are respectfully connected: no other charge has ever been brought or prefered against them. Your petitioners, with strong assurances from the accused of th<unclear/> reformation, respectfully request your Exellency to pardon them. </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>I with A. G. Roberts defended the young men who have petitioned for Executive clemency. They are respectably connected: are quite young and I believe their pardon would have the effect to reform them if guilty. L. F. Throope</p>
<p>I endorse the statements of Maj Throope A G Roberts</p>
<p>E J Rawlings
<lb/><hi rend="underline">S. Tho. Hauser</hi>
<lb/>J. S. Coleman
<lb/><cb n="2"/><hi rend="underline">T E Moore</hi><milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>The undersigned, who were jurors in the case above mentioned unite with the petitoners for the pardon of David Boner &amp; Joseph Hendricks<pb/></p>
<p>R W Dudley Juror
<lb/>W G Myers Juror
<lb/>N J Levengood Juror
<lb/>John M. Pribble Juror
<lb/>G. W. Lewis Juror
<lb/>C F Ellis Juror
<lb/>James W Logan Jur
<lb/>Wesley Purdy Jur
<lb/>Taylor Ewing Juror
<lb/>John Childers Jr</p>
<p>Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>Pendleton Circuit Court } Sct</p>
<p>I Geo M Ameson D C for M Mullins <unclear/> do hereby certif that foregoing list of names Served as Jurors on the with named case. Given under my hand this <date when="1861-12-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of December 1861</date></p>
<p>M Mullins Ck
<lb/>By Geo. W Ameson D C<pb/></p>
<p>Hendricks Case
<lb/>Pendleton
<lb/><unclear/></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
