<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1983"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Ann Carson to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6620</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-124 to BR14-125</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>His Excellency
<lb/>Thomas, E, Bramlett
<lb/>Governor for Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Anne Carson a Free woman of Collor would respectfully represent to your Excellency that she was fined the sum of fifty dollars by the Police Court of Louisville upon the charge of Keeping a disorderly House</p>
<p>She states that the proof before the Jury was conclusive against her But the real facts in the Case was not before the Jury She has three Small Children to suport She is very poor She only can depend upon her labour as a wash woman for support She occupied only One small room on Marchall Street Colored soldiers would call at Her House often intoxicated She was unable to control them being fearful of them they being allways around the neighbourhood in wich she here is filled with Collored people with few exceptions<pb/>
<lb/>The House in which she lives contained five Rooms all the rooms except the front room was Occupied by Collored people she occupied the front room all the inmates of Said House except herself entertaned Collored Soldiers who were often disorderly Pititioner Occupying the front Room was held responsible for all the misconduct of all parties the police believing that petitioner had controll of the whole House which was not true all of which will be sertified by her nieghbours</p>
<p>Pititioner says she is unable to pay said fine except to work the same out in the City work House where her Children must suffer She Prays your Honor to remit her fine and she will ever pray</p>
<p>Ann ^her X mark^ Carson</p>
<p>The neighbours of Ann Carson Join in the truth of foregoing statements</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W. Howard
<lb/>W. O. Brown
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J Bacon
<lb/>John Miles
<lb/>Henry Townsly
<lb/>William Carter<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>I appeared for Ann Carson in the Police Court and defended for her the petition containing the facts as regards the proof I believe her statements to be true</p>
<p>J. P. Gailbreath
<lb/>Atty at Law
<lb/>Louis Same</p>
<p>I have Bin acting as city Marshal of Louisvill for some Eight years and stait that this petition is True</p>
<p>Henry C Russell<pb/></p>
<p>Louisville Police Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Petition
<lb/>for
<lb/>Ann Carson<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>$50,
<lb/>Disorderly House
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Remit</hi>
<lb/><date when="1865-06-27">27 June/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
