<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-027-0026"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. H. Buckley to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1259</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R2-41 to R2-42</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>New Castle, Henry County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-08-27">27 August 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Newcastle Henry Co Ky
<lb/><date when="1862-08-27">August 27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>Hon J F Robinson
<lb/>Frankfort Ky 
<lb/>Dear Sir -- </p>
<p>I write you at the request of some of the most earnest and <hi rend="underline">practical</hi> Loyal men of this county requesting <hi rend="underline">if practical</hi> that about 100 -- efficient mounted men be kept in this county for some days -- or until those now engaged in scouting for the confederate rebels -- shall be caught or routed -- This has been going on with <hi rend="str">an</hi> a remarkable activity -- being adjacent to Trimble and Owen -- they have had a pretty clear <unclear/> -- I have had since here a fair oportunity to hear and learn and I assure you sir this is no <hi rend="underline">hobgoblin</hi> -- but an actuality -- and the rebel <unclear>Jessee</unclear> -- we thought killed has been<pb/>
<lb/>successful at work here up to last Sunday night -- There are many hiding places on the border of Owen -- and Trimble and many think he is yet skulking here. The few union men of Trimble have been agrieved by the uneven and the untimely action of Dickens a <hi rend="underline">Provost</hi> from this county who in a mistaken zeal (to say the least) has given to the recruiting Rebels a new impulse -- and it is telling in the members of recruits -- The troops now here under -- Holman we have not heard from -- but they were too late for the Locality they were sent to -- This place should be the head quarters -- and work out from here in squads -- There are a number of efficient men here to cooperate with them but some permanent organization is necessary as a <unclear/> for them -- </p>
<p>I do hope my dear sir that your health will be equal to the demands that are upon you and that God will favor this this commonwealth in a kind providence over you, and this is the prayer of scores<pb/>
<lb/>and hundreds of loyal hearts all over this land -- Mrs B joins in regards to you -- </p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>R H Buckley<pb/></p>
<p>R. H. Buckley
<lb/>New Castle</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
