<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0003-092-0133"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Madison C. Johnson to Anne E. V. Johnson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14423</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Historical Society</repository>
      <collection>George W. Johnson Papers</collection>
      <idno>Folder 6</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1862-04-16">16 April 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">157</note>
<lb/><date when="1862-04-16">April 16<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>My Dear Mother</p>
<p>I suppose before now that you all have heard of dear father death and the manner in which he was killed in the late battle. I went with Captain Keene Richards on the sunday after the fight with a flag of truce to learn what we could in regard to what they had done with him. I saw Gen Nelson of Ky and he told us that my father was taken on Monday morning wounded. At the time he was wounded he was fighting in Col Tribue's regiment on foot, his horse having been shot as I learned the day before. O mother what an untarnish name he has left behind him and what a legacy to his family and to his children.</p>
<p>Gen Nelson told us that father suffered from his wounds in the <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> whatever and he died on <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>the <date when="1862-04-09">9<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi></date> and that his remains would be sent to you in Ky. I start this evening to brother Willa with fathers things which he had left with Arnold.</p>
<p>Brother Willa and all of our friends of Old Town and Lake Washington are well when I last heard from them.</p>
<p>Dear Mother I know you will excuse bad writing and my short letter, as you know to tell you that I am well is about all that I can write these times since I can not write what I would like to. Give my love to Grand-pa and Grand-ma and all my relations -- Kiss brother Euclid and Henry for me -- Tell Cousin Mary the General and Cable are both well. With the hope that I may see you all again I am yours affectionate son<pb/></p>
<p><note place="header">158</note>
<lb/>Mrs Ann E Johnson
<lb/>Georgetown
<lb/>KY</p>
<p>A letter from Geo. W. Johnson's Second Son, Madison ("Matty") who was with Morgan's command. An older son Willa V. was also in the service</p>
<p>Mrs Ann E Johnson
<lb/>Georgetown
<lb/>Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
