<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2595"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. W. Gault ot Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7232</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-149 to BR16-150</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-25">25 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville Ky. <date when="1865-10-25">Oct 25th 65</date>
<lb/>Thomas E Bramlette,
<lb/>Gov. of Kentucky -- 
<lb/>Frankfort Ky,
<lb/>Govenor,</p>
<p>I have the honor to respectfully make the following statement in the case of C R Stull of the 24th Ky, Vol, Infantry; for your consideration and action. He was tried by a Federal court held in this city in the month of <date when="1865-10">Oct, 1865</date>, for passing a counterfeit twenty dollar bill, and sentenced to the penitentiary for the term of one year and five months, and has already been forwarded to Frankfort, Ky, in conformity with his sentence.</p>
<p>There are extenuating circumstances in this mans case, which induces me to believe that he ought to be pardoned on his family's acount at least, if not his own. The money, (a twenty dollar U S treasury note was passed in Maysville Ky. while the man was very drunk,<pb/>
<lb/>on the night of the illumination of the city in honor of the fall of Richmond. It was given him by a comrade, and when arrested no other bad money was found upon his person He was held to bail in the sum of six hundred dollars, which he gave and was released, but was subsequently rearrested and brought to this city, and lodged in jail where he remained until tried as before stated. He had no money to fee a lawyer with and no friends to interest themselves in his behalf. He has served his country three years as a Soldier, having been twice wounded in the line of duty. His family was driven from their home in Bath county Ky, by the guerrillas, and compelled to take refuge in ohio; sacrificing by so doing the little property they had. He has heretofore borne a good character for honesty and sobriety A conviction of the crime with which he was charged, forfeits all pay, bounty, &amp;c due him from the U. S. government. This family is a very helpless one consisting of a wife four children and an aged mother-in-law with<pb/>
<lb/>no means of support whatever, except by the needle of his wife, who is a very clever and good woman. She was present at her husbands trial, and after his conviction, got up a petition for his pardon, which was signed by all of the juryman she saw, Genl Palmer and other officials. I sympathise deeply with her condition, and hope that on <hi rend="underline">her</hi> account, if for no other reason, you will use your influence to have her husband pardoned. Enclosed you will find a letter from T C Campbell touching this subject.</p>
<p>Very Respectfully
<lb/>Your Obt Servt.
<lb/>J. W. Gault
<lb/>Mil Agent for Ky.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
