<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0581"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky vs. James C. Brookover, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9033</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-418</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mason County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Mason Circuit Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky.
<lb/>Against } Indictment
<lb/>James C. Brookover.</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Mason County, in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, accuse James C, Brookover of the offense of selling spirituous liquor to slaves, committed as follows: The said James C, Brookover on the <date when="1861-07-15">15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of July 1861</date> at the County aforesaid, did sell Spirituous liquor to certain slaves, whose names are unknown to the Grand Jury, belonging to the persons whose names are unknown to the Grand Jury, he at the time not having the rightful care and custody of said slaves, or either of them, and not have the written order of the owner, or owners of said slaves, or either of them, or of the person or persons entitled to the custody and care of said slaves to furnish them, or either of them with said liquors, against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>R. H. Stanton
<lb/>Attorney for the Commonwealth.
<lb/>(Endorsed as follows towit:)
<lb/>"A True Bill -- 
<lb/>L. B. Gaggin Foreman -- 
<lb/>A Copy. <hi rend="underline">Attest</hi>. Jn<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">o</hi></hi> M Duke Jr Clerk
<lb/>Mason Ct Ct.<pb/></p>
<p>Comlth of Ky -- 
<lb/>vs. } Copy of Indictment.
<lb/>James C. Brookover.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
