<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1150"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John W. Crockett to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10618</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-299 to MG20-300</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Henderson, Henderson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-29">29 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Henderson <date when="1861-06-29">June 29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>B Magoffin
<lb/>Dear sir</p>
<p>With this will be handed you copy of a record in the case of the Commonwealth vs Beverly</p>
<p>I was the counsel defending and the facts proven, were as follows. Mr Beverly is a wholesale and retail Grocer of our place last fall his clerk Henry Gobin sold to an old boy Tom, whiskey, The boy is the property of Mrs Clay as charged in the indictment, but was at the time &amp; has been for years in the employment of Mr Pasey Mr Gobin swore that he did ^not^ know wether Mr Beverly was in the building or not at the time of the sale, the room is very deep and &amp; Beverly might have been at the desk and known nothing of the selling which took place in the back part of the room The sale took place in the fall of last year_ We offorced are orders from Pasey for whisky which had no date, We also introduced Pasey who swore the order was given last fall, but could not fix the precise time_ the Court refused to let the order be read because it was not dated, as is shown by the bill of exceptions taken at the time, We think the Court erred in several other particulars as shown by the record, Mr Beverly is a man of wealth<pb/>
<lb/>and a large slave-holder_ The amt is not great for him, but he thinks &amp; I think injustice was done him on the trial He does not desire to be put the expense of an appeal, and therefore asks you to relieve him from the fine</p>
<p>The chances in this county are greatly against us, but we "will not give up the ship" We hope yet the county will by august give a Southern Rights Majority</p>
<p>Your friend
<lb/>J. W. Crockett</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
