<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2912"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James S. Rowland to George W. Poindexter</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7549</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-235 to BR17-236</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hopkinsville, Christian County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-06">6 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Hopkinsville, Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-12-06">Decr 6<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>Col Geo W Poindexter
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>My Bro Reuben spoke to ^me^ a few days since of the conversation he had with you in reference to a certain fine I owe the commonwealth and your promise to interest yourself in having it remitted. -- I will proceed to give you the facts -- in the fall of <date when="1861">1861</date> I was appointed by Genl Tilghman as Provost Marshall of the brigade of confederate Soildiers that were then at this place. I was fully as much so as any other officer in the pay and service of the confederate states and answerable for my conduct to my superiors While acting in the capacity of Provost Marshal it was Thou^gh^t necessary by the Medical Director and the other surgeons belonging to the army<pb/>
<lb/>to take posession of a small Bakery belonging to W H Pelton of this place. The object in securing the Bakery was to supply the confederate Hospitals with bakers bread. of which they stood much in need. Being Provost Marshal it became my duty to take posession of the bakery and turn it over to use of the Hospitals, After taking posession of the Bakery I ascertained that there was no one to take charge of it who was competent to do the baking and moreover as Mr Pelton was willing to do the baking for the Hospitals I immediately returned to him his establishment as I found it. he having sustained no injury or loss whatsoever. Nor did I intend that he should sustain any loss I remarked to him that it was a duty that I <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>owed to the sick soildiers to take his establishment -- and furthermore more observed to Mr Pelton in the presence of Mr W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Shipp and<pb/>
<lb/>Fisher that he should be fully compensated for any loss he might sustain in having his bakery taken -- </p>
<p>For this act I was fined in the circuit Court at this place 250$ -- One hundred Dollars of this amount has been paid -- And as I think the fine unjust I trust you will exert yourself in my behalf with his Excellency and have the balance due <hi rend="str">in</hi>on this fine remitted</p>
<p>Your friend truly
<lb/>James. S. Rowland<pb/></p>
<p>Christian Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>J. S. Rowland
<lb/>$250.
<lb/>Breach Peace
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1866-01-11">11 Jany/66</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
