<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2294"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Unknown et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6931</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-170 to BR15-172</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-08-18">18 August 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E Bramlette Gov. of Ky.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner J P Bardy would respectfully State that on the <date when="1864-01-17">17<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of January 1864</date> he was convicted of the crime of horse Stealing in the Jefferson Circuit ^Court^ and sentenced to be <unclear>imprn</unclear> in the Penitentiary for the term of four year at hard labor and that soon after his conviction he was confined in said Penitentiary and has remained there ever since, Your petitioner fother says that he was confined in the Jefferson County Jail for <gap/> months which together is now about two years imprisonment for what he has not been guilty of, it may be said that most guilty men say they are not guilty but the facts in this case are, that your petitioner proved that he was in the city of Louisville at the time said horse was stollen <hi rend="str">in</hi> and said horse was Stolen some twenty five miles from Louisville, Yet all it needs for a man to be charged with horsestealing and so prejudiced is the public mind in this class of cases that there mind is frequently made up before the evidence is through. Your <hi rend="str">the</hi> petitioner would fother state that he has conducted himsel<pb/>
<lb/>well from his boyhood up and also ever since he has been confined, to which the warden of the Penitentiary will certify. Your petitioner would fother state that he served in the army of the united States between one and two years, and that he has an aged Mother no living near Knoxville Tennessee, who is a widow and has been such for the last twelve years, and your petitioner is her only Child now living, and the only Support of his Said aged mother; who does not know of his wherabouts as he did not want to hurt her fealings by a history of his misfortunes. For the reasons alreddy given and in consideration of his suffering alreddy Sustained, as he is a man in feble health, and the fact that he has alreddy confined taking the Jail and penitentiary together about two years; Your petitioner respectfully prays that your Excellency will exercise your Executive clemency and grant him a parden, so that he may return once more to the arms of his aged mother and that he may be able to gladen the heart of her who would rejois at his coming and who know not where he is</p>
<p>Respectfully Submitted <date when="1865-08-18">Aug 18<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1865</date><pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned Citizens of Louisville would Suggest that we believe the above is a case which deserves the interference of Your Executive Clemency and we therefore pray that your Excellency will grant him parden;</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="3"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>Donald <unclear/>
<lb/>Dana R <unclear/>
<lb/>John Schoeder
<lb/>Henry Stracler
<lb/>Samuel Jones
<lb/>L. Marshall
<lb/>James Tyral
<lb/>John Leaf
<lb/>Mickel Coney
<lb/>Daniel OConner
<lb/>Michael Donoghue
<lb/>John Murphy
<lb/>Timothy Moriarty
<lb/>J T Horwood
<lb/>Thos K Shuell
<lb/>John Marrs
<lb/>James Shuell
<lb/>John F Mattingly
<lb/>John Knapp
<lb/>Henery Schmitt
<lb/>John Keene
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/>Charles Schaber
<lb/>Daniel Swindling
<lb/>A. Kempff
<lb/>Henry Dunker
<lb/>John Fristch
<lb/>Peter Knobloch
<lb/>John Spritsnagel
<lb/><cb n="3"/>Names
<lb/>F G Dannecker
<lb/>J. J <unclear/>
<lb/>John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Carthy
<lb/>Jos Harris
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Sam</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> Matlock</hi> J P.
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> A Walter D S
<lb/>M. J. Schmitt
<lb/>John Joyes
<lb/>Joseph Clermont, J P
<lb/>L. W. Sale
<lb/>B. F. Trimble D. C. L. C. C.
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Cha</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> A Smith</hi> D. Court L. C. C
<lb/>Phil Tomppert Jr
<lb/>Clerk City Court,
<lb/>James C Gill
<lb/>Coroner J C Ky
<lb/>Philip Tomppert. Mayor
<lb/>R. M. Pound
<lb/>L Kinstle M. S. D.<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Names</p>
<p>I Know all about the facts in this case There was no proof in this case except the fact that he had the horse in possession. He claimed that he bought the horse in Louisville and claims that he could prove it by Some withness who was with him at the time but had went to East Tennessee. I believe this is a case of more than ordinary merit</p>
<p>L. A. Wood
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/><cb n="3"/>Names<pb/></p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>J. P. Bandy
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Refused
<lb/></hi>Notified</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
