<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-024-0129"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. F. Carter to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG12179</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Mitchell A Krock</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>1st - 20th Regiments Kentucky Infantry Primary Source Documents</collection>
      <idno>Box 8, Folder 19th Ky. Inf. - Misc</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-12-03">3 December 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville, Ky, <date when="1862-12-03">Dec 3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi>, 62,</date>
<lb/>Gov. Roberson: -- 
<lb/>Dear Sir,</p>
<p>Stern necesity forces me to approach your excellency in this manner. I was born and reared at Stamping Ground, Scott Co. Ky., and have known you from boyhood, thoug not personally acquainted with you, and believe you are not deaf to the voice of humanity.</p>
<p>My reasons for intruding upon your Excellen^cy^ attention are these: -- The hardships incident to a soldiers life, for 15 Mo. have rendered Myself, G. W. Ragan &amp; Elby Perkins, unfit for service; and, consequently, were left here to be discharged, I find that we might as well ^have^ been sent to London for that purpose. Here we are, with no friends to do anything for us, confined to the hospital, and not able to do anything for ourselves, Such is the condition of some of the Indiania troops, but they have appealed to their Govener for help, and he ordered their discharge which was done, Will your Excellency be less kind to his troops, who have served their State and Country as long as able to, who have suffered the hardships of the Cumberland Gap experdition under Gen. Morgan?</p>
<p>Govener Roberson, it is hard, indeed, after one has offered his life and become disable in the service of there Country to be turned<pb/>
<lb/>over to the <hi rend="underline">tender mercies</hi> of men in this city who never experienced one hardship of a soldiers life, and to whose hearts, I am told by those more conversant <hi rend="str">what</hi> with what is going on here, that "<hi rend="underline">money</hi>" is the only avenue to their hearts -- yes it is, indeed, hard to be left to "root hog or die." Such is a true statement of our condition, but should your Excellency doubt it, I have but to refer you to my Cmy Capt, Henry Hicks of the 19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Regt. Ky. Vol, and also, to Doctor J. H. Peyton of the 11<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky. Cavalry, for the truth of my statement. Under tbe circumstances will your Excellency send me an order to Dr. Heade Medical Director here for our discharge or inform me what to do? Will your Excellency condecend to answer this at his earliest oppor^tunity^ My address is J. F. Carter, Barracks No. 1. Louisville. Ky, Very Respectfully,</p>
<p>J. F. Carter,</p>
<p>19
<lb/>Military
<lb/>J. F. Carter
<lb/>J. F. Carter
<lb/>Louisville Ky
<lb/><date when="1862-12-03">Dec 3/62</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Gen. Boyle
<lb/>Carter J. F.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Conc<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">g</hi></hi> his discharge.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
