<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1672"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Fred Rothenhofer to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6309</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-147 to BR13-148</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-04-03">3 April 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thos. E. Bramlette Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner states that in the year <date when="1864">1864</date> he was a tavern keeper in Somerset, and in one of the rooms of his house erected a "Pigeon hole table" -- on which the citizens of the town used to play -- He states, that it was his express directions that gaming of all kinds was prohibited -- He was indicted for keeping a gambling house, and at the present term of the Pulaski Circuit Court, fined $200= It was proven on the trial that men would play on his table, and the unsuccessful party would sometimes pay a treat -- this if construed as betting was against his positive orders -- He states, that <hi rend="str">no</hi> money <hi rend="str">or any</hi> <hi rend="str">nor</hi> ^nor^ any other thing was never bet at the game to his knowledge, and the proof failed to show any such betting -- But it was proven that the young men would play on the table and <hi rend="str">th</hi>at the termination of the game pay a treat at some of the groceries in the town -- </p>
<p>Your petitioner states, he did not know that <hi rend="str">this</hi> <hi rend="str">was</hi> <hi rend="str">prohibited</hi>, <hi rend="str">if he had</hi> <hi rend="str">of</hi> any such bets as even for whiskey, cigars or treets were made, if he had, he would have stopped it -- </p>
<p>He avers he is poor, and that the judgment is oppressive; and unless Your Excellency will remit the same, it will be a great hardship to have it to pay -- That if the la<hi rend="str">nd</hi>ws of the land were broken, it was not done by his knowledge or consent= He asks Your Excellency to remit the fine -- </p>
<p>x F Rothenhofer<pb/></p>
<p>The foregoing petition was sworn to by Fred Rothenhofer before me, that the statements therein <hi rend="str">a</hi>were true, This <date when="1865-04-03">3 Ap<hi rend="sup">l</hi> 1865.</date>
<lb/>x</p>
<p>I Know pretty much of the facts and am of the opinion that the amt which he has to pay for costs &amp; comth atty, is an ample punishment for the offense Committed, The "Pigeon Hole" was not intended or let up to cover gambling but for amusement &amp; the boys about town preverted it into a place to pay treats</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">E L Van Winkle</hi>
<lb/>C<unclear/> Wirt
<lb/>Hiram Dugan
<lb/>Mit E Ingram
<lb/>W, P, Ingram
<lb/>W M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee Fox
<lb/>W. B. Moore<pb/></p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>Richard T Jacob
<lb/>Lt. &amp; act. Gov.</p>
<p>Pulaski Co
<lb/>vs
<lb/>$200
<lb/>F Rothenhofer
<lb/><date when="1865-05-03">3<hi rend="sup">d</hi> May/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
