<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2074"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John L. Sallee to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6711</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-269</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Monticello, Wayne County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-07-06">6 July 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Monticello Ky <date when="1865-07-06">July 6" 1865</date>
<lb/>His Excellency Thos E Bramlett
<lb/>Frankfort Ky
<lb/>Dear sir</p>
<p>I write you relative a young man James Granville Beckman who unfortunately for himself and family during the awful time of Moral depravity has got himself into the State Prison. I am not familiar enough with the facts in relation to his case to give them to you in detail but am clearly of the opinion from an intimate acquaintance with him from a small boy that he is not a theif neither had he any such training by his parents who I know were honest in the strict sense of the word Governor please see this young man at your Earliest convenience and I can vouch that any Statements made by him relative to his case may be relied on His Father &amp; Younger Brother have both given their lives in defense of what you and I considered a holy cause Defending the Stars &amp; Stripes.. He has a wife who is in the worst of health who is now reduced to last Extremity of Poverty with 4 helpless Children to support and if he is not released and permited to come to their aid God only knows how they are to live his Mother who was already almost heart broken by the recent loss of Husband &amp; Son now has this calamity the worst of all added to her<pb/>
<lb/>former troubles Governor release him I would not ask if I believed I was doing wrong and my Country <hi rend="str">Inj </hi>and Society Injured thereby he may have done wrong who has not. I am confident if he is released knowing his disposition as well as I think I do he will be an orderly Man and return to his family in good faith and do the best he can to Earn an honest living</p>
<p>Should you in your clemency See fit and I have confidence to believe you will I think you will be amply reward for the Good deed</p>
<p>Yours truly
<lb/>Jno L Sallee</p>
<p>P S Should you wish any thing further in way of Petition you can get any amount J L S</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
