<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-022-0009"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George C. Hallet to John Boyle</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11935</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>37th - 76th Regiments Enrolled Militia Primary Source Documents (1861-1866)</collection>
      <idno>Box 80, Folder 863-64 FULTON COUNTY Recruiting and Raising Company 40th Rgt. Ky. Militia</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hickman, Fulton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-11-10">10 November 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Head Quarters 40<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky. Militia.
<lb/>Hickman <date when="1863-11-10">Nov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> 10<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1863</date>.
<lb/>General John Boyle.
<lb/>Adjt Genl Ky. Vols.
<lb/>Sir,</p>
<p>On Sunday night last about 9 o'clock a band of from ten to fifteen men, some of them dressed in United States Cavalry over-coats and others in citizens clothing suddenly made their appearance in town, and in a short time, by force battered in the principal entrance to M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. R E Miller's store. Being sent for, I at once started and armed with a Smith &amp; Wesson's revolver, came upon the sport, just as they effected an entrance. They said they belonged to Capt Merriwether's Company of Confederates, and wanted some goods. Upon being informed, that Col Waring, Commanding at Union City, had been in town, in the afternoon with a detachment of Cavalry, they said, they had been so informed and had come for the purpose of "having a fight and some fun." They took about $75.00 of goods from M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Miller, paying for them. in counterfiet Confederate paper. While there engaged, they were suddenly startled by a boat coming up the river and as suddenly mounted their horses and left.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, having some suspicions as to their true character, I had started off to raise some twelve or fifteen men, in order to give them a fight. In this, as upon a former occasion, I was unsuccessful, being unable to secure the assistance of a single man: The citizens are perhaps, to some extent excusable, from the fact, that they are generally disarmed, while those who still have guns, are without any<pb/>
<lb/>ammunition. The marauders having left town hurriedly, I sent a scout or two out to ascertain the route they had taken. They remained so long that becoming apprehensive for their safety, I started myself in company with a tried man to hunt them up. Hearing some voices at a distance on the Dresden Road, we proceed to conceal ourselves. In so doing, I was unfortunate ^enough^ to seriously injure my ankle, which at present and most likely for a couple of weeks will effectually disable me. For the first time, to day, am I able to sit up.</p>
<p>The scouts having returned, reported the men as going out the Dresden road and towards Union City. Yesterday, while lying on my Lounge some citizens from Gibson Co. Tenn. reported to me, that their wagon camp (they having teams freighted with cotton &amp; Tobacco.) was attacked by it is presumed the same men, who stole a horse, a full suit of clothes &amp; other articles. The same day, I learned from other sources, that these same me, had been in Troy, Tenn. on Sunday morning and that they are known to citizens of that place -- that they committed some depredations there and said they going to Hickman that night. They are represented to me, as Home Guards or as recruits affecting to belong to the 13th Tenn. Cav. a Regiment now trying to be raised by one Col Bradford, but not yet mustered into service. Such were my suspicious, when I first saw them; but I may be mistaken.</p>
<p>I caused a full report to be made out and sent to Col Waring Commanding at Union City. He is a gentleman, a man of strict integrity, a lively sense of justice and a gallant soldier. I have no question, but that he has already taken action in the premises. Still his force is too small to afford full protection agt such marauders and assassins They are unprincipled men who plunder alike from friends &amp; foes. Thus in fact bringing reproach upon the armies of the Republic. This is the second or third<pb/>
<lb/>time that we have been thus annoyed.</p>
<p>For the correction of this great &amp; growing evil, I must confess, that I see no other remedy, than the organization of the Militia and the calling of the same into service by draft. As I advised in a former letter, this draft should embrace the counties of Fulton, Hickman, Graves, M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracken, Ballard, Marshall &amp; Calloway. the whole to be under the command of a competent Major General and put into active service. Without this, there will be no security. no peace for the citizens. As a further illustration of this state of thigns. I may say, that some four weeks since, on a Sunday morning, I was forcibly abducted by four soldiers of the 4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Mo Cavalry, carried out some four miles &amp; a half into a dense thicket and then robbed. I am gratified to say, that after a week spent in searching them out, I found the men, who were immediately sent in irons to Columbus and from thence to Alton. It is but right to say, that Genl Smith Commanding at Columbus, &amp; Col J K Mills then in command at Union City were uniting in the efforts to secure the robbers.</p>
<p>It then is not sufficient power to order out the militia in the manner suggested a special act ought to be passed to meet the emergency.</p>
<p>With great respect
<lb/>Your Obt Servt
<lb/>Geo C Hallet
<lb/>Col 40<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky M.<pb/></p>
<p>Respectfully referred to Ins. Genl. Lindsay</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">John Boyle</hi>
<lb/>Adjt. Gen of Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
