<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1324"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Owen Conway to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10792</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-226 to MG21-227</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Carlisle, Nicholas County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-08">August 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency, Beriah MaGoffin, Governor of the Comth. of Kentucky:</p>
<p>Your Petitioner, Owen Conway, would respectfully represent and state, that at the <date when="1861-03">last March</date> term of the Nicholas Circuit Court, he was fined Sixty dollars for keeping a Tippling House.</p>
<p>He states he was a working hand on a Turnpike Road near Carlisle, and kept some whiskey in his shanty_ on one or two occasions he let a fellow labourer or two have some of his whiskey, and they paid him for it, knowing he was poor and not able to let them have whiskey for nothing. Your petitioner did not know it was an offence against the penal laws, and had no idea of being presented for it: but one of his countrymen fell out with ^him^ and maliciously went before the Grand Jury and presented him.</p>
<p>Your petitioner says he is poor, and has a family, and it will greatly oppress him to be compelled to pay it: He therefore, respectfully solicits Your Excellency to remit said fine, and will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Owen Conway</hi></p>
<p>Carlisle,
<lb/><date when="1861-08">August 1861.</date></p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Nicholas County respectfully unite in requesting the Governor to remit the fine mentioned in the foregoing Petition. We know Mr. Conway, and believe him to be an orderly, sober and good conditioned Irishman,<pb/>
<lb/>is poor, and has a wife and three children to support -- </p>
<p>William Nowell
<lb/>W J. Statt
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Benj</hi> <hi rend="underline">F.</hi> <hi rend="underline">Edwards</hi>
<lb/>B. S. Miller
<lb/>Jno A. Campbell
<lb/>Charles Neal
<lb/>J. B. Holladay
<lb/>W. W. Howard
<lb/>A. J. Banta
<lb/>C W Congleton
<lb/>Oscar. F. Orr
<lb/>J Z Morgan
<lb/>Joel Howard
<lb/>F W Hills
<lb/>M Berry
<lb/>J J Ostill
<lb/>Rob<hi rend="sup">t</hi> C. Hall
<lb/>Nelson Hedd
<lb/>Thomas Banton
<lb/>Elizah Coons<pb/></p>
<p>Nicholas Cir Ct
<lb/>$60. } Tipling
<lb/>O. Conway</p>
<p>Respite 12 Mos
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-08-14">Aug 14 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
