<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1265"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Virginia Ingram to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10733</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-136 to MG21-137</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Orangeburg, Mason County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-07-10">10 July 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Govenor
<lb/>Mason Co
<lb/>Orangeburg <date when="1861-07-10">July 10^th^</date></p>
<p>I scarcely know how to address one in your position though I hope you will grant my request I thought I would write this time myself though I could not have as much influence as Col Stanton C Throop. you will sipathize with a female more than the other sex. Col Stanton C Throop were out here and heard the nature of the <hi rend="str">from</hi> case from one of the witnesses as well as from myself - - - it is this my husband was tried for cursing a woman he called her names which was proven and threatened to strike her but did not strike nor attempt to strike<pb/>
<lb/>Col Stanton says it was not a breach though the verdict find him fifteen days imprisiment they took Mr Ingra to jail and he remained there one day and night the following day. the same magistrate that tried him went to maysville with Mr Thomas Glasscock and took Mr Ingra out of Jail for a new trial this was on Wednesday the tue^s^day coming he was to be tried if Mr Long was fined 13 days imprisiment he did not attend his trial there for they could not get him as he left the country I think liberty is liberty so if a prisenor is not placed under guard he is free I also thought no one had -- <pb/>
<lb/>the power to take a prisoner from confinement but the Govenor, unless it was for a money fine Now your simpathy my husband could not come home ^untill^ his babe Oh a darling babe was sick and the citizens looked for it to die the Doctor had very little hope the officer told others The father might come home to see his dying babe if he would leave after he seen the result of his babe I wrote to him on Staturday <hi rend="str">eveng</hi> eaveing and he came home in the night midnight he stayed untill friday when our babe died. The Constable come in our house and told Mr Ingram he would not disturb him if he would leave after he burried his babe. so his children three in nuber a daughter 12 years and 2 sons and wife had to to be left a lone after parting with her infant, it is hard though our savior said Father forgive they know not what they do as we must also -- Now I wish you to respond to this though it is not formed as it might of been but you will excuse please have mercy on us and be so kind as to grant this favor and request I am not well nor was not before my babe death Oh it is so hard to stay alone I hope this will cause you to sympathize as some as my father would with me I repeat Oh please release my husband so he can come home he is in fleming County it was not fair as you may rely on my statement did the officer have any right to let him stay at home while his babe was sick excuse this I will be thankfull if you will release my husband it is hard to have to leave ones County</p>
<p>V Ingram<pb/></p>
<p>To the Govenor <gap/> Respectfully to your mercy and kind^ness^. Virginia Ingram</p>
<p>Mason J. P.
<lb/>15 days Imprisonment
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Ingram</p>
<p>Remission Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-07-12">July 12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi>. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
