<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-033-0007"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James F. Robinson, First Lieutenant, Asa Beldon</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11558</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Andrew P Patrick</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>1st - 2nd Regiments Kentucky Cavalry Muster Rolls</collection>
      <idno>Box 45, Bundle 1</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-05-10">10 May 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Commission/Appointment</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>IN THE NAME AND BY THE AUTHORITY OF
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky,
<lb/><figure type="seal"><ab>KENTUCKY
<lb/>UNITED WE STAND DIVIDED WE FALL</ab></figure>
<lb/>JAMES F. ROBINSON,
<lb/>GOVERNOR OF SAID COMMONWEALTH,</p>
<p>To all whom these Presents shall come, Greeting:</p>
<p>Know Ye, That Asa Beldon having been duly appointed to the office of Commissary, with rank of 1st: Lieutenant In the 1 Cavalry Regiment of Kentucky Volunteer Militia, organized under the Acts of the General Assembly of the Commonwealth and to be mustered into the service of the United States:</p>
<p>NOW KNOW YOU, That, by the powers vested in me by the Constitiution and Laws of said State, and reposing special trust and confidence in your patriotism, valor, fidelity, and ability, I do, by these presents Commission you as 1st Lieutenant as aforesaid, for the term of <hi rend="underline">three years</hi> unless sooner discharged, upon condition that you take the oath indorsed hereon, within ten days from receipt hereof, send=ing a certificate thereof to General Headquarters; and I do hereby authorize and require you to discharge, all and signular, the duties and services appertaining to your said office, agreeably to law and general regulations, and to obey such orders and instructions as you shall, from time to time, receive from your superior officers.
<lb/><note place="body">Cancelled</note></p>
<p><figure type="seal"><ab>SEAL OF KENTUCKY
<lb/>UNITED WE STAND DIVIDED WE FALL</ab></figure></p>
<p>In Testimony Whereof, I have hereunto set my name, and caused the seal of the State of Kentucky to be affixed, at Frankfort, the <date when="1863-05-10">Tenth day of May, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and sixty=three</date> and in the eighty=seventh year of the Indpendence of the United States of America.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J. F. Robinson</hi> </p>
<p>BY THE GOVERNOR:
<lb/>D. C. Wickliffe, Secretary of State.</p>
<p>Commonwealth Office -- WM. E. HUGHES, State Printer.<pb/></p>
<p>OATH.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>I <gap/> do solemnly swear, that I will faithfully support the Constitution of the United States and the Constitution of the State of Kentucky, and will discharge, all and singular, the duties and services appertaining to the office of <gap/> in the Kentucky Volunteer Militia, agreeably to law and general regulations, and will obey such orders and instructions as I shall from time to time receive from the proper officers,</p>
<p><gap/></p>
<p>Before me, personally appeared the above <gap/> and made the oath above written, and signed the same in my presence.</p>
<p><gap/>
<lb/><gap/>A. D. 186<gap/><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><figure type="seal"><ab>UNITED WE STAND, DIVIDED WE FALL.
<lb/>KENTUCKY</ab></figure>
<lb/>Head-Quarters Ky. Volunteers,
<lb/>ADJUTANT GENERAL'S OFFICE,
<lb/>Frankfort, <date when="1863-05-14">May 14, 1863 </date></p>
<p>This is an original appointment</p>
<p><hi rend="str"><gap/> is entitled to act and receive pay under this Commission from the date of its actual receipt and acceptance by him, or of his actual entry on duty under the same after its receipt, provided <gap/> has at the time been actually relieved from duty with his command. The Commanding Officer of the Regiment will endorse hereon a certificate of the date of actual relief from duty of said <gap/> and of the receipt of said <gap/> of this Commission, his acceptance of the same, or his entry upon duty hereunder. These facts should also be stated upon the muster for pay rolls of the next ensueing periodical muster.</hi></p>
<p>John W. Finnell
<lb/>Adjutant General Kentucky Volunteers</p>
<p>1 Cav<hi rend="sup">y</hi><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Lt. Beldon<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Com cancelled <date when="1863-06-06">June 6. 1863</date><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Cancel and Send to Elijah Cox -- 
<lb/>J W F</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
