<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0694"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John T. Masshet to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10162</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-46 to MG19-47</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Newport, Campbell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-02-13">13 February 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Newport Ky <date when="1861-02-13">Feb 13 /61</date></p>
<p>To The Hon B. Magoffin
<lb/>Governer of Kentucky</p>
<p>Dear Sir</p>
<p>Having being Summon for the Commonwealth against E. J. Hooper for saleing Liquer without Licence Mr F. Stageman and myself wee have only seen him sell at the differnd times, The Jury Accordingly assets the find at Sixty Dollars and Cost, I would say that I have nown Mr Hooper for more then Thirty years he is high minded Gentleman in every respect, he has been a man of wealth, but my misfurtion in trading has become poor, I well now that he has not the money to pay the find, if the Officers would goe in his House and take his furniture it would leave him in distresss<pb/>
<lb/>Mr Hooper was occuping a very pleasent Summer residence near the City, he was perswadet by his neibors to open a Summer Garden, I now myself that he was oppose <hi rend="str">to</hi> in selling intoxicating Liquors, because he is a temrence Man I was living at the time withen a hundred feet of his Garden, I was in and out every day i dont beleave he has sold a quart of Liquor, during the two weeks he kept Garden open I would not had written to you if would be a chartible Act for your Honer to remitt the find,</p>
<p>For the truth of my assertion i would refer you to Hon G. B. Hodge Member of the Legislator, and Col Thos. L. Jones C -- Col Jas Taylor all of with is respectfully submitted to your Honer</p>
<p>Your Very Truly</p>
<p>Jno. T. Masshet
<lb/>F Stagman</p>
<p>Please address to
<lb/>Jno. T. Masshet
<lb/>Newport
<lb/>Ky<pb/>
<lb/>Campbell 
<lb/>Cir. Ct
<lb/>$60. } Tipling
<lb/>E. J. Hooper</p>
<p>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-02-15"><hi rend="underline">Feby 15. 1861</hi></date></p>
<p>Respite 12 mo
<lb/>B. M</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
