<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0956"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. William C. Dorsey et al., Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10424</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-513 to MG19-516</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Pendleton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-07-12">12 July 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">1</note>
<lb/>Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>Pendleton County &amp; Circuit } Sct</p>
<p>Pleas before the Honorable Saml M Moore Judge of the Pendleton Circuit Court on the <gap/> day of <date when="1861-04">April 1861.</date></p>
<p>The Commonwealth of Ky plaintiff
<lb/>against } Recognizance
<lb/>Wm C Dorsey &amp; others defendants</p>
<p>Be it remembered that at a circuit court began and held in and for the county of Pendleton on the <date when="1860-10-18">18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of October 1860</date> the following order was made herein towit,</p>
<p>This day came the atty for the commonwealth and and the defendant failing to appear it is ordered that his recognizance with Saml F Swoope M Mullins E W Knight and A G Roberts his sureties be forfeited, and that summons issue against against them returnable to the first day of the next term,</p>
<p>The following is the bond Refered to W C Dorsey in custody charged with the offence of attempting to intice away Slaves from the State of Kentucky into the State of Ohio and being allowed to give bail in the sum of Five hundred Dollars ($500.00) now we M Mullins E W Knight S. F Swoope &amp;, A. G. Roberts hereby undertake that the aboved named W. C Dorsey will appear in the Pendleton Circuit Court on the first day of its next October term to answer said charge and will at all times render himself ameniable to the orders and process<hi rend="str">es</hi> of said court in the prosecution of said charge and if convicted will render himself in Execution thereof or if he shall fail to perform either of these<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">2</note>
<lb/>conditions that we will pay to the Commonwealth of Kentucky the Sum of five hundred dollars Witness ower hands this <date when="1860-09-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of September 1860</date></p>
<p>M Mullins
<lb/>Edward W Knight
<lb/>Saml F Swoope
<lb/>A. G. Roberts</p>
<p>Acknoweldged before me, Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> J Hudnall Presiding Judge of the Pendleton County Court this <date when="1860-09-01">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> day of September 1860</date></p>
<p><hi rend="str">O</hi> On the <date when="1861-02-19">19<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of Feby 1861</date> a Summons issued on the foregoing Recognisance which was returned Executed on M Mullins S F Swoope &amp; A G Roberts on the <date when="1861-02-21">21<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Feb 1861</date> and on E W Knight <date when="1861-03-04">March 4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>At a Circuit Court held as aforesaid on the <date when="1861-04-15">15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of Aprill 1861.</date> The following order was made herein towit)</p>
<p>This day came the parties by their attorneys and the defendants tendered their answer herein which is filed and the plaintiffs demurred to the defts answer and the cause Submitted on demurrer</p>
<p>The folloing is the answer Refered to in the foregoing order</p>
<p>Pendleton Circuit Court
<lb/>Commonwealth of Kentucky, Plaintiff
<lb/>vs } Answer
<lb/>W. C. Dorsey defendant</p>
<p>The defendants for answer to the Scifa &amp;c Say that said defendant W.C. Dorsey since the recognizance &amp;c has been found insane by a court of<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">3</note>
<lb/>competent Jurisdiction in the state of Ohio (towit) The probate Court of Hancock County in said state and by the Judgement of said court was committed to the Lunatic Asylum of said State as an insane person and has been and was so, found insane at the time of the forfeiture of the Recognizance at the last term of this court, and has been held and Kept in custody in said asylum as an insane person as appears by the record and proceeding of said court filed and therefore has failed to appear before this court and defendants have been unable to produce him here</p>
<p>Sam<hi rend="sup">l</hi> F Swoope
<lb/>Att for defts</p>
<p>A. G Roberts says he believes the Statements of the foregoing answer are true</p>
<p>A G Roberts</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by A. G Roberts <date when="1861-04-16">Aprill 16<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>Att, M, Mullins Clk</p>
<p>The following is the Proceeding of the Probate Court of Hancock County Ohio as Refered to (Towit)</p>
<p>Be it remembered that on the <date when="1860-09-04">4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of September A. D 1860</date> the following Statement was filed in the Probate Court of Hancock County Ohio towit) The State of Ohio Hancock County Ss</p>
<p>The undersigned a Citizen of Hancock County Ohio being duly sworn says that he believes William C Dorsey is insane and hi<hi rend="str">a</hi>s <hi rend="str">been</hi> insaneity is of less than two years duration and his being at large is dangerous to the community and to himself. He has a legal settlement in Allen Township in said County dated the<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">4</note>
<lb/><date when="1860-09-04">fourth day of September 1860</date> W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Dorsey Sworn to and Subscribed this <date when="1860-09-04">4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of September 1860</date> before me</p>
<p>J H. Barr Probate Judge</p>
<p>Thereupon the following writ was issued to the Sheriff of said County; The State of Ohio Hancock County ss, To the Sheriff of said County Greeting Whereas on the <date when="1860-09-04">4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of September 1860</date> William Dorsey made a statement under Oath that he believed that William C Dorsey was insane that his being at large is dangerous to himself and to the community you are therefore hereby Commanded to arrest and Safely keep the said W. C. Dorsey in the Jail of Said County and that you have him before the Probate Court of said County on the <date when="1860-09-07">7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of September 1860</date> for the purpose of investigating said alledged insanity and until he is discharged by a due course of law <hi rend="str">of</hi> witness my Signature and the seal of said court at Findlay this <date when="1860-09-04">fourth day of September 1860</date></p>
<p><figure type="seal"/>
<lb/>J H Barr Probate Judge</p>
<p>Probate Court Hancock County Ohio <date when="1860-09-07">Sept 7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1860</date> Sheriffs return of writ <hi rend="underline">Recd</hi> this writ <date when="1860-09-04">Sept 4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1860</date> and according to the within command I did arrest the within named W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> C Dorsey &amp; lodge him in Jail and have him now present in court <date when="1860-09-07">September 7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1860</date></p>
<p>J M. Neibling Sheriff, H C, O,</p>
<p>Thereupon the following witnesses were sworn and Examined Charles Oesterlin a Practicing<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">5</note>
<lb/>Physician of Said County and William W Siddall, Thereupon Said Charles Oesterlin Medical witness made the following written Report (as required by law)</p>
<p>The State of Ohio Hancock County ss. I Charles Oesterlin a Practicing Physician of Said County and State, Having Examined personally William C Dorsey of the County and state aforesaid, do find that he is laboring under insanity He is free from any infectious disease and <unclear/> he is about (20 years old and had a short attact of insanity about one year ago has been melancoly at times and showed Symptoms of his present insanity some two months since The supposed cause of his disease is heriditary has never been subject -- Epilipsy has been violent to his friends has had no medical treatment</p>
<p>Signed, Charles Oesterlin</p>
<p>Sworn to and subscribed this <date when="1860-09-07">7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of September 1860</date></p>
<p>J H Barr Probat Judge</p>
<p>And on the <date when="1860-09-07">7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of September 1860</date> The following entery was made in the Probte Court to wit,</p>
<p>In the Matter of the insanity of William C Dorsey, after hearing the proofs and allegations in this matter. It is considered by said Court that William C Dorsey is insane and that he is Entitled to the provisions made by law for the Benefit of insane persons, Therefore a transcript of Said <hi rend="str">judgement</hi> proceedings was forwarded to the Superintendant of the Asylum, at Columbus Ohio and afterwards on the <date when="1860-09-15">15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of September 1860</date><pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">6</note>
<lb/>The Superintendant of the Lunatic Asylum at Columbus Ohio ordered Said patient to be Sent to said Asylum, Thereupon the following Warrant was issued to the Sheriff of Hancock County The State of Ohio Hancock County ss Office of the Probate Judge of said County To J M Neibling Sheriff of Said County all the proceedings prescribed by law to Entitle William C Dorsey to be admitted to the lunatic Asylum having been had you are Commanded forthwith to take charge of and convey said William C Dorsey to the Asylum at Columbus, and you are <hi rend="str">therefore</hi> authorized to take William Dorsey as assistant, after executing this warrant you Shall make due return thereof to this office Witness my hand and official seal this <date when="1860-09-15">15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of September 1860</date></p>
<p><figure type="seal"/>
<lb/>J H Barr Probate Judge</p>
<p>And Said warrant was returned Endorsed as follows Lunatic Asylum Columbus Ohio <date when="1860-09-15">September 15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1860</date> Received this day of J M Neibling W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi>. C Dorsey</p>
<p>R Hills Supt</p>
<p>The State of Ohio Hancock County ss</p>
<p>I J H Barr Judge of the Probate Court in and for the County of Hancock and State of Ohio (Said Court being a Court of Record) and the Judge being also Clerk of his Court do certify the foregoing to be a true copy of the proceedings and of the record made in Said Court in the foregoing case of<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">7</note>
<lb/>insanity and that the Same was made agreable to the laws of Ohio in Such cases made and provided, Witness my signature officially and the Seal of Said court at Findlay this <date when="1860-10-12">12<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of October A D 1860</date> J. H. Barr Probate Judge</p>
<p><figure type="seal"><ab>Probate Court Hancock County
<lb/>Ohio</ab></figure></p>
<p>The following is a copy of the Superentendents ^certificate^ of the Lunatic asylum (towit)</p>
<p>Central Ohio Lunatic Asylum
<lb/>Columbus O <date when="1860-09-17">Sept 17<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1860</date></p>
<p>I hereby certify that W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> C Dorsey was admitted into this asylum as an insane <hi rend="str">person</hi> patient on the <date when="1860-09-15">fifteenth of this month</date> upon the legal proceedings and decision of the Probate Court for the County of Hancock and State of Ohio. I further Certify that from observation made Since his admission I have no doubt that he is now insane</p>
<p>Given under my hand and the Seal of the Asylum the day and date above written</p>
<p><figure type="seal"><ab>Lunatic Asylum at
<lb/>Columbus Ohio</ab></figure></p>
<p>R Hills M, D
<lb/>Superintendent of the Central O Lunatic Asylum</p>
<p>The following is the Judgement of a Circuit Court held ^as aforesaid^ on the <date when="1861-04-17">17<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of Aprill 1861</date> (To wit)</p>
<p>This day came the parties by their attorneys and the plffs demurred to the answer<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">8</note>
<lb/>Which being considered was sustained and leave to defts to amend and failing to answer It is adjudged by the court that the plaintiff Recover of the Said Defendants $500, the amount of the forfeited recognizance together with cost herein expended and defendants except and prayed an appeal which is granted</p>
<p>Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>Pendleton County } Sct</p>
<p>I Matthew Mullins clerk of the circuit court for the county aforesaid do certify that the foregoing eight pages including this page contains a correct and complete transcript of the record of the case as the same is of record &amp; on file in my office Given under my hand this <date when="1861-07-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day July 1861</date></p>
<p>M Mullins ck</p>
<p>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Transcript Record
<lb/>W C Dorsey &amp;c</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
