<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1442"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Paul Garris et al., Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10910</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-1 to MG22-2</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Nelson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Nelson Cir. Court. <date when="1861-09">Sept. Term 1861.</date>
<lb/>Commth. of Ky. Plff.
<lb/>against } Larceny,,
<lb/>Paul Garris. Defd</p>
<p>Defendant not appearing though called. It is ordered that the Bail Bond be and the same is hereby declared forfeited, and that process issue thereon, and on further motion of Plantiff ordered that a Bench Warrant issue against the Defendant endorsed that he be admitted to Bail in the sum of $600 for his appearance.</p>
<p>Nelson Cir. Court, <date when="1862-03">March Term 1862</date>
<lb/>Commth. of Ky. Plff.
<lb/>against } Forfeiture of Bail Bonds.
<lb/>Paul Garris, Jos Henin. &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi> Defd.</p>
<p>The Process herein having been duly executed and the Defend. not appearing, It is ordered and adjudged by the Court, that the Plaintiff recover of the Defendant Jos. Henin, the Sum of Four Hundred Dollars, the amount of the Bail Bond forfeited herein, and the Costs hereof and may have Execution &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi></p>
<p>Nelson Cir. Court, <date when="1861-09">Sep. Term 1861.</date>
<lb/>Commth. of Ky. Plff
<lb/>against } Enticing negroe
<lb/>Paul Garris. Defd</p>
<p>Defendant not appearing though Called. It is ordered that the Bail Bond be and the same is hereby declared forfeited, and the Process issue thereon, and on further motion of Plaintiff it is ordered that an Alias Bench warrant<pb/>
<lb/>issue endorsed, that he be admitted to give Bail in the Sum of Three Hundred Dollars for his appearance.</p>
<p>Nelson Cir. Court, <date when="1862-03">March Term 1862</date>
<lb/>Commth. of Ky. Plff.
<lb/>against } Forfeiture Bail Bond
<lb/>Paul Garris, Jos Henin. &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi> Defd.</p>
<p>The process herein having been duly served on the Defd. Jos. Henin, and he not appearing, It is ordered and adjudged by the Court, that the Plaintiff recover of the Defendant Jos. Henin the Sum of Five Hundred Dollars, the amount of the Bail Bond forfeited, and the costs herein expended and may have Execution &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi></p>
<p>The foregonig, are true Copies.
<lb/>Att:
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Wm Murphy C. N. Cir Co</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Comth of Ky.
<lb/>v. } Record
<lb/>Paul Garris &amp;c</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
