<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3097"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas Ruth et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5216</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-253</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Governor Thomas E Bramlette</p>
<p>We the undersigned jurors who were selected to try the issue between The Commonwealth plaintiff an Elisha Lunsford Defendant on an Indictment for Grand Larceny. Would respectfully represent to your excellency that notwithstanding, that we a jurors on our oath said that the defendant was guilty of the charge in the indictment, and we affixed his punishment at one year's confinement in the penitentiary, the lowest period. We would have been glad to have acquitted him if we could have done so and saved ourselves.</p>
<p>The proof before us was that the defendant in a fit of intoxication took from the drawer of his former employer (John Lucas) about five dollars and sixty five cents. ^<hi rend="str">from</hi>^ <hi rend="str">the drawer from of his former employer</hi> at the time he was drinking and very drunk so much so to be incaple discriminating correctly between right and wrong. his character hitherto had been unimpeached. He was among the first of the volunteers in the 7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Regt of Ky Infty under the command of Co<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> T. T. Garrard and by his soldierly bearing won the Respect and confidence of his comrades in arms and was promoted from the ranks to the grade<pb/>
<lb/>sergeant for meritorous conduct. And was honorably discharged after three years service during which time there is not a single act of his to even raise a suspicion against his character We therefore ask Your excellency in the plenitude of Mercy to pardon Elisha Lunsford</p>
<p>Thomas Ruth
<lb/>Willis D Sesermon
<lb/>Harvy Delf
<lb/>John L Coldinn
<lb/>Silas Davidson
<lb/>Ethan Allen
<lb/>James Miller
<lb/>Elijah M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Gee
<lb/>Robert Hensly
<lb/>Levi Asher</p>
<p>Gov Bramlette</p>
<p>Dear Sir Elisha Lunsford served his country well in the 7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Infantry I knew him in the service and he may have been so much intoxicated that he did not know what he was doing when he took the money if you will pardon him I believe every person will be satisfied</p>
<p>Your friend Truly
<lb/>Granville Pearl</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
