<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-153-0097"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Boyle to Lorenzo Thomas</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14219</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Assistant Adjutant General Letter Book - No. 1 ; 5 Sept 1863 - 2 Feb 1864</collection>
      <idno>449 to 452</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-12-21">21 December 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">449</note>
<lb/><date when="1863-12-21">December 21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> <gap/>3</date>
<lb/>Brig Genl Lorenzo Thomas
<lb/>Adjutant General U. S. A.
<lb/>Washington City
<lb/>General -- </p>
<p>In compliance with the resulition of the General Assembly of Ky, his Excellency Gov Bramlette, has directed one to place before the Federal Authorities the following:</p>
<p>The records of this office show that Kentucky has placed in the field 37,<unclear>636</unclear> men for three years -- 13,679 men for one year and 3737 men for shorter periods -- making a total of 55,052 -- accompanying herewith are schedules marked A. B. C. D. E. F. showing the exact number of men furnished for the various periods, with a recapitulation of same. For peculiar reasons Kentucky was authorized to raise men for one years service by Special act of Congress, to the number of 20,000 -- under this authority near 10,000 have been already recruited -- the exact number<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">450</note>
<lb/>cannot be given as it is daily increasing -- more than two thirds of whom have been already mustered into the U. S. service -- one regiment of heavy artillery is being recruited -- and recruiting for the <unclear/> <unclear/> is progressing.</p>
<p>As will be seen by the accompanying <unclear/> <unclear/> resolutions of the General Assembly -- it is <unclear/> <unclear/> to correct the disparity between ours <unclear/> <unclear/> and obtain the exact credit to which we think ourselves entitled.</p>
<p>The calls for troops by the General Government of 1861 and 1862, we understand was based on the <unclear>census</unclear> <unclear/> of 1860 -- From the population of Kentucky capable of bearing arms -- in the beginning of the War. There should be deducted 17000 men -- the number supplied from the best <hi rend="underline">data</hi> at command, to have originally joined the rebel armies -- this is above one eighth of our militia and is the number which calculations by reliable authorities have <unclear/> assumed to have so <unclear/>.</p>
<p>In obedience to the above named resolution, and the direction of the Govr, I have the honor to submit the following in your consideration and answer -- <pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">451</note></p>
<p><note place="left margin">1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi></note> That the quotas of Kentucky for 1861 &amp; 1862 be so far modified as to allow for the <unclear/> for the fighting population -- the <unclear/> assurance by the General Government in assigning such quotas of 17000 men or more than one eighth of our militia who fled beyond the jurisdiction of the state -- </p>
<p><note place="left margin">2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi></note> That you be kind enough to communicate the number of men so consisted, if possible, required from Ky, under the call up to this date -- </p>
<p><note place="left margin">3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi></note> That if customary with other states, you communicate the ratio of the relative value of the various terms of service -- That is how many men for the various short terms of service <unclear/> against as equivalent for one three years man, and if such value is determined, the compliment of Kentucky <unclear/> to the <unclear/> of three year service</p>
<p><note place="left margin">4<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi></note> That you be kind enough to suggest some plans by which the rolls of the War Department, and your own, may be made to <unclear/> -- and the large discrepancy exisiting between them be rectified -- In this correction, it may be stated that the disparity of numbers may be considerably <unclear/>, if those who are mustered into state service, and<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">452</note>
<lb/>some disabled by Wounds or are Killed before their commands are received by the U. S. <unclear>se</unclear>rvice be credited to the State or certified from this office.</p>
<p>Your early attention is especially desired to the foregoing questions, which it is <unclear/>, within your answering communication will satisfy fully the object of the <unclear>resolutions</unclear>, of the General Assembly -- In her loyalty and patriotism Kentucky faces, without distrust that was and is <unclear/> mentioned require only to be <unclear/> to meet correction by the War Department -- </p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>Your obd't servnt
<lb/>John Boyle
<lb/>Adj Gen of Ky</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
