<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0537"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. T. Davis et al. to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8989</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-353 to R4-354</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Paris, Bourbon County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-08-15">15 August 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Paris Ky <date when="1863-08-15">Aug 15 1863</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency,
<lb/>James F. Robinson
<lb/>Governor of the State of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your petitioners state that the grand-Jury of Bourbon County indicted Willoughby Scott for being a man of "bad fame", that he was arrested and entered into a bond in the sum of two-hundred Dollars ($200) with George <hi rend="str">A</hi> Parker as his surety for his appearance at the <date when="--04">April</date> term of Bourbon Circuit Court to answer the indictment against him, that said bond was <hi rend="underline">forfeited</hi> at said term, that summons issued against said Parker and judgment was obtained at the <date when="--07">July</date> term against said Parker for $200, that there were indictments found by the same grand jury against several other parties for the same offense, that none of them have ever been tried but continued from term to term, that had Scott been present his case would also have been continued, that said Scott had so acted that he could not appear to answer said "bond" without being liable to arrest by the Military, that in fact he is now in custody of the military authorities in the state of Ohio, that Willoughby Scott is insolvent. Your petitioners therefore pray that you will <hi rend="underline">remit</hi> in favor of Geo. <hi rend="str">A.</hi> Parker so<pb/>
<lb/>much of the <hi rend="underline">forfeited</hi> bail as goes to the trustee of the Jury fund</p>
<p>R T Davis
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Geo: M Williams</hi>
<lb/>Jas W <hi rend="underline">Ingels</hi>
<lb/>Jesse. A. <hi rend="underline">Talbott</hi>
<lb/>B F Patten
<lb/><hi rend="underline">R, H, Hanson</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Hon. Jas. F. Robinson
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Bourbon Cir. Ct</p>
<p>I am satisfied from reliable statements as well as the Petition that this fine against G. Parker should be remitted</p>
<p>J F Robinson
<lb/>$200 } Recog.
<lb/>Geo. Parker
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1863-08-19">Aug 19. 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
