<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2685"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Ozias Barnes to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7322</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-316 to BR16-317</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency Govr. Thomas E. Bramlette</p>
<p>Your petitioner Ozias Barnes states that a Judgment has been rendered at this present term of the ^Russell^ court for $100. Upon an Indictment for malicious stabing. The facts are as follows. One David Wallen citizen after mustered out took by force from your petitioner a waggon load of corn. This corn was in the possession of one W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Wilson petitioners agent was charged with the duty &amp; trust of<hi rend="str">f</hi> selling out the corn. When Wilson asked Wallen to pay for the corn he beat Wilson until his life was despaired of &amp; told Wilson that if petitioner ever asked him for pay for the corn he Wallen would pay him in the same way he had paid Wilson. Afterwards your petitioner was in the grocery at Mr. William Lucas in Jamestown Ky &amp; was drinking &amp; treating freely &amp; met with said Wallen &amp; asked him to pay for the corn at which Wallen took offense &amp; seized an And Iron &amp; he &amp; your petitioner met about <hi rend="str">halfway</hi> ^midway the room^ &amp; struck Wallen with the And Iron first &amp; your petitioner with a small pocket Knife inflicting a small flesh wound on Wallens shoulder which never disabled or laid him up for an hour. Wallen has failed to appear as witness and the Court being crowded &amp; behind &amp; your petitioner having attended the court regularly for ten days to the great neglect of his business in Wayne, without being able to get a trial at length consented to this Judgment on account of being compelled to leave the Court on other business. He prays your excellency to pardon said fine except fee &amp; costs. He was not infault but may have acted upon excitement created by spirits. W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Lucas was present &amp; saw the difficulty &amp; others who will make statements about it<pb/></p>
<p>He asks your excellency to transmit a pardon to George Bryan clerk. or to Joseph E. Hays at Jamestown &amp; he will ever pray</p>
<p>Ozias Barnes</p>
<p>We Join the petitioner in his prayer for pardon</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>I witnessed the difficulty between Barnes &amp; Wallen. I think Wallen was the aggressor &amp; struck with an and Iron before Barnes struck with the Knife</p>
<p>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Lucas
<lb/><cb n="2"/><hi rend="underline">W, M</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi><hi rend="underline">Kee. Fox</hi>
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Garnett
<lb/>N, B, Stone
<lb/>T. C. Winfrey
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> E Russell
<lb/>J A Williams
<lb/>J G Scholl
<lb/>W. T Jackman
<lb/>Reuben Payne
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Irwin
<lb/>Jno G VanWinkle
<lb/>A. P. Simpson
<lb/>W Jones
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Jones</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>I have talked to some of the witnesses and think this a proper case for Executive Clemency</p>
<p>M. H. Owsley</p>
<p>Governor Bramlette, My Dear Sir. I could get any number of singers to this petition had I the time but our sheriff starts up to day with convicts &amp; our court adjourned last evening &amp; I am short of time to get signers &amp; the proof of the difficulty. I Know by talking with the witnesses that the facts are correctly stated in the petition &amp; thinking you will not doubt my word corroborated by the statement of your special friend Lucas &amp; Major Owsley. I send the petition in haste without further preparation. In addition I can say that wallen has left here &amp; is regarded here as rather a bad man.</p>
<p>Your friend
<lb/>Joseph E. Hays<pb/>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">James Garnett Esq.</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Russell Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Ozias Barnes
<lb/>$100,
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-11-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
