<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1207"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Prewitt. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5844</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-354 to BR11-345</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-09">September 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Louisville Kentucky.
<lb/><date when="1864-09">September <gap/> 1864</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thos. E. Bramlette.
<lb/>Gov. of Ky.
<lb/>Sir.</p>
<p>I would respectfully submit that on the <gap/> day of <date when="1864-09">September</date> I was fined before the City Court Sixty -- dollars The charge was keeping a tippling House -- I was detained at home on the day of trial -- not knowing the case would come on that day. The Docket of the Court having been continued for three or four days consecutively -- I am a poor man and unable to pay the fine. It is too late to take advantage and ask for new trial which if done I could easily prove I was not guilty as charged -- the indictment was procured by Mary Barr who bore Extreme malice towards me: Had she come before the court in my presence to prove the charges I could easily have shown she was of such bad character as not to be Entitled to credit. Since the finding of the Court she has been arraigned on a charge of stealing</p>
<p>I hope Your Excellency will remit the fine. I have never been guilty as charged but on the contrary. I have always tried to obey the laws</p>
<p>William Prewitt<pb/></p>
<p>We citizens of Louisville respectfully petition your Excellency to remit the fine in the above case, Mr Pruit being a poor and deserving man</p>
<p>W. Lenning
<lb/>J. D. Hodgkin
<lb/>George C. Kofmeier
<lb/>C. A. Sleade
<lb/>George Bender
<lb/>Joseph Raibb
<lb/>Andrew Martin
<lb/>E. Metcalf
<lb/>H. Fossin
<lb/>Joseph Kampf
<lb/>Henry Block
<lb/>A. Lauber
<lb/>A. Kohlhepp
<lb/>B Stoll
<lb/>K. Metten
<lb/>D. Esselmann</p>
<p>The above who have signed the foregoing petition, are immediate neighbors to Mr Prewett who keeps a small grocery, Mrs Barr the person refered to in the petition lives in his neighborhood, and keeps a brothel. Judgment was rendered against him by default for Sixty dollars, The statute authorises a fine of $20 -- for selling one drink -- and $60 -- for selling two or more drinks. I suppose in this case, the payment of $20 -- by Mr Prewet, would not hurt him,</p>
<p>W, G, Reasor city atto<pb/></p>
<p>Louisville City Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Wm Prewitt
<lb/>$60.
<lb/>remit $40 -- of the fine
<lb/><date when="1864-10-04">4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Oct/64</date>
<lb/>Tipling</p>
<p>not examined</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
