<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2286"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Rufus K. Williams to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6923</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-151 to BR15-152</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mayfield, Graves County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-08-18">18 August 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Mayfield Ky <date when="1865-08-18">Augt 18. 1865</date>
<lb/>Governor Thos. E. Bramlett
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>Jas. C. Calhoun has been elected Sheriff of M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracken County and has qualified, but is now under military arrest and only has the limits of Paducah. The tax books are now in his hands, but unless he is released from arrest of course cannot attend to this,</p>
<p>The c^h^arges are in violation of your Proclamation and of Genl Palmers orders, as I understand,</p>
<p>Mr Calhoun was once Sheriff of this County where I was Circuit judge and he made a most faithful and impartial officer discharging his duties at all times according to law. I have known him all the time since the rebellion began he was a Southern Sympathiser but was not a violater of law his conduct was that of a peacable quiet citizen whilst here, I have every confidence that he will discharge his duties faithfully and importantly<pb/>
<lb/>As I understand it his only violation consist in hereof as candidate, he is not Expatriated by the laws of Kentucky, and I know, nor never have heard, of any act which places him under any legal disabilities.</p>
<p>We are trying to have a restoration of civil law here, and I believe there is a general disposition by all parties to have this.</p>
<p>I hope you will address Maj Genl Palmer on this Subject and have Mr Calhoun released, If he has violated any law or military order let him be regularly tried but in the mean time there is certainly no legal reason for interefering with the discharge of his official duties</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>R. K. Williams</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
