<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1543"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Sopha Knor et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11011</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-150 to MG22-154</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Campbell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-07-29">29 July 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency B Magoffin Govenor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Sop<hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>ha Knor states that her husband George Knor, was tried at the <date when="--10">oct term</date> of the Campbell Circuit court, on a charge for the killing one M Hidesman, and was found guilty of Manslaughter, &amp; Sentenced to confinement in the Kentucky Penetentiary for ten years although Sent to prison for ten years she feals that the case of the Said George presents Strong Equitable reasons in his behalf. but at the law they were of but little avail the facts are as follows. To wit, her husband had moved from the County of Pendleton abut one year before the killing afor<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">sd</hi></hi> to Campbell County. &amp; settled in the city of Newport. that he was a man of Small means, pecuniary. but through his Industry he was anabled to Suport his familey. which consisted of himself your Petitioner and one Child. they had always bor. a good name &amp; character. Boath himself &amp; wife. that the said George had business in the state of Missuri. &amp; left his wife with the said M. Hidesman. who was his Brotherinlaw to Stay until his Return, believing that the said Hidesman. would gard and protect his wife. your Petitioner, he was absent Some months. &amp; when he Returned, he was astonished to hear Reports, against the character of his said wife.<pb/>
<lb/>&amp; upon investigation of the said Report. he found, that the whole of it had orginated with the said Hidesmand. &amp; that he through mallice had Started the Sla<hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>nder. because he could not carry out a hellish wish of his own. that while her said Husband was gone. the Said Hidesman attempted to cause your Petitioner to violate her marriage vow.. that she Indignantly left his house. &amp; Refused to return. &amp; the said Hidesman. then started the Slanderious Report. either in fear of her husband, or through mallice. determined to Ruin her because She would not consent to his hellish wish. &amp; that after her husband had Returned. &amp; was living in his own house with his family in peace. the said Hidesman come to his house. &amp; come in after he had So Shamfully betrayed the trust confided to him. when the prisioner civilly Requested him to leave his house, but he Refused so to do, but began to abuse the Said George &amp; your Petitioner. when George Stabed him, with a Pockett knife. which caused his death. no person being present. Save your Petitioner who was not a legal witness, &amp; that the Said Hidesman made Some dying declarations, which threw the Blame on George. which were to the effect that George Stabed him. before he ordered him to leave but the Said Hidesman. did not tell the truth<pb/>
<lb/>when making Said s<hi rend="str">aid</hi>tatements. for your Petitioner Distinctly heard George tell him to leave and he <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> Replyed that he would not go until he felt like it, or words to that effect. through the advice of friends, who have known her &amp; the prisioner for a number of years. She makes an appeal to Your Excellency, hoping that <hi rend="str">your</hi> <hi rend="str">Clemency</hi> you will give the case of the Said George a carfull &amp; impatial hearing. &amp; that you will find Some merrit for the Interposition of the Executive Clemency. in this case from which you can pardon him, knowing you are a married man. &amp; that you would protect the Reputation of your familey. or of feemail virtue in any body. your Petitioner induced to make this appeal to you. as, the govenor of the State who views all the whole case not by the tecinacal rules. of law. but by Rules. of Equity &amp; Mercy.</p>
<p>Sopha Knor</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Sopha Knor this <date when="1861-07-29">29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of July 1861.</date></p>
<p>A G Roberts N P P C<pb/></p>
<p>Campbell Cir. Ct
<lb/>Sopha Knor
<lb/>vs } Pet. 
<lb/>Commonwealth<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Geo. Knore
<lb/>10. Yrs Penty
<lb/>manslaughter
<lb/>Pardon Iss<hi rend="sup">d </hi><date when="1861-11-14">Nov 14. 1861</date><pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of the County of Pendleton &amp; State of Kentucky State that we are well aquainted with the Petitioner Sopha Knor &amp; her husband George Knor that they had lived for a number of years in this County &amp; at all times Boar a good character &amp; the Said George has always been Regarded aS a peacible Quiete &amp; good citizen not inclined to get into difficultys &amp; from our knoledge of the parties &amp; of the killings of the man Hidesman we Join in the prayer of the Petitioner for the pardon of Said Knor -- </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>C. Duncan
<lb/>M Lockhart
<lb/>Jas. J. Hudnall
<lb/><hi rend="underline">M Mulins</hi>
<lb/>Geo W Jameson
<lb/>A G Roberts
<lb/>Nimrod Calvin
<lb/>John. S. Jacoby
<lb/>Thos Casey
<lb/>A, J, Patton
<lb/>Robt H Reed
<lb/>G M Parker
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>Waller Jeffrey
<lb/>Jas. Clayton
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Moses Summers 
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> H Casey
<lb/>Q W O Clark
<lb/>H Bullock
<lb/>H Browning
<lb/>F R Piatt
<lb/>D N Williams
<lb/>Jas A Watson
<lb/>Wm Thompson
<lb/>O N Shanks
<lb/>T E Moore Clerk. C. C
<lb/>Harvey Smith J. P. 
<lb/><unclear/> Riley
<lb/>J H Blackburn
<lb/>Robert M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kinley
<lb/>W. A. Petit<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>F R M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kenny
<lb/>C R Hiff
<lb/>F. <unclear/>
<lb/>T, W, W, DeCoursey
<lb/>E Marshal
<lb/>W C Kirkwood
<lb/>L Day
<lb/>W. W. King
<lb/>Jas W. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kenny
<lb/>John T Wyatt
<lb/>H B Gibbord
<lb/>William Gibbord
<lb/>E J <unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>Alonzo Kitt
<lb/>L C Abernathy
<lb/>W G Tumer
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>M Shepherd
<lb/>W. H. <unclear/>
<lb/>George Doel
<lb/>A J Roberts
<lb/>H. Duncan
<lb/>D. W. Yelton
<lb/>I E Lightfoot
<lb/>G. B. Raulings
<lb/>W L Stower
<lb/>P Ammorman
<lb/>A F <unclear/>
<lb/>Levi Colvin
<lb/>D L Hunter
<lb/><cb n="2"/>N. R. Colvin
<lb/>R. Stower
<lb/>F S M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>kenny
<lb/>John Chouning
<lb/>John H Bennett
<lb/>Thos. C<unclear/>
<lb/><unclear/> Shehan
<lb/>B. F. Hume
<lb/>J S. Coleman
<lb/>B L Forsyth
<lb/>B Witson
<lb/>J. W. Chany
<lb/>J H Blackburn
<lb/>J Freeman
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Murphy
<lb/>C W Keith
<lb/>W R Fisk
<lb/>Frank E Coppage
<lb/>James M Tratson
<lb/>Wm H. Lawson
<lb/>J J Pettis
<lb/>James Johnson
<lb/>J. H. Barbour
<lb/>D D Harrison
<lb/>S M Karrick
<lb/>Robert M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Cracken
<lb/>W. F. Coppage
<lb/>H. Clay Dills<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Alonzo Cookendorfer
<lb/>J. S. Bishop
<lb/>F G Reed
<lb/>David Hardman
<lb/><hi rend="str">J</hi> Minor Colvin
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>, L, Garrard
<lb/>E. S. Williams
<lb/>Peter L Forsyth
<lb/>J, M, Craffard
<lb/>W. P. Addames
<lb/>John D Keith
<lb/>David fogel
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> C. Reeder
<lb/>John Delaney
<lb/><cb n="2"/>E. A. W. Roberts
<lb/>H, A, Fitzpatrick
<lb/>P C Coyle
<lb/>Haney Gordon
<lb/>W. C. Rule<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/>
<lb/>W. L. Nowell
<lb/>R. H. Browning (Esq)
<lb/>John <unclear>S</unclear>. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kenney
<lb/>E N Gifford
<lb/>Edward W. Knight
<lb/>W. B. Wood
<lb/>James F. Browning<pb/></p>
<p><hi rend="str">Sopha Knor</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>We the undersigned citizens of the County <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>of Pendleton &amp; State of Kentucky State that we are well acquainted with the Petitioner Sopha Knor and her husband George Knor that they had lived for a number of years in this County &amp; at all times Boar a good character &amp; the Said George has always been Regarded as a peacible Quite &amp; good citizen not inclined to git into difficulties &amp; from our knowledge of the parties &amp; of the killing of the man Hidesman we Joine in the prayer of the Petitioner for the Pardon of the Said Knor</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Willis Lovelace
<lb/>L. H. Sanders
<lb/>John Burnes
<lb/>W Chiles
<lb/>G Ballenger
<lb/>H. Frakes
<lb/>Amos Jayne
<lb/>Alen Jayne
<lb/>W R Porter
<lb/>A J Arnold
<lb/>T M Arnold
<lb/><unclear/> Arnold
<lb/><unclear/> J, Shiveley
<lb/>m, c. delaney
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John <unclear>Pace</unclear>
<lb/>William murrell
<lb/>Edward Donahoe
<lb/>John W Pace
<lb/>John Shireley
<lb/>J. Callen
<lb/>James H Payne
<lb/>Joseph Sreeter
<lb/>Harison Perry
<lb/>T Marion Perry
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/>
<lb/>Lewis Perry
<lb/>James Doan
<lb/>Milton Doan
<lb/>Jno Doan<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Absolom Perry
<lb/>W G Cram
<lb/>J. M. Blackburn
<lb/>G. W. Lumern
<lb/>A. Riley Esq
<lb/>J. D. Polly
<lb/>Thomas Wiggins
<lb/>Casper Gleickmann
<lb/>H Shels
<lb/>C H<unclear/>
<lb/>H T Blackburn
<lb/>W E Blackburn
<lb/>J Butner
<lb/>George Monroe
<lb/>Alexander Monroe
<lb/>J W Monroe
<lb/>G W Arnold
<lb/>J P Rust
<lb/>A J Fryer
<lb/>Elias Arnold
<lb/>William Gulick
<lb/>Joseph Gulick
<lb/>G W Egelston
<lb/>W Egelston
<lb/>J S Egelston
<lb/>E. J Egelston
<lb/><cb n="2"/>H Courtney
<lb/>W Craddock
<lb/>F Thet
<lb/>L Spiele
<lb/>N Spell
<lb/>John Hall
<lb/>Lewis Lovelace
<lb/>Joseph Gulick
<lb/>H. Summers
<lb/>K. Ott
<lb/>John Ott
<lb/>G Stemler
<lb/>A D Blackburn
<lb/>J. <unclear/>. Summers
<lb/>Wilson Wadsworth
<lb/>David Ambler
<lb/>John Ambler
<lb/>J. B. Wadsworth
<lb/>G. H. Nonemaker
<lb/>N. Lovelace
<lb/>A<unclear/> g<unclear/>
<lb/>Peter <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>foard
<lb/>Alex Lovless
<lb/>A Ford
<lb/>S. A. Wilson
<lb/>S. Ford</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
