<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0637"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Alanson Trigg, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4756</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR9-507</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Warren County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-04-05">5 April 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Warren Equity &amp; Criminal Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against
<lb/>Alanson Trigg</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Warren County in the name and by the authority of the Comwlth of Kentucky accuse Alanson Trigg of the Offense of suffering licensing and permitting his Slaves, to go at large and trade as free men, Committed as follows to wit. The said Trigg heretofore towit on the <gap/> day of <gap/> in the County aforesaid did unlawfully license &amp; permit his negro man Slaves Jerry &amp; Beverly to go at large and trade as freemen.</p>
<p>They further charge that said Trigg on the day aforesaid in said County did unlawfully permit said slaves to go at large and hire themselves out for their Own benefit against the peace and dignity of said commonwealth -- </p>
<p>W B Jones atty for the Comwlth</p>
<p>Information of
<lb/>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi>. Petty
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> J Hendrick
<lb/>R W Hendrick
<lb/>John Ewing
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Lothridge
<lb/>Benj Shirley</p>
<p>"Endorsed" A True bill S S Jones foreman
<lb/>Filed in Open Court <date when="1863-09-19">19<hi rend="sup">th</hi> August 1863</date> L L Cooke CWCC<pb/></p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Warren Equity &amp; Criminal Court <date when="1864-02">Feby term 1864</date>
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kenty
<lb/>against } Indictment for Licensing his Slaves &amp;c
<lb/>Alanson Trigg</p>
<p>This day comes the Attorney for the Commonwealth and the defendant by his Attorney who plead not guilty and therefore came the following Jury towit John Barnett Benj Ward Harden Perkins J B Hagerman W H Crabb Hiram Newton Noel Sweeney Vincent Combs W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> H Tayler Woodford Miller W C Valentine &amp; John Tygert who were elected tried and sworn and who having heard the evidence returned the following verdict towit "We of the Jury find the defendant A Triff guilty of the Offense herein charged as to both the slaves Jerry &amp; Beverly- Harden Perkins foreman- It is therefore adjudged by the court that the defendant Alanson Trigg make his fine to the Commonwealth by the payment of Eighty Dollars and the cost herein and may be taken &amp;c.</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Warren County Sct</p>
<p>The undersigned clerk of the Warren Circuit Court certify that the foregoing as a true copy of the Indictment and Judgment thereon as former in any office <unclear/> under my hand this <date when="1864-04-05">5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> April 1864</date></p>
<p>L L Cooke</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
