<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0280"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Peter Miller to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4399</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-444</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Maysville, Mason County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-11-12">12 November 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Maysville Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1863-11-12">November 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>Gov Bramlette</p>
<p>Dear Sir, At the late term of the Mason Circuit Court, I was fined for selling spiritous liquors to a slave, whose an agreed statement of facts, a copy of which together with a Copy of the judgment I enclose. I have kept a Bar in Maysville for a number of years, and have always endeavored to comply with the strict letter and spirit of the law. I knew that I had no right to sell liquor to a slave and always refused to do so without the permission of the master. I knew the boy to whom the liquor in this instance was sold, to be the slave of my neighbor Samuel W Wood, but I knew that he was hired to a free negro barber who also kept a shop a few doors from me. The negro boy came in with the barber to whom he was hired, and his temporary master told me to let him have a drink of whiskey, and supposing I had a right to do so under this authority I sold the boy a drink for himself and his temporary master. Poliltical excitement was bitter at the time and I was indicted for selling, although s w wood cared nothing about the matter, and although it was the only drink the boy ever took at my bar. I respectfully required your excellency to remit so much of the fine as by law you are permitted to do, as the balance makes a sum as large as I am able to pay</p>
<p>Respectfully Peter Miller<pb/></p>
<p>Mason Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Peter Miller
<lb/>$50 -- 
<lb/>Tipling
<lb/><date when="1863-11-16">16<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov 1863</date></p>
<p>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
