<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1373"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Paul Garris, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10841</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-310</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Nelson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Nelson Circuit Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Ky
<lb/>against } Indictment
<lb/>Paul Garris_</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Nelson County in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky accuse Paul Garris of the offence of Grand Larceny Committed as follows: The said Paul Garris on the <date when="1861-05-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Day of May 1861</date> in the County aforesaid did felloniously take steal and carry away two dresses a quantity of Jewelry and other female apparel the property of John Dawson of the value of more than four Dollars -- against the Peace and the dignity of the Commonwealth of Ky -- </p>
<p>Andy Barnett
<lb/>Atty for Comth</p>
<p>Witnesses before the Jury -- 
<lb/>Julius Hays
<lb/>G S Mock
<lb/>Jno Dawson S<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi>
<lb/>E Fard, F. Foyle
<lb/><unclear/> Dawson</p>
<p>A. Copy attest
<lb/>Wm H Slaughter
<lb/>Clk N C C</p>
<p>And in Court <date when="1861-09-24">September 24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>The Deft not appearing <hi rend="underline">tho</hi> called it is Ordered that the bail bond be and is hereby declared forfeited and that summons issue thereon.<pb/>
<lb/>And it is Ordered that an alias bench warrant issue endorsed that he be admitted to give bail in the sum of Three Hundred Dollars for his appearance -- </p>
<p>And again in Court <date when="1862-03-25">March 25<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1862</date> The process herein having been duly executed and the Defendant not appearing -- It is Ordered and alledged by the Court that the Plff recover of the Defr Jos Henin the Sum on Four Hundred Dollars the amount of the bail bond forfeited herein and the costs hereof for which Execution may issue. -- </p>
<p>A Copy attest
<lb/>Wm H Slaughter
<lb/><hi rend="underline">C N C C</hi></p>
<p>Comth
<lb/>v
<lb/>Garris -- </p>
<p>fee 50t</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
