<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2324"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Unknown, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9400</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG25-83 to MG25-84</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-07-13">13 July 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>this affiant M Shealey states that he is well aquanted with the petitioner &amp; the Prisnor Gorge Knarr &amp; the circumstances of the killing of M Hidesman he also knows that knarr left his wife with the Famaly of of Hidesman while he whent to the states of Mo &amp; that the <hi rend="str">Riff</hi> said Hidesman started a Report about the wife of knarr to the offect that men had visited her at his house &amp; that she had been gilty of Lude Licivis behavor as Indicate an mechart woman that he had a co<hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>nversation with Hidesman about said Report &amp; Remonstrated with him obout circulating said Report &amp; told him what the concequences would be if Knarr Returned &amp; found out that he had started said Report he Replyed that he did not Care a Dam that he Intended to Ruin<hi rend="str">g</hi> her caracture that she had made him mad &amp; he did not care for the concequences<pb/>
<lb/>after Knarr Returned home I at knarr Request told Hidesman that he must not Come to the House of knarr he said he would go when he felt like it &amp; would aske Knarr no boat he knows that Hidesman was kiled at the House of knarrs some few days after I had delivered the message Requesting him to stay away &amp; further this affiant states that he was sepened as a witness to prove said facts at the trial but he was at the time of the trial &amp; is yet living in Pendleton Cty &amp; on the day before the trial he was taken sick so that he could not attend</p>
<p><unclear/> <unclear/></p>
<p>sworn to before me by M Sheley this <date when="1861-07-13">13th day of July 1861</date> &amp; I verify that the affiant M Shely is a credeble witness</p>
<p>G C Lightfoot J P P C<pb/></p>
<p>John Knarr
<lb/>vs } affidavit
<lb/>Commenwealth</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
