<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1131"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John P. Harrison to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10599</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-272 to MG20-273</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-06-21">21 June 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J. P. Harrison,
<lb/><cb n="2"/>G. T. Limberg.<milestone unit="column" n="1"/>
<lb/>HARRISON &amp; LIMBERG,
<lb/>ATTORNEYS AT LAW,
<lb/>NOTARIES PUBLIC,
<lb/>And Commissioners of Deeds
<lb/>FOR SEVERAL STATES.<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Depositions taken; and all Collections prompty attended to</p>
<p>Covington, Ky <date when="1864-06-21">June 21 1864</date>
<lb/>Hon. B Magoffin;
<lb/>Dear Sir:</p>
<p>I am well acquainted with Joseph Blackwell who resides in South Covington where I was Magistrate for a year or two before my removal to this City. He is an honest, industrious man with a wife and children. He is now in Jail.</p>
<p>Our Circuit Court began its sitting on Monday when I was spoken to by Blackwell to attend to his case. I found that an important <hi rend="str">case</hi> witness was absent in Pendleton and that he, had no witnesses to attack the Prosecuting<pb/>
<lb/>witnesses character and that in fact he was unprepared for trial. I endeavored to have the case postponed for a few days, but this was refused as the Defandant had neglected to have his subpoenas issued before the sitting of the Court.</p>
<p>I am satisfied in my own mind. that the Prosecuting witness, Charles Blevin, <hi rend="underline">alias</hi> Pitts, swore falsely on the trial He acknowledged that he was an enemy of the Defandants, because the Defendant had charged him with stealing his tumblers.</p>
<p>I send you a Petition signed by the Commonwealths Attorney, the Circuit Court Clerk, and<pb/>
<lb/>by ten of the Jury- (the other two are engaged in a Felony case this morning, and I am unable to say whether they would sign or not.) and also by various members of the Bar. I also enclose letters from John G. Carlisle Esqr and R Simmons Esqr. together with Petitions signed by a large number of citizens in Blackwell's neighorhood, among whom are Joel Dedman, Squire minter, and a large number (as I know) of honest, intelligent men.</p>
<p>It will be impossible for Blackwell to pay a fine of $200. In fact it would puzzle almost any man to pay that amount, in this County.<pb/>
<lb/>If he were guilty, (which in all sincerity I do not believe) the fee to the Com. Attorney, and the costs, he will have to pay, would be a sufficient punishment,</p>
<p>With great respect, I rely with great confidence upon the belief that you will at once pardon so much of the fine as lies within your ^power to^ pardon.</p>
<p>Permit me to sign myself yours</p>
<p>Most Respectfully
<lb/>John.P. Harrison</p>
<p>Please address to my care Box 303, Covington Ky, An immediate pardon would be a great relief to his family.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
