<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2351"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Luke Dye et al. to Unknown</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9427</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG25-126</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned state that they were members of the regular Jury which tried George W Wilkinson indicted and <hi rend="str">was</hi> tried at the <date when="1861-04">April Term of the Mason Circuit Court. 1861</date> for stabbing in sudden affray without malice and not in self defence Samuel Hall, The Jury under the evidence were compelled to find a verdict of guilty against the said defendent it being clearly proved that in a sudden affray, without malice he did stab and cut one Samuel Hall, and there was not sufficient evidence to that effect to authorize the Jury to find that the act was done in self defence. At the same time there were circumstances of extenuation attending the commission of said offence, which taken in connection with the ^good^ character of the deft, and his enfeebled conditions of body, enduce the undersigned to recommend the said defendent as a proper subject for executive, clemency, and they would respectfuly recommend that his excellency ^the Governor^ <hi rend="str">to</hi> should remit that part of his punishment which consists in imprisonment in the county jail for Six months, and also so much of the five of fifty dollars as is subject to the Executive control,</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Luke Dye
<lb/>James Jacobs
<lb/>H H Bramall
<lb/>Samuel Herr
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Chas Humphreys
<lb/>J A Jackson
<lb/>W B Carroll, a Juror in the case
<lb/>James M Rogers Do
<lb/>William P. Fox do
<lb/>W Prather</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
