<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2324"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. H. Thomas et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6961</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-212 to BR15-213</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Alexandria, Campbell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-09-08">8 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thomas E. Bramlett Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky,</p>
<p>Whereas at the <date when="1865-08">August Term 1865</date>. of the Campbell Cirucuit Court, of Campbell County held at Alexandria Ky, there was a verdict returned by the jury empaneled in the Case of the Com"wth against Mathias Tritcheler on Indictment for Selling Liquors to a Minor, by which verdict the Court assessed a fine of Fifty $50 -- Dollars against said Tritcheler, the facts of the case are, a young man a Citizen of Alexandria, by the name of William Nelson testified as to having purchased liquor of the Said Tritcheler, who to all apperance was past the age of 21 years, and was as proven quite near that age from Mr Tritchelers orderly deportment who is a Tavern Keeper at<pb/>
<lb/>of this Town, "Alexandria" and quiet orderly house kept by him at this and all former time, who is and has been a law abiding man in all respects,</p>
<p>We the undersigned petitioners would most Respectfully ask your "Honor" to remit Said fine of $50<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi></p>
<p>Also the fine of ($50<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi>) Fifty Dollars assessed against Peter Ruckel at the Same Term of Said Court, who is also a Tavern Keeper at the same place, who also fully deserves your clemency, and we take pleasure in recomending two of our best Citizens for Such as in duty bound will every prey</p>
<p>Alexandria Ky <date when="1865-09-08">Sept 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>W. H. Thomas Deputy Clk Campbell County Court
<lb/>James Rardin Ex Sheriff C. C
<lb/>Joseph H Wright<pb/>
<lb/>A. Rehmer,
<lb/>C. Smith, (Merchant)
<lb/>Wm. Hartman
<lb/>Samuel Wright Foreman of both Jury<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi>
<lb/>Thoma<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Jones, Clerk Campbell <hi rend="underline">Circuit Court</hi></p>
<p>Could furnish many persons who would willingly join in this petition but enough I trust</p>
<p>Yours Truly
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Tho</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> Jones</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Campbell Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Peter Ruckel &amp; Mathias Tritchelor
<lb/>$50. each
<lb/>Selling to Minor
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-09-18">18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sept/65</date></p>
<p>Sent for fee <date when="--09-13">13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sep</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
