<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0006"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William H. Baley et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9474</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17A-42 to MG17A-44</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Caldwell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-01-22">22 January 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency. Beriah Magoffin Govenor of Ky.</p>
<p>Dear Sir -- We the citizens of the town of Princeton and acquaintances of Thomas B. Wadlington who was convicted of the crime of murder, and sentenced to be hung, at the last term of our Caldwell Circuit Court, respectfully and earnestly solicit your Excellency, that you may and will interpose your Executive clemency in his behalf, and that he be <hi rend="underline">pardoned</hi>. We will now represent unto your Excellency, a few of those reasons, which have induced us to make this appeal in his behalf.</p>
<p>Thomas B. Wadlington was born, and raised in our midst, and is now about fifty years of age -- and from childhood, up to the time of this difficulty has been a peaceable, quiet, industrious and worthy citizen of our community -- </p>
<p>Whether we consider him as a husband, father, neighbor -- citizen, or an industrious Tiller of the soil, he stood without reproach, and he had our respect -- By a jury of his country he has been found guilty of murder, and such finding has ^been^ upon an appeal, pronounced to be in accordance with the Law.</p>
<p>His son, was also, jointly indicted with him &amp; was found guilty of manslaughter, and is now confined in the Penitentiary for the same offence. -- Up to this time, that son -- a youth, was esteemed<pb/>
<lb/>by his neighbors &amp; friends &amp; the community in which he lived, for his industrious habits, &amp; his moral standing and character, he being a consistent member of the Cumberland Presbyterian Church -- And the remarkable fact is presented to your Excellency, of two citizens of such established character being presented before you, in the position of criminals condemned for murder and manslaughter. The statement of William J. Wadlington, son of Thomas B. Wadlington, is so totally different from that of the witnesses in behalf of the Commonwealth. (namely, Prince &amp; Blaylock.) upon whose testimony the aforesaid parties have been convicted and are so entirely consistent with the circumstances of the case, as shown by other witnesses, that it has impressed us strongly with the belief that our neighbor &amp; fellow citizen, under the rules of the <hi rend="underline">rigid</hi> <hi rend="underline">law</hi> <hi rend="underline">has</hi> <hi rend="underline">been</hi> <hi rend="underline">badly</hi> &amp; <hi rend="underline">hardly</hi> dealt with, and that in fact &amp; truth he is no murderer. The statements of the son William are clear and positive that Milton A. Cartwright, the D<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">ecd</hi></hi>, shot <hi rend="underline">first</hi>, and if under the rules of our law, his statement had been admitted, it appears to us that the transaction would have appeared <hi rend="str">to</hi> <hi rend="str">us</hi> in the light of a case of Self Defence. But if under and by Law the statements of the<pb/>
<lb/>youth &amp; Son, was rightfully or wrongfully excluded from the jury, in Thomas B. Wadlington's trial, yet we do think that it should come before your Excellency, and that freemen should have the right at least, to proclaim to you their wrongs, and appeal to you to redress them. The statements of the parties have been totally excluded from the consideration of the court or jury -- With this petition, you will see the statement of the unfortunate young man, as also his father's statement, made in open court, at the time of the sentence of judgement, and also the record containing the statement of the witnesses, now on file in the office of the Court of Appeals. What a conflict and how irreconsilable!</p>
<p>Let us appeal to your Excellency in behalf of the doubt, which such a conflict of statements of facts presents -- May that character which the poor man has borne for fifty years, appeal to you in his behalf. May the gray haired and honored sire, may the broken hearted wife and his three little children, through us appeal to your Excellency to <hi rend="underline">restore</hi> <hi rend="underline">him</hi> <hi rend="underline">to</hi> <hi rend="underline">life</hi>, to <hi rend="underline">liberty</hi>, to the protection of the <hi rend="underline">Hearth</hi> <hi rend="underline">Stone</hi> and that the bitter cup might be spared them, and the unfortunate accused. But should this by your<pb/>
<lb/>Excellency be deemed unadvisable, (which God forbid) may we be still allowed to ask and entreat that the life of the unfortunate man may be spared, and that his sentence be commuted;</p>
<p><date when="1861-01-22">Jany 22<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Respectfully Yours</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Will. H. Baley
<lb/>Conrad Rohrbach
<lb/>George. W. Barbour
<lb/>J. P. Roscoe
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Will. H. Miller
<lb/>D. W. M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Goodwin
<lb/>L, Pepper
<lb/>W. H. Calvert
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> H Edwards</hi>
<lb/>J R Hewlett
<lb/>A J Patterson attorney and editor of "Bulletin"
<lb/>J, P, M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goodwin
<lb/>Jesse Stevens Sheriff of Cald Cty
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> F Ingram Town marshall
<lb/>W E Mitchensson Deputy clerk Caldwell County Court
<lb/>James C. Barnes Deputy clerk of Caldwell Circuit Court
<lb/>James C Weller clerk of the Caldwell County Court.
<lb/>B, N, Dawson Constable of Caldwell County<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>E. P. Watkins clk ct ct.
<lb/>M. Dudley J. P. c. c.
<lb/>James S Lowery Jailor C C
<lb/>C. H. Ingram 
<lb/>Publisher "<hi rend="underline">Bulletin</hi>"
<lb/>C, T, Dabney
<lb/>John M Higgins
<lb/><hi rend="underline">John Y. M</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi><hi rend="underline">Lin</hi>
<lb/>L. Withers P. M
<lb/>John.G. Pettit
<lb/>R, Whittington
<lb/>R, B, Ratliff
<lb/>H. J. Evans
<lb/>Al M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goodwin
<lb/>James M Pearce
<lb/>J. Y. Chambers
<lb/>J W Harpesiding
<lb/>B J Mason
<lb/>W. S. Scott
<lb/>E. H. Daniel
<lb/>A,, Dennis
<lb/>James, ,Gale
<lb/>Perry Blount
<lb/>J, J, Wylie
<lb/>A Reynolds
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Wells
<lb/>J, H, Calvert
<lb/>James <hi rend="underline">a Carr</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
