<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0241"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">City Court of Louisville, Order</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8693</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R3-362</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Order</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><hi rend="underline">January</hi> <hi rend="underline">Term</hi> <hi rend="underline">City</hi> <hi rend="underline">Court</hi> <hi rend="underline">of</hi> <hi rend="underline">Louisville</hi>
<lb/>Com"th of Kentucky vs. Thos Sweeny, James Welch, John Turner and Bridget Kearney -- Indt</p>
<p>This day came as well the Attorney for the Commonwealth as the Defendant Sweeny, Welch and Kearny and the Defendant Turner although having executed bond with security for his appearance &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi> came not but made default which so ordered to be entered of Record. And the said Sweeny, Welch, and Kearny, for plea herein say they are not guilty in manner and form as the Commononwealth against them hath alleged, and pray this may be enquired of by the Country; and the Commonwealth saith likewise. Thereupon to try the issue joined it is ordered that a Jury come. Thereupon came a Jury, towit, John Dennison, Joseph Smith, W. C. Kennedy, M. S. Grass, Silas Gray, E Beckwith, W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Winston, Jonathan Collins Stephan Edmundson A. A. Harbison, Chas Godfrey &amp; S. W. Pugh, who having been duly elected tried &amp; sworn well and truly to try the issue joined &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi> after hearing the testimony and retiring to consult &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c </hi></hi>returned into Court the following verdict viz~"We of the Jury find the Jury find the Defendants guilty as charged in the within Indictment and assess their fine at Fifty dollars each to the Commonwealth of Kentucky" Whereupon it is ordered that the said Sweeny, Welch, and Turner, and Kearny make the fine to the Com'th by the payment of Fifty dollars, together with all costs that may have accrued herein, and that they be taken therefor &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi></p>
<p>At the same term of the Court the said Bridget Kearny was fined Twenty five dollars on an Indictment for assault &amp; Battery, tried by same Jury as above this being a separate Indictment, for the same offence<pb/>
<lb/>as in the above Indictment,</p>
<p>Attest Phil, Tomppert, Jr C C C L</p>
<p>Mrs Kearney Pettn to remit fine from Louisville
<lb/>Louisville City Ct</p>
<p>No good ground to remit all half remitted in each case</p>
<p>J F R
<lb/>$50
<lb/>$25 } Mis.
<lb/>Bridget Kearney
<lb/>Iss <date when="1863-02-09">Feby 9. 1863</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
