<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-005-0129"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">N. Sandifer to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1018</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Apprehension of Fugitives from Justice Papers, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR7-201</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Garrard County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-11-06">6 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thos E. Bramlette Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky.</p>
<p>The undersigned N. Sandifer Presiding Judge of the Garrard County Court would respectfully represent to your Honor that at the <date when="1865-02">February term 1865</date> of the Garrard Circuit Court an<hi rend="str">d</hi> indictment was found by the Grand Jury of s'd court against Green Slaughter and James Slaughter for the murder of one Absolum Pollard and that the s'd Slaughters are yet at large the civil officers of this county being unable to take them or even find them and that they are very dangerous characters; and would respectfully petition your Honor to offer a reward to the very extent of the law for the apprehension of the s'd Slaughters.</p>
<p>The description of Green Slaughter is as follows, to wit, About 35 years old, about 5 feet ten inches high, heavy set weighs about 180 lbs, black eyes, black hair and whiskers and the description of James Slaughter is as follows, to wit, about 19 years old, round face about 5 feet 6 to 8 inch high and slightly round Shouldered and heavy set; this the <date when="1865-11-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Nov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> 1865</date></p>
<p>N Sandifer P, J, G, C, C<pb/></p>
<p>Garrard Co
<lb/>Reward $500. for Judge of Garrard County Cour
<lb/>To } Petition for Reward
<lb/>James &amp; Green Slaughter
<lb/>T. E. Bramlette Gov. &amp;c
<lb/>murder of A. Pollard $250 each
<lb/><date when="1865-11-08">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov /65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
