<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2833"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. M. Reamer to Ephraim L. Van Winkle</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7470</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-114 to BR17-115</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>REMOVED TO CORNER OF SEVENTH AND MAIN.
<lb/>D. B. LEIGHT &amp; CO.
<lb/>IMPORTERS AND DEALERS IN FOREIGN AND DOMESTIC DRY GOODS,
<lb/><hi rend="str">604 Main Street, between Sixth and Seventh</hi>, Louisville, Ky.</p>
<p>D. B. LEIGHT,
<lb/>ROB'T F. COOKE,
<lb/>LATEN B. PORCH.
<lb/>Hon E L. Van Winkle
<lb/>Secretary of State
<lb/>Sir -- About the first part of July a young man employed in one of the largest retail dry goods stores of this city was arrested on the charge of having taken from the store two <hi rend="str">lb</hi> of sewing silk -- He was about From the city at the time the silk was missed &amp; was brought from Mt Washington in the state to the city &amp; had a hearing before the city court Judge He was taken completely by surprise &amp; had no time to prepare for his trial or confer with an attorney -- He was committed to await his trial at the <date when="--09">September</date> term of our Circuit Court -- The young man (his name was Earnest Cramer) had circulatd with the young men of the city<pb/>
<lb/>and made a very respectable appearance in our city -- He had host of friends to attend him in his prosperity but when he feel he was deserted by all -- I had no acquaintance with the Young man &amp; never saw him to know him until I visited him at his prison He had no one to bail him for trial &amp; perfectly crest fallen he solicited my sympathies -- He had attended regularly I understood from one of our members the Presbyterian church of Mr M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Kee and his many protestations of innocence together with the hope of reclaiming him from his errors if he had committed any <unclear/> upon me to such an extent that I was prevailed to assist him to this extent -- He had one hundred Dolls in gold which was equivalent to $140 &amp; his bail<pb/>
<lb/>amounted to $300 I advanced the remaining $150 for him, he promising me faithfully to present himself for trial on the 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> monday in <date when="--09">September</date> -- In the mean time he was to remain with a friend he had at Mt Washington -- He was a german by birth &amp; to all appearances an innocent unoffending simple person &amp; not a person who would have been thought a criminal -- Shortly before Court day I received a letter From him postmarked New York stating that he would sail in a few days for the Barbadoes, that he could not stand his trial, feeling that he was guilty, acknoweldging the crime &amp; promising to reform his life &amp; be henceforth a better man -- I enclosed this letter from him to Gov Bramlette in a previous letter on the subject &amp; is doubtless now among the papers in<pb/>
<lb/>his office -- I have not heard from since &amp; hope to be able to have that portion I advanced for his bail refunded -- The bail was forfeited at the <date when="--09">September</date> term of the Jefferson Circuit Court -- Hoping the brief statement may meet Your attention &amp; if possible relieve me from a loss I can illy stand</p>
<p>Respy Yr Obd Srvt
<lb/>J. M Reamer</p>
<p>Jefferson Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Remit -- $160 of the forfeiture -- <figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>J M Reamer
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-12-15">15 Dec/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
