<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1653"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Robert Miller to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6290</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-121</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Campbellsville, Taylor County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-03-28">28 March 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Campbellsville Ky. <date when="1865-03-28">March 28. 1865</date>
<lb/>Hon. Tho. E. Bramlet
<lb/>Gov. of Ky.
<lb/>Dear Gov.</p>
<p>On reaching here from Columbia I learn that John H. Hardin of Marion Cty. <hi rend="str">I learn</hi> has been has been convicted &amp; sentanced to the penetentiary, the circumstances attending, his conviction will be detailed to you by those who know them better than I. I do not know Mr. Hardin personally, but I have reliable information that he is an orderly citizen, has been engaged <hi rend="str">in</hi> as an officer in the homeguard service of his country, and has discharged his duty as such in a commendable manner, and for an official act done in good faith as I am credibly informed he has been prosecuted and convicted. Their is one circumstance, of his life of which I am acquainted, that goes fair to establish a good character as law abiding orderly man, -- Some time last summer or perhaps rather in the spring, of the year I had two horses stolen from my Waggon on the road not fair distant from Muldres Hill, This man Hardin being in the neighborhood suspected that he could catch the rogues &amp; get the horses<pb/>
<lb/>he gets one or two men to go with him, they went the next nite after the horses were stolen, and after wrideing a considerable distance, sure enough overhalls two men with the solen horses, they got one of the men, the other got away from them, it being in the nite -- they brought the man which they caught and the stolen horses back to new market, he was tryed by a court of enquiry, &amp; held to bail, for want of bail was commited to jail -- In this he exhibited most clearly great avertion to violation of law and good order, and a readiness to make personal sacrifice to bring bad men to justice -- This was done by Hardin because of the breach of law, good order, &amp; the crime and not for favour to me, for he had no personal acquaintance with me. ^When you shall be fully advised in the premises You will^ pardon me Governor for saying that to <hi rend="underline">my</hi> <hi rend="underline">mind</hi> this is a clear case for Executive clemency -- Inconsequence of a small portion of verbage in the large and respectable petition in his behalf shewed me this evening I could not sign it but I hartily ^&amp; most earnestly.^ join in the prayer for John ^H^ Hardin'<hi rend="sup">s</hi> pardon</p>
<p>Very Truly
<lb/>Yr. friend &amp; hum Srvt
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Rob</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> Miller</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
