<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-021-0007"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. John R. B. Watkins, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG3077</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Apprehension of Fugitives from Justice Papers, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG8-77 to MG8-78</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Greenup County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-11-12">12 November 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>At a Circuit Court holden within and for the County of Greenup and Commonwealth of Kentucky at the Courthouse of said County in the town of Greenupsburg on Monday the <date when="1860-11-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of November 1860,</date></p>
<p>The Grand Jurors empanelled and sworn in and for the body of Greenup County returned into Court an Indictment in the following words and figures viz:</p>
<p>"Greenup Circuit Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>against } Indictment
<lb/>John R. B. Watkins</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Greenup County, in the name, and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, accuse John R. B. Watkins of the crime of obtaining money under false pretenses committed as follows: The said John R. B. Watkins on the <date when="1859-09-03">3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> day of September 1859,</date> at the County aforesaid by falsely pretending and representing to Green S. Bumbass, that he the said John R. B. Watkins had bought four negro slaves in the said County, that he had a right to get them and bring them to Lexington Kentucky to the said Bumbass in Lexington Kentucky, as his slaves, obtained from the said Green S. Bumbass the sum of Four Thousand Dollars, with intent to commit a fraud upon him against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>R. B. Stanton
<lb/>Attorney for the Comomonwealth</p>
<p>Upon which Indictment is the following endorsement to it. "A True Bill Geo. Swap Foreman<pb/></p>
<p>The Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>Greenup County Court:</p>
<p>I William Corum Clerk of the Circuit Court of, Greenup County in the State of Kentucky do certify that the foregoing is a true copy of the original Indictment and the endorsement thereon as the same is found in my office.</p>
<p><figure type="seal"><ab>GREENUP CIRCUIT COURT
<lb/>UNITED WE STAND DIVIDED WE FALL
<lb/>KENTUCKY.</ab></figure></p>
<p>In Testimony whereof I have hereunto subscribed my name and affixed the seal of said Court at my office in Greenupsburg Kentucky this <date when="1860-11-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of November 1860.</date></p>
<p>William Corum clerk
<lb/>Greenup Circuit Court</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Greenup Circuit Court Sct.</p>
<p>I Elijah C. Phister Circuit Judge in and for the 10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Judicial District in the State of Kentucky and by virtue of my said office, sole Judge of the Greenup Circuit Court, being the Circuit Court of Greenup County, which is one of the counties comprising said 10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Judicial District, do hereby certify that W<hi rend="sup">m</hi>. Corum whose name is signed to the foregoing certificate is Clerk of said Greenup Circuit Court and that his signature thereto is genuine and that the foregoing attestation is in due form. Given under my hand as Judge of said Court this <date when="1860-11-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of November 1860.</date></p>
<p>E. C. Phister Judge of Greenup Ct. Ct.<pb/></p>
<p>Missouri<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Demand for Jno. R. B. Watkins "obtaining money under false pretenses"
<lb/>Is<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1860-11-16">Nov 16. 1860</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
