<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2262"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">S. W. Owens et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6899</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-97 to BR15-98</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excelency
<lb/>Thomas E. Bramlett.
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Governor of Kentucky</hi></p>
<p>I Undersigned your petitioners would represent that at the <date when="1863-10">October Term 1863</date> of the Ballard Circuit, Joseph Mansfield was tried and convicted of Keeping gameing House, and fined the Sum of two Hundred Dollars; that the said Mansfield being in Court upon the rendition of the Verdict was ordered into the hands of the Shff until he Could find Sureties for the fine and Costs; that the said Mansfield having failed to find such sureties, was about to be Committed to the Jail fo the County, when Thomas Valanding for whom the undersigned We now petition your Excelency, moved with pity, and thinking Mansfield not the worst man in the world, and unwilling to see him go to Jail undertook as Surety to the State for the fine and costs. The undersigned would farther represent, that Soon after the Debt was Secured to the State, upon the application of Mansfields friends, your Excelency interposed by respite to put off the payment of the Judgment for 12 months, and that Mansfield, then entered the Service of the Country as a volunteer in the federal army, since which time he has not returned. That upon the expiration of the 12 months, the respite expired, and execution issued upon the Bond and is now in the hands of the Sheriff and will be at once<pb/>
<lb/>Collected from Valandingham unless your Excelency Shall think proper to interpose and give him relief. The undersigned would represent to your Excelency that Valandingham is a poor man has quite a large family, and at present finds it rather difficult matter to Support them and that if he Shall be Compelled to pay the and fine and Costs it will very nearly, if not quite, result in his ruin; We hope your Excelency will interpose So far as may be in his behalf, and your petitioners will ever pray &amp;C -- </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/>S. W. Owens, for. S, B, C
<lb/>G W Utterback
<lb/>T J Juett
<lb/>C. S. Marshall
<lb/>Z W, Bugg
<lb/>F J Coffee
<lb/>J D White
<lb/>T P Garrett
<lb/>Asa Richardson
<lb/>Z Eliott
<lb/>H. C. Johnson
<lb/>W M Eliott
<lb/>L, W, Weaver
<lb/>James. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Canley.
<lb/>R, I, Logan
<lb/><unclear/> Boyers
<lb/>L R Rich
<lb/>W. H. Watson
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names
<lb/>S. L. Powell
<lb/>James L <unclear/>
<lb/>F G Cleaves
<lb/>Elisha Unsell
<lb/>O T Nichols
<lb/>J, G, Gaines
<lb/>John Woolfolk
<lb/>W, S, Watson
<lb/>M. L Stahl
<lb/>G,, O,, Haden
<lb/>C, C, Terrell
<lb/>O. Bell
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Dunst
<lb/>P. A. Bondurant
<lb/>J. C. Garrett<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Names
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Names<pb/></p>
<p>Ballard Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> Valandingham
<lb/>$200,
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/><date when="1865-08-08">8 Aug/65</date></p>
<p>Sent for fee
<lb/><date when="1865-07-20">20 July/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
