<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-027-0041"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William H. Wadsworth to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1274</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R2-67 to R2-68</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Maysville, Mason County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-09-16">16 September 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Maysville, <date when="1862-09-16">Sep 16<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1862</date>.
<lb/>His Excellency
<lb/>Jas. F. Robinson. 
<lb/>Louisville, Ky.
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi></p>
<p>Since receiving yr appointment as Commander of "the Home forces in mason" I have done what I could to provide for the defence of this part of the state. Being without arms, amunition &amp; everything else needful, I could do but little against an enemy numerous &amp; active, &amp; well mounted, able to advance quickly &amp; retreat faster than I could persue.</p>
<p>My only organized means of defense, consisted of a fragment of the 14<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky Cav., dismounted recruits, some fugitives from the invaders (about 70) partly mounted, 60 of the 7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky, Cav. &amp; my ^city^ Home Guards. The recruits for the 14<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky. Cav. amounted to nearly 700 men at M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Sterling, but retreating from that point after the battle of Richmond on foot, &amp; <hi rend="str">mainly</hi> mostly unamed, they arrived here about 300 strong -- some without coats, some without shoes, &amp; some either armed or clothed by the state or Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> -- I sent them into Camp at the expense of the state, with the straggling fugitives from the 7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky. Cav. &amp; about 70 men formed into a militia company as state troops under Capt<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">n</hi></hi> Mitchell.</p>
<p>Wednesday night last, the enemy 800 strong, under Gano, occupied Mayslick, 12 miles from here. From the misconduct of one of my own officers, I only learned the fact at 3 o'clk a.m.<pb/>
<lb/>thursday. I made my dispositions either to fight or cross the river, as I might think best; intending to adopt the latter course, if the enemy advanced in force. After day light I proceeded with the mounted men, numbering about 100 (including 60 of the 7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky. Cav.) to reco<hi rend="str">m</hi>nnoitre on the Lexington road. The 7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky. Cav. with their consistent cowardice &amp; insubordination, refused to march, or obey my orders, but <hi rend="str">broke &amp;</hi> deserted &amp; forced their way on the Ferry boat &amp; crossed to Aberdeen ^O.^ With the remainder I went as far as Washington, The enemy soon made his appearance &amp; drove in my pickets, capturing three -- the rest rallied on the support I had brought. I at once fell back slowly &amp; in order to Maysville &amp; crossed over my whole command &amp; all its small property, without haste or confusion. The enemy sent in a flag of truce, shortly after to the Mayor of Maysville demanding its surrender. The mayor replied that he had no means of resistence.</p>
<p>The rebels never occupied the town or hoisted their flag. The main body remained at Washington 'till sundown &amp; then, learning that we had joined with some of the Ohio militia, &amp; was attempting to sourround them by a movement across the Ohio river at Logan's Gap, they fell back to Lewisburgh &amp; next morning retreated from Mason County. They continued to fall back through Millersburg to Paris -- there about 300 under the rebel Cameron left Gano &amp; proceeded to M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Sterling where they are now encamped &amp; recruiting. Gano we hear went to Lexington.<pb/></p>
<p>Since my return to this city, I have examined the roads by a small force for some miles, &amp; have accurate news of the enemy as far as Owingsville, M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Sterling &amp; Paris. There is no enemy that I cannot take care of, this side of those points.</p>
<p>We hear that Humprhey Marsall is coming through the mountains. we have heard it for 10 days, &amp; have ceased to credit it, but have taken means to know all about his movements.</p>
<p>I desire authority to buy or press 500 horses &amp; two wag<hi rend="str">g</hi>ons, for the purpose of mounting that many men of the 14<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky. Cav. now in my Camp, <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> that soon will be. If I am permitted to do so, I will go to Owingsville &amp; M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Sterling &amp; break up the rebel camp, thereabouts, protect &amp; rally the people there. I have a light six pounder (iron) but wish one or two mountain Howitzer's still lighter, -- I want fixed ammunition for my gun. I have nothing. The Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> wholly neglects us: of all the regiments raised in our part of the state, not one <hi rend="str">ram</hi> remains to help us -- Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Wright took away the last (the 10<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky. Cav.) &amp; left us naked to our enemies.</p>
<p>If I can get permission to press the horses, I have the men <hi rend="str">&amp;</hi> guns &amp; equipments -- but will need ammunition. 500 mounted men, with a section of light artillery will run the rebels &amp; their recruits out of my District or destroy them.</p>
<p>Judge Bush of Clarke, R. Apperson jr, Gen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Dick <pb/>
<lb/>Williams, Van B. Young, &amp; other gentlemen are here with me<hi rend="str">n</hi>, &amp; have been the greatest comfort &amp; support in my troubles. They will help me drive the rebel marauders from their homes should you furnish us the horses. The affair requires speed.</p>
<p>Very truly
<lb/>yr obt &amp;<hi rend="sup">c</hi>
<lb/>W. H. Wadsworth</p>
<p>W. H. Wadsworth</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
