<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1141"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Martens to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5778</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-249 to BR11-250</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-08-03">3 August 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency,
<lb/>Thomas E. Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Ky.</p>
<p>The undersigned your petitioner John Masters, a citizen of Boone County, Ky, respectfully shows -- that on the <gap/> day of <gap/> he became bound as surety in a recognizance for the appearance of William Craig. at the <date when="1864-03">March term ^1864^</date> of the Kenton Circuit. to answer a charge of Larceny &amp; that said Craig had been in the employ of the Government as a teamster, and says that while so employed, he purchased 2 pairs of pantaloons of a soldier, who brought them to the house of said Craigs mother, and which pants is charged to have been stolen, and for which Craig was indicted. Said Craigs <hi rend="str">wife</hi> ^mother^ was related to your petitioner &amp; had lived at petitioners house for a time before, and family representations of innocence, which your<pb/>
<lb/>petitioner believed and still believes he became surety as aforesaid.</p>
<p>The said Craig failed to appear and the recognizance was forfeited.</p>
<p>Your petitioner would show that the <date when="1863-12">Dec. term 1863</date> at Covington, commenced with <hi rend="str">28</hi>4 -- Monday of the month, and he understood that the succeeding term -- <date when="1863-03">March</date> -- was to have commenced also on the 4 -- monday, but it did commence on the 2 -- which was the 14 -- instead of the 28 -- that he went to Covington on the 28 which he supposed was the first day of the term to see if Craig appeared, when he was supprised to learn that the court had been in session 2 weeks &amp; the bond was forfieted -- and that Craig had entered in the United states army -- &amp; had been removed to Louisville, thence to the front -- that afterwards his regiment was in the battle of Resaca, Georgia on the <gap/> day of <gap/> under Sherman, and he Craig was there wounded, then<pb/>
<lb/>removed to Nashville, thence to Louisville. where he still is in the military hospital.^that if he had known the court had commenced on the 14. he would have proceeded in appearance of Craig -- as he did not <unclear/> until the 19th -- ^</p>
<p>your petitioner say judgment was rendered against him as surity on said bond for $150 -- and $4.05 cents -- for which execution is now in the hands of sheriff of Kenton -- </p>
<p>That he is a poor man, having only a small farm of 50 acres in the hills, upon which by his <unclear/> labor -- he barely supports his <unclear/> consisting of a wife &amp; 3 ch<unclear/> -- eldest 6 years &amp; youngest 18 mo<unclear/> -- a mother aged <hi rend="str">6</hi>77 years a sist<unclear/> 39. who is a helpless invalid a sister-in-law, who is deranged -- </p>
<p>your petitioner is in his 53 year.</p>
<p>He prays your excellency to remit said judgment &amp; and in duty &amp; -- </p>
<p>John Masters</p>
<p>Sworn to by John Masters before me this <date when="1864-08-03">3 aug. 1864</date></p>
<p>A C Ellis DC
<lb/>Kenton Cir Court<pb/></p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Clerks office Kenton Circuit Court</p>
<p>B. W. Foley Clerk of said Court do certify that at the <date when="1864-06">June Term of this Court 1864,</date> Judgment was rendered against John Masters as Security of W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Craig in a Bail Bond in the Case of Comwth vs, Said Craig. for the sum of $150<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">00</hi></hi> &amp; costs $5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">55</hi></hi> and that an Execution of Fire facias is now in the hands of the Sheriff of Kenton County</p>
<p>Witness my hand this <date when="1864-08-03">3. day of Aug 1864</date></p>
<p>B. W. Foley Clerk
<lb/>by A C. Ellis DC</p>
<p>I will add that Mr. Masters is a very honest good citizen of good repute in his neighborhood. I had in my possession the certificate of the Pro. Marshal. of the enlistment of William Craig on the <date when="1863-12-09">19. Dec last.</date> &amp; saw and conversed with the recruiting officer who took him to Louisville.</p>
<p>I hope your Excellency will exercise clemency towards this worthy old man -- </p>
<p>Yrs
<lb/><hi rend="underline">M M Benton</hi></p>
<p>The letters enclosed show the series &amp; wording -- </p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
