<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2527"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. J. T. Whitlow &amp; L. P. Pace, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7164</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-42 to BR16-43</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Metcalfe County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-09">9 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Metcalfe Circuit Court
<lb/><date when="1865-06">June term 1865</date>
<lb/>Commonwealth Plff
<lb/>vs
<lb/>J T Whitlow &amp; L P Pace Defts</p>
<p>Be it remembered that on the <date when="1865-06-05">5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of June 1865</date> the plff. by her attorney filed in said her notice against the defts, as follows viz:</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Notice</note>
<lb/>J T Whitlow and L P Pace, take notice, that whereas at the <date when="1864-12">December term 1864</date> of the Metcalfe Circuit Court, a judgment was rendered in said Court, and entered of record against you in favor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, for one hundred dollars and costs upon a forfeited bail bond, and which said judgment is yet uncollected and the same was on or about the <date when="1865-03-15">15 day of March 1865</date> destroyed by fire; therefore you are hereby notified that I will on the first day of the <date when="1865-06">June term 1865</date> of the Metcalfe Circuit Court, move said Court to execute said Judgment of Record</p>
<p>J H C Sandidge Atty for the Comth</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Return</note>
<lb/>Said Notice was executed by the Sheriff of Metcalfe Count on L P Pace <date when="1865-05-05">May 5 1865</date> and on J T Whitlow <date when="1865-06-05">June 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>.</p>
<p>On the same day, at a Circuit<pb/>
<lb/>Court commenced as aforesaid the following judgment was rendered herein</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Judgt.</note>
<lb/>It appearing to the Court that the judgment heretofore rendered in this action against the defts. has been destroyed, and the deft Pace having been duly summoned and failing to answer, and the deft. Whitlow entered his appearance in Court, and the proof having been heard, it is adjudged by the Court that the Commonwealth recover of said defts $100. the amount of the original judgment, and the costs of the original action.</p>
<p>On motion of the defts their motion for a new trial, made at the last <date when="--12">December</date> term of the Court is reentered of record and said motion is continued till to tomorrow.</p>
<p>Afterwards at a Circuit Court court continued and held as above on the <date when="1865-06-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of June 1865</date> the following order was made herein viz</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Order</note>
<lb/>The defts by their attorney produced grounds for a new trial herein, and the same is ordered to be filed</p>
<p>And afterwards at a Circuit Court Continued and held as above, the following order was made herein viz</p>
<p><note place="left margin">Order</note>
<lb/>The motion for a new trial herein was heard by the court and over ruled, to which ruling of the Court the defts except,<pb/></p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Metcalfe Circuit Court Sct.</p>
<p>I R H Young clerk of the Metcalfe Circuit Court in the State of Kentucky do hereby certify that the foregoing is a full true and complete transcript of the case therein mentioned as fully as the same appears of record and on file in my office Given under my hand this <date when="1865-10-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Oct. 1865</date>.</p>
<p>R H Young Clk<pb/></p>
<p>Metcalfe Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Transcript
<lb/>J T Whitlock &amp;c
<lb/>$100
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/><date when="1865-12-02">2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> Dec /65</date>
<lb/>For J T Whitlow
<lb/>$1.00</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
