<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-003-0074"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">S. P. Cope to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1591</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR5-132 to BR5-133</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Paducah, McCracken County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-02-08">8 February 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Paducah <date when="1864-02-08">Feby 8 1864</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky
<lb/>Sir,</p>
<p>While I was Seated at my breakfast table this morning, four negro Soldiers armed with muskets and bayonets came to my house and demanded my only negro man. They went into my kitchen to search for him, not finding him they went to my business house, Still not finding him they went to the Market House, when they found him, took forcible possession of him and compelled him to go with them to the camp of one Col Cunningham who is recruiting a regiment of nego Soldiers here. </p>
<p>He was claimed I suppose as a sort of quasideserter; as he tells me that he was coerced to the camp a few days ago and urged to become a soldier. Not being thus inclined he was wrought upon by unwarrantable threats until he made the promise that <hi rend="underline">he</hi> <hi rend="underline">would</hi> <hi rend="underline">return</hi> <hi rend="underline">to</hi> <hi rend="underline">the</hi> <hi rend="underline">camp</hi> <hi rend="underline">again</hi>. He denies that he voluntarily Enlisted in the Service. The Sequel is as I have above Stated. The accompanying Statement from Mr A. Bradshaw, who is one of our msot prominent citizens, a most uncompromising Union Man, and a member of our Enrolling Board, will Explain to you more fully the means that were employed to Seduce, intimidate and terrify my boy into the Service. His wishes are to return to my house. Had I ever aided and abetted in the Subversions of our Government,<pb/>
<lb/>or acted or affiliated in any way with traitors to our country, then my lips would be sealed, and I could not have the effrontery to ask protection at your hands. But from the inceptiion of the rebellion to the present moment I have given my heart and my voice and my feeble energies to the Cause of the Union against Secession, law against lawlessness, and order against anarchy.</p>
<p>In the earlier period of our troubles I struggled against tremendous odds in point of numbers and influence, when violence and threat and intimidtion were rife around me. And at no time have I ever in any way promoted the political advancement of any man who has even sympathized with the enemies of our Country. But I am now, with other other loyal men, made to pay the penalty of rebellion by having my right of property violated, the feelings of my wise outraged, and my children alarmed by the forcible, insolent and offensive intrusion of armed negroes upon my premises to drag from my possession my only remaining family Servant, who really occupies no mean place in the affections of my family.</p>
<p>Was it for this that I Espoused with Such honest ardour to the cause of my country?</p>
<p>My cheek burns with the blush of wounded pride when I remember the vehemence with which I used to meet the charge that the authorities of our Government would ever render the property of loyal Slave owners insecure. Even had I wavered in my fidelity to the government which I have never done, yet I ask<pb/>
<lb/>is this the way or noble President promised "to win men back to loyalty"? He may See the wisdom of the way but my helpless family can not see it. I staked my all in the cause of the Union of Our Fathers and now I will give all if need be to preserve it, but as a citizen of a free county, and as the birthright of a loyal Kentuckian I claim that my right of property Shall be Sacred and inviolate. To you, Sir, as the Governor of my State I look for interposition in my behalf.</p>
<p>My fences have been destroyed, my grounds laid waste, my produce and stock despoiled and killed, but I have patiently borne these evils without a murmur, regarding them as the necessary local concomitants of war.</p>
<p>But I deny the necessity of having my most vital interests torn from me, the welfare and peace of my family obstructed, and myself placed in the humiliating position of a rebel without a claim to the protection of his government. I scorn the paltry sum of $300. for property for which I have refused $2000. Yea, more -- for an appendage of my family which money could not have bought without his consent.</p>
<p>I ask you, Governer, to indicate to me the best and wisest plan to pursue. I have consulted no Counsel -- You are my counsel. Is there a remedy against this great evil, this unbearable oppression?</p>
<p>I can furnish you the most ample testimonials of my loyalty and Standing. If Col B. H. Bistow is in your City I refer you to him for the present.</p>
<p>May I hope to hear from you as soon as you can give your attention to the matter</p>
<p>Your obedient Ser<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">vt</hi></hi>
<lb/>S, P, Cope<pb/></p>
<p>P, S, I would add that it has been told to me that Col Cunningham threatens to serve any citizen to a place inour Grand House with ball and chain to his legs, who shall dare to lay his grievances before your Excellency. Threats did not terrify me from doing my duty when Secession run riot over this part of our State -- and there Shall be no cowardly Skulking from duty on my part now. I only mintion this to show you the reign of terror that exists here.</p>
<p>I told my negro boy to tell Col Cunningham that I should lay the matter before my Governor. I have done it.</p>
<p>S, P, C,</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
