<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-027-0045"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Joshua F. Speed to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1278</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R2-95 to R2-96</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Washington, District of Columbia</placeName>
    <date when="1862-10-14">14 October 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Washington <date when="1862-10-14">14 Octo 62</date>
<lb/>Gov J. F. Robinson
<lb/>Dear Sir.</p>
<p>I failed to get an interview with Mr. Stanton till Sunday -- Both he &amp; the President were present -- They both gave your letter careful consideration -- </p>
<p>While they have not done all that I desire to be done -- The department <hi rend="str">have</hi> has given such instructions to Genl Wright as will prevent the repetetion of such abuses as we have had from petty provost marsalls in the future -- and in a seperate order directed him to arrest any Provost Marshall in the state who has in any way used the power given; to<pb/>
<lb/>exact fees from parties arrested for administering the oath -- or who have in any way abused their trust for private gain -- </p>
<p>Now if we can have one or two of these rascals punished it will do us much good in the future and effectively stop this nuisance -- </p>
<p>The Govt is anxious to make an example of some of them -- and they will rely upon you as Gov and the loyal citizens of Ky to give Genl Wright the necessary information -- </p>
<p>Your despatch about Morgans men came too late the matter had been decided in the morning -- I saw Genl Halleck in the<pb/>
<lb/>evening &amp; submitted your despatch to him -- </p>
<p>He said that the who<hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>le matter had been considered -- That he must send men where according to his judgment they are most needed.</p>
<p>I will leave here on thursday &amp; See Genl Wright as I return -- You will I trust find that my visit here has been productive of much good</p>
<p>Your friend &amp;c
<lb/>J. F. Speed.</p>
<p>Recd Finnells letter for Carbines will try &amp; get some.<pb/></p>
<p>J. F. Speed</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
