<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1161"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. W. Crawford to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5798</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-282</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mount Sterling, Montgomery County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-08-31">31 August 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Mt Sterling Ky. <date when="1864-08-31">Augst. 31<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency Tho. E. Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Ky.
<lb/>Sir.</p>
<p>M. C. O. Connell was indicted by the Grand Jury of Montgomery county at its <date when="1864-02">Feby. term 1864.</date> for selling liquor to a minor. The facts were that he is, and was a regularly licensed grocer and retailer of liquor by the drink. That he sold a drink of liquor to Albin Barnes Jr. a young man 19 years of age, <hi rend="underline">big enough</hi> to be 21, and a very nice young man, and one who had been trading to a considerable extent for himself, and who was generally recognized by his associates even, as being an Adult, Mr. M. C. O. Connell confessed Judgment, and asks yr. excellency to remit the fine due the state under the circumstances of the case and We whose names are signed hereto, know such to be the case, and know that Mr O.Connell is very particular in regard to the premises, and that he is a good, law abiding citizen.</p>
<p>J. M. Crawford clk. M. Ct. Ct.</p>
<p>The above are about the facts in this case</p>
<p>J. S. Dury
<lb/>Com<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Atty.<pb/></p>
<p>Montgomery Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>M C. O,Connell
<lb/>Remit
<lb/>$50 -- 
<lb/><date when="1864-09-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sept/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
