<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0428"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas W. Rowland to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9896</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-167 to MG18-168</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Pendleton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-12-24">24 December 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Exelency the Gov of the Commonwelath of kentucky your petitioner Thos W Rowland states that he purchased a tavern stand in the town of knoxville pendleton cty that he took possession of sd property on the <date when="1859-10-05">5th day of Oct 1859</date> that Stephen Brittenham had obtained licens to keep tavern at the same property on the <gap/> day of <gap/> <date when="1859">1859</date> &amp; his lincens was not out untill one year from these date that he bough the property from M Race &amp; then bough out the ballance of the time of Brittenham that he was told that he had a Right to go on &amp; sell under Brittenhams Licens that he got Dr Rich to make Enquires from the County Judge of s<hi rend="sup">d</hi> county &amp; he said he had the Right to sell that he commenced selling spirits under Brittenham Licens &amp; did sell for two days when he was told by an Atty that he had no Right to sell &amp; he did not sell Any More untill he obtained Licens in his own name which he did at the <date when="1859-11">Nov County Court 1859</date> a copy of the Licens to B &amp; to himself is filed as a part here of that at the <date when="1860-04">April term of the pendleton Circuit Court 1860</date> he was Indited for keeping a tippling House &amp; at the<pb/>
<lb/>term of sd Court he was fined the sum of $60 he files the affidavit of Dr Rich &amp; M Race who prove his statements to be true he hopes you will give his case a hearing for it would be hard to have to pay when he had sent as he thought the proper man to give him information he prays that you will Remit this fine</p>
<p>Thos W Rowland</p>
<p>sworn to before me by Thos W Rowland this <date when="1860-12-24">24th day of Dec 1860</date></p>
<p>A G Robert N P P C</p>
<p>This affiant stephen Rich states that he is a practicing Physician that he lives in the vilage of Knoxville that at the time Mr Rowland moved to sd vilage he Request'd this affiant to see the county Judge of sd County of find out if he had the Right to sell under Brittanhams licens which was not out that he Caled on the Judge &amp; he told him that R had the Right to sell under sd Licens that he so informed R &amp; he sold some two days &amp; was told that he had not the Right to sell when he stoped selling that he was indited for sd selling &amp; he thinks if there ever was a case where the gov should interfer this is one M Race says he has heard the foregoing pet &amp; affidavit of Dr Rich Read<pb/>
<lb/>that he knows that they are true &amp; he hopes the Gov will grant the prayrs of the pet</p>
<p>the foregoing affidavits where sworn to before me by stephen Rich &amp; M Race this <date when="1860-12-24">24th day of Dec 1860</date></p>
<p>A G Roberts N P P C<pb/></p>
<p>Pendleton Cir. Ct
<lb/>the Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } pet
<lb/>$60 } Tipling
<lb/>Thos W Rowland
<lb/>Respite 12 mos
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>Is<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1861-01-03">Jany 3. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
