<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0388"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. W. Woodside to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9856</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG18-95 to MG18-96</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Boyd County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-10">October 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Boyd County Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1860-10">October the <gap/> day 1860</date></p>
<p>To his Excellency the Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky, Your Petitioner Isaiah W. Woodside, Resident of Ritchie County and State of Virginia would respectfully represent unto Your Excellency that on the last Saturday in <date when="1860-02">February 1860</date> went to the house of one Abram Adams in the County of Greenup &amp; state of Kentucky being somewhat intoxicated, said Adams being a tavern Keeper of said County your petitioner being intoxicated when he went to the house of said Adams, and he let your petitioner have whiskey until he became so intoxicated and as he understands pushed him out of the dooor as he understands and your petitioner threw a small rock and struck the door and no other damage done being perfectly so drunken that he did not know what he was doing and by the violation of law of Said Adams letting your petitioner have spirits when he was drunk and the imprudence of your petitioner the act was done, which he acknowledges on his part was wrong and is willing to pay for and promises to do so no more, that same night your petitioner was arrested with out a warrant as he is informed -- no trial was had until the <date when="1860-04-17">17<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of April 1860</date>. which was then had before on Peres Randall without any authority of law a Jury was pretended to be summoned and a verdict of $30, was given against your petitioner, and as he thought would have to go to Jail i<unclear>n</unclear><pb/>
<lb/>the County of Greenup and stay these fifteen days or give a replevin bond and one Jacob Morgan being a reletive of mine rather than see me go to Jail and being on a visit to see him went my securtiy in the bond who is a poor man and having a large family will have to pay the debt, but your petitioner will ^further^ state that the said Peres Randall pretending to act as a Police Judge of the town of Catlettsburg had a Jury summoned a trial had a fine Imposed and bond given all without authority of law and a clear violation of the legal rights of any person whatever, and therefore as any no great damage was done that your excellency will remit all of said fine or such part as he deems right and hoping that the prayers of your petitioners will be heard your &amp;c will ever pray</p>
<p>P. S. 
<lb/>and that Execution is about to Issue and will greatly harras the security of your petitioner</p>
<p>J, W. Woodside</p>
<p>I John Wilson Police Judge of the town of Catlettsburg and County of Boyd and State of Kentucky do hereby certify that the said J,, W. Woodside petitioner above personally appeared before me on the <date when="1860-10-05">5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of October 1860</date> and made oath to the facts <hi rend="str">to the</hi> as stated in the petition and that the statements therein contains a full and fair statement of said case given under may hand the day and date above written</p>
<p>John Wilson P, J, T, C,<pb/></p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Boyd County formerly Greenup County petition his excellency the Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky to grant the J, W. Woodside the petitioner hereunto annexed a remittance of said fine or such part as will justify good <unclear/> <unclear/> <unclear/> <unclear/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Kelsey N, Harris</hi>
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> J, Layne
<lb/>J. W.. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Intyre
<lb/>C. S. Guilkey
<lb/>j thompson
<lb/>Alfred Thompson
<lb/>Frank Nanbairn
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H, Johnson
<lb/>George W Walter
<lb/>J M Layne
<lb/>William Ferguson
<lb/>thomas Ferguson
<lb/>C, E, Wood
<lb/>R, M, WEddington
<lb/>Jas, F, Jenkins
<lb/>E, K, Gaviet<pb/></p>
<p>Catlettsburg Po. Ct.
<lb/>Respite 12 mo
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>$50 } Breach
<lb/>J. W. Woodside
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-01-25">Jay 25. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
