<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1178"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Henry Struck to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10646</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-2 to MG21-3</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-06-11">11 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency, The Govener of Kentucky.</p>
<p>At the last Term of the Police Court of Louisville Your Petitioner Henry Struck was fined the sum of $60, for the alledged offence of Selling liquor without License. He would represent to your Excellency that the Warrant in the case was served on him the <date when="1861-02-01">1st of Feb. of this year.</date> That being satisfied of his innocency of the charge he employed Counsel to defend him. The case was called in <date when="1861-03">March,</date> at which Court he attended with all his witnesses and at great expense, but the Commonwealth not being ready the case was continued to the <date when="1861-04">April</date> Term. At the <date when="1861-04">April</date> Term the case was again called and tried and the Jury not being able to agree were dismissed, eleven of the Jury being in faver of his acquital. Again at the <date when="1861-05">May</date> Term the case was called and continued by the Commonwealth. At the <date when="1861-06">June</date> Term it was called again and tried and this Your Petitioner much to his astonishment and that of every one else was fined as above stated. He says he has been greatly aggrieved by it, and has been subject to heavy expenses and that without any guilt of any intention on his part to violate the law. He says the facts in the following<pb/>
<lb/>Petition are all true and prays Your Excellency to release him from his said fines.</p>
<p><date when="1861-06-11">June 11<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date> } Henry Struck</p>
<p>The undersigned Petitioners state that the facts stated in the foregoing Petition are true. That they are satisfied that Henry Struck is not guilty of the charge for which he was fined. The proof was that he kept a small Grocery and as all Grocers in this City ^do^ whether Licensed or not, kept a small quantity of Beer and other Liquors. It was in proof that Struck was a social sort of a fellow and fond of a glass and when his friends came in he would treat them. Some of the Commonwealths Witness is stated that when they offered to buy liquor, Struck would invariably reply he could not sell it. That if they would buy something else he would give them a drink. No Single Witness proved that he had ever sold a glass of Liquor On the Contrary it was in proof that a Policeman and others had tried in everyway to catch him and could not do it. We are
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Ben Pulsford
<lb/>H G Press
<lb/>Henry Pfeiffer, Jr.
<lb/>A. H. Speed
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Bushrod Williams
<lb/>Mosses Graham
<lb/>John Baker<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Jacob.. H.. Conrad
<lb/>Jno Hughes
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Wilgam Jangom
<lb/>W W Walter<milestone unit="column" n="1"/>
<lb/>assured that Mr Struck ought not to have been fined. That he is not guilty of any violation of law and intended none. We hope your Excellency will release him from his fine</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>H Jones
<lb/>John.H. Rodger
<lb/>John Martz
<lb/>Thomas Slater
<lb/>Jerry Antte
<lb/>Paul Byerly
<lb/><unclear>Lake</unclear> Shirley
<lb/>J A Bayr
<lb/>Jacob Young
<lb/>Peter Hermann
<lb/>T. Bronger
<lb/>John Kuhbauch
<lb/>Wiley Rogers
<lb/>A. H. Sinclair
<lb/><unclear/> Donald
<lb/>A. Schuler
<lb/>John Houck
<lb/>John Birkel
<lb/>Conrad Drauts
<lb/>Ora Le De Le
<lb/>Thomas J. Osborn
<lb/>Jesse P Zimmerman
<lb/><cb n="2"/>John B Lentr
<lb/>James Holms
<lb/>Geo Schmitt
<lb/>George Schmitt, Jr
<lb/><unclear>Tobur Toite</unclear>
<lb/>Conrad Winterstine
<lb/>Andrew Fritz
<lb/>Louis Sangrolf
<lb/>T. Benjamin
<lb/><unclear/> Doll
<lb/>Phillip Grieb
<lb/>Philipp Haas
<lb/>F. Froseher
<lb/>Gorge Kibler
<lb/>H Rautenbus Sr
<lb/>John Routenbush
<lb/>Peter Handren
<lb/>William Lousey
<lb/>James Rynolds
<lb/>Joseph Fisher
<lb/>Louis Eichrott
<lb/>W. Lamppin.
<lb/>John M. Callahan
<lb/>M. T. Callahan
<lb/>J H Brown<pb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>We are acquainted with the Subscribers to this Petition. They are respetable citizens &amp; Several of them Policeman. M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Struck is a clever German grocer who has resided here for several years &amp; has set forth in his Petition substantially the facts proved before the Jury.</p>
<p>Geo. W. Johnston.
<lb/>W. G. Reasor</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Geo W. Sladder
<lb/>George Thompson
<lb/>E. P. Rousseau
<lb/>D. Z. Rousseau
<lb/>George thopon
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> A. Lee.
<lb/>W. B Smith
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Frank Simon
<lb/>H Busling<milestone unit="column" n="1"/></p>
<p>Remitted 
<lb/>B. M.</p>
<p>Is<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1861-06-24">June 24</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
