<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-022-0079"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Burgess Preston to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG12004</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>37th - 76th Regiments Enrolled Militia Primary Source Documents (1861-1866)</collection>
      <idno>Box 81, Folder 65th Regiment 1863-1864 Commissions and Oaths</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisa, Lawrence County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-06-07">7 June 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Headquarters 65<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky. E. M.
<lb/>Louis Ky. <date when="1864-06-07">June 7" 1864</date>
<lb/>Thos. E Bramlitt.. Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi>
<lb/>Frankfort Ky</p>
<p>Dear Sir, There has occured a vacancy in the office of Lieutenant Colonel of the 65<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky. Enrolled Malitia. by the former incumbent Joining the united states army. And accepting a position in the Quartermasters Department. We are ^now^ in the active Service and have no Lt Collonel I therefore recommend (George W Brown, as a suitable person to fill Said position whose appointment dates the <date when="1864-05-26">26<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> of May 1864 -- </date></p>
<p>I have appointed Wiley W Howes, adjutant of the 65<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> and recommend that he be commisioned, to have date from <date when="1864-05-26">26" of May 1864</date></p>
<p>I have also appointed James Nibert Quartermaster and recommend that he be commisioned to have date the <date when="1864-05-31">31<hi rend="sup">st</hi> of May, 1864.</date></p>
<p>I also recommend H. S. Sweatman to be commisioned as surgeon<pb/>
<lb/>of the 65<hi rend="sup">th</hi> E. M. whose appointment <unclear/> date <date when="1864-05-26">26" of May 1864.</date> all of the <unclear/> moniness are now in the active Service &amp; performing the duties of their serveral offices.</p>
<p>I suppose the Quartermaster will have to Execute bond. If so send form of bond &amp; amount to be Executed I have appointed a Paymaster, but and at a loss to know whether or not there is such an officer for the regiment being in the united States service for the present, inform me on the subject.<hi rend="sup">s</hi></p>
<p>On the <date when="1864-02-27">27" of February 1864</date> the malitia of Johnson Co. was organized under me as their Collonel and Captins and Lieutenants Elected for the various companies- and the certificates of their Elections wrote out and forwarded to you, but as yet there has been no commisions received- I would like to know, If they have been forwarded If not pleas forward<hi rend="str">ed</hi> them,<pb/>
<lb/>Any communication you may have for our regiment direct to care of the Post Commander at this place.</p>
<p>I am verry Respectfully yours
<lb/>Respt yours
<lb/>Burgess Preston Col.
<lb/>65<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Regt. Ky. E. M<pb/></p>
<p>65
<lb/>Ky State Militia
<lb/>Louisa Lawrence Co Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-06-07">June 7, 1864</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Preston Burgess Col. Comdg
<lb/>65th E. M. <hi rend="underline">Johnston</hi> Co<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Recommends George W. Brown for Lieut Col vice -- who have joind the U. S. Service- Has appointed various Staff officers- wants to know if he is entitled to a P. M. and if his Q. M. will have to execute bond &amp;c.</p>
<p>On the <date when="1864-02-27">27<hi rend="sup">th</hi> February/64</date> he sent election returns but the officers elected have not yet recd their com<hi rend="sup">ms</hi> &amp;c<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Ans. <date when="1864-06-21">June 21<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> 1864</date> on letter book Page 424. and coms &amp; duplicate co<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">ms</hi></hi> ordered &amp; forwarded to the place &amp; con requested<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Rec. I. G. O. <date when="1864-06-18">June 18. 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
