<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2015"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. W. Cleary to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9091</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-13 to MG24-14</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1862-06-17">17 June 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Govenor of Ky,</p>
<p>More than a year ago, I was appointed at the <gap/> Term of the Harrison Circuit Court, commonwealths attorney pro tem, in the absence of W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Mathew the Regular atty for the commonwealth, as such I attended to the prosecution in the case of commonwealth against Saml Craig for passing counterfeit money, He was convicted and sentenced to the Penitentiary for two years. where he now is having several considerably more than half his time, The conviction was had upon the testimony of our witness our Noah Eddleman -- and though he swore positively, that he had seen Craig offer to pass the counterfeit bill, yet his statement was so<pb/>
<lb/>indistinct and confused upon every other circumstance connected with the matter, that I was surprised at the time, that the Jury found a verdict against Craig -- Since the trial I am satisfied, that Craig ought not to have been convicted -- that his brother one James Craig, was the really guilty party -- and that Eddleman the witness must have been <hi rend="underline">mistaken</hi> in saying that he saw ^said^ Craig in possession of those counterfeit Bill -- Other witnesses were introducted. beside Eddleman, but their testimony ^alone^ would have been insufficient, James Craig has fled the country, to avoid prosecution for passing the same bill, and attempting to pass it, having tried it, several times before he put it on Saml, I make this statement at the<pb/>
<lb/>request of Saml Craig, who desires a pardon from your Excellency, I have no sort of hesitation, in saying, that I think he ought to be pardoned, I have heard a number of persons in Harrison County speak of the case, who think he ought to be pardoned</p>
<p>Very Respectfully &amp;c
<lb/>W. W. Cleary
<lb/><date when="1862-06-17">June 17<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1862</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
