<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3363"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. Irvin Baker to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5482</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-218</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E Bramlet Governor of Ky</p>
<p>Dr sir I send ^against <unclear/> Parker^ you a copy of Endictment for preventing Jno Kiser from <unclear/> the <unclear/> is he challenged his vote as a citizen and Kiser did not wait for, investigation and declined to vote, for while he is indicted the proof showes in all of the contested Election cases that no man was prevented from voting by the Military at Indian Springs the place where Kiser offered to vote, We ask for a pardon for the reasons above I could send 100 names, but I am authorized to speak for them I am much pleased to see your response to Judge Goodlow in the Lexington Freedmans Bureau case, it is the time <unclear/> and I hope to find every union man Standing apart I am in the midst of the most Exciting canvas ever in my county and to see and hear then you would think, Jef Davis had taken Washington</p>
<p>R Irvin Baker</p>
<p>I indorse the above, and I live in the district
<lb/>W. P. Dyman</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
