<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-019-0075"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John M. Johnson to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1381</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG5-140</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Paducah, McCracken County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-05">5 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Paducah Kentucky
<lb/><date when="1861-06-05">June 5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>B Maggofin Governor of Kentucky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>I have the honor to enclose herewith the reply of Hon John A Gardner Confidential agent of His Excellency the Governor of Tennessee for the Western divission of the State, to my letter of the <date when="1861-05-28">28<hi rend="sup">th</hi></date> Inst, a copy of which I enclosed by Capt Cobb</p>
<p>After my dispatches from Union City Tennessee by Capt Cobb, dated <date when="1861-06-02">June 2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi></date> I visited Columbus Ky in Company with Col Tilghman &amp; Judge Bigger to have a Conference with prominent Citizens in regard to Col Austins plan for fortifying the place, I showed ^them^ your instructions to me, and also assured them, that the State of Tennessee had given me a pledge that neither guns, munitions of War, or Men from that State Would be allowed to go to Columbus for the purpose indicated, as it Would be a Violation of your Excellencies proclaimation as the line of policy which Ky had determined to assume -- awaiting your further instructions, I have the honor to be &amp;C</p>
<p>Jno M Johnson</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
