<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2922"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Richard D. Braun to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7559</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-249 to BR17-250</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Catlettsburg, Boyd County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-13">13 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Catlettsburg Ky
<lb/><date when="1865-12-13">Decr 13th 1865</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thomas E,, Bramlett</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Richard D,, Braun respectfully represents that in the Summer of <date when="1864">1864</date> he became the security of one Alexander Tomblin for his personal appearance on the first day of the <date when="--10">Oct</date> Term of the Boyd circuit court next thereafter, <hi rend="str">and</hi> under a charge of Grand larceny in the sum of five hundred dollars -- He says on the day and in the month and year <unclear>consendnted</unclear> to have sd Tomblin in court he did have him there &amp; Kept him there until it was learned there would be no circuit Court at that time; He says afterwards a special Term of the Boyd circit court for the Trial of criminal and Equity causes was ordered by the Judge of the circuit which was held in <date when="1864-12">December 1864</date> and that said Tombolin nor your Petitioner had no notice of the same until after<pb/>
<lb/>the <date when="--12">Decr</date> Court was over, and then learned it through the advice of some friends who informed him his recognizance of $500,00 had been forfeited; he says he then procured said Tomblin and had him in court at the <date when="1865-04">april term 1865</date> of the Boyd circuit Court at which term he was convicted &amp; sentenced to 4 years confinement in the Ky Penitentiary where he is now confined and then on answer moved the Court to set aside the forfeiture of his Recognizance, But the court refused to set sd forfeiture aside and unless your Excellency does remit the same he will have it all to pay he says he has been at great expense and trouble already in the premises above referred to; and that he thinks as the lawless offender has by (his) your Petitioners exertions and outlays have brought to trial and punished, And <hi rend="underline">this</hi> <hi rend="underline">he</hi> <hi rend="underline">hopes</hi> <hi rend="underline">your</hi> Excellency will think a full compliance with his covenants &amp; recognizance; He therefore prays your Excellency to remit the <hi rend="underline">five</hi> <hi rend="underline">hundred</hi> <hi rend="underline">dollar</hi> <hi rend="underline">Recognizance</hi> and in duty will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p>R,, D,, Braun<pb/></p>
<p><note place="left margin">R D Braun
<lb/>To } Petition
<lb/>Governor of Ky</note></p>
<p>Sworn to &amp; subscribed before me by R D,, Braun this <date when="1865-12-13">13th Decr 1865</date></p>
<p>John M, Burns notary Public Boyd <hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">co</hi></hi></p>
<p>We the undersigned say that we are satisfied that the statements in the foregoing Petition of R, D, Braun are true and hope your Excellency will find it both consistent with your Duty &amp; feelings to remit said five hundred Dollar Recognizance</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>John M,, Burns
<lb/>John Bowling
<lb/>John P,, Lesley
<lb/>C, S,, Guilky
<lb/>J J Sturgeon
<lb/>P,, P,, Cooles Jailer B,, C,
<lb/>J L Ziegler
<lb/>A Adams
<lb/>Jas, R, Ford
<lb/>N O Hampton Clerk,
<lb/>Winston M, Conly
<lb/>George Cole
<lb/><cb n="2"/>R, D, Brown
<lb/>Rowland. C. Burns
<lb/>S. Rous, J<hi rend="sup">r</hi>
<lb/>Jacob Lockwood
<lb/>A. J. Prichard
<lb/>John. P. Strother
<lb/>George. R. Burgess J, P, B, C
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Beckelheiner
<lb/><unclear/>. Chaffean
<lb/>Wm Prichard
<lb/>R. H. Prichard
<lb/>Lewis, Prichard.
<lb/>H, J, Hale,
<lb/>Columbus, Prichard,
<lb/>Robrt Stewart</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Remit forfeiture<pb/></p>
<p>Boyd Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>R, D Brown
<lb/>for
<lb/>$500,
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/><date when="1866-01-23">23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Jany 1866</date>
<lb/>Remit</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
