<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1441"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John McNickle to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6078</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-242 to BR12-243</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-12-28">28 December 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency the Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your petitioner John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Nichol respectfully states that one John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Closky was indicted in the Scott Circuit Court for murder &amp; was committed to jail at the term subsequent to his arrest &amp; indictment the principal witness for the Commonwealth &amp; the only one by whom the atty was able to prove the killing was absent &amp; the comth<hi rend="sup">s</hi> atty unwilling to rely upon circumstantial evidence had the case continued until the next term of the court &amp; the prisoner remanded to jail -- At the <date when="1863-11">Nov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> term 1863</date> the witness was still absent with no prospect of the Comth being able to procure his attendance as he was in the army &amp; the case was continued by the Comth<hi rend="sup">s</hi> atty. as the prisoner had been in jail for one year, had 6 or 7 children, the eldest about 11 years of age, and there was no prospect of a trial, the court admitted him to bail in the sum of $400 with petitioner as his surety -- M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clusky was poor &amp; being unable to employ counsel, the court assigned to his defense Hon Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> F Robinson &amp; Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> B Beck who upon conference with him reported to the court that they believed him to be crazy -- All these circumstances induced the court to admit him to bail &amp; petitioner through sympathy consented to become his surety<pb/>
<lb/><hi rend="str">After he</hi> At the <date when="1864-05">May term 1864</date> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Closky came to the house of petitioner at Lexington &amp; procured a horse to ride to Georgetown to attend his trial In a few days he returned the horse to petitioner &amp; said his trial had been continued &amp; petitioner supposed he had made his appearance until process upon the forfeited bond <hi rend="str">had been</hi> was served upon him. At the <date when="1864-11">Nov term 1864</date> petitioner went to Georgetown on the first day of the court to make defense to the proceedings against him &amp; was informed, by an attorney that it was continued until the <date when="1865-05">May court 1865</date> &amp; he came home. To his surprize in a few days the sheriff came to him with a capias &amp; he then learned that judgment had been rendered -- No jury business was done at the <date when="1864-11">Nov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> term 1864.</date> The Circuit judge met on Monday discharged the juries &amp; did not return until Saturday &amp; it was announced in court on Monday that all contested business would be continued. Petitioner respectfully asks your excellency to remit so much of said judgment as the Law permits. John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Nickle<pb/></p>
<p>The facts in regard to the indictment are correctly set forth, My only witness who could prove the killing by the accused, was recognised and failed to appear and in his absence I did not feel willing to try -- The other facts I have no doubt are also correct.</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>W. S. Downey
<lb/>Com Atty </p>
<p>John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Closky was poor &amp; unable to pay counsel in the above named case &amp; in the absence of the counsel assigned for him I assisted him as a matter of gratuity in learning his witnesses summoned &amp; from repeated conversations with him &amp; many of his witnesses became pretty well acquainted with his case -- I regarded him as sincere at the time the killing took place &amp; insane the last time I saw him ^in <date when="1864-05">May 1864^</date> -- I am well satisfied that John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Closkys absense was without the knowledge approbation or consent of the sureties on his bail bond -- As Gov Bramlette may not remember me I take the liberty of referring him to Hons Geo W Robertson J. F. Bullitt B. J.<pb/>
<lb/>Peters, Genl Combs, Genl John M Harlan &amp; Col R. R. Bolling -- I am an atty but aid in this case without fee or the hope of any -- The party asked this release is a poor hard working man -- the remission prayed for by him as an act of simpe justice to him -- M Polk</p>
<p>Georgetown Ky <date when="1864-12-22">Dec 22. 1864</date></p>
<p>Please address M Polk Georgetown Ky</p>
<p>John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Nichols
<lb/>To } Petition Remit
<lb/>Gov: Bramlette<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/><date when="1864-12-28">1864 Decr 28</date>
<lb/>Presented to the Governor
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1865-01-04">4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Jany/65</date>
<lb/>M. Polk
<lb/>Attorney.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
