<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2198"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Jeremiah Davidson et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9274</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-320 to MG24-321</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his excellency the Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky your Petitioners Jeremiah Davidson James M Rill &amp; George N Brown ^Stall^ that at the <date when="--07">last July Term</date> of the Greenup circuit court they entered themselves as security for one J. R. B. Watkens who had been confined in jail some three months, on a charge of obtaining money under false pretense. they say he was presented by a man by the name of -- Bumpus from Tennessee who had been a trader in slaves or negro driving they state that said Bumpus had appeared before the grand jury in Greenup the term before and procured an Inditement, then took a copy to your excellency and procured a requisition in the Governor of Missouri where Watkens had removed having formerly resided in Mccracken County Kentucky, Watkens was taken from his Home by the posse and delivered to Bumpus who conveyed him from his Home in Dunklin county Mo_ to the Greenup jail without permitting him to see his wife &amp; children on converse with them prior to his departure said Watkens from his confinement in the hot weather last summer suffered very much -- Watkins instituted a suit in Greenup cirucit court against Bumpus, many of the citizens about<pb/>
<lb/>Greenupsburg believe Watkens innocent &amp; badly treated -- <hi rend="str">Bumpus</hi> <hi rend="str">failed</hi> <hi rend="str">to</hi> <hi rend="str">appear</hi> <hi rend="str">as</hi> <hi rend="str">witness</hi> <hi rend="str">against</hi> <hi rend="str">Watkins</hi> <hi rend="str">the</hi> <hi rend="str">Commonwealth</hi> <hi rend="str">attorney</hi> <hi rend="str">claim</hi> <hi rend="str">a</hi> <hi rend="str">continuance</hi> -- Watkins distant from his friends. Much emaciated from confinement it appeared as a consequence he had to return to jail the court from the circumstances placed bail at $250 -- your petitioners went said Watkens security from his appearance at <date when="1861-11">last Nov Term (1861)</date> of Greenup circuit court -- Walkins promising if a live or able to pass the Military times to appear Watkens left for Home in Missouri: At the said <date when="--11">Nov Term</date> said Bond was forfeited for his failure to attend -- and likewise did Bumpus fail to attend -- your petitioner have been unable to hear from Watkens unless he was killed in Fort Donelson as reported in the list Ky Yeoman <date when="--03-14">March 14<hi rend="sup">th</hi></date> under the name of J R Watson we have no doubt but he was in the army -- from the foregoing statements and distress prevailing in the country &amp; the impossibility to get from Missouri last fall mattered not how willing a person might be -- your petitioners think in good consince they should be relieved<pb/>
<lb/>from the forfeiture -- they therefore aks the interfearance of the executive clemency &amp; they be relieved from the forfeiture aforesaid &amp; in duty bound will ever &amp;c</p>
<p>Jeremiah Davidson
<lb/>George N Brown
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> M. Rice</p>
<p>Commonwealth vs. Morgan 14. B. M. 392
<lb/>" " vs Spraggins 18 B. M. 513 -- <pb/>
<lb/>No Judgt -- 
<lb/>Davidson Rill &amp; Brown
<lb/>to } Petition
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r </hi></hi>Magoffin</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
