<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1382"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">H. Royalty and John Royalty et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6019</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-145 to BR12-146</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-12-16">16 December 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The commonwealth of Kentucky,
<lb/>To his Excellency, Thomas E Bramlet governor of the commonwealth of Kentucky at Frankfort</p>
<p>Very respectfully your petitioner represents to your Excellency, that in the circuit court of Baren county in said state your petitioner H Royalty was indicted and convicted under an act Entitled an act "to prohibit the sale or gift of intoxicating liquros to officers or soldiers" approved <date when="1861-10-03">oct 3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> 1861.</date> and a fine and Judgement rendered against him for $20 besides cost $7.<hi rend="underline">30</hi> Your petitioner John Royalty a son of said H Royalty was also indicted and convicted at the same court under the same act and a fine &amp; Judgment rendered against him for $10. besides ccost $9 <hi rend="underline">45</hi>. Your petitioner H Royalty was when said act was violated keeping a public Hotel in Glasgow Kentucky and as such allowed to keep spirits for sale and his son John Royalty was his <hi rend="underline">Bar</hi> Keeper They state that federal soldiers were stationed at Glasgow at the time and the officer highest in Rank and command gave orders to the soldiers to our house for spirits The officer sometimes in person ordering us to let the soldier have spirits under the circumstances your petitioners were powerless to Resist the orders and when indicted presented the written orders from the commanding officer But the orders were rejected<pb/>
<lb/>because it did not appear that the spirits were for the use of the medical department of the army Your petitioners did not deliver the spirits of their own free will but in obedience to a military order directed to them by the commander of the post. as all crimes are presumed to have been done wilfully and in as much as this is a case in which your petitioners were forced to act contrary to their will They Humbly petition your Excellency to pardon &amp; Remit said fine Your petitioners have always been loyal to the laws of their country and did not violate said law willingly and the costs are somewhat oppressive as they are both poor men</p>
<p>Grant this Relief and as in duty bound your petitioners will ever pray &amp;c.</p>
<p><date when="1864-12-16">December 16<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>H Royalty
<lb/>John Royalty</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Glasgow Ky very Respectfully Represent to his Excellency Thomas E Bramlet Govenor of Ky That they are well acquainted with H Royalty John Royalty that they keep an orderly house they are both entitled to full credit on their statements and from personal observation<pb/>
<lb/>they state that it would have been next to impossible to have prevented the soldiers from having the spirits for which they were indicted and convicted,</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> Lampton</hi>
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> W. Waring
<lb/>S. R. Tolle
<lb/>John Lowry
<lb/><hi rend="underline">G. W. Trabue Sr</hi>
<lb/>D B Denton
<lb/>C, W, Terry
<lb/>J. S. Morgan
<lb/>James Bryan.
<lb/>J. W, Howard<pb/></p>
<p>Barren Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>H &amp; J Royalty
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1864-12-23">23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Dec/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
