<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2584"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">G. D. Veatch et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7221</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-132</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-10-26">26 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency
<lb/>The Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Washington County respectfully represent that Henry C Gillispie of said County was tried at the recent <date when="1865-10">Oct term 1865</date> of the Washington Circuit Court on an Indictment for Killing John B Lawrence and convicted of manslaughter and sentenced to undergo a punishment of six years and six months confinement in the penitentiary -- Your petitioners represent that on the trial of the cause the evidence was conflicting That credible witnesses proved that the decd assaulted Gillispie immediately before the latter shot him in a manner and under circumstances amply sufficent to justify said Gillispie in believing that when he shot Lawrence said Lawrence was about to stab him with a Knife -- and that it was made circumstantially to appear that he was actually stabed by Lawrence before <hi rend="str">he shot</hi> he shot him -- Said Gillespie is a poor young man of good character and family and has a wife and one child dependent on him -- He has served the country over two years in the federal army in the recent war and was honorably<pb/>
<lb/>discharged from the service a short time before the trial -- The record of his case will show that one of the Grand Jurors who indicted him was on the jury who convicted him -- The sentence is severe, and may be wholly unjust; and believing as we do that his case appeals strongly for the interposition of Executive clemency we respectfully ask that he be pardoned -- <date when="1865-10-26">Oct 26 1865</date></p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>G. D. Veatch
<lb/>D C Thompson
<lb/>John. W. Graves
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Ballew
<lb/>Mayfield Hays
<lb/>Martin baker
<lb/>William Lawson S<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi>
<lb/>Brazel. Parrot
<lb/>James Cutsinger
<lb/>Louis Cutsinger
<lb/>Henry Noel
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> J.. Simpson
<lb/>Dudley Woods
<lb/>John Jennings
<lb/>James Divine
<lb/>John Hooper S<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi>
<lb/>Calvin Coslow
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi>.. Ruby
<lb/>Joseph Coslow
<lb/>W. B. Taster
<lb/>Samuel Bottom
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> J Badgett
<lb/>John Smith
<lb/>Willam R Watts
<lb/>Thomas J Watts
<lb/>John H. Robinson
<lb/>James J Cull
<lb/>Luciford L Crofford
<lb/>Louis Sammons
<lb/>James T. Call
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> R Watts sr
<lb/>R W Dickerson
<lb/>Solomon Harmon
<lb/>John Warner
<lb/>E Berry Hatch
<lb/>T. C. Richardson
<lb/>John R Trent
<lb/>James Reed
<lb/>George Phelp
<lb/>William Lawson
<lb/>Huey C. Cull
<lb/>Daniel Green</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
