<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0904"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Michael H. Owsley to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5023</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Bradley Strait</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-389 to BR10-390</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Columbia, Adair County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-05-03">3 May 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Columbia Kentucky 
<lb/><date when="1864-05-03">May 3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rd</hi></hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Gov. Tho. E. Bramlette 
<lb/>Frankfort Ky
<lb/>Dear Gov.</p>
<p>Mr. Sandidge Comlth's attorney for this district requested me to represent him at this term of the court to prosecute Allen Smith formerly of Clinton County for keeping a tipling house at neatsville and Mr. Smith was found guilty of so keeping a Tipling house by the Jury. The facts are about these as proven Mr. Smith being driven from home. moved to Neatsville in this county - and John M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Whorter having obtained tavern lisence and having no family himself let Mr. S take the tavern and they undertook to sell liquor under said license together - and under the instructions of the court the Jury were bound to find as they did, I am satisfied Mr S. never intended to violate the law-nor did he think he was violating the law at the time - Under the circumstances I hope yr. excellency will see proper to exercise executive clemency &amp; remit the fine</p>
<p>Respectfuly 
<lb/>M H Owsley<pb/></p>
<p>The undersigned concur in the within statement and request </p>
<p>Respectfully 
<lb/>J. A. Rausseau 
<lb/>Timoleon Cravens 
<lb/>Parker G. Harden, Jr. 
<lb/>Z. Wheat 
<lb/>T T Alexander<pb/>
<lb/><unclear/> a Judge in the case the facts are fairly <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> <unclear/> statid.<pb/></p>
<p>Adair Cir ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Allen Smith </p>
<p>Remit except 
<lb/>fee &amp; costs 
<lb/>Thos E Bramlette 
<lb/>$60. 
<lb/>Tipling 
<lb/><date when="1864-05-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> May/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
