<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0007"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John G. Merritt et al. to James F. Robinson or Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4126</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-9 to BR8-10</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hopkinsville, Christian County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-09-01">1 September 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><placeName ref="cwgk:P00002431">Hopkinsville</placeName>, Ky.,<lb/><date when="1863-09-01">Sept 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency <persName ref="cwgk:N001004">James F. Robinson</persName> Governor of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O001025">Commonwealth of Kentucky</orgName> or his successor, the Hon. <persName ref="cwgk:N001000">Thos E. Bramlette</persName></p>
<p>Your petitioner <persName ref="cwgk:N00008092">John G. Merritt</persName>, respectfully showeth to your Excellency, that at the March term of the , two several fines were assessed upon your petitioner by said Court upon verdicts rendered in the trial of two indictments the one for carrying concealed weapons &amp; the other for disturbing religious worship, the fine in the first case being twenty dollars, and in the second case being fifty dollars. Your peitioner further showeth to your Excellency that, at the time of the trial of said indictments, he was sick and confined to his bed being afflicted with hemorahage of the lungs and for that reason could not attend the said trials -- that, if he had been able to attend said trials, he could have made it appear that the was not gulity as charged in the indictment for disturbing religious worship, but that he (at the time said offence was alleged to have been committed) ^was^ at the church as a peaceable citizen, disturbing no one, but was himself disturbed and insulted by others and that, if there was any disturbance at the time it was not casued by him; but by others. Your petitioner is in the habit of attending the public worship of God and <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000362">Christian Circuit Court</orgName> 1863<hi rend="str">is</hi> fully appreciates the necessity of enforcing the laws<pb/>
<lb/>of the Commonwealth wh<hi rend="str">ich</hi>ose objects are to secure the freedom of religion and religious worship. Certainly your petitioners reverence for God and for religion and respect for his house and his people would restrain from such offences. Your petitioner further showeth to your Excellency that long before the trials aforesaid (say for three years) he has been and is now afflicted with disease of the lungs which has assumed the form of Consumption, and that his afflication is so great that he is now and has been for a long time unable to work for a support but depends for a living upon the charity of his father. Your petitioner has no property and is wholly unable to pay the said fines.</p>
<p>For the reasons aforesaid your petitioner would respectfully pray your Excellency to remit to and pardon him of so much of said fines as by the law belong to the Commonwealth and your petitioner will ever pray &amp;c</p>
<p>J G Merritt</p>
<p>The undersigned would respectfully recommend the above petitioner to executive clemency &amp; state that the facts in the peition are true, and request your Excellency to grant the prayer of the said peition, for the reasons set forth<pb/></p>
<p>therein. This <date when="1863-09-01">September 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> 1863</date>.
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008093">J. B. Boyd</persName> (Juryman)<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008094">G S Witty
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008095">W. T Witty
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008096">Jas B Witty</persName> Juryman<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008097">J A Witty
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008098">D F Witty
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008099">W W Boyd</persName> Juryman<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Linnville
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008101">J A youngs</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008102">J Mervs
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008103">G W Witty
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008104">Georage Galay
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008105">R A Morris
</persName><lb/><hi rend="str">G D Mor</hi>
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008127">G D Morris
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008128">R Knight
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008129">J S Renolds
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008130">James Roberts
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008131">John Ryan</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008132">A. Armstrong
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008133">R. Golay
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008134">S M Boyd</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008135">James Slolling
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008136">John Linsville
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008137">J Wagoner</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008138">F G Morris</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008139">G Kinight</persName><lb/>J <hi rend="str">T</hi> T. Teuller
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008141">R S Feuller
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00008142">G. N. S. Wood</persName><pb/></p>
<p>Christian
<lb/>Cir Court
<lb/>Judgt
<lb/>J. G. Merritt
<lb/>Rejected &amp; ans<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1863-09-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sept 1863</date></p>
<p>Christian
<lb/>Cr Ct.
<lb/>vs
<lb/>J. G. Merritt
<lb/>Rejected
<lb/><date when="1863-09-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sept/63</date></p>
<p>Jno G Merrit
<lb/>Pet for Remission fine
<lb/>$50 <hi rend="str">Clo</hi>and $20 for carrying concealed weapons &amp; distbg R. worship
<lb/><date when="1863-09-12">Sept 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1863</date>
<lb/>Refused
<lb/>Thos E Bramlette</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
