<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-009-0071"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">M. Van Royally, Rules and regulations of the Pigeon hole Table</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1226</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR1-282</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Note</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Rules and regulations of the Pigeon hole Table</p>
<p>1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> No Minors are allowed to play on this Table</p>
<p>2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> No betting allowed in the room or any other part of the house on any proposition</p>
<p>3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> No playing for treats allowed</p>
<p>4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> For every game of 300 20<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">cts</hi></hi></p>
<p>5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Sweepstakes game of 300 for each person playing 10<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">cts</hi></hi> or at the option of the partied playing each may buy 15<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">cts</hi></hi> worth of refreshments or a ticket calling for same and play without charge a game of 300 Games for higher number than 300 will be charged in proportion</p>
<p>6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> For every game of eight balls five cents for each person playing which must be spent for refreshements</p>
<p>7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Gambling of all sorts including betting drinks or treats of all kinds is positively prohibited</p>
<p>8<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Bystanders will <hi rend="underline">be</hi> please ^refrain^ from making from making remarks about the game either advising how to play or correcting mistakes made in the <unclear/> unless called on to do so by the parties engaged in playing</p>
<p>9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> The price charged for playing must be paid as soon as the game is over as there will be no accounts kept</p>
<p>M. Van. Royally</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
