<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0063"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Green V. Hall to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14092</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1865</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Stanton, Powell County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-17">17 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Stanton <date when="1865-10-17">Oct 17. 1865</date>
<lb/>Thos E. Bramlette Gov. of Ky
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>We take the privelege of addressing a few lines to you in regard to the recruiting a company of Enrolled Militia for our County. It does Seem fit and proper to give this Country an oppurtunity of raising a Company for ^its^ defense <hi rend="str">of this</hi> There is no section in Ky where troops are needed more than in this County. Powell Co Situated as it is in the very midst of the Mountains, infested with rogues and guerrillas ever since the war Commenced -- Sent her sons to the field with out <unclear>Sting</unclear>, never suffered herself to be drafted -- should have some of the priveleges bestowed upon more fortunate counties -- I flatter myself having more than three years experience in the Federal Service as Capt ^of the 24th Vol. Inf.^ that I can render yet some service to my native state -- I have learned that an order has been issued to raise Companies in other Counties. If such be the fact I hope I will be advised of the fact and authority given me to recruit a Company &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi></p>
<p>Yours Respectfully
<lb/>Green V Hall<pb/></p>
<p>Stanton, Powell County.
<lb/><date when="1865-10-17">Oct. 17, 1865</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Hall, Capt. Green V.
<lb/>(To Govenor.)<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Desires to recruit a Co. of active militia in Powell County, as it is badly needed. the county being situated in the mountains, and infested with rogues and guerillas.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Ans <date when="1865-10-26">Oct 26</date>. Let Bk B. p 306<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Rec I. G. O. <date when="1865-10-24">Oct 24. 65</date>.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
