<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1338"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">McKenney Maloney et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5975</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR12-84 to BR12-85</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-11-02">2 November 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excelency
<lb/>Thos. E. Bramlet
<lb/>Govenor of Kentucky</p>
<p>The undersigned Petitioner, McKenney Maloney would most respectfully represent -- that some five or six years ago He was indicted in the Owsley circuit court for keeping a Tipling House.</p>
<p>That said cause was continued from term to term, sometimes by your Petitioner, and some times by the Comlth.</p>
<p>That since the Rebelion the courts Have been quite irregular the Judge filing at times to come.</p>
<p>That at the Last <hi rend="str">May</hi> Spring Term of the Owsley Circuit Court a Judgement was rendered against Him for sixty Dollars &amp; cost</p>
<p>He says that it was the general impression in the country that no<pb/>
<lb/>court would be Held at the Term at which Judgement was rendered against Him. That He Had a valid defence and could Have defeated the same if He Had been there -- That owing to the condition of the country the frequent failures of the court to meet that He was not present at the Term when Judgement was rendered</p>
<p>He further states that at this time He is a soldier in the Kentucky state guards. Has a family with but slight means to subsist upon -- That if His Property is sold under <hi rend="str">the</hi> an Execution <hi rend="str">which is now</hi> it will greatly distress His family in His absence and woul if He ware at Home</p>
<p>He Has been informed and believes it true that no proof was taken against Him, that a Judgement was rendered by Default</p>
<p>The Premises considered He asks your Excelency to respite said fine <hi rend="str">which</hi> &amp; cost until the next Term of the Owsley circuit court, That at the <date when="1864-10">Oct. Term <hi rend="str">1864</hi> 1864</date><pb/>
<lb/>There was no court Held, The Judge of said court Having sent a written order to the clerk, that none would be Held -- and consequently He could take no steps before the court to vacate the Judgement</p>
<p>Mc Kenney Maloney</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by the said Mc Kenney Maloney this <date when="1864-11-02">2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> of November 1864</date></p>
<p>E. S. Cockrill J P O C</p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Kentucky state that we be believe the affidavt of <unclear><hi rend="str">the</hi></unclear> Petition and would most respectfully ask of your Excelency that His fine be remitted, at Least Respited -- <hi rend="str">most</hi> some of us are soldiers in the state guard</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="1"/><cb n="1"/> Names
<lb/>Harrison Cockrill
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J A Stampes
<lb/>E. S. Cockrill
<lb/>A A Curtis
<lb/>C. W. Oaks<milestone unit="column" n="1"/><pb/></p>
<p>Owsley Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>McKinney Maloney
<lb/>Respite until <date when="1865-06">June/65</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/><date when="1864-11-08">8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
