<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2575"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John T. McLain to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7212</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-118 to BR16-119</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-10-12">12 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Frankfort Ky <date when="1865-10-12">Oct 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date>
<lb/>To his Excellency Gov Bramlette -- 
<lb/>Dear Sir -- </p>
<p>I have the honor to make the following statement in regard to John V Randall convicted &amp; sentenced, <hi rend="str">from</hi> to the penatentiary, from the Metcalf Circuit Court, for the period of five years, upon charge of horse stealing.</p>
<p>Randall entered the service of his country in <date when="1861-08">August 1861</date>, &amp; attached himself to Co. "J" 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Ky. Cav (commanded by Capt M H Owsley). He made a good &amp; faithful soldier up to the time of his arrest. Conducted himself with gallantry in ^the^ chase after Morgan, when he made his daring raid through Ky &amp; across the River. And in the terrible winters campaign in East Tennessee, <hi rend="str">conducted</hi> demeaned himself as a <hi rend="underline">soldier</hi> and <hi rend="underline">gentleman</hi>. He bore as good a character as any soldier in the command. When arrested he was off on leave granted by Col. Wolford Commanding Our Division.</p>
<p>I am unable to set forth all the facts in relation to the charge of horse stealing; but so far as I have been able to learn, Randall did not take the horse<pb/>
<lb/>himself but was with one Jo<hi rend="sup">s</hi> R Lawson a soldier of the 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Ky Cav, who did take it. Said Lawson is the guilty one <hi rend="underline">if</hi> <hi rend="underline">either</hi> <hi rend="underline">be</hi> <hi rend="underline">guilty</hi> and is now also in the penatentiary -- </p>
<p>It is hard that federal soldiers should be handled by a loyal people with such severity; whilst persons who were attempting to overthrow the Government, have been guilty of <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> greater crimes in the same locality &amp; still go unpunished</p>
<p>Considering the prejudices against ^the deperedations as they are termed, of^ our troops and the fact that Randall did not actually take the horse, although present, I hope you consider his case as one worthy of executive Clemency His family is to poor to hunt such mitigating circumstance as might bear in his favor. You will favorably remember then ^their circumstances^ as they formerly lived in Clinton Co. Ky -- </p>
<p>John T. M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Lain
<lb/>Late Capt <hi rend="str">co</hi> J. 1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Ky Cav<pb/></p>
<p>Metcalfe Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John V. Ranall
<lb/>Pardoned <date when="1865-10-14">14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Oct 1865</date>
<lb/>Convicted -- term 1864 -- 5 years to Penitentiary upon charges of horse stealing
<lb/>Pardon granted</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
