<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3099"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Unknown, Note</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5218</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-256 to BR41-257</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Note</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="left margin">94
<lb/>3</note></p>
<p>Than I dared to be he proposed to me to fix up a plan to Rob and Kill Geo Carter he said he was a man that had a great amount of money I was to go and remain a few days with Carter and and find where he kept his money and then we would go and get it he also proposed to work with John J Jordan the same way he said he was his unkle but that made no diffference he could kill and rob the damed old Miser as quick as any body else we also had made a plot to rob a store on the dry fork belonging to Bill Kitchen also a plot to rob Charley Barrett and W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Tayler on the East fork. Jim Lyns often told me that he intended to make a living without work I went to George Carter and Stayed awhile and dicovered that nothing could be done at that time in that neighborhood and concluded to get off some where ^else^ <hi rend="str">were</hi> ^where^ we were not Known so well Jim Lyons asked me <gap/> was acquainted with Joseph Hatten <gap/> of bear Creek John Lyons was with <gap/> the time I told him that I was not <gap/> he Hatton has got a store there let us <gap/> down there and get him in the store and get what goods we want and his money then make him go with us across bear creek and Kill him for a dead man cannot tell on us says he we can do this and never be suspected it is so far out of our neighborhood This matter was spoken of frequenly by Jim Lyons and also by John I told him that it was a bad plan to Kill him for muder would tell he then made me agree to go with him down there and see what was in the store I then agreed and we went down (Here ^Wright^ held up his hand and requested<pb/>
<lb/><note place="left margin">4</note>
<lb/>me to swear him I then swore him that the statements he was about to make should be the truth ^the whole truth^ and nothing else but the truth) ^he then proceeded^ We arrived in on the top of a high rocky hill Just above Hattons store some time in the night I could not tell we stayed untill every thing seemed still we then came down and crossed at the mouth of bear creek on a log John and I went to the house we called for Hatten a woman asked us what we wanted I spoke and <hi rend="str">asked</hi> told her we wanted a plug of tobacco She said Archer was at the store I did not understand his name <gap/> went to the store and Jim Called <gap/> up he unlocked the door Jim <gap/> in first I walked in next and <gap/> that I wanted a plug of tobacc <gap/> have been near 10 Oclock Jim asked <gap/> a pair of boots says the man "I have no <gap/> boots Jim reached and took down a pair of heavy boots and tried them on they did not suit he then asked the man if he had any men's gaitors The man told him that he had says Jim let me see them he then laid a few pairs on the counter Jim picked a pair out the man spoke and asked Jim if he came up on the <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> Red Buck Jim told him he had he then asked Jim if he was going on up in the morning Jim told him that he was Jim then asked the man if he had any ready made clothing the man answered that he had some &amp; showed him a pair of pantaloons he took them and asked for shirts the man showed him a shirt Jim took that Jim then asked him if he had any fine womans shoes the man said he had and showed him some Jim took two pair he then asked if he had any worsted goods the man said he had
<lb/><note place="left margin">93</note><pb/>
<lb/><note place="left margin">7</note> <gap/> <note place="right margin">113</note>
<lb/>was at John M Jordans, and Bill Wright came up there and said to me that he had seen some men from the <hi rend="str">d</hi>Dry <hi rend="str">f</hi>Fork who wanted him to go with them and rob a store, and that he agreed to go with them, and said that he wanted me and John to go with them. I told him that I nor John would go, that I was not going to rob any man nor have anything to do with it. He then asked me to go to the top of the hill with him. That was where they were to meet John, and ^I^ went with him to the top of the hill. we there found Elijah Jackson, Joseph Spivy, and Jas. Wilburt. They all tried to get John and I to go with them, ^but^ we told them that we would not go that they might go if they wanted. John and I then went back to John Mullin's and stayed there until Saturday. On Saturday we started over to Ursula Holbrook's, and on the way we met Bill Wright. Bill owed me thirty dollars; he had some goods and I bought goods of him for the debt. I asked Bill where he got the goods. He said at the mouth of Bear Creek. John asked him if he killed the man, and Bill said yes, by ^god^ I did. I told Wright that that was a bad spot of work; that it would come out on him. Wright said he was not affraid. I here stoped him and asked him if he, Bill Wright, and John Lyons were not the men <hi rend="str">that</hi> ^who^ murdered Archer. He said that they were not. I then pulled out John Lyon's confession and read ^it^ to him, and left him. Afterwards, when he was under the gallows, he called to me and said that John Lyons had told me correctly about the Killing of Archer<pb/>
<lb/><note place="left margin">114</note></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
