<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0884"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Robert P. Snell to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5002</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-356 to BR10-357</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thos E. Bramblett</p>
<p>Your Petitioner Robert P. Snell respectfully represents that at the <date when="1857-11">Novr term of the Scott Circuit Court 1857</date> he upon a punishment of the Grand Jury was fined the sum of One Hundred dollars for betting upon an election. Before on the trial your petitioner had removed to the State of Missouri and his Council agreed to the sum afs<hi rend="sup">d</hi> in a fine and no doubt properly for the charge was true. Your Petitioner caused to be placed in the hands of a Friend means to satisfy said payment and he maybe <unclear/> <unclear/> had <unclear/> <unclear/> since settled and satisfied but to his surprise recently having returned to Kentucky he finds that the Atty. to whom payment was made has entered upon record payment <unclear/> of his fee having the remainder in full force. The Atty of W. S. Donnaly who was then County Atty aided the Comth in the Circuit Court by law and was authorized to collect fines. The said Donnaly joined the Rebel Army and is beyond the reach of your petitioner and he has no proof of the settlement of said payment-</p>
<p>By the progress of the War in Missouri with its <unclear/> and outrages (although always a Union Man) he has been ruined in his fortune and divested of much of his property He returned to Kentucky with his family poor penniless and would now be oppressed by even the small fine which he believed to be <unclear/> since adjusted and which<pb/>
<lb/>he yet believes was settled but he cannot so prove- His Surety was always good and the Money could have been made out of him at all times &amp; the very fact that it was not done is my <unclear/> pray that it was settled- Your Petitioner most respectfully ask a remission of the fine</p>
<p>Robt P. Snell</p>
<p>The undersigned unite in urging a remission of the fine in the case believing under all the circumstances that it is right</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J. G. Morrision</hi>
<lb/>J F Beatty clk S. C. C
<lb/>B. S. Sinclair
<lb/>Jas E Ennison S. S. C
<lb/>J. C. Yeman ^D C &amp;^ acting clk <unclear/> for Jno W Holloway Clk
<lb/>F H Abbott
<lb/>Urias M Offutt<pb/></p>
<p>I was the Atty of R. P. Snell in the foregoing named presentment I believe the statements of the Pettn to be substantially true and think under all the circumstances his request should be granted. The offence was not aggravated. An ordinary <unclear/> moral prayer made under political excitement in the <unclear/> of the concluded election</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J. F. Robinson</hi></p>
<p>Scott Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Approved
<lb/>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/><hi rend="str">Tho</hi>
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/><hi rend="str">McConnelley</hi> &amp; Robt Snell
<lb/>of
<lb/>$100-
<lb/><date when="1864-05-31">31<hi rend="sup">st</hi> May/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
