<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1825"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Solomon Harris to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6462</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-379 to BR13-380</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Lexington, Fayette County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-05-16">16 May 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>The undersigned says they have been fined in the County Court of Fayette County Kentucky in the sum of $200 &amp; costs in two cases -- towit $100 &amp; costs for auctioneering without license and $100 -- &amp; costs for pedling without license,</p>
<p>They say that they innocently violated the law in selling some dry goods in Lexington, at auction -- Some years ago they were in Lexington with goods and were permitted to sell them through and by an auctioneer who had license -- and when they recently came back they were informed by an auctioneer -- D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Keith -- that they might still do so without violating any law, and the said auctioneer told them, he could sell for them, Under this information and advise and in ignorance of the law they sold some good through said Auctioneer in Lexington,</p>
<p>They beg your Excellency to relieve them of the penalty of the violated laws so far as the interest of the Commonwealth of Kentucky is concerned,</p>
<p>Sol. Harris</p>
<p>Lex <date when="1865-05-16">May 16. 1865,</date><pb/></p>
<p>The subscribers solicit the Governor to remit the fine mentioned within So far as the interest of the Commonwealth is concerned</p>
<p>C D Carr Pres Judge of F Co Crt
<lb/>Geo A Kinkead
<lb/><hi rend="underline">F. K. Hunt</hi>
<lb/>Jno B Norton
<lb/>E Bowman Clk.
<lb/>W T Scott<pb/></p>
<p>Fayette County Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Sol Harris
<lb/>2 judgts
<lb/>$100. each
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1865-05-22">22<hi rend="sup">d</hi> May 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
