<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-2178"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Unknown, Note</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9254</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG24-284 to MG24-285</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Note</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><hi rend="underline">W. Blewett Cont</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi></p>
<p>I communicated to Ben Grider after Wilson's trial that if the jury had had the conversation I have detailed they would not have acquitted Wilson -- Communicated to Counsel for Comwlth -- but not till after first trial of Wilson -- Dont know of any one else to whom he communicated -- never told before on any of trials -- The Conversation was held at the last change of her <unclear/> in stage beyond <hi rend="str">Nu</hi> Franklin coming up -- I had a conversation with my brother Chas E Blewett <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> the Court house yard -- S. A Gossan came up. I told them that coming up the ridge Jones wanted to tell me about the case &amp; I told him to stop, but I never told them Jones did not tell me anything about it. I never ^told^ this to Gosson in Wood while laying off the land -- Gosson did not ask me why I liked one of the Jones beter than the other -- there was nothing said about this subject -- In the conversation in the Court house yard -- I said a heap of things I now deny -- I said many things I ought not to have said -- but they represent my saying things I did not -- Did not state to them that Jones did not tell him -- I located no time or place -- can't say where the ridge is -- &amp; I dont know that I said it was on the ridge Jones attempted to tell me -- I dont recollect whether Jones &amp; I walked up the ridge to ourselves -- I do not wish Jones conviction &amp; my feelings not inimical -- have taken no active part in prosecution &amp; responsible for no fees -- Never had bad feelings to Jones -- Jones is now about 23 yrs -- Jenkins would have been a year or two younger -- I employed the police at Nashville I have never hunted up a witness &amp; for Comwlth. Dont think I have conversed with witnesses &amp; then communicated to comwlth. Roberts staid with me &amp; I told him that Jones wanted to tell me about the occurence &amp; I would not let him &amp; Jones repeatedly offered to tell me all about it &amp; I would not let him -- Roberts appealed his views &amp; I did not agree with him -- I told Roberts Jone, had attempted to tell me &amp; I would not let him -- Dont know that he did or did not tell Roberts Jones<pb/>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">W Blewett Cont</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi>
<lb/>never told him anything about it -- I think I told Rodes about the conversation with Jones -- The conversation in the yard with my brother I dont recollect what it was. dont think had anything to say about Jones. At time of surveying Potter was surveyor -- I was chain carrier <hi rend="str">part of time</hi> -- Gosson &amp; I were not always with Potter.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Arthur</hi> <hi rend="underline">Graham</hi>.</p>
<p>After shooting Jones &amp; Wilson started off together -- I was in 6 or 7 ft. Didnt see Wilson when Jones shot -- first I saw of Wilson after shot Wilson was 6 or 8 steps off -- Jones walked up to WIlson before Wilson moved -- I saw them getting over the fence -- didn't see Wilson come back. Wilson staid where Jones left him till Jones returned to him. I had drank some before I started -- furnished <unclear/> liquor that evening -- <hi rend="str">dron</hi> Dont know what time Jones &amp; Jenkins came to store. Jones left there late in the evening -- before seen. down. 1 <hi rend="sup">1/4</hi> from my store to Mrs Jones' -- pretty certain Wilson was not right behind Jones when he shot -- </p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Jas</hi>. <hi rend="underline">Mitchell</hi>
<lb/>saw Jones when he shot -- Wilson at that time was 6 or 8 steps from Jones -- standing still -- I was in 4 ft of Jenkins -- Jones wheeled &amp; ran to where Wilson was -- I was not noticing Wilsons when pistol fired. Did'nt see Wilson come back -- Heard no cry that Jenkins had a knife -- was not in passage when difficulty began -- </p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Tho L. Stevens</hi></p>
<p>saw Wilson directly after pistol fired, behind Jones 10 or 15 feet. Wilson came back about <hi rend="sup">1/2</hi> way. I saw them after shot till they got nearly to fence. Did'nt see Wilson come back my attention was attracted to Jones -- Jones turned &amp; walked back to Wilson -- great excitement about time of shot -- </p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Alfred Vernon</hi></p>
<p>Was along time A D Roberts speaks of -- Dont recollect any conversation about Jones because I was not near enough to hear. <hi rend="underline">I want that</hi>.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Chas</hi>. <hi rend="underline">Spalding</hi></p>
<p>Was a witness on trial of Wilson -- Dont think he has made any different statement -- At former trial I stated when I saw Jones start he drew the pistol advanced &amp; fired. leveled the pistol before he stopped -- I said Jones leaned over as he came up because he came up so fast. Saw Jones &amp; Wilson start off -- Wilson was 15 or 20 feet from Jones when he fired Did not hear any one say Jenkins had a knife -- Thinks Judge <unclear/> examined me last court -- Jones leaned forward all the time -- never said Jones shrank back.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Defts</hi>. <hi rend="underline">Evidence</hi></p>
<p>I went round the court house &amp; was asked by strange to stop W &amp; C S Blewett -- Blewett said he could have known all about the matter if he had tried -- he said as they were walking up the hill this side of Nashville &amp; Jones wanted to tell him all about it &amp; he would'nt let him -- he said about same in Woods when surveying I asked him how he happened to be more friendly with Rufers than Henry Jenkins -- he explained why -- Said Rufus had gone to school to him &amp; he liked &amp; he could have known all about the matter if he had let Jones tell him.</p>
<p>C. E. Blewett</p>
<p>I was present at time Gosson speaks of in yard -- he said he could have known all about it -- Jones began to tell him &amp; he stopped him &amp; would'nt let him tell anything about it -- that is my recollection, my brother excited -- <pb/>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">B. C. Grinder</hi></p>
<p>was present when Blewetts were talking as stated by Gosson &amp; Blewett cant state what Blewett said about Jones -- </p>
<p>I cross examined Spalding on Wilson's trial -- my recollection is Spalding was setting about where I am -- he said that Jones just before shooting shrunk back, scringed or dodged as if dodging a blow &amp; shows the motion -- he made Spalding repeat it -- &amp; argued it -- <unclear/> springs 18 or 20 miles this side of Nashville -- </p>
<p>J C Watkins</p>
<p>statement of Jones' shrinking as stated by Grinder was made by some witness, but cant say it was Spalding -- </p>
<p>J. R. Underwood called by Comwlth</p>
<p>Has no notes of Former trial -- has a recollection the statement as made by Grider &amp; Wilkins as having been made by <hi rend="underline">some one -- I</hi> cannot state the motion -- a little dodge -- </p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Jas</hi> <hi rend="underline">Jones</hi></p>
<p>one of the Wilson jury -- dont recollect Spalding was examined. Dont recollect the statement made as referred <hi rend="str">to</hi> of Spalding -- Dont recollect all the Evidence -- </p>
<p>S S. Potter -- </p>
<p>Saw Jenkins -- ball entered on left side &amp; ranged thru -- 3 or 4 inches from navel=</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
