<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1545"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Patrick Cummins et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11013</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Amanda Boczar</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG22-158 to MG22-159</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To the Hon<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">ble</hi></hi> Beriah M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Goffin, Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>Your petitioner Parick Cummins begs respectfully to represent, that, <hi rend="str">a few days Since</hi> on the 2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi> day of <date when="--09">September</date> Court a fine or verdict was rendered against him in the Police Court of the City of Louisville on the prosecution of Hannah Duffy, <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>for the sum of <hi rend="str">Sixty</hi> $50. dollars, &amp; ^at same times for Keeping a tipling house, <hi rend="str">Fifty</hi> $60 dollars -- ^ The said Hanna -- with others, occupied <hi rend="underline">Rooms</hi> as <hi rend="underline">tenants</hi> in the house of Petitioner, -- during his absence, She with another woman -- both under the influence of Liquor became engaged in a fight &amp; used each other badly up -- your petitioner at this time came back to his house, &amp; finding the Condition of affairs between these two women, he in Company with a M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Gill went up to Seperate &amp; if possible to pacify these enraged belligerants, M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">rs</hi></hi>. Duffy was perfectly mad with rage, and attacking y<hi rend="sup">r</hi> petitioner with a <hi rend="underline">Knife</hi> &amp; <hi rend="underline">Brickbat</hi>, she cut him below the <hi rend="underline">knee</hi> &amp; to prevent further injuries, he was Compelled to lay hold on her &amp; to wrest from her the weapons of attack, your petitioner used no more force than was necessary for said purpose and did not inflict any injury to her person --  --, Out of <hi rend="underline">pure</hi> <hi rend="underline">malice</hi> she charged <hi rend="underline">him</hi><pb/>
<lb/>with committing an Assault on her ^added that he kept a tipling house^ And without proof to sustain her charge y<hi rend="sup">r</hi> petitioner not being able to procure witnesses ^except, one W. J Quick, who disproved all her statements^ on his behalf was hurried into trial &amp; he was subjected most unjustly to the foregoing Verdict</p>
<p>Your Petitioner is a poor man, Keeping a small Grocery for Support of himself and family -- and in the present <hi rend="underline">awful</hi>, and distressing times of trouble and alarm, would be ruined by the exacting off him the said finis, he then humbly prays y<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Excellency would extend to him that clemency to which he is so justly entitled ^and order this fine to be remitted^ and as in duty bound will ever pray. </p>
<p>Patrick Cumming</p>
<p>We join in the prayer of the foregoing Petition -- </p>
<p>W. R. Murphy -- <unclear/>, &amp;e</p>
<p>I Join with Petitioner, and recommend that the fine of $50- be remitted,</p>
<p>W. G. Reasor</p>
<p>I Know Pat Cummins to be a man of industrious habits sober and temperate he is a poor man and from my knowledge of the case recom<hi rend="str">e</hi>mend him to your clemmency as a man deserving your sympathies } W R Hydes M. C. C. L<pb/></p>
<p>M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Cummins is a Temperate man quiet &amp; civil &amp; clever Citizen I. concur with M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Reasor the city atto in recommending the remission of the fine of Fifty Dollars. Geo. W. Johnston.</p>
<p>The Fines assessed against Cummings was $50 for an assault on H. Duffy &amp; $60 for Keeping a Tipling House</p>
<p>Johnston.</p>
<p>Mr Cummins has been in our Employ for five Years, and we can truely concur in all that has been said in his <hi rend="underline">favour</hi> as sober industrious and trustworthy -- he has a wife and four children whom he is struggling to support, his wife attends the grocery while he works for us -- and we would earnestly reccomend that the <hi rend="underline">fines</hi> above named be remitted -- We have always found him a man of <hi rend="underline">truth</hi></p>
<p> -- J. F. Stone. &amp; Co -- 
<lb/> -- Carriage Dealers -- </p>
<p>P.S Please direct Patrick Cummins
<lb/>Case J T Stone &amp; Co
<lb/> -- Louisville Ky -- <pb/></p>
<p>Louisville City Ct</p>
<p>Remitted as to the fine of $50 -- 
<lb/>B. M.</p>
<p>$50 } Mis
<lb/>Pat. Cumminss
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-11-19">Nov 19. 1861</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
