<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1101"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. John Rice, Bond</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5738</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-191 to BR11-191-1</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Mercer County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-06-20">20 June 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Mercer Circuit Court
<lb/>Wednesday <date when="1860-04-11">April 11 1860</date></p>
<p>The Commonwealth Plff
<lb/>vs } Upon Indt
<lb/>John Rice Deft</p>
<p>The parties appeared by their attorneys and the defendant filed his plea of not Guilty and thereupon came a Jury M D Hall C H Buford Stephen Stone Ben F. Ransdall Jas S Burnell Jno W Gray G S Terhune Jas P Terhune Jas Kirby Jas D Smith Philip Mosely &amp; Elijah Gabbert who were Sworn well &amp; Truly to try and a true Verdict render herein Having heard the evidence returned the following verdict We of Jury find the defendant Guilty of the offence charged against him in the indictment. It is therefore adjudged that the plaintiff recover the defendant Sixty dollars for Keeping a tippling house &amp; the costs &amp; c</p>
<p>The following Replevin Bond was taken in Satisfaction of the above Judgment viz</p>
<p>We Jno Rice principal and W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> A Chambers J D Hale Securitys do bind ourselves, three months after the date<pb/>
<lb/>hereof to pay the Commonwealth of Kentucky the plaintiff in <hi rend="underline">fine</hi> of $69.07 fine which issued from the Clerk's office of the Circuit Court of Mercer County on the <date when="1863-07-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of July 1863</date> in favor of the said Commonwealth for the sum of $60 debt or damages,.40 cents for bond Cost ^of suit^ $7 -- $1.67 Sheriff's half commission amounting in the whole to the sum of $69.07 aforesaid against the said J R Rice and we the said W A Chambers security have hereby replevied the same.</p>
<p>Witness our hands and seals this <date when="1863-07-07">7 day of July 1863</date></p>
<p>J R Rice <figure type="seal"/>
<lb/>William Chambers
<lb/>J D Hale <figure type="seal"/></p>
<p>attest
<lb/>Jno C Gabhart D.S</p>
<p>Upon which Replevin bond an Execution issued on the <date when="1863-10-30">30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> October 1863</date> which has not been returned</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Mercer Circuit } Sct</p>
<p>I Richard Clerk Mercer Circuit Court certify that the within Judgment Replevin bond and date of Execution on Said bond is a true copy as is of record and on file in the office of the Clerk of <pb/>
<lb/>the Mercer Circuit</p>
<p>Given under my hand this <date when="1863-07-20">20 day of June 1863</date></p>
<p>Richard Board Clerk
<lb/>Mercer Circuit Court<pb/></p>
<p>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Copy Replevin Bond &amp;c
<lb/>John Rice &amp; others</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
