<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0996"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">George Shirley and Ezekiel Wilty, Affidavit</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5115</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR11-40</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-06-13">13 June 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>We George Shirley and Ezekiel Wilty-</p>
<p>State that John Branstetter an infirm old man of near 70- years has lived many years in this county (formerly Barren County) a respected &amp; good citizen and up to the commencement of this Rebellion a Sober &amp; discreet man- that the Guerrilas Robbed him of a great deal of his property. From the troubles consequent there to &amp; the additional fact we suppose, that his two sons Joined an independent company called the "Metcalfe Tigers" for the purpose of hunting down guerrillas &amp; were exposed to many dangers the Old man took to drink- While in one of his drinking sprees he was induced by some bad men to go into the woods &amp; play a game of cards. The game was played on his land &amp; money was bet &amp; won as appears by the <hi rend="str">evidence</hi> Testimony of a credible witness- who chanced to come upon them &amp; saw the game He has been indicted therefore tried &amp; fined $200- which is the least the law provides in such cases This old man is often delirious &amp; wild wherein these drinking sprees &amp; has to be guarded sometimes We his neighbors &amp; friends are candid in representing that we think this is one of the <hi rend="underline">few</hi> cases which demand the interposition of the Governor and ask that his fine be remitted.</p>
<p>George Shirley &amp; E Wilty Say that they believe the Statements in the above petition are true <date when="1864-06-13">June 13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date></p>
<p>Geo Shirley
<lb/>E Wilty</p>
<p>Sworn to be fore me by Geo Shirley &amp; E Wilty <date when="1864-06-13">June 13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1864</date></p>
<p>Tho E Young. C. M. C. C<pb/></p>
<p>Edmondson C. Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John W Bailey
<lb/>$200-
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1864-07-05">5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> July/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
