<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2830"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Emit to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7467</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-108 to BR17-109</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thomas E. Bramlette Governor of Kentucky, Your Petitioner William Emmet would respectfully State,</p>
<p>That some time about the <date when="--09-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day of Sept 186<unclear/></date>, he endorsed as bail a recognizance of George Carter who had been attached as a witness under an order of the Lincoln Circuit Court, in the case of the commonwealth against one Frank Morrison (of color) charged with Tipling, <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi>condition for said Carters appearance as witness at the trial of the cause in the Lincoln Circuit Court Your petitioner states that said Carter during the time <unclear/>that said action was pending was a private in the 13<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Reg<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">t</hi></hi> Ky. Vol,</p>
<p>That at the <date when="1865-09">September Term of the Lincoln Circuit Court 1865</date> a forfeiture of said bond was taken against your petitioner and a Judgement rendered thereon for the Sum of one hundred dollars &amp; costs &amp;c</p>
<p>Your petitioner states that he is poor, and has a large family, that as a neighbor he went in the bail bond that his principal had been in the Federal Army, and could not attend as a witness -- that petitioner supposed the case had been dismissed and he relieved from the bond, and did not attend the Court at the Term at<pb/>
<lb/>which the Judgement for the forfeiture of the bond was taken, That it was for no contempt of court, or disregard of the Laws of his Country that he did not attend at the Court</p>
<p>Under the circumstances of the case, he humbly asks that your Excellency interpose in behalf and release him from the penalty of the bond, and discharge him from the liability of the Judgement as far as in your power and for which relief your petitioner will ever feel grateful.</p>
<p>With the sincere hope that you will favorably consider this his petition he respectfully subscribes himself</p>
<p>Your obedient Servant
<lb/>+ William Emit
<lb/><note place="left margin">J. A. Bryant</note></p>
<p>We the undersigned <hi rend="str">acquainces of William Emmitt</hi> citizens of Lincoln County, and acquaintances of William Emmitt, would respectfully recommend him to your Excellency's clemency and hope that you will grant the relief he asks, in his petition We are induced to do this from the considerations that his statements are true that he is poor, and the circumstances of his case demand your interposition, and<pb/>
<lb/>sincerely hope you will grant the relief sought by him</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>Your friends 
<lb/>R Blain<pb/></p>
<p>Lincoln Cr Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Petition
<lb/>of
<lb/>W. Emmit
<lb/>$160.
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/><date when="1865-12-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Dec /65</date>
<lb/>Remit</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
