<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0001"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Cal Underwood and William Sprowls to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4120</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-1</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Taylor County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. E. Bramlette Governor of the <orgName ref="cwgk:O001025">Commonwealth of Kentucky</orgName> -- Your Petitioners <persName ref="cwgk:N00000512">Cal Underwood</persName> &amp; W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Sproul respectfully State, that they were indicted by the Grand Jury of <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000681">Taylor County</placeName> at a former term of the Court for a Breach of the Peace upon the testimony of <persName ref="cwgk:N00000504">Lewis Bell</persName> and his wife, and at the <date when="1863-09">September Term 1863</date> Inst. upon a trial of the case, they were fined Ten dollars each. Your petitioners state that the verdict of the Jury was wholly unexpected to them, as they were concious of having been guilty of no breach of the Peace, nor was any such thing intended. Nor could it rationally be construed into a breach of the Peace on the part of said Underwood &amp; Sproul. The proof in the case was simply, that Underwood &amp; Sproul stoped at the house of said Bell, on their way home from the camp at <placeName ref="cwgk:P00000507">Campbellsville</placeName> where they had been to visit sons and neighbor boys who were in the army. and having imbibed a little freely, they felt funny good natured and frolicsome. having some of the ardent along with them, they asked Bell to drink out of their bottle, which he did, they then gave all of their children a drink, and last offered the old lady some, and she having become offendid at some remarks that had been made about her sons who were in the <orgName ref="cwgk:O00000506">Confederate army</orgName>, struck the bottle with violence knocking it out of Sprouls hand, and spilling some of the liquor in her own face and breaking the bottle. No one was mad on the<pb/></p>
<p>occasion but M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi>. Bell. She ordered your petitioners Underwood &amp; Sproul out of the house, and they immediately obeyed, and went out. she closed the door on them, then took a gun from the rack, and shot through the door at them but they were gone. there was no proof that your peititioners Sproul &amp; Underwood did or said any thing in anger, or intended harm or wrong in any respect. May it therefore please your Excellency the premises considered to remit the fines aforesaid, and as in duty bound they will ever pray &amp;c.</p>
<p>C,, Underwood
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> sprouls</p>
<p>The undersigned neighbors and County men of the above Petitioners, join with them in the above petition, and request that the fines above stated be remited.</p>
<p><persName ref="cwgk:N00000508">Jas Jones</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00000509">J W Overstreet
</persName><lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Burress
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00000511">S. W. goalhart
</persName><lb/>J B M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Whorter
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00000496">Samuel A Jones
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00000497">J H Chandler
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00000498">John Wood
</persName><lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> C Thompson
<lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00000500">S. B. Stinnett
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00000501">Ralph Watson</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00000502">G. W Redmon
</persName><lb/><persName ref="cwgk:N00000503">C Hoskins</persName></p>
<p>Taylor Co
<lb/>No grounds presented for Executive clemency
<lb/><date when="1863-09-22">Sept 22nd 1863</date>
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
