<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0831"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Richard H. Stanton to Landaff W. Andrews</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10299</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-307 to MG19-308</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Carlisle, Nicholas County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-03-19">19 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Carlisle, Ky,
<lb/><date when="1861-03-19">March 19, 1861</date>
<lb/>Hon L. W. Andrews,
<lb/>My dear Sir,</p>
<p>I promised to remind you of the case of John Kissick, who was convicted at the last term of the Rowan Circuit Court of shooting at Barney Hayden, and fined $21 and imprisoned six months, you heard the testimony, and know that it was a drunken spree, and accompanied with such circumstances as did not indicate malice toward Hayden, He is now in the fourth week of his imprisonment, and I think has been sufficiently punished, and it would be a mercy to relieve him from the balance of the sentence, The fine I suppose has been, or will be paid by his father,</p>
<p>I authorize you to file this letter with<pb/>
<lb/>the Govenor as my recomendation of Kissick to his clemency,</p>
<p>Your friend truly,
<lb/>R. H. Stanton<pb/></p>
<p>Senate Chamber
<lb/><date when="1861-03-22">Mar 22<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Hon B. Magoffin</p>
<p>Der Sir At the accomping request of Hon R H Stanton attny for Commwth I cheerfully unite in the recommendation that you Excellency pardon Mr Kessick I am very sure ^he^ has been punished fuly Sufficet. as he has now ben in jail one month and it will be at least a week before a Parden can reach him</p>
<p>Your frd
<lb/>L W Andrews<pb/></p>
<p>Rowan Cir. Ct
<lb/>$21. &amp; 6 mo impris<hi rend="sup">t</hi>=
<lb/>Jno. Kissick'</p>
<p>Is<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1861-03-23">Mar 23. 1861</date></p>
<p>Remitted
<lb/>B M</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
