<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-028-0068"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">A. G. Baldwin to James F. Robinson</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7723</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Appointments by the Governor, Military Appointments, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R2-212</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1862-11-22">22 November 1862</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Head-Quarters Louisville, Kentucky,
<lb/>Louisville, Ky <date when="1862-11-22">Nov 22<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> 1862</date>
<lb/>Your Excellency -- </p>
<p>I would most respectfully request that I may be given a field officers position, In making this request, I would beg leave to call your attention to the fact, that I was recommended by Genls Nelson Jackson and Gilbert for a Colonelcy sometime in August last, and you were then kind enough to promise me the first vacancie. There is now a vacancy in the 7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Calvary as also in some of the Inft Regts, I would say in conclusion that I served five years in the Regular Army -- that I commanded a company at shiloh, that I was upon the staff of Genl Nelson at Richmond Ky and upon the staff of Genl Gilbert at the battle of Perryville Ky for each of which I received honorable mention in the published official reports.</p>
<p>I am sir
<lb/>very respectfully
<lb/>your most 
<lb/>obdt servant
<lb/>O L Baldwin
<lb/>Capt 2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> Ky &amp; Asst Inspt Genl</p>
<p>To his excellency
<lb/>The Governor of Kentucky<pb/></p>
<p>Head Quarters Louisville
<lb/><date when="1862-11-22">Nov 22<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1862</date></p>
<p>I cordially recommend Capt Oliver L Baldwin for promotion -- He is a faithful, efficient, <unclear/> and brave officer -- He is a native of Woodford Co Ky and is and always has been a citizen of our state.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">J. T. Boyle</hi>
<lb/>Brig Genl
<lb/>Louisville Ky
<lb/><date when="1862-11-23">Nov. 23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 62</date></p>
<p>Capt Baldwin has had the advantage of most thorough training in the regular ^army^ when he passed from private to 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Sergt under Major Paul 7<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Infy. This early training I conceive to be invaluable &amp; the State of Kentucky will do well to avail itself of this element of success whenever and by whomever offered -- </p>
<p>In the particular instance of Capt Baldwin as the war progresses, the state Authorities will recognize his value</p>
<p>C. C. Gilbert
<lb/>Brig. Gen.</p>
<p><hi rend="str">I fully recognize and appreciate the worth and services of Capt Baldwin &amp; much regret that I have now no place vacant to tender him worthy of his acceptance. I very cordially commend him to the justice &amp; confidence of his country</hi></p>
<p><date when="1862-11-26">26 Nov. 62</date>
<lb/><note place="body">mistake
<lb/><unclear/> <unclear/></note>
<lb/>J. F. Robinson</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
