<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2422"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John W. Letcher et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7059</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR15-364 to BR15-365</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-09-25">25 September 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>His Excellency Thomas E. Bramlett. Gov of Ky.</p>
<p>Your petitioners citizens of Garrard co. would respectfully represent that at the last <date when="--08">August</date> term of the Garrard circuit Court The Grand Jury Among other rather remarkable things indicted W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Ross for the murder of M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Clure. We are Satisfied that the facts of the Case are <hi rend="str">about</hi> Substantially as follows, on the retreat of Braggs Army from Ky in the fall of <date when="1862">1862</date>, a Squad ^of Federal Soldiers^ was sent out from Crab Orchard, in the direction of the Big Hill to look after &amp; pick up straggling rebels that were supposed to be in that part of the Country. Lieut W. D. Carpenter was in Command of said Squad in the upper portion of Garrard Co. but a few miles from where John Morgan was <hi rend="str">Campt</hi> Camped. The said W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Ross was directed to take Charge of John L. Slavin &amp; Ben F. Slavin who were prisoners &amp; permit them to go by their houses -- They met McCluer dressed some like a rebel Soldier <hi rend="str">Carpe</hi> Ross went back towards him, halted him &amp; Called on him to surrender, which he did not do but drew his pistol, shots were fired &amp; Ross Killed him, no person was near but the slavins &amp; they were some distance off -- the parties believe that rebels were upon them &amp; hastened to join the Command. McClure was a Stranger to Ross &amp; the Slavins, the slavins were citizens of Garrard Co. &amp; are men of good Character for veracity but have been rebel sympathisers -- It turned out that McCluer was not a rebel Soldier, but was a citizen of Rockcastler Co. -- </p>
<p>By Common Consent Ross was regarded as guilty of <hi rend="str">any</hi> no <hi rend="str">thing</hi> crime, whatever in the matter, but that he had acted in good faith in the discharge of ^at least^ a supposed duty &amp; this opinion has been acquiessed in until these "Conservators of the ^Peace"^ &amp; Vindicators of <hi rend="str">the</hi> Violated law," the grand Jury ^of Garrard Co.^ decided otherwise -- <pb/></p>
<p>Ross was in the Federal service &amp; was one of said squad he has served three years. was a good soldier &amp; is a good citizen, Believing that Federal Soldiers ought not now to be harrassed by rebels, for acts done by Said Soldiers in the line of duty during the war. We ask your Excellency pardon said Ross.</p>
<p><date when="1865-09-25">Sept. 25. 1865</date> -- </p>
<p>John W Letcher
<lb/>H. S. Burnam
<lb/>George Dunn
<lb/>John Watson
<lb/>G, P, Brown
<lb/>John V, L, Brown
<lb/>R. Hackley
<lb/>S M Sackey
<lb/>B. F. Pheriss
<lb/>C C <unclear>Storm</unclear>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">L R M</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi><hi rend="underline">Murtry</hi>
<lb/>C. I. Spilman
<lb/>William Sellers
<lb/>S. C. Henderson
<lb/>Davis Layton
<lb/>A, J, Burnam
<lb/>John Rowans Jailor
<lb/>William Ray, M, D,
<lb/>J. Q. A. Walker
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> H, Kinnaird</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
