<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0276"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Lovell Head to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9744</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-258 to MG17-259</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Harrodsburg, Mercer County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-12-29">29 December 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency, Beriah Magoffin, Governor of the state of Kentucky:</p>
<p>Lovell Head makes oath to the following statements: In <date when="1860-07">July last</date> he was arraigned before the Police Court of Harrodsburg for fighting with one Bill Carter, and a judgment was entered Against him by s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">id</hi></hi> Court for $20. -- and costs. He states that there was no riotousness or fuss connected with fight; only a blow or two was struck in mere momentary passion. He states that he believes that he was in no-wise blameable; that he done nothing for which he ought to be fined. He states that he is a poor boy, dependent on his daily labor for a support, and that he is unable to pay the fine: That unless it be remitted by Your Excellency he will have to go to Jail. He states that he never engaged in a fight either before or since, and that it was never his intention to do anything against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth; wherefore he prays and humbly petitions Your Excellency to remit this fine.</p>
<p>L. Head</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Lovell Head this <date when="1860-12-29">29<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Dec. 1860</date>.</p>
<p>J A Sillard J P M C</p>
<p>The undersigned state that they believe Lovell Head to be an honest, hard-working<pb/>
<lb/>boy, and that they believe his statements above, are true; and they do humbly petition Your Excellency to remit the s<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> fine.</p>
<p>P. B Thompson
<lb/>Geo. W. Tompkins
<lb/>T H Buckner
<lb/>Eyre Askew
<lb/>B F Patterson
<lb/>Turner, Bottom
<lb/>J G. Carter
<lb/>James Burke
<lb/>Thomas B Carter
<lb/>J. B. Thompson<pb/></p>
<p>Harrodsburg Po. ct
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/>B. M
<lb/>Is<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> <date when="1861-01-03">Jany 3</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
