<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0209"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Jabel Smith et al. to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG9677</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG17-164 to MG17-165</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Clay County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-11-21">21 November 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Beriah Magoffin Gov<hi rend="sup">r.</hi> of the Commonwealth of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your Petitioners Jabel Smith Elias Smith Hiram Smith and Milam Smith would respectfully state that at the present <date when="--11">November Term</date> of the Clay Circuit Court a fine of $20. was assessed against each of your petitioners Jabel, Elias and Milam Smith &amp; Hiram Smith upon a charge of illegal gaming They state that the game played was a game for 5 Cents only and played outside of any tenement or enclosure, They are verry illiterate and live in an out of the way place about 15 miles from Manchester the seat of Justice, and did not know that it was against the law to play a game in an out of the way place, unless there was as much as $20. bet, won or lost -- They are not only unlearned but very poor and have families -- </p>
<p>And at the same Term of the Court there was a fine of $20. assessed against each of your petitioners Hiram &amp; Milam Smith for retailing liquor one time -- your petitioners do not follow the business of Selling liquors, and owing to their ignorance and poverty, they pray your excellency to remit said fines -- they cannot pay said fines &amp; costs without Serious injury to them and their families</p>
<p>Jabel Smith
<lb/>Elias Smith
<lb/>Hiram Smith
<lb/>Milam Smith</p>
<p>Sworn to before me by Jabel, Elias, Hiram &amp; Milam Smith. <date when="1860-11-21">Nov 21 1860</date>.</p>
<p>J S, M, Dickerson D Clk
<lb/>for G W Price Clk<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersinged Citizens of clay County believe the Statemts in the foregoing petition and would also ask your Excellency to remit the fines therein named.</p>
<p>T. T. Garrard
<lb/>J. S. M. Dickson
<lb/>John Heyden
<lb/>F. Z. Gilbert
<lb/>Dan<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">l</hi></hi> Garrard
<lb/>G. W. Price Clerk c. c. C.
<lb/>D, Y, Lyttle<pb/></p>
<p>Clay cir. ct.
<lb/>Clay Co
<lb/>Respite 12 mo
<lb/>B, M
<lb/>$20.
<lb/>$20
<lb/>Smith Family
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="sup">d</hi> <date when="1860-12-01">Decr. 1 1860</date><pb/></p>
<p>Manchester <date when="1860-11-21">Nov 21<hi rend="sup">st</hi></date>
<lb/>Gov Magoffin</p>
<p>The foregoing petitioner are ignorant honest men who live a considerable distance from the county seat and being illiterate and so far removed from where any information can be had in relation to the penal laws that I have no Idea that they as either of them knew that they were violatiang the law and I am fully satisfied that they never will violate the law again in the manner they have done for which they were fined I hope that you will remit the fines against them</p>
<p>yours respt
<lb/>Granville Pearl
<lb/>John Dishman</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
