<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0716"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. P. Downs to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4835</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-96</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thos E Bramlett</p>
<p>Your petitioner hereto state that at the <date when="--03">last March term</date> of the Ohio Circuit Court they were found guilty of keeping a tippling house and fined sixty dollars. They hereto state that they petitioners go before court, indulging the hope that they would be <unclear/>, but recd no answer presuming that you failed to give any Relief on account of the trial not being had they again object to your clemency They reiterate the statements in their former petition which was sworn to by both parties to wit John Roley &amp; W P Downs. The statements in former were substantially then. that they were keeping and selling goods as merchants on a very small scale &amp; obtained license from the Government and thought they had the right to sell and did for a short time publicaly &amp; privately The assessor thought they had the right. They had license as merchants from the county court also The Sheriff of the County presumed to know said he had the right to sell and it was the understanding generally and believing it we sold by the drink and otherwise, we sold out liquor and goods &amp; quit. These facts are true. We are for man and the penalty falls very heavy on us. The Judge said on defence was not good in court, but under Law to appeal to you. We earnestly petition for Executive clemency. M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Roley does not sign this because he lives a long ways from town.<pb/>
<lb/>He signed &amp; swore to the other. The Sheriff will be pressing us the law <unclear>Reflective</unclear> the debt under this confident Life that you would relieve us</p>
<p>W. P. Downs</p>
<p>We could procur any number of names, but thought a fair statement under oath would answer as well or better.</p>
<p>Ohio Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>John Roley
<lb/>&amp;
<lb/>W. P. Downs
<lb/>Remit
<lb/>55
<lb/>Remitted
<lb/><date when="1864-04-21">21<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Apl/64</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
