<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2541"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John G. Fletcher to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7178</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-63 to BR16-64</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-10-29">29 October 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><hi rend="str">T</hi> To his Excellency Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> H. Bramlette Governor of the Commonwealth of Kentucky -- </p>
<p>Your Petitioner <hi rend="str">N</hi>J. <hi rend="str">J</hi>G. Fletcher a citizen of Fulton County, Kentucky would respectfully state unto your Excellency that at the last <date when="1865-09">Sept Term 1865</date> of the Fulton Circuit Court he was convicted in three cases of the Commonwealth of Kentucky against him of selling liquor to slaves, &amp; in each case fined $50.00 -- Now your Petitioner would state that at the time said liquor was sold, he was a regular licensed tavern keeper in Fulton County Ky and had the privilege of retailing spirituous at his house, and he had no intention to violate the Laws of this Commonwealth -- Your Petitioner would state that he has ever been a good citizen of this Commonwealth and that he is a poor man with a large family to support -- Your Petitioner would call your Excellencys attention to the unsettled condition of our country for the last four years and especially this part of Ky, &amp; the exact status in which the military have regarded slaves within the past two years and ask your Excellency to look with clemency on his action in selling liquor to a class who were upheld &amp; supported by the military down here as superior<pb/>
<lb/>to the white race, and grant remission of the said fines -- </p>
<p>All which is most respectfully and urgently asked -- 
<lb/><date when="1865-10-29">Oct 29<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date> -- </p>
<p>John G Fletcher<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned citizens of Fulton County Ky, would state that we have known <hi rend="str">N</hi>J. <hi rend="str">J</hi>G. Fletcher, the foregoing Petitioner, for the last eight years that he has ever been a quiet, peaceable and orderly citizen, that he is an honest &amp; upright man, has a wife and large family living here, that he is a poor man, &amp; would respectfully ask the Executive to remit the fines imposed upon him at last Sept Court, believing that the good citizens of this County would approve the act -- <date when="1865-10-30">October 30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date> -- </p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>W D Hutchinson
<lb/>J R Upshaw
<lb/>J Matthews
<lb/>A, M, Perry
<lb/>J A Douglass
<lb/>M. L. &amp; M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Jilton
<lb/>W C M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Daniel
<lb/>R S Chapman
<lb/>Williamn Higgs
<lb/><unclear/> L Lankford
<lb/>R. D. Harrwood
<lb/>A,, Shuck
<lb/>O. P. Smith
<lb/>J. W. Powell
<lb/>W M Hughes
<lb/>John F. Lyles
<lb/>C Wodard
<lb/>R C Miller Police Judge City of Hickman Ky
<lb/>G W Stoner
<lb/><cb n="2"/>A, D, Kingman
<lb/>Samuel Landrum Judge of Fulton County Court.
<lb/>W R Walker
<lb/>J E Atkins
<lb/>J A Overton
<lb/>John Mays
<lb/>J B Rose
<lb/>J, L, Luttrell
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Jo</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi><hi rend="underline"> Royster</hi>
<lb/>M. R Sherron
<lb/>J. F. Marrs
<lb/>Jno Thomas
<lb/>D T Church
<lb/>Z M M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>all
<lb/>N, H, Roner
<lb/>O, D, Clark
<lb/>G, P, Saunders
<lb/>A Prather
<lb/>H. C. Bailey<pb/>
<lb/><milestone unit="column" n="1"/>Levi Maddox
<lb/>R A Faris
<lb/>W B Legeate
<lb/>W C Anderson
<lb/>Thad W Thomas
<lb/>Howell F Craves
<lb/>J H Montgomery
<lb/>B F Casey S F C
<lb/>G, S, Miles</p>
<p>If fine remitted please enclose remission to Petitioner -- John G. Fletcher -- or to A D. Kingman his atto -- Hickman Fulton Co. Ky.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
