<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2967"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Casey, Georg W. Sebastian, and Alexander Leasure to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7604</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR43-48 to BR43-49</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thomas E Bramlet Governor of Kentukcy</p>
<p>your Petitioners John Casey George Sebastian &amp; Alexander Leasure would respectfully represent unto your Honour that they wer indicted for maliciously Shooting &amp; fighting the <unclear>Mis</unclear> Lands Some years Since &amp; had one trial &amp; Jury could not agree all that the Jury proposed doing with them was to fine them but was unable to agree upon the fine and at the Last term of the Garrard Circuit Court they confessed Judgement for $25 each &amp; an Attorneys fee of five Dollars each the cost in the case was $32. and 60 in each case which amounted to $57 and 60 cents each now your Petitioner G W Sebastian has paid all his fine &amp; costs Except $12 your Petitioner John Casey has paid all but $22 and your Petitioner Alexander Leasure has not paid any thing to wards the<pb/>
<lb/>fine and Costs and we unite in this Petition &amp; ask your excellency to remit our fines as the expense of the Law suit &amp; our Lawyers fees have oppressed us and we have made friends with the Lands &amp; have peace &amp; good will for all mankind &amp; we assure you we will not trouble the Courts with trying us againe nor will we trouble you with any furthe Petitions</p>
<p>John Casey
<lb/>Georg W Sebastian
<lb/>&amp; Alexander Leasure<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>I state that the above petition contains the facts touching said Trial &amp; the Judgments were Confessed as Stated and I know the parties have made friends &amp; so fare have been quiet &amp; industriuous &amp; the sums have been paid as stated I would be very thankfull for your Excell to remit the fines</p>
<p>R D Lusk</p>
<p>I concur in the above statement</p>
<p>W. D. Hopper</p>
<p>the undersigned join in the above petition</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>R. M. and W. O Bradley
<lb/><cb n="2"/>W. H. Wherritt
<lb/>John. Y. Lowell
<lb/>G. W. Dunlap<pb/></p>
<p>Rejected
<lb/>Thomas E Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Ky</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Pr of Wm O Bradly</hi></p>
<p>Garrard Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Casey, Sebastian &amp; Leasure</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
