<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-029-0516"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky vs. Edward Humphry, Indictment</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG8968</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Leppman</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, James F. Robinson: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons, Remissions, and Respites, 1862-1863</collection>
      <idno>R4-320 to R4-321</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Hancock County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-08-13">13 August 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Hancock Circuit Court.
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky Plaintiff
<lb/>Against } Indictment
<lb/>Edward Humphry Defendant</p>
<p>The Grand Jury of Hancock County in the name and by the authority of the Commonwealth of Kentucky accuse Edward Humphry of the offense of selling spirituous liquors to a white person under the age of 21. years without the written consent <hi rend="str">of</hi> or request of the father to such sale, he being alive at the time of such sale, committed as follows, viz: On the <gap/> day of <gap/> in the year of <date when="1862">1862</date> and on divers days since then in the County aforesaid did unlawfully sell to one William Herron Jr a white person under the age of 21. years and son of W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Herron Sen<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> spiritous liquors without the written consent o<hi rend="str">f</hi>r request of the said William Herron Sr to said sales, though he then was and still is living.</p>
<p>Against the peace and dignity of the Commonwealth of Kentucky,
<lb/>Jno. Chapeze
<lb/>Atty for Commlth.</p>
<p>Information by W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Herrin Frank Mirphy N Remington</p>
<p>The above Indictment was found at the <date when="1862-08">August Term 1862</date> of the Hancock Circuit Court, endorsed a True bill and signed by Robert Beauchamp foreman.</p>
<p>And on the <date when="1862-09-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Day of September 1862</date><pb/>
<lb/>a summons was issued, and returned by the Sheriff of Hancock County, executed on the <date when="1863-01-12">12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Day of January 1863</date>. and at the <date when="1862-02">February term 1862</date> it was Continued for the Commonwealth, and at <date when="1863-08">August term 1863</date>. the following Judgment was entered. viz:</p>
<p>The Commonwealth of Kentucky Pltff
<lb/>Against } On an Indict for selling liquor to minor
<lb/>Edward Humphy Defts</p>
<p>This day came the Attorney for the Commonwealth and the defendant also appeared by his Attorney, and for plea, says he is not guilty of the charges alleged in the Indictment, And thereupon came a Jury as follows, by consent of parties they agreed to be with ten Jurors, towit: L F Grayham Alfred Clark Henry Haynes. D L. Thomas, William Temple George C. P. Baker, James Connell William Newman Joseph L. Greathouse and Roderick Purcell, were sworn well and truly to try the issue, and a true verdict render, &amp; having heard the evidence returned the following verdict, towit: "We of the Jury find for the Commonwealth,"</p>
<p>"Geo C. P. Baker foreman."</p>
<p>Whereupon it is adjudged by the Court that he is guilty of the charges alleged in the Indictment, and that the defendant make his fine to the Commonwealth by the payment of the sum of Fifty dollars, and the costs of this prosecution and may be taken &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi><pb/></p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Hancock Circuit Court, Sct:</p>
<p>I Eldred E Pate Clerk of said Court certify that the foregoing two pages contains a copy of the Indictment and the Judgment &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi> as appears of record in my office,</p>
<p>Given under my hand as Clerk of said Court this <date when="1863-08-13">13 Day of August A D 1863</date>.</p>
<p>Eldred E Pate Clerk.
<lb/>Hancock Circuit Court Ky<figure type="hr"/><pb/></p>
<p>The Commonwealth
<lb/>v } Indict &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>
<lb/>Edward Humphry
<lb/>I
<lb/>A Copy.
<lb/><hi rend="str">Fee $1.</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
