<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2678"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Margaret Long et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7315</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-305</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-11-14">14 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Thomas E Bramlette
<lb/>The Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>Margaret Long the Petitioner would respectfully represent to your Excellency That she resides in the City of Louisville and for some time has been very much afflicted and which affliction continues in such a way as to confine her to the house and most of the time to her bed</p>
<p>She states that she has no relatives living and but few friends her only brother who was her chief support before the war and who gave his life to his country in his recent Battles; for the Union being now dead and gone:</p>
<p>She states that at the last Term of the City Court of Louisville: on the 10<hi rend="sup">th</hi> day thereof. at the <date when="--11">No<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">v</hi></hi></date> Term she was fined $150.<hi rend="sup">0</hi>/<hi rend="sub">00</hi> for Keeping a disorderly house:</p>
<p>She states that she lives in a little shed of a house in an obscure part of the city and that while<hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> Gen Shermans army was here some soldiers came to her house: She did not invite them and was unable to Keep them away and a Watchman indicted her for Keeping a disorderly house therefor<pb/></p>
<p>She states that the neighbors never complained for they Knew the soldiers could do what they pleased: She says she is poor &amp; sick and wholly unable to pay the fine, and She humbly prays your Excellency to remit to her the same: and will ever pray &amp;</p>
<p>Margaret ^her X mark^ Long</p>
<p>State of Kentucky
<lb/>Jefferson County Sct</p>
<p>Margaret Long states that the above petition is true</p>
<p>Margaret ^her X mark^ Long</p>
<p>Sworn to Before me on this <date when="1865-11-14">14 of November 1865</date></p>
<p>J. Connell J P J C</p>
<p>we the undersigned Citizens respectfully join in the prayer of the petitioner Margaret Long.</p>
<p>I am aware that ^the^ facts Set forth in the above petition are true, and would recomend the remission of Such portion of her fine as the Executive may deem prudent under the Circumstances</p>
<p>Respectfully
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Hipwell
<lb/>Lieut Police</p>
<p>P. S. This woman is not worth one Hundred and fifty Dollars Visable means</p>
<p>Hipwell</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
