<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1170"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Henry Steirn, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10638</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG20-331</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-05">5 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>City Court of Louisville
<lb/>Wednesday <date when="1861-06-05">June 5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Commonwealth vs Henry Steirn</p>
<p>This day came as well the attorney for the Commonwealth as the Defendant in person who for plea herein Says he is guilty in manner and form as the Commonwealth against him hath alledged and prays for mercy. Thereupon came a Jury Viz Allen Hughes Henry Rowland, James Shindler, John Graff, W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Barcus, Jos Smith, John W Summ, Robt Latimore, W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Curry, W D Clark. Robt Martin, Chas Summers who being duly Elected tried and sworn well and truly to enquire &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi> after hearing the testimony and retiring to consider returned into Court the following Verdict Viz. We of the Jury find the Defendant Guilty as charged in the within Indictment and assess his fine at Fifty Dollars to the Commonwealth of Kentucky. Thereupon it is ordered that he make his fine to the Commonwealth by payment of Fifty Dollars together with all costs herein. And that he be taken therefore &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi></p>
<p>A Copy Attest
<lb/>O H Strattan clk
<lb/>By W Shryock D C<pb/></p>
<p>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Transcript
<lb/>Henry Steirn</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
