<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1805"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">A. W. Gazlay to James R. Page</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6442</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-348 to BR13-349</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-05-24">24 May 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><date when="1865-05-24">Louisville May 24/65</date>
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> R. Page. Esqr.
<lb/>ass<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Secy of State.
<lb/>Frankfort Ky
<lb/>Dear Sir.</p>
<p>Yr fav<hi rend="sup">r</hi> of yesterday is rec'<hi rend="sup">d</hi> -- and excited Some surprise and I give you the facts to show you why= Stoeckel is the agent of the extensive Pittsburgh House of Fahnestock &amp; Co -- and was sent here by them to introduce to this maket a new article of Ware -- </p>
<p>Not being aware of any ordinance requiring a license from the city he made Some Sales. and as he was about leaving was arrested -- </p>
<p>He applied to me for advice and on Investigation I found the case was clear against him -- and therefore stated the facts to the Judge.<pb/>
<lb/>The Judge in open Court stated that if he had the power to do so he would dismiss the case but that he could not do otherwise than inflict the lowest penalty the ordinance would allow, but recommended that I should apply to the Governor to have the penalty remitted, My client however preferred to pay up the fine and in my presence paid it to the Clerk of the Court= $50. &amp; costs &amp; took a reciept -- It is evident from your writing me that Some one has been using <hi rend="underline">my</hi> <hi rend="underline">name</hi> without <hi rend="underline">authority</hi> in making the application to remit the penalty, and if you can do so I wish you would advise me who it is=I know that my clerk left the city immediately and am satisfied he knows nothing of the proceeding,</p>
<p>Nevertheless as there has been<pb/>
<lb/>an attempted rascality in the matter I am disposed to turn it to the ends of Justice, and to get the money back for my client, and therefore inclose to you the $2 -- fee -- and you will please forward the papers=</p>
<p>Yr<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Truly.
<lb/><hi rend="underline">A. W. Gazlay</hi></p>
<p>I show this to Judge Johnson before sending it -- and wish you would show it to my friend Governor Bramlette -- </p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Gazlay</hi></p>
<p>on inquiry Seince writing the above I find that Judge Johnson has gone to Cincinnati &amp; therefore send it at once -- </p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Gazlay</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
