<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0695"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John B. Huston, William Clinton Goodloe, and John K. Goodloe to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4814</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR10-66</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1864-04-04">4 April 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E. Bramlette Govr of Kentucky.</p>
<p>At the <date when="1864-04">April Term 1864</date>, of the Woodford Circuit Court, a judgment was taken by the Commonwealth, on a bond executed by John Gwynn, for the appearance of Christopher Chilton, in said Court, to answer a charge of, Affray," made against him. The bond was for one hundred dollars, and was conditioned for the appearance of said Chilton at the <date when="1861-10">October term 1861</date> of said Court, particularly, but also conditioned generally as other bail bonds. It was shown to the Court, that there was no term of the Woodford Circuit Court, held in <date when="1861-10">Octr 1861</date> and consequently said Chilton was not tried and his bond was, not discharged, as decided by the Court. Said Chilton has since failed to appear and said Court has entered judgments on said forfeited recognizance. Mr Gwynn is an old man, a quiet and good citizen and in quite moderate circumstances. We respectfully request your Excellency to remit said forfeiture so far as you have power over it. We are confident that said Gwynn was never privy to the offence of Chilton, nor to his nonapeparance to answer the charge against.</p>
<p><date when="1864-04-04">Apl 4 1864</date></p>
<p>I was acting Commonweaths attorney at the time named &amp; recommend that the prayer of the petition by granted</p>
<p>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi> B Huston
<lb/>W C Goodloe Crt Judge
<lb/>Jno. K. Goodloe</p>
<p>Please answer me
<lb/>Jno K Goodloe<pb/></p>
<p>Woodford Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Remit except fees &amp; costs
<lb/>Tho E Bramlette
<lb/>John Gwynn
<lb/><date when="1864-04-06">6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Apl/64</date>
<lb/>Forfeiture</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
