<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-019-0002"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Beriah Magoffin to John S. Gault et al.</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG1308</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Military Correspondence, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG5-35 to MG5-36</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1860-12-24">24 December 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Commonwealth of Kentucky
<lb/>Executive Department
<lb/>Frankfort <date when="1860-12-24">Dec 24 1860</date>
<lb/>Gentlemen</p>
<p>Your very kind letter of the 12<hi rend="sup">th</hi> inst tendering to me the services of your gallant regiment in the contingencies alluded to has awakened in me emotions of the liveliest sensibility and would have been sooner answered, but I was away from home. In declining to accept your generous offer I am deeply impressed with the patriotic motives which have induced it -- </p>
<p>In the tender you have made at a time like this when the ties which have bound our Union together seem to be growing weaker and weaker every day, I fully appreciate and reciprocate the fraternal spirit in which it was done -- In such kind offices the friendship which should ever exist between the states of Indiana and Kentucky will be kept actively alive, and should it ever become necessary (a thing I can scarcely imagine) for Kentucky to accept the Servi<hi rend="str">s</hi>ces of volunteers <hi rend="underline">outside</hi> of the state, there are none<pb/>
<lb/>She would more cordially accept or more readily receive than those of the gallant regiment you have the honor to command -- Thanking you for the offer, you have made I have the honor to be</p>
<p>Your Obedient Servt
<lb/>B. Magoffin</p>
<p>To
<lb/>Brig. Genl Jno S. Gault &amp; other officers of the First Regiment Vanderburg Co Indiana Volunteers
<lb/>Evansville
<lb/>Ind<pb/></p>
<p>Copy of letter to Gen. Jno S. Gault &amp; others
<lb/>Indiana Volunteers
<lb/>Evansville Ind<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/><date when="1860-12-24">Dec 24 1860</date>
<lb/></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
