<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-1278"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">William Rafferty to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10746</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG21-157 to MG21-158</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1861-03-11">11 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency Beriah Magoffin
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. of Kentucky</p>
<p>Your petitioner would respectfully state that he was fined Fifty doll<hi rend="sup">s</hi> for an assault &amp; Battery in the city Court of Louisville on <date when="1861-03-05">5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ins<hi rend="sup">t</hi></date> under the following circumstances, He lives in the suburbs of the city &amp; has a lot enclosed with plank, to rear a nursery of a variety of fruit trees -- his brothers widow lives adjoining, upon whose estate the petitioner administered the widow has been very quarrelsome of a violent temper &amp; <unclear/> in her abuse which heretofore failed to excite petitioner, on the day the assault is charged M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Rafferty the widow whilst the petitioner was absent, tore down several planks of the fence &amp; when he came home to his dinner he attempted to repair the damage by nailing on the plank from where they had been thrown down, she came out of her house &amp; in a furious rage commenced abusing him which he disregarded then she picked up a large piece of plank &amp; struck him with another piece of plank which was all that was done, he could have proven all this by a man named Postlewaite who is employed on the<pb/>
<lb/>of the Louisville &amp; Nashville Rail Road &amp; whose attendance could not be had at the trial, supposing the case would not be tried in his absence &amp; not knowing any thing of Judicial proceedings y<hi rend="sup">r</hi> petitioner himself was not at the trial &amp; this a verdict was rendered for the sum of Fifty doll<hi rend="sup">s</hi> ags<hi rend="sup">t</hi> him as he was assaulted &amp; not in fault in the affair &amp; the facts are as stated above I hope &amp; pray your Excellency to remit the fine, I am known as an industrious peaceable man to all my acquaintance <hi rend="str">wh</hi>Some of whom join me in this petition &amp; I will ever be grateful</p>
<p>William Rafferty</p>
<p>Sworn to before me a notary public this <date when="1861-03-11">March 11<hi rend="sup">t</hi> 1861</date></p>
<p>Pat Joyes N P J C</p>
<p>We acquaintances &amp; friends of W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Rafferty join in <hi rend="str">the</hi>his prayer to his Excellency to remit his fine We know him to be an honest industrious &amp; Clever man</p>
<p>John Joyes
<lb/>James Trabue
<lb/>R Trabue
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Garvin
<lb/>T. C. Cole<hi rend="underline">man Jr</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Louisville City Ct
<lb/>$50 } assault
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> Rafferty</p>
<p>Respite 12 Mo
<lb/>B. M</p>
<p>Is<hi rend="sup">d</hi> July 30</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
