<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2638"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">W. B. Thompson to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7275</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-215</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Russellville, Logan County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-11-18">18 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Russellville Ky <date when="1865-11-18">nover 18<hi rend="sup">th</hi>/65</date>
<lb/>T. E. Bramlett Esqr. Govenor of. Ky.
<lb/>Respected. Sir</p>
<p>A few days ago a man in this county (Logan) by the Name of Robert G. Turner Killed a man by the name of R, L, Porter. his tryal was commenced before examining court. and he fled to parts unknown. The crime we think was murder, as the county attorney of Logan I ask you that you offer a reward for his apprehension, say $500.00</p>
<p>He is thought to be about 35. or 40 years of age about 5 feet 10 inches high, light hair, Said when he came here that he was from, Mo. had a blue mark under one eye.</p>
<p>verry respectfully your freind
<lb/>W. B. Thompson</p>
<p>P.S. we the undersigned have read the above letter and concur with mr Thompson our county attorney in his statements and earnestly think that the man Turner should be brought to justice</p>
<p>A. D. Kennedy County Judge
<lb/>G T Blakey Sheriff<pb/></p>
<p>Reward
<lb/>$300,
<lb/>For Robert G. Turner for the murder of R. L. Porter
<lb/><date when="1865-11-20">20<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Nov/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
