<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2715"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James Smitha and Granville Smitha to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7352</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR16-365 to BR16-366</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Clark County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-11-29">29 November 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His excellency, the Governor of Kentucky.</p>
<p>Your petitions, James Smitha and Granville Smitha state unto your excellency, that at the <date when="1862-05">May term of the Clarke Circuit Court, in the year 1862</date> an indictment was found by the Grand jury of said County for an assault made by your petitioner, James Smitha, upon Robert Berry, as is alleged in said indictment That afterwards the said James Smitha was arrested by the sheriff of said County upon process that issued against him upon said indictment and your petitions then, before said Sheriff executed a recognizance for the appearance of the said James Smitha, in said court, at its next term thereafter in which your petitioner, Granville Smith become bound as security. That afterwards, at the <date when="1865-05">May term of said court in the year 1865</date> the said bond was forfeited and a summons ordered to be issued against your petitions -- And afterwards to wit, at the <date when="1865-11">Nov<hi rend="sup">r</hi> term of said court 1865</date> a judgement was rendered for One hundred dollars against your petitioner, Granville Smitha Said Indictment is still defending in said court.<pb/></p>
<p>Your petitioners state that as a reason for the forfeiture of said bond and the non appearance of said James Smitha, in said court, is that after he had left his home and started to said court for the purpose of entering his appearance and making his defence to said Indictment, he was informed and verily believed that John Morgans Rebel Cavelry was in Winchester taking of horses and being fearful that he would loose his horse or receive some bodily hurt he returned home</p>
<p>Your petitioners pray that your excellency extend to them executive clemency and remit said judgement so rendered against your petitioner, Granville Smitha -- and relieve your petitioner, James Smitha from all loss by reason of the forfeiture of said bond</p>
<p>Clarke Co Ky. <date when="1865-11-29">Nov 29th 1865</date></p>
<p>James Smitha
<lb/>Granville Smitha<pb/></p>
<p>We the subscribers, citizens of Clarke Count Ky. Concur in the prayer of the <unclear/> or foregoing petition. <date when="1865-11-29">Nov. 29 1865</date>.</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>Cha<hi rend="sup">s</hi> <hi rend="underline">Eginton</hi>
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Geo. Smith
<lb/>E. T. Taylor
<lb/>Theodore <hi rend="underline">Kohlhass</hi>
<lb/>A. H Buckner
<lb/>Lewis Adams
<lb/>W. T. Poynter
<lb/>.J T Williams
<lb/><hi rend="underline">James Simpson</hi>
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Harrison Thomson</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Clarke Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Granville &amp; Jas Smitha
<lb/>$100
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/><date when="1865-12-02">2<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Dec/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
