<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1962"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">James Wilson et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6599</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-96 to BR14-97</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-06-18">18 June 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To Governor Thomas E Bramlette</p>
<p>The undersigned citizens of Falmouth and Pendleton County Ky would most respectfully represent to your Excellency that in the case of the Commonwealth vs King Plummer ^in the Pendleton Circuit Court^ indicted for the offense of bigamy two bond executed for the appearance of Said defendant in Said Court for trial have thereby been declared forfeited -- one of Said bonds is for the Sum of two hundred dollars with W. J. Myers Security and the other for the Sum of three hundred dollars with Said W. J. Myers and Elizabeth Moore Securities. Both Mr Myers and Mrs Moore are residents of Pendleton County and known to the latter is a widow in very moderate Cirucmstances in life having to Struggle hard to get the comforts and necessaries of life for herself and infant chldren living with her. We are Satisfied from <hi rend="str">the</hi> ^our^ knowledge and information concerning this matter that he became bound in Said bonds<hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> out of Sympathy for the defendant in his unfortunate Situation and believe from often repeated promises made by him to them that he would promptly appear for trial in obedience to the requirements of his Said bonds Should they be compelled to pay the full amount of the aforesaid bond (Copies of which are herewith present) it will Seriously embarrass them pecuniarily. We therefore in consideration of the facts<pb/>
<lb/>above detailed respectfully ask your Excellency if consistent with your sense of duty and right to remit and cancel the liabilities of Said W J Myers and Mrs Moore as far as by law you are authorized to do <date when="1865-06-18">June 18<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1865</date></p>
<p>James Wilson
<lb/>James J Hudnall
<lb/>J. N. Kennett
<lb/>W<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Murchy
<lb/>C A Wandelohr Clk Ct Ct
<lb/>H. N. Newman
<lb/>Robt H Reed
<lb/>Jn<hi rend="sup">o</hi>. E Records
<lb/>John. B. Applegate D. S. P. C.
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>K Applegate D. S. P. C.
<lb/>W W Ireland
<lb/><hi rend="underline">M Mullins</hi><pb/></p>
<p>Pendleton Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Commonwealth
<lb/>vs } Petition for Remittance
<lb/>King Plummer<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>If the facts stated be true the Defts can obtain relief by surrenderng the accused into Custody before Judgt -- </p>
<p>Application at present refused</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
