<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1972"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Y. O. Booker to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6609</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR14-110</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-06-03">3 June 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. E. Bramlette Governor of Kentucky -- Your Petitioner Y. O. Booker would respectfully state that at the late <date when="1865-05">May</date> term of the Green Circuit Court he was fined $40 -- ($10 each in four cases) for selling spiritous liquors to soldiers and $50 in one case for selling spiritous liquor to a negro, in all $90 -- under the circumstances, your Petitioner believes that the fines, are unjust and oppressive, and he asks the clemency of your Excellency to interpose and remit the same, or so much thereof as may be right and proper -- Your Petitioner keeps a bar in connection with his Hotel, and pays regularly and promptly all the Licenses required of him -- and has employed for his convenience his nephew Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. Green Booker to superintend and sell at the Bar -- His said nephew is young inexperienced and timid -- and in the absence of your Petitioner did on several occasions sell liquor to soldiers being authorized by their officers on each occasion, the said Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. Green Booker being ignorant of the law in regard to such matters, did not know he was wrong in doing so, and your Petitioner would not have allowed it, if he had been personally present when the aforesaid liquor was sold Your Petitioner states that one of the fines above alluded to of ten dollars was against the said Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi>. Green Booker, but your Petitioner calls it his own, because he alone holds himself responsible for the same as the said T. G. Booker was in his employment and acting for him -- As to the fine of $50 for selling liquor to a negro, Your Petitioner did not know any thing of it until since the adjournment of Court -- He supposed all the cases were for selling liquor to soldiers, and agreed with the Commonwealths Attorney that judgment might go without a trial for $10 in each case, reserving to himself the right of Petition to your Excellency for such interposition and relief as your Excellency might deem just and proper -- I have stated to you in truth the facts of the case, as is known by the bearer of this M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. A. C. Cox the Sheriff of this county <date when="1865-06-03">June 3<hi rend="sup">d</hi>. 1865 -- </date></p>
<p>Y O Booker<pb/></p>
<p>I concur with Mr. Y. O. Booker in the above petition.</p>
<p><hi rend="underline">W</hi><hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">m</hi></hi><hi rend="underline">. B Allen</hi></p>
<p>P. S. such fees as are required by the Assistant secretary I will forward immediately on being informed of the remission of the fines alluded to in the foregoing Petition. -- </p>
<p>Y O Booker</p>
<p>Green Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Y. O. Booker
<lb/>Petition to Governor
<lb/><date when="1865-06">June 1865</date>
<lb/>$50
<lb/><date when="1865-06-14">14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> June/65</date></p>
<p>Remit the $50 -- for selling spiritous liquors to a slave except fees &amp; costs &amp; the other cases
<lb/><hi rend="underline">refused</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
