<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-079-0026"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas E. Bramlette et al., Bond for Arms</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14025</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Enrolled Militia Records 1864 - 1865 ; Adair, Allen, Boyle, Daviess, Garrard, Owen, Pendleton, and Shelby counties</collection>
      <idno>Flat Box 7, Folder 1861 ADAIR COUNTY - 3d Regt Home Guards organized 1 Jun 1861 Cpt Thomas E. Bramlette</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Adair County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-06-01">1 June 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Commonwealth of Ky Adair Co <hi rend="underline">SS</hi></p>
<p>We Thomas E Bramlette Captain of Home Guards, of Adair Co. principle T. T. Alexander Eli Wheat C. F. Epperson Rich<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Garrett <unclear/> G R. Page</p>
<p>sureties -- undertake that Thomas E Bramlette shall safely keep &amp; return to the State Arsenal at Frankfort at the expiration of five years or sooner if his company be dissolved all the Arms which may be drawn by him as Captain of the Home Guard aforesaid or make compensation to the Commonwealth of Kentucky for a <unclear>failure</unclear> and to the extent of any failure so to do this <date when="1861-06-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> June 1861</date>.</p>
<p>Tho. E. Bramlette
<lb/>R. T. Garnett
<lb/>T T Alexander
<lb/>Geo, R, Page
<lb/>Cha<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> F Epperson
<lb/>Eli Wheat</p>
<p>attest
<lb/>E. T Willes P J A C. C<pb/></p>
<p>Commonwealth of Ky</p>
<p>I E. T. Willes Presiding Judge of the Adair County Court, certify that a Company of Home Guards was this day organized in Adair County at the Court house, in Columbia, and the officers were all duly elected in my presence &amp; under my supervision. Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E Bramlette was duly elected Captain. The officers &amp; men took the Oath prescribed by the act entitled "An act for the <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> regulations &amp; to provide for the army of the state" "approved <date when="1861-05-24">May 24<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>".</p>
<p>The said Thos. E Bramlette extends bond as required by the act aforesaid which he certify to be a good bond &amp; the surety sufficent to secure the performance of this covenant or to answer for the breach,</p>
<p>Given under my hand this <date when="1861-06-01">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> day of June, 1861</date></p>
<p>E. T Willis. P. J. A. C. C</p>
<p>For Captain Tho. E. Bramlette
<lb/>1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Lieutenant John R Wheat
<lb/>2<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">nd</hi></hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
