<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2930"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. A. Brents to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7567</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-262 to BR17-263</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Albany, Clinton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1865-12-23">23 December 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Albany, Ky.
<lb/><date when="1865-12-23">Decr 23 1865</date>.
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">s</hi></hi> E. Bramlette,
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky
<lb/>Frankfort, Ky.
<lb/>Sir;</p>
<p>Enclosed I send you a petition in behalf of James M Smith, who is now confined in the State Penetentiary.</p>
<p>It is signed only by Citizens of Clirton County and mainly by his neighbors. It was not taken to <hi rend="str">Wayne</hi>Russell County His Mother informs me that she could get a very large number of names to it there which I believe; but I did not think it necessary to delay for that purpose, for the young man and his mother are made miserable by his present position and I desire to hasten his liberation if it is compatable with your feelings and official duties.</p>
<p>It was returned to me this evening with the names signed except those on the 3<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> page; which I procured my self. I thought it best to get some names that you knew. I could have procured others.</p>
<p>I, also, enclose the statements of two of Smiths officers, honorable young men, proving clearly that Smith was in the<pb/>
<lb/>line of his duty as a Soldier doing battle for his country and not robbing. Perdue &amp; Huff were his officers in the 7<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Tenn. Col. Morrison in the 13<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky. and Capt Stephenson &amp; Lt J. C. Story in the South Cumberland Battalion (State Trops.) What better could he do than obtain the names of his neighbors and <hi rend="str">the</hi> officers in three Regiments of loyal troops under whom he served?</p>
<p>Governor I will add one other remark. Smith proves an alibi that he was at another place at the time of the Robbery, but if it was true that he was present and <hi rend="underline">guilty</hi>, yet the crime might not be so great as it would be now, for then officers often taught there men that it was not wrong to take from a Rebel, that rebels forfeited all rights, &amp;c. I do not plead for violators of law for the sake of plunder &amp; money, but I do think that many young men ought to be forgiven for violations under the excitement &amp; stimulation of the war and lessons taught to them by their officers! I do not believe Smith was there, but admit that he was he might have thought it no wrong to take from one who had the name of being a Rebel.</p>
<p>If from the facts and circumstances, it is compatible with your duties and agreeble to your feelings to grant a pardon to young<pb/>
<lb/>Smith I believe it will result in great good to the family and work no injury to the community.</p>
<p>Yours truly
<lb/>J. A. Brents.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
