<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-020-0768"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. K. Sunnewell to Beriah Magoffin</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG10236</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Petitions for Pardons and Remissions, 1859-1862</collection>
      <idno>MG19-195 to MG19-196</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Covington, Kenton County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1861-03-14">14 March 1861</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Covington Ky
<lb/><date when="1861-03-14">March 14<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 1861</date>
<lb/>Gov<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Magoffin</p>
<p>D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Sir yesterday evening old M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Temple was found guilty by a jury in our court of False swearing His friends in Newport where he formerly resided for a number of years are very unanimously in favor of having him pardoned and I understand Col Hodge will be over here tomorrow on his way to see you in his behalf I have been very busily engaged in court all the morning and have had but a <hi rend="str">momt</hi> moment to devote to making an effort to <hi rend="str">get</hi> ^<hi rend="str">make</hi>^ any preperation to <hi rend="str">by</hi> ^present^ his case properly <hi rend="str">before</hi> ^to^ you And ^sending^ <hi rend="str">such</hi> petitions are so common<pb/>
<lb/>it seems like imposing on your good nature to ask your clemency I was taken quite unwell at noon &amp; have been confined to my house since then during the forenoon every one that spoke of the case were anxious to have the old man pardoned I have not heard of a single dissenting voise I spoke to M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">r</hi></hi> Arthur Aty for the Commonwealth he says he is very desirous he should be released but he would rather avoid writing to you but he will do so if you will not grant a pardon without his recomendation All the jurors whom I have spoken to will sign a recomdation and nearly all had done so when I left<pb/>
<lb/><hi rend="str">where I left</hi> the court house all who were there had done so several went last night to their houses &amp; have not returned to day <hi rend="str">it</hi> I am confident all will write in the matter if they can be <hi rend="str">rea</hi> found <hi rend="str"><unclear/></hi> before Col Hodge leaves here for Frankfort I am too unwell to go into details of the case but I feel confident if you will pardon the old man your authority be universally approved of ^here <hi rend="str">to</hi>^ and you need have no fear of having done an improper act</p>
<p>Your Respectfully
<lb/>R K Sunnewell</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
