<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-1794"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">O. Waddill et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG6431</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR13-327</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date when="1865-05">May 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency, Tho's. E. Bramlette, Governor <hi rend="str">of the Commonwealth</hi> </p>
<p>The undersigned respectfully represent, that one Tho's. Davis was heretofore indicted in the Hopkins Circuit Court, on the charge of Robbery -- and was recognized for his appearance in Court to answer said indictment, in the sum of five hundred dollars, with his father Vincent F Davis, as his surety He failed to appear at the last November Term of the court, when his said recognizance was taken for forfeited, and such proceedings were had thereon, that at the <date when="1865-05">May Term 1865</date> of said Court, judgment was rendered against his surety Vincent, F. Davis for the full amount, of said recognizance,</p>
<p>The said Thomas Davis, prior to the Term of the Court at which his recognizance was foreited, had entered the military service of the United states, and was in actual service at the said Term of Court and was absent from the County, His father was advised that the said recognizance had been destroyed and that it was therefore unnecessary for him to appear in court and consent to continue bond therein, as required by statute in such cases -- The said Thomas Davis was ^still^ in the army of the United States at the said <date when="1865-05">May</date> Term of the Court at which judgment was rendered in said recognizance, and was absent from the County, so that he could not appear and show cause why judgment should not be rendered on the recognizance<pb/>
<lb/>The undersigned are well acquainted with the obligers in said recognizance, and are satisfied that the non appearance of said Thomas Davis was caused only by the restraints of the Military service, and not by any disposition to avoid a trial -- They therefore respectfully petition your Excellency to remit the said judgment, or so much thereof as may be within your perogative</p>
<p><date when="1865-05">May 1865,</date></p>
<p>O. Waddill
<lb/>J B Peyton
<lb/>J M Compton ck
<lb/><hi rend="underline">Hopkins cirt. court</hi>
<lb/>Amos Bassett
<lb/>James E Slatern
<lb/>J. L. Robertson S h c
<lb/>W. P Hamton P. J. C. C. C.
<lb/>R. J. Littlepage D. C. H. C. C.
<lb/>John. G. Morton
<lb/>S. Rorer</p>
<p>I believe the statements in the foregoing petition are true=&amp; if consistant deserves your clemency</p>
<p>Jno Barret Comlths atty.</p>
<p>Please direct your answer to A. K. Bradley Madisonville Hopkins County Ky.</p>
<p>Hopkins Cir Ct
<lb/>vs
<lb/>V. F. Davis
<lb/>$500,
<lb/>Forfeiture
<lb/><date when="1865-06-09">9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> June/65</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
