<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-033-0017"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Henry S. Robson to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG11568</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Andrew P Patrick</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>1st - 2nd Regiments Kentucky Cavalry Muster Rolls</collection>
      <idno>Box 45, Bundle 1</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Memphis, Shelby County, Tennessee</placeName>
    <date when="1865-03-30">30 March 1865</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>Hospital Pinkney
<lb/>Memphis Ten <date when="1865-03-30">March 30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> 65</date>
<lb/>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thos. E Bramlette
<lb/>Gov. of Ky
<lb/>Dear Sir</p>
<p>Permit me to trouble you with a few lines, at the same time making a request. I am a native of Frankfort Ky. and a resident of Lancaster Ky. I served under Col. Woolford in the first Ky cavalry about one year as second Lt. and then under Col Watkins in the Sixth cavalry for nearly two years as a first Lieut. I am now in the Navy as a private enlisted with the positive understanding from Cap. Brown at Cinti. that I was to be promoted in a very short time. I enlisted for two years but have heard nothing of promotion since. I was was transfered to this Hospital in Sep. last sick and when I was well enough they placed me on duty as clerk I have a family to support and my pay is only $20 -- pr month and that will not support any one <hi rend="str">a</hi>person<pb/></p>
<p>My object in writing was to request that you would commission me in some Ky Regt where there is a vacancy. I think after having served as long as I did in the army and then one year in the navy that I either might be relieved either with a commission or discharge and their is no probability of my getting a discharge under one year, unless I get a Commission I must remain where I am at. and in that case my family must suffer. for I can not now get the small amount of pay that is promised me until my time is out. I think Gov. if you could grant me a commission however small you would never regret it. and Sir I would owe you a debt of Gratitude that I could never repay. as for my character &amp;c I would refer you to A. C. Keenon Joseph Clark J. B. Akin of Frankfort. Also Major J. W. Page of the 9<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky cavalry Hoping Gov. that you will decide in my favor and send me a commission at <hi rend="str">the</hi>your earliest <hi rend="str">possible</hi>convinence I am Sir</p>
<p>your most obdt. Srvt
<lb/>Henry S. Robson
<lb/>Hospital Pinkney 
<lb/>Memphis Tenn.<pb/></p>
<p><note place="left margin">1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Cav</note>
<lb/>Hospital Pinckney
<lb/>Memphis Tenn.
<lb/><date when="1865-03-30">Mar. 30. 1865</date><figure type="hr"/></p>
<p><hi rend="underline">Robson Henry S</hi>. 
<lb/><hi rend="underline">To The Gov.</hi> </p>
<p>Applies for a commission in some Kentucky Regiment.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>Give the rule upon which <hi rend="underline">Coms are issued</hi></p>
<p>LB N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 11 -- 1865 P. 281<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Rec<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">d</hi></hi> A. G. O. Ky <date when="1865-04-03">3 April 1865</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
