<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3170"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">J. J. Miller et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5289</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-213 to BR41-214</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Thos E. Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky}</p>
<p>We the undersigned, citizens of Boone and adjacent counties, would respectfully recommend to your Excellency as a subject for executive clemency John T Chittenden, late of company B 30th Ky Mtd Infty indicted at the last term of the Grant Co circuit court for the murder of Henry Weymire at Tuckers Store, near Williamstown, Grant Co Ky, on or about the <date when="1864-12-26">26th day of December 1864</date>.</p>
<p>We have been acquainted with said John T. Chittenden for many years, and can testify that he has always borne a good character as a peaceable and unoffending, as well as an honest and industrious man and a good citizen, and was never known to be engaged in broils or breaches of the peace of any kind. During the late rebellion, he was always noted for his unshaken loyalty; though exempt from the draft by reason of his age he entered the army with four of his sons who have proved brave and efficient soldiers. Many of us having served in the same company with him and three of his sons, can testify to his uniform good behavior while in the service, having never been engaged in a quarrel with any of his fellow soldiers; and we are perfectly convinced that if he committed the deed<pb/>
<lb/>of which he stands accused, it was done while in a state of mental alienation brought about by the following causes.</p>
<p>While in the army, he frequently received letters from home, representing his family to be in a state of destitution, and suffering from the oppression of an exacting landlord, while he was unable to relieve them, his company not having been paid for more than six months. Having obtained a furlough, he visited his family in Boone county to see what could be done for their relief, and found that matters were even worse than had been represented; that his landlord who is a wealthy rebel sympathizer had seized for rent and taken away his only milk cow on which his younger children mainly depended for subsistence, and had placed another family on the premises.</p>
<p>Grieved and mortified that his family should be subjected to such treatment while all the male members of it over fifteen years of age were in the field, fighting the enemies of their country, he sought relief for his feelings in the intoxicating boal and of anything that he may have done while under its influence we are certain that he has no knowledge or recollection whatever. It can be abundantly proved that he had had not acquaintance or dealing<pb/>
<lb/>whatever with the deceased, and could not consequently, have been actuated by malice in the commission of the deed. Since then he has never been known to taste ardent spirits of any kind, and no one can regret more than he does any unlawful act that he may have committed while under its influence</p>
<p>In view of these circumstances, the uniform good conduct of the accused, and the fact that he has a large family of small children depending on his labor for support, we would most respectfully and earnestly petition your Excellency to grant him a full and free pardon, as soon as you may deem it practicable; and your petitioners will pray</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>J J Miller
<lb/>G C Glare
<lb/>J. B. Furman Co. B 30th Ky.
<lb/>William Odon do do
<lb/>William W M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Intire do
<lb/>George L. Miller do
<lb/>T N Finnell do
<lb/>Jas. W. Fullilove
<lb/>W. R. Johnson
<lb/>G. W. Baker
<lb/>James Kelly
<lb/>Alec Perkins
<lb/>Ja<hi rend="sup">s</hi> Perkins
<lb/>John Cave
<lb/><cb n="2"/>J W Calvert
<lb/>John E Calvert Capt Co. "D" 55<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky
<lb/>J G Calvert
<lb/>A. G. Winston
<lb/>S. A. Hagarty
<lb/>James N. Stephens
<lb/>Jas A. Miller
<lb/>William Underhill
<lb/>Joseph Underhill
<lb/>O D Perkins
<lb/>S G Botts ast. assessor
<lb/>B. F. Stevenson
<lb/>Jesse Baker Co E 55
<lb/>Thomas taylor Co E 55
<lb/>James Wily<pb/>
<lb/><cb n="1"/>Boone Ct Ct
<lb/>J S Chittenton
<lb/>A Q Baker
<lb/>Edw<hi rend="sup">d</hi> Webber Dep Clk
<lb/>W W Hedges
<lb/>J. D. Conner
<lb/>W C Calvert 55<hi rend="sup">th</hi>
<lb/><unclear/> Landford
<lb/>E V Anderson 55 Ky <unclear/>
<lb/>L. W. Webb Clerk Boone Co Court
<lb/>J H Miller Co B 30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Intry
<lb/>William Glore
<lb/>Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> J M Hatton 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> Lt Co "f" 55 Ky In
<lb/>James P Johnson Co. B. 30<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Ky
<lb/>John Glore 55<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Int
<lb/>Addam Miller
<lb/>J. C Miller
<lb/>William Dorman
<lb/>John A. Kite Co B 30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky
<lb/>James W Kite C E 55 Ky <unclear/>
<lb/>Benj. F. Green Co B 30 Ky
<lb/>J H Miller Co E 55<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky <unclear/>
<lb/>W G Cayton
<lb/>William Glore Co E 55 Ky
<lb/>Benj F Finnell
<lb/>R. B.. Johnson
<lb/>James W. Miller
<lb/>Emary Kenniday Co B 30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky
<lb/>Patrick Bambry
<lb/>Nathan Lowes
<lb/>Michael Long<cb n="2"/>
<lb/>William Connelly Co B 30
<lb/>J M M<hi rend="sup">c</hi>Intire Co B 30 Ky
<lb/>John Fitzmorris
<lb/>R K M<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi>Manamus Co B 30<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Reg Ky
<lb/>James Willson 7 <unclear/> Co C
<lb/>Jonathan Patmore
<lb/>J S Johnson
<lb/>R O M <unclear/>
<lb/>30<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Inf
<lb/>T J Miller Co B 30th <unclear/>
<lb/>Alexander Oder Co B 30 Ky
<lb/>L p Fullilove<milestone unit="column" n="1"/>
<lb/>Grant</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
