<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3207"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">L. N. M. Cook et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5326</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR41-388 to BR41-388A</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Wilson County, Tennessee</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Hon Tho<hi rend="sup">s</hi> E. Bramblett,
<lb/>Gov. of Kentucky,
<lb/>Sir</p>
<p>We the under Signed citizens of Wilson Co. Tenn. and neighbors of Mr ^C^ F. <hi rend="str">Y</hi>. Young; who is under charged for acts done in the State of Kentucky during the war, and while a Confederate Soldier; beg leave to present the following petition in his behalf to the favorable consideration of your excellency. We are well acquainted with Mr ^C^ F <hi rend="str">Y</hi>. Young, and can substantiate the following statements.</p>
<p>1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> Mr ^C^ F. <hi rend="str">Y</hi>. Young up to the close of the war was a private in Capt Jno R. Davis' Co. 4th Tenn. Cav. Forrests old Brig.</p>
<p>2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> Mr Young has three brothers living in Simpson Co Where the acts laid to his charge were committed. ^Muhlberg Co Ky^ The lady to whom he paid his addresses and whom he subsequently married lived in Greenville Mulenburgh Co. Gen Forrests raids and Scouts through Tennessee and portions of Kentucky, gave him ample opportunity for leg^it^imably visiting those of which he repeatedly availed himself. Many depredations were committed in this Section about this time, by persons not regularly in the service for which Mr Young has been charged <hi rend="str">of</hi> and of which we believe him innocent</p>
<p>3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> Circumstancial evidence alone had been adduced in proof of the charges</p>
<p>4<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Mr Youngs home previous to the war was in Simpson Co with his brother Wright Young</p>
<p>5<hi rend="sup">th</hi> He is a poor many respectably connected and now a work on his father's farm.</p>
<p>6<hi rend="sup">th</hi> His character is that of an honorable honest man, and, with the exception of the above charges, above suspicion,<pb/>
<lb/>We respectfully submit the above to the attention of your Excellency praying that in consideration thereof, executive clemency be extended to Mr C F. Young and he be discharged from further custody</p>
<p>Respectfuly Submitted</p>
<p><milestone unit="column" n="2"/><cb n="1"/>L. N. M. Cook
<lb/>John, W. Thomas
<lb/>W. P. M. Smith
<lb/>D E Smith
<lb/>G. S. Williamson
<lb/>W M Johnson
<lb/>J. N. Sullivan
<lb/>Jonathan Eatherly Jr
<lb/>D. J. Mines
<lb/>Irvin Eatherly
<lb/>James L Eatherly
<lb/>W. T. Bayne
<lb/>W W Eatherly
<lb/>J. F. Davis
<lb/>D Searcy
<lb/>K. G. Ozshent
<lb/>J. B. Vivrett
<lb/>John Belk Vivrett
<lb/>H. L. Bass
<lb/>John A McKiney
<lb/><cb n="2"/>Asa Jackson Jr
<lb/>J. A. W. Johnson
<lb/>I Crum
<lb/>G,, W,, Bynam
<lb/>W, Thomas</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
