<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-2767"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Osburn to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG7404</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Patrick A Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR17-20 to BR17-21</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To his Excellency Gov Thos E Bramallte</p>
<p>Your Petitioner John Osburn States that the <date when="1865-09">September Term 1865</date> of the Pulaski Circuit Court, a judgement was taken by Confession against him for the Sum of $25 for the offense of participating in an affray -- He states that he was not guilty but that in the midst of the disturbance which occurred on the 1<hi rend="sup">st</hi> day of the last <date when="--07">July</date> Term of sd court, there was so much confusion, that it was impossible to get a correct history of the affair -- He was a Lt in the state Guard and was endeavoring to quiet the difficulty -- but the excitement ran so high -- and the evidence so conflicting, that Justice could not be done by a trial. For this reason he confessed a Judgement, trusting to executive clemency -- Wherefore he prays that sd fine be remitted -- </p>
<p>John Osburn -- </p>
<p>The undersigned concur in the prayer of the Petition</p>
<p>W S Carpenter
<lb/>W F Ascott<pb/>
<lb/>M, E, Ingram
<lb/>Allen. J. Cox
<lb/>John M. Fight
<lb/>john <unclear/>
<lb/>S, F, Tomlinson
<lb/>Calloway Ashley
<lb/>J M Sandifer
<lb/>J. S, Burk
<lb/>R J Lester
<lb/>J. E. Cosson
<lb/>Jno M Hail
<lb/>Wm Waddle
<lb/>S M Hall
<lb/>M G Richardson
<lb/>W E Vaught
<lb/>Josephus Meece
<lb/>W. B. Moore
<lb/>Wiley <unclear/>
<lb/>D. H. Denton
<lb/>E D Perch<pb/></p>
<p>The undersigned was present at the affray alluded to by Petitioner. From what I saw I am satisfied that Lt Osburn was endeavoring to quiet the difficulty and took no part in untill he was fined on and wounded -- I concur with the petitioners in their prayer for relief</p>
<p>Thos Z Morrow<pb/></p>
<p>Pulaski Cir Ct
<lb/>Petition of Osburn John For remission of fine imposed at the <date when="1865-09">Sept Term 1865</date> Pulaski Circuit Court<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>$25.
<lb/>Remitted <date when="1865-12-11">11 Dec 1865</date>
<lb/>Remit<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>hand to Col T Z Morrow, Senate</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
