<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-001-0009"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Thomas E. Bramlette, In House of Representatives</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG0859</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Joshua D Farrington</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Proclamations, 1863-1865</collection>
      <idno>BR1-357</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Frankfort, Franklin County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-01-08">8 January 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Proclamation/Legislation</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>In House of Representatives.
<lb/>FRIDAY, <date when="1864-01-08">JANUARY 8, 1864.</date></p>
<p>A message in writing was received from the Governor, by Mr. VANWINKLE, Secretary of State, which was referred to the committee on Military Affairs, and is as follows, viz:</p>
<p><hi rend="italic">Gentlemen of the Senate and House of Representatives:</hi></p>
<p>Under an act of Congress, entitled, "An act to authorize the raising of a volunteer force for the better defense of Kentucky," approved <date when="1863-02-07">Feb. 7th, 1863,</date> and pursuant to authority of the President thereunder, a force of some eight thousand men has been raised. Under an agreement made with the Secretary of War in <date when="1863-11">November last,</date> I stayed all further recruiting under that law, and agreed, if the Government would mount this force, to undertake the defense contemplated by the act with them and the organized militia, and give up all our further recruits to fill the old regiments, and such other three years service as the Secretary of War should authorize.</p>
<p>I confidently relied upon an observance of the laws under which these forces were raised, and the promise given to mount them, and faithfully set to work to carry out the agreement.</p>
<p>Under the judicious disposition made of these forces, security and protection was assured to our suffering people, and confidence in the protection of the government again restored.</p>
<p>The first section of the act provides, "That the Governor of the State of Kentucky, by the consent and under the direction of the President of the United States, shall have power to raise and organize into regiments a volunteer force, not exceeding twenty thousand rank and file, to be raised within the State of Kentucky, to serve for the term of twelve months, to be employed within the limits of Kentucky in repelling invasion, suppressing insurrection, and guarding and protecting the public property : <hi rend="italic">Provided</hi>, That at any time it may be necessary, in the discretion of the President of the United States, these troops may be employed out of the limits of Kentucky, against the enemies of the United States."<pb/></p>
<p><note place="header">2</note></p>
<p>These troops have been ordered out of the State, and none provided to supply the defense which they give us. As it is evident that we cannot rely upon forces raised under the act of Congress to serve in Kentucky ; and as the desolation of our homes must follow the removal of these forces, unless speedy provision be made, it devolves upon you to provide for the speedy organization of a State force, which will not be subject to such capricious action, as our only reliable defense.</p>
<p>To utter complaints is useless; whether it be right or wrong thus to remove these forces, it does no good to inquire. We are a loyal people, ready to meet our full measure of responsibility, and lend aid beyond even what the government can rightfully demand. We must keep faith, no matter who may not. We must be true to our government, and we will. We must be true to ourselves in this emergency, and should provide a permanent security against the recurrence of future dangers. It cannot serve our present needs to say that the Federal government ought to do this service. It does not do it, and complaining raises no soldiers for defense. It is action we need, and not criminations. The question is, will you provide for the defense of our people? I earnestly recommend that you do so promptly. It is our only hope, and only true reliance. All that I could do to stay this danger has been done. It is before us, and you remain the last and only power to which I can appeal for the protection of our people.</p>
<p>THOS. E. BRAMLETTE
<lb/>By the Governor: 
<lb/>E.L. VANWINKLE, Secretary of State.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
