<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0166"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Commonwealth of Kentucky v. Joseph Shoenberger, Transcript</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4285</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-260 to BR8-270</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">(1st)</note>
<lb/><date when="1863-05">May Term 1863</date> of the Jefferson Circuit Court
<lb/>The Commonwealth of Kentucky Plff
<lb/>against
<lb/>Joseph Shounberg by -- that is Shenneberger Deft</p>
<p>Indicted with one Elisha Applegate, charged with Robbing the house of M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Elizabeth Newton on the day of <date when="1863-01">Janry 1863</date>, the parties claimed seperate trials and upon the trial of Said Joseph Shenneberger the following Witnesses were introduced in behalf of the Commonwealth to wit</p>
<p>1<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">st</hi></hi> M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi>. Elizabeth Newton -- who states an oath that She lived on the Shelby Street Plank road near the City of Louisville that she is a widow, and that on Saturday night the <gap/> day of <date when="1863-01">January 1863</date> about 10 oclock at night, she and her granddaughter Miss Ann J Newton were -- aroused from their sleep by Some ones trying to break into the house at the front door, and demanding admittence -- that she got up opened the door and that Elisha Applegate Came into the house and Said that he was a government Soldier and was hunting for government property -- that he had the right to take what he pleased -- that the house was surrounded with soldiers -- that he had a shot gun in one hand and a pistol in the other -- that there was no one in the house but witness -- the grand Daughter of witness and two or three small children -- that he told us if we made any noise he would burn the house -- that he took and carried away 4 wollen Blankets worth $10 a log chain worth $5 -- a musket worth $<gap/> and one Bridle worth $200 that she said Shenneberger standing at the yard gate <gap/> yards from the house -- that she and her grand ^(Applegate had a large, fierce looking dog with him which he fre-<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">(2<hi rend="sup">d</hi>)</note>
<lb/>quently whistled to while in the house &amp; the dog would then growl fiercely)^ Daugther Miss Ann J Netwon again went to bed and went to sleep and that at about 4 oclock the same night Applegate again returned to the house and awoke them and forced them to let him into the house -- that that she again said Shenneberger standing at the gate where he stood the first time that Applegate then took and Carried away two sheets worth $3 -- two quilts worth $15 and Some other articles ^using threat &amp; putting un in fear^ never saw Applegate before that night but knows possitively he was the man who took her property, that Shenneberger did not come in the house or inside the yard gate, that she recognized Shenneberger -- that he had on a soldiers Blaizer -- that she knew him well -- that he lived about 200 yards from her house -- that Applegate had on a coat like one she had colord for Shenneberger -- believed it to be the same -- that Shenneberger cursed Applegate at the gate in English for taking the musket &amp; said it was the last thing they wanted -- that she offered Applegate the money for the things he took and he would not receive the money -- that it was a moon light night and she did not give any alarm -- that Frank Aikens her friend lived in about 150 yards of her<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">(3<hi rend="sup">d</hi>)</note></p>
<p>Miss Ann J Newton -- am the Grand Daughter of M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Elizabeth Newton -- that she concurs with M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Elizabeth Newton as to the taking of the articles -- their value and the manner they were taken &amp;c, recognized Shenneberger standing at the gate when Applegate robbed the house knew him well -- it was a moon -- light night -- Saw Applegate &amp; Shenneberger leave together at the gate and go to Shennebergers house and go in Saw them all the way from our house to Shennebergers house and cannot be mistaken -- the Distance is about 200 yards -- stood in our door &amp; saw them go into his Door -- there are several fences between our house and his the next morning My Grand Mother M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Elizabeth Newton Sent me to Deft Shennebergers to borrow milk for breakfast -- that My Grand Ma M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Elizabeth Newton did not recognize that night <hi rend="str">recognize</hi> Shenneberger as the man who stood at the gate said she did not know who it was and was said all the time she did not know who the man was who stood out side at the gate, that her Grand Ma stated in the police court that she heard a man outside but did not see him that night, Said that Applegate threatened to kill them and burn the house if they interfered and that they were all -- greatly alarmed (Sam Shenneberger take about one half the goods from Applegate, when Applegate left the house &amp; as Applegate passed through the gate at which Shenneberger was standing -- both then proceeded immediately into Shennebergers house, near by)(Com' attty)<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">(4th)</note></p>
<p>Frank Aikens -- lives about 150 yards from M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Netwons on the Same side of the road Shenneberger lives on the opposite side of the road from M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi>. Newtons and nearly Square off of the road from My grocery about 175 to two hundred yards my grocery is close to the road Shennebergers house is some 200 yards or more froim M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Netwons there are several fences between their houses, on the evening before the robbery was committed Shenneberger Called at my house, he was in the habit of calling there frequently, and while there (I suppose it was between 7 &amp; 8 o clock) <hi rend="str">Came</hi> Applegate Came, Applegate had a large Dog and a shot gun, Applegate wanted to trade off the Dog and Shenneberger Said he had two Dogs &amp; would trade with him Either of his dogs &amp; give him boot Shenneberger and Applegate Seemed to be strangers to each other, &amp; in fact I think they were entire Strangers to each other, they left my house together between seven &amp; eight oclock as I thought to complete the dog trade, &amp; I saw nothing more of Either that night the next day M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi>. Newton came to my house and asked me who had been to my house the evening before and I told her that Applegate been there ^with^ Shenneberger, She then said that they were the men who robbed her house, her Grand Daughter Anne J. Newton was with her and -- neither spoke of Shennebergers being -- present untill I told them that both Shenneberger &amp; Applegate had been at my house the Evening before the robbery was committed -- See 5th Sheet<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">(5th)</note>
<lb/>Continuation of Frank Aikens Testimony</p>
<p>I am acquainted with the Deft Joseph Shenneberger he is a near neighbour of mine, his character for honesty is good -- he is a hard-working honest industrious man is a man of a family<pb/></p>
<p><note place="header">(6th)</note>
<lb/>Thomas Ryan I am a police officer I arrested Joseph Shenneberger the accused -- found some of the articles named by M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi>. Newton in an out house about <gap/> yards from Shennebergers house the house was not occupied, cant say who had controle of it the goods were found hid up in the chimmney -- pressed in very tight &amp; <unclear/>in black<unclear/> -- (<hi rend="underline">com atty</hi>)<pb/></p>
<p><note place="header">(7th)</note>
<lb/>The following is the testimony offered for Deft Joseph Shenneberger To Wit</p>
<p>1st Jefferson Williams who being sworn states that he had examined the locality of M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Elizabeth Newtons house where the robbery is said to have taken place also the house that Shenneberger occupied -- the house where the goods stolen is said to have been found and the location of the grocery of Frank Aikens where Shenneberger and Applegate is said to have been seen together the Evening before the robbery was committed &amp;c -- He says that M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Elizabeth Newton lived about one mile from Louisville on the Shelby Strret road west side -- that Aikens grocery is on the same side of the road about 150 yards from M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Newtons between her house and Louisville -- that Shenneberger lived about 225 yards from M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Newtons on the East Side of the road and Square off of the road from Aikens grocery -- that the house where the good were found was about 133 yards from Shennebergers house, and a little to the right of Shennebergers house, but pretty much in the same direction from M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Newtons house that he had in company with M<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. Price Steped the ground and Examined the premises -- that on a straight line between M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Newtons house and Shennebergers there are four fences (two plank and two rail) that the fence nearest Shennebergers house is about 8 or ten Steps from the house a very close rail fince and at least 5 feet high, that he stood in the door of M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Newton and looked to the house of Shenneberger and is Sattisfied that Even in day time you could not more than see the head of a man when he would Enter the door of Shennebergers house and that he does not believe it possible for any^one^ in the night time to stand at M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Netwons house (over)<pb/>
<lb/>and See a person Enter Shennebergers house that Shennebergers house does not directly front M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Newtons house but that the End of Shennebergers house is next to the road -- that the road where M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Newtons house stands make a curve which gives her a partial side view of the Entrance to Shennebergers house -- that the distance from M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Newtons house to the gate at which it is ^said^ Shenneberger was standing when Applegate robbed the house is 35 steps and that he does not believe that a person could be recognized in the night time under the circumstances detailed by the Witnesses -- at least Witness could not, he says that he has known, the Deft Shenneberger 7. or. 8 years that Shenneberger has worked for witness one or two years that he speaks Very bad English so much so that Witness cannot understand one half he says -- (that Deft is a very hard working -- industrious honest man -- and he believe as honest as any man -- that he is a man of a family) Brackets put by "<hi rend="underline">com atty</hi>"</p>
<p>Witness stated that -- he did not know how light a night it was upon which the robery was perpetrated -- but asserted the general proposition that he did not believe that the <hi rend="underline">countenance</hi> of a man could be recognized by moonlight at a distance of <hi rend="underline">thirty-five yards</hi><pb/></p>
<p><note place="header">(8<hi rend="sup">th</hi>)</note>
<lb/>D<hi rend="sup">r</hi> J. S. Seaton had known Deft from <date when="1857">1857</date> or <date when="1858">1858</date> that Deft had worked for him some four months during one of those years his character was then good that he regarded him as a Very trustworthy faithful man that he had known but little of him Since and that he never heard his character for honesty doubted that he was a hardworking moral man -- had'nt known him for the last two or ^three years^ M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> M Goss called -- have known Deft 7 or 8 years during the time his character has been first rate never heard any thing wrong alledged against him he is industrious and had worked a good Eal for me on my favor</p>
<p>M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Thos Goss called -- am the Son of the last wit and fully concur with my father in his -- statements as to Defts character</p>
<p>Mag<hi rend="sup">r</hi>. B. Farmer -- have known Deft intimately 5 or 6 years had worked with him more than a year knew him to be an industrious faithful honest man his character was unexceptional</p>
<p>W. G. Reasor Esq<hi rend="sup">r</hi> I am the City attorney for Louisville Applegate was arrested and tried first I prosecuted him -- I was not present the day that Deft Shenneberger was tried in the City Court My recollection is that upon the trial of Applegate that M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> Elizabeth Newton Swore she did not know who the man was that stood at the gate when applegate robbed the house and neither M<hi rend="sup">rs</hi> E. Newton or her Grand daughter <hi rend="str">in their testimony</hi> Miss Ann J Newton in their testimony spoke of Shenneberger as the man who stood at the gate or said that they knew who that man was<pb/></p>
<p><note place="header">9</note>
<lb/>Addenda by com' atty It was proven by the officer who made the arrest that as soon as he heard of the commission of the offense he went in search of deft went to his house could'nt find him, -- returned to the city &amp; still could'nt find him &amp; then posted himself near defts house &amp; after waiting some time said defts wife drive up to defts house in a wagon -- get out -- unharness the horse milk the cow, bring water &amp;c &amp; at length return to the city in the wagon -- officer followed ^her^ to a certain house in the city where he found deft -- who, as soon as he saw policeman, made haste to escape.</p>
<p>It was also shown that in one of the matrasses in Shenebergers house (by officer) there was found (in the inside of the matrass) a soldiers overcoat of such material as is generally<pb/> 
<lb/><note place="header">10</note>
<lb/>furnished by the US to her soldiers which evidently presented the appearance of having been dyed. The officer described the color as being the same color &amp; the coat as being the same kind of coat which Mrs Newton stated she had dyed herself &amp; as having been taken from her house. It was <hi rend="str">shown</hi> stated by officer who made arrest that Shenneber spoke <hi rend="underline">intelligible</hi> English when arrested, that at that time he understood his conversation without any difficulty -- &amp; that while as Shennebergers he looked over frequently towards Newtons &amp; while at Newtons he looked over towards Shennebergers &amp; that there would be in his opinion no difficulty in seeing the upper half of the form of a man, when standing in either door ^in entering the door of the other house.^ -- the witness spoke positively that the fences which were between the places<pb/>
<lb/><note place="header">11</note>
<lb/>did not preclude the possibility of one's being recognized from one tenement to the other -- thought not only that it might probably ^be^ done but was positive the fences did not so obstruct the view as to prevent its being easily done -- com atty"</p>
<p>The foregoing Eleven pages Embrace about the substance of the testimony in the above styled cause, at least as near so as can now be obtained it being written principally from memory</p>
<p>J R Dupuy
<lb/>Com' atty 7th judicial Dist</p>
<p>Louisville <hi rend="str">May</hi> <date when="1863-06-07">June 7, 1863</date></p>
<p>Mr Dupuy having signed and certified the evidence in the above case I will add that I am satisfied he would not have so certified but for his belief in its correctness.</p>
<p>P. B. Muir<pb/></p>
<p>This man ought not to have been convicted and the affidavits in connection with the evidence satisfy me that he is not guilty I therefore in Justice to him and consideration of the innocent order his pardon. <date when="1863-10-02">Oct 2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> 1863</date></p>
<p>Tho E Bramlette</p>
<p>This case upon the facts presents some difficulty in to the identity of the Deft. The uncertainty of all human evidence is one of the great difficulties in <unclear>customary trick</unclear> </p>
<p>The Jury are the chosen <unclear/> of fact. I cannot say that their verdict in this case is wrong or even that I would have found differently. I do not think the case is one for Executive interference</p>
<p>J F Robinson</p>
<p>Comth
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Shenneberger</p>
<p>Jefferson Co
<lb/>Pardon
<lb/>J. Shenneberger
<lb/><date when="1863-10-02">2<hi rend="sup">nd</hi> Oct/m63</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
