<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-022-0002"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">John Wood, Requisition</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG2900</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Elizabeth J Van Allen</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Beriah Magoffin: Governor's Official Correspondence File, Requisitions for the Return of Fugitives from Justice, 1859-1861</collection>
      <idno>MG7-150 to MG7-154</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Springfield, Sangamon County, Illinois</placeName>
    <date when="1860-12-06">6 December 1860</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Legal/Financial</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>JOHN WOOD,
<lb/><figure type="seal"><ab>STATE SOVEREIGNTY.
<lb/>NATIONAL UNION</ab></figure>
<lb/>Governor of the State of Illinois,
<lb/>To His Excellency, the Governor of Kentucky</p>
<p>It appears by the annexed papers, duly authenticated, according to the Laws of this State, that Henry Parish stands charged in Brown County with the crime of Murder and it has been represented to me that he has fled from the justice of this State, and has taken refuge in the State of Kentucky</p>
<p>Now, Therefore, Pursuant to the provisions of the Constitution and Laws of the United States, in such case made and provided, I do hereby require that the said Henry Parish -- be apprehended and delivered to Robert A. Cox who is hereby duly authorized to receive him and convey him to the State of Illinois, there to be dealth with according to Law.</p>
<p><figure type="seal"/></p>
<p>In Testimony Whereof, I have hereunto set my Hand and caused the Great Seal of State to be hereunto affixed. Done at the City of Springfield, this <date when="1860-12-06">sixth day of December in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and sixty,</date> and of the Independence of the United States the eighty-fifth.</p>
<p>John Wood</p>
<p>BY THE GOVERNOR:<hi rend="underline">
<lb/>O. M. Hatch</hi>
<lb/>Secretary of State.<pb/></p>
<p>State of Illinois
<lb/>Brown County } ss</p>
<p>Of the <date when="1860-05">May Term of the Brown Circuit Court in the year of our Lord 1860.</date> The Grand Jurors chosen, selected and sworn in and for the County of Brown in the name and by the authority of the People of the State of Illinois, upon then oaths present. That Henry Parish and Charles Riddle on the <date when="1859-11-26">twenty sixth day of November, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and fifty-nine,</date> at and within the County of Brown and state of Illinois, not having the fear of God before their eyes, but being moved and seduced by the instigation of the devil, with force and arms in and upon one Jonah Clark, in the Peace of the People of the said State of Illinois, then and there being unlawfully, feloniously wifully and of their malice aforethought did make an assault; and that the said Henry Parish and Charles Riddle with a certain knife of the value of ten cents which he the said Henry Parish in his right hand then and there had and held, the said Josiah Clark in and upon the right side of him the said Josiah Clark then and there unlawfully, feloniously wilfully and of their<pb/>
<lb/>malice aforethought, did strike and thrust, giving to the said Jonah Clark then and there with the knife aforesaid, in and upon the right side of him the said Josiah Clark one mortal wound of the breadth of ten inches and of the depth of six inches, of which said mortal wound the said Jonah Clark from the said <date when="1859-11-26">six day of November in the year aforesaid</date> until the <date when="1859-11-27">twenty seventh day of November in the year aforesaid</date> in the said County of Brown and State of Illinois, did languish and languishing did live; on which said <date when="1859-11-27">twenty seventh day of November in the year aforesaid</date> the said Jonah Clark at the County and state aforesaid of the said mortal wound died; and so the Grand Jurors aforesaid, upon their oaths aforesaid do say that the said Henry Parish and Charles Riddle the said Jonah Clark in manner and form aforesaid, unlawfully, feloniously, wilfully and of their malice aforethought, did kill and murder, Contrary to the form of the Statute in such case made and provided and against the peace and dignity of the same People of the State of Illinois</p>
<p>And the Grand Jurors aforesaid upon their oaths aforesaid, in the name and by<pb/>
<lb/>the authority of the People of the State of Illinois aforesaid, do further present, That Henry Parish and Charles Riddle, not having the fear of God before their eyes, but being moved and seduced by the instigation of the devil on the <date when="1859-11-26">twenty sixth day of November, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and fifty nine,</date> and at and within the County of Brown and State of Illinois, with force and arms, in and upon one Jonah Clark in the peace of the said People then and there being unlawfully, feloniously and wilfully and of their malice aforethought did make an assault: and that the said Henry Parish and Charles Riddle with a certain knife of the value of ten cents and of length of six inches which he the said Henry Parish in his right hand then and there had and held the said Jonah Clark in and upon the right side between the sixth and seventh ribs of him the said Jonah Clark then and there unlawfully feloniously and wilfully and of their malice aforethought did strike thrust and stab giving to the said Jonah Clark then and there with the knife aforesaid in and upon the right side <hi rend="str">of</hi><pb/>
<lb/>between the sixth and seventh ribs of him the said Jonah Clark one mortal wound of the breadth of two inches ^and of the depth of six inches^ of which said mortal wound the said Josiah Clark from the said <date when="1859-11-26">twenty sixth day of November in the year <hi rend="str">aforesaid</hi> of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and fifty nine</date> until the <date when="1859-11-27">twenty seventh day of November in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and fifty nine</date> in the County of Brown aforesaid did languish and languishing did live, on which said <date when="1859-11-27">twenty seventh day of November in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and fifty nine</date> the said Jonah Clark at and within the said County of Brown of the said mortal wound died; and so the Grand Jurors aforesaid, upon their oaths aforesaid, do say that the said Henry Parish and Charles Riddle the said Jonah Clark in manner and form aforesaid unlawfully, feloniously wilfullly and of their malice aforethought did kill and murder, Contrary to the form of the statute in such case made and provided and against the peace and dignity of the same people of the state of Illinois,<pb/>
<lb/>And the Grand Jurors aforesaid, upon their oaths aforesaid, in the name and by the authority of the People of the State of Illinois, aforesaid do further present that Henry Parish and Charles Riddle not having the fear of God before their eyes, but being moved and seduced by the instigation of the devil on the <date when="1859-11-26">twenty six day of November, in the year of our Lord one thousand eight hundred and fifty nine</date> at and within the County of Brown an State of Illinois, with force and arms in and upon one Jonah Clark in the peace of the said people of the state of Illinois then and there being, unlawfullly feloniously wilfully and of their malice aforethought did make an assault; and that the said Henry Parish with a certain knife ^of the length of six inches and^ of the value of ten cents which he the said Henry Parish in his right hand then and there had and held the said Jonah Clark in and upon the right side, below the ribs of him the said Jonah Clark then and there unlawfully feloniously wilfully and of their malice aforethought did did strike thrust and stab, giving to the said Jonah Clark then and there with the knife aforesaid<pb/> 
<lb/>in and upon the right side, below the ribs of him the said Jonah Clark one mortal wound of the breadth of two inches and of the depth of six inches, of which said mortal wound the said Jonah Clark from the said <date when="1859-11-26">twenty sixth day of November in the year last aforesaid,</date> until the <date when="1859-11-27">twenty seventh day of the same month of November in the year last aforesaid</date> at and within the said County of Brown and State of Illinois did languish and languishing did live; on which said <date when="1859-11-27">twenty seventh day of November in the year last aforesaid</date> the said Jonah Clark at and within the said County of Brown of the said mortal wound died; and that the aforesaid Charles Riddle then and there unlawfully feloniously wilfullly and of his malice aforethought was present aiding, abetting assisting and maintaining the said Henry Parish the felony and Murder and manner and form aforesaid to do and commit And so the Grand Jurors aforesaid, upon their oaths aforesaid do say that the said Henry Parish and the said Charles Riddle the said Jonah Clark then and there in manner and<pb/>
<lb/>form aforesaid, unlawfully feloniously wilfully and of their malice aforethought did kill and murder, contrary to the form of the Statue in such case made and provided and against the peace and dignity of the same people of the state of Illinois</p>
<p>L. H. Waters
<lb/>State attorney 5<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> Judicial Circuit Illinois</p>
<p>State of Illinois
<lb/>Brown County } SS</p>
<p>I A A Glenn Clerk of the Circuit Court of said County of Brown do hereby certify that the above and foregoing is a true and perfect and complete copy of an indictment found by the Grand Jury of said county at the <date when="1860-05">May Term A D 1860</date> of the Circuit Court of said County against Henry Parish and Charles Riddle for Murder, and that said copy is correctly made -- I further certify that the endorsements on the back of said indictment are correctly hereon</p>
<p><figure type="seal"/></p>
<p>In testimony whereof I have hereto set my hand and the seal of said court this <date when="1860-08-09">9<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi> day of August AD 1860 -- </date></p>
<p>A A Glenn Clerk<pb/></p>
<p>Illinois<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Warrant
<lb/>Iss<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">ed</hi></hi> for Henry Parrish for Murder
<lb/><date when="1860-12-10">Dec 10. 1860</date></p>
<p>The People of the State of Illinois
<lb/>vs
<lb/>Henry Parrish and Charles Riddle<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Indictment for Murder<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>A true Bill
<lb/>William See
<lb/>Foreman of the Grand Jury<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Witnesses
<lb/>Charles Clark
<lb/>Soloman W Lake
<lb/>William G. Irvine
<lb/>Joseph A Cox
<lb/>Calvin Wilson
<lb/>David Brown
<lb/>Joseph J Hedrick
<lb/>Eli Barker
<lb/>David F Orr
<lb/>John C Orr
<lb/>James Hemphill
<lb/>Joseph R Lear
<lb/>George W Emerick
<lb/>Wesley Six
<lb/>Hiram Barker Jr</p>
<p>Dr Andrew J Stiner
<lb/>William F. Cox.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
