<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-3489"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Shadrach Combs et al. to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG5608</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR42-422 to BR42-423</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <date>n.d.</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Thomas E Bramlett
<lb/>Gov of Ky</p>
<p>We would respectfully represent that in <date when="1864-05">May 1864</date> a horse was taken from Elihu Wells in Perry County &amp; John Pace was suspected of stealing said horse. William <hi rend="str">Cooks</hi> ^Coats^ a young man who is a cripple was <hi rend="str">tr</hi> travelling from Harlan to Clay county on foot and Pace let him ride the horse &amp; he was seen with it, there was but little proof against Pace &amp; it was intended to use Coots as a witness but as he did not reside in Perry County the grand Jury of Said county returned an indictment against Pace &amp; him jointly so that the Whole facts could be brought out, they were both arrested &amp; previous to the present term of the Perry Circuit Court Pace died;</p>
<p>The prosecution &amp; the Community are satisfied that Coots is not guilty yet he was seen in possession of the horse &amp; can make no proof whatever as to how he came by him- Coots is a young man of good character is very poor- &amp; it will of necessity<pb/>
<lb/>put him to great troube &amp; expense to defend the case &amp; as the whole object was to try to convict Pace who was the guilty party We Earnestly hope your Excellency will pardon the said William Coots.</p>
<p>Shadrach Combs
<lb/>John A Duff
<lb/>M L Rice
<lb/>Rob<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Braddaus Jr
<lb/><unclear/> Clark
<lb/>Joseph Hill
<lb/>John F. Begley
<lb/>Johnny Yonger
<lb/><unclear/> Combs
<lb/>Wm <unclear/>
<lb/>John Dishman
<lb/><unclear/> Lucas
<lb/>William Baker
<lb/>G W Davis
<lb/>William Sizemore
<lb/>W C Fields
<lb/>G H morgan
<lb/>Samuel Combs
<lb/><unclear/> Lyttle
<lb/>L A Ryner
<lb/>Robert Hamilton<pb/></p>
<p>We are satisfied that the within named William Coots ought to be pardoned_</p>
<p>Granville Pearl
<lb/>H. F. Finley
<lb/>Josiah.H. Combs<pb/></p>
<p>Perry
<lb/>Rejected
<lb/><hi rend="underline">John Pace</hi></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
