<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0001-004-0169"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">Charles Smith to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG4288</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Matthew C Hulbert</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department for Libraries and Archives</repository>
      <collection>Office of the Governor, Thomas E. Bramlette: Governor's official correspondence file, petitions for pardons, remissions, and respites 1863-1867</collection>
      <idno>BR8-273 to BR8-274</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Louisville, Jefferson County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1863-10-30">30 October 1863</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Petition</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p>To His Excellency
<lb/>Hon. Thos. E. Bramlette
<lb/>Governor of Kentucky &amp;c.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner, Charles Smith, would respectfully represent that he is a young man, and never until called to answer this Indictment, under which, as the accompanying certificate of the Clerk will show, he was convicted has he been charged with the commission of any crime.</p>
<p>He would further state ^that^ for five years last past he has been a faithful soldier for the Government, and was seriously wounded, being shot through the lungs at the battle of Stone River, from which wound he long languished in the hospital in this City (Louisville Ky.)</p>
<p>He further states that he is very poor and counsel was assigned him by the Court, upon the trial of his case, he not being able to employ counsel of his own selection. He was charged with stealing some five or six dollars in Treasury notes and at the time he was destitute and influenced by intoxication.</p>
<p>Your Excellency will see from the accompanying certificate of the Clerk that<pb/>
<lb/>the Jury in their Verdict have recommended your Petitioner to Executive Clemency. He desires to rejoin his Regiment (the 3<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> United States Regular Cavalry) and live an honest life.</p>
<p>Your Petitioner finally states that he has a widowed Mother dependent for her support on his earnings, that he has always remitted to her the larger portion of his income and will continue so to do as long as her and his life are spared.</p>
<p>He humbly prays Your Excellency to exercise your power of pardon in his case and restore him to liberty and he will ever continue to pray.</p>
<p>Charles ^his X mark^ Smith</p>
<p>Subscribed and sworn to by Charles Smith before me this <date when="1863-10-13">thirtieth day of October 1863</date></p>
<p>Jno H Talbott
<lb/>Notary Publick
<lb/>Jefferson County</p>
<p><figure type="seal"><ab>JNO. H. TALBOTT
<lb/>NOTARY
<lb/>PUBLIC.
<lb/>JEFFERSON CO., KY.</ab></figure></p>
<p>As the Jury have recommended Charles Smith to Executive Clemency I am induced also to ask his pardon resplly &amp;c</p>
<p>P. B. Muir
<lb/>W. G. Reasor<pb/></p>
<p>We the undersigned Jurors who tried the case of the Commonwealth vs. Charles Smith join with him in his Petition to your Excellency and recommend him to Executive Clemency.</p>
<p>J H Meyers foreman
<lb/>S A Hartwell
<lb/>W. W. Owens
<lb/>M. Billing
<lb/>Hu Arterburn
<lb/>Leams Hughs
<lb/>W<hi rend="sup">m</hi> Winston
<lb/>John Ashwraft<pb/></p>
<p>Petition
<lb/>Geo. Kilpatrick.</p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
