<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="KYR-0002-225-0040"> 
 <teiHeader>
  <fileDesc>
   <titleStmt>
    <title level="a" type="main">R. V. Grinter to Thomas E. Bramlette</title>
    <title level="a" type="parallel">CWG14069</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="transcriber">Transcribed by:</resp>
     <name>Whitney R Smith</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="proof_1">Single Proof by:</resp>
     <name>Christina K Adkins</name>
    </respStmt>
    <respStmt>
     <resp n="encoding">Markup by:</resp>
     <name>Anthony P Curtis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </titleStmt>
   <publicationStmt>
    <publisher>Kentucky Historical Society</publisher>
    <pubPlace>Frankfort, Kentucky</pubPlace>
    <availability>
     <p>This image and transcription is publicly accessible. The image appears courtesy of the repository named in the Source Description. The transcription and annotation were undertaken by Kentucky Historical Society staff, volunteers, and interns. If referencing this document title, accession number, and permanent URL.</p>
    </availability>
   </publicationStmt>
   <seriesStmt>
    <title level="s" type="main">Civil War Governors of Kentucky Digital Documentary Edition</title>
     <title level="s" type="sub">Early Access</title>
    <respStmt>
     <resp>Project Director</resp>
     <name>Patrick A. Lewis</name>
    </respStmt>
   </seriesStmt>
   <sourceDesc>
    <msDesc>
    <msIdentifier>
      <country>UNITED STATES</country>
      <region>KY</region>
      <settlement>Frankfort</settlement>
      <repository>Kentucky Department of Military Affairs</repository>
      <collection>Guerilla Letters</collection>
      <idno>Document Box 1, Folder G. L. 1864</idno>
     </msIdentifier>
    </msDesc>
   </sourceDesc>
  </fileDesc>
  <profileDesc>
   <creation>
    <placeName>Cadiz, Trigg County, Kentucky</placeName>
    <date when="1864-05-23">23 May 1864</date>
   </creation>
   <textClass>
    <keywords>
     <term type="genre">Correspondence</term>
    </keywords>
   </textClass>
  </profileDesc>
 </teiHeader>
 <text>
  <body>
   <p><note place="header">Rec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 26<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">th</hi></hi>
<lb/>P. 12<figure type="hr"/></note>
<lb/>Cadiz Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-05-23">May 23<hi rend="sup">rd</hi> 1864</date>
<lb/>Your Exclellency
<lb/>Tho Bramlette</p>
<p>In the deplorable condition of our County I am compelled to write to you for if Something isn't done the People will be entirely broken up -- we hear evry day the Stealing of Horses by Guerrillas Stores broken open &amp; Pilliaged and plundered by these theiving bands -- our County has Several small band which are continually prowling <hi rend="str">along -- </hi>around I propose Sir that you give me Permission to raise a few men for the purpose of repelling these Scoundrels, the troops at Hopkinsville our nearest Military post affords us (Very little protection -- </p>
<p>these men I propose to get up Can Mount, themselves or most of them and our rendevous will be Golden Ponds or near Cantron Ky </p>
<p>these men are for six months -- for which the County will be creditied by the reason I propose being Stationed at Ferngoner Golden Pond is that the Citizens an ^the^ furthest from any Military post of any Citizens in the County, are More Exposed being between the Rivers ^and^ are <hi rend="str">are</hi> in great danger of being broken up at any time the Supplies for the men can be had very Easily, from Paducah -- by way of ^the^ Rivers,<pb/>
<lb/><unclear/> will be a very Easy thing to get one Hundred Men in this County for Six Months Service -- </p>
<p>If you approve of the plan proposed I wish you would at once write me So that I can at once proceed to the work</p>
<p>Your Friend
<lb/>R. V. Grinter
<lb/>Late of 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> Ky Cavalry U, S,<pb/></p>
<p>Cadiz Ky
<lb/><date when="1864-05-23">May 23<hi rend="sup">d</hi> 1864</date><figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Grinter R. V.<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>To the Governor stating the condition of his section of country, here overrun by guerrillas &amp;<hi rend="underline"><hi rend="sup">c</hi></hi> and desires authority to recruit a company for 6 months<figure type="hr"/></p>
<p>L B. N<hi rend="sup">o</hi> 4 -- <date when="1864">1864</date> P. 12<figure type="hr"/>
<lb/>Rec<hi rend="sup">d</hi> A G. O. <date when="1864-05-26">26 May 1864</date></p>
  </body>
 </text>
</TEI>
